<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nynephhs">nynephhs0003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Bernard/Crispell Family Papers</titleproper><author>Eric Roth</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2016-11-18">November 18, 2016</date><address><addressline>Historic Huguenot Street</addressline><addressline>88 Huguenot St, New Paltz, NY 12561</addressline></address><publisher>Historic Huguenot Street</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nynephhs.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Bernard/Crispell Family Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1824/1973" type="inclusive">1824/1973</unitdate><abstract>?</abstract><physdesc><extent>.25 cu.ft.</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><famname>Crispell Family</famname></origination></did><accessrestrict><p>Unrestricted</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>Reuben Bernard (1830-1916), lawyer in Kingston, NY, was born to David Lawrence Bernard and Abigail Demarest at the town of Plattekill in Ulster County. On June 3, 1856, he married Jane Catharine Crispell (1833-1903), daughter of Gerrit DuBois Crispell and Sarah P. Post. They had three children, Mary, Amelia, and Sarah.
Reuben Bernard earned his education at the New Paltz Academy and Amenia Seminary before beginning his career at Forsyth &amp; Hasbrouck the law firm in Kingston, NY in 1849. He attended law school in Ballston Spa in 1851, where he received a license to practice law in the Circuit Court of the United States. Bernard also worked as an attorney for several area banks and the Wallkill Valley Railroad. Positions as director or president include Kingston National Bank, Kingston &amp; Rondout Railroad, Wallkill Valley Railroad, Kingston Board of Trade, and Ulster County Sunday School Association.
Other individuals represented in the papers include Bernard’s father-in-law Gerrit DuBois Crispell (1801-1880), physician at Kingston and Hurley; Bernard’s grandson Reuben Bernard Crispell (1889-1967), lawyer and past Crispell Family Association president; and Bernard’s great-nephew Lawrence Stearns Crispell (b. 1919), physician and past Crispell Family Association president.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><p>Records include deeds, wills, law licenses, letters, memorial notices, marriage, baptism and membership certificates, financial papers, letters testamentary, and other materials concerning Gerrit DuBois Crispell, Reuben Bernard and wife Jane Catherine Crispell, Henry S. Crispell and wife Amelia Bernard, Reuben Crispell, and Lawrence Crispell. </p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>?</p></userestrict></archdesc></ead>