<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nynephhs">nynephhs0002</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Ayres Family Letters (1839-1900)</titleproper>
                <author>Eric Roth</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-07-01">July 1, 2016</date>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Historic Huguenot Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>88 Huguenot St, New Paltz, NY 12561</addressline>
                </address>
                <publisher>Historic Huguenot Street</publisher>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nynephhs.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Ayres Family Letters (1839-1900)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1839/1900" type="inclusive">1839 - 1900</unitdate>
            <abstract>Letters from various Ayres family members from Libertyville, NY. The collection primarily contains letters written by James and Alexander Ayres during the Civil War.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>.2 cu.ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination/>
        </did><bioghist><p>James and Alexander are the sons of Philip Ayres and Sarah Ann Requa. Philip and Sarah married in the Guilford Church on December 12, 1839. Sarah was the daughter of Gilbert Kipp Requa and Elizabeth Woolsey. Philip was died sometime between 1852 and 1855. Sarah married John Eyett by 1859, who James addresses letters to at this time.

 The Ayres family can be found in the 1850 United States Census.  Philip Ayres, a 30-year old carpenter livedin New Paltz with his wife, 29 year-old Sarah D. Ayres, three children, James N. (aged 9), Alexander (aged 7), and Albert (aged 1). Also listed is Elizabeth Requa, who is Sarah’s mother. The New York State Census of 1855, however, lists Sarah A. Ayres as a 36 year-old widow, working as a ‘tailoress’ in the town Lloyd, with two sons, Albert and Phillip. Alexander Ayres, aged 11, is living in the household of John and Hanna B. Requa in the town of Gardiner.

 Beginning in 1859, letters written by James are addressed to John Eyett of New Paltz Landing (Town of Lloyd), who Sarah married second. In the 1865 Census, Sarah and John both claimed to have married twice, Sarah has claimed to have 10 children; this likely includes John’s children from his first marriage.

 James Ayres joined Company F of the 52nd Illinois Infantry in 1861, was stationed at “Camp Sampson” and Cairo, Illinois, participated in the Battle of Corinth and the Battle of Pittsburgh, and died on October 19, aged 21. Alexander Ayres enlisted with Company I of the Second U.S. Infantry, was primarily stationed near Washington D.C. and died in July, 1863, aged 19. </p></bioghist>
        <accessrestrict>
            
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>James and Alexander Ayres are the sons of Philip Ayres and Sarah Ann Requa. They had a brother, Albert, born in approximately 1849. Philip died sometime between 1850 and 1855. Sarah married John Eyett by 1859. Sarah was the daughter of Gilbert Kipp Requa and Elizabeth Woolsey, born 1819 and died in 1892.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess/>
        <scopecontent>
            
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>