<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nanb">nanb0005</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Jacob Grossberg Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Debra Klein</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2020-03-10">March 10, 2020</date>
                <publisher>Bard College Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Stevenson Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>1 Library Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Annandale-on-Hudson, NY 12504</addressline>
                    <addressline>845-758-7396 </addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Debra Klein</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Jacob Grossberg Sketchbook Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/2003" type="inclusive">1963 - 2003</unitdate>
            <abstract>Jacob "Jake" Grossberg (1932-2014) taught sculpture at Bard College from 1969 until he retired in 1996.  He was also instrumental in developing and starting Bard’s MFA program and was named director of the program in 1981. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1'6" linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Grossberg, Jake,1932-2014</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bard College Archives</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Stevenson Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>1 Library Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Annandale-on-Hudson, NY 12504</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.bard.edu/archives/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is available for viewing in the Special Collections reading room at the Stevenson Library during scheduled hours.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Jacob “ Jake” Grossberg (1932-2014) was called “an unusually knowledgeable craftsman” by Art News, whose sculptures “are paradoxically both powerful and elegant” (The New York Times). He studied at Brooklyn College, where he received his B.A. and M.F.A., and earned an M.A. from Teacher’s College, Columbia University. He began teaching at Bard in 1969, as an assistant professor of sculpture, and was granted tenure three years later. He also helped create Bard’s MFA program, and became director of the program in 1981. In addition to teaching, he participated in numerous shows, including groups shows at the Max Hutchinson Gallery, the Riverside Museum, and the Sculpture Now Gallery, and solo shows at the Neo Persona and Aegis Galleries. His wife, Di Williams ‘66 (Diane Sisson Baldwin), donated this collection to the Bard College Archives on November 28, 2018. On subsequent visits, Ms. Williams provided photographs, reviews, slides, and MFA program literature.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Grossberg, Jake, 1932-2014</persname>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300027354" source="aat">sketchbooks</genreform>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5107221" source="geonames">Annandale-on-Hudson (N.Y.)</geogname>
        <occupation authfilenumber="300025533" source="aat">professors (teachers)</occupation>
        <genreform authfilenumber="300047112" source="aat">public sculpture</genreform>
        <genreform authfilenumber="300168233" source="aat">art criticism</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="" source="aat"/>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Series 2 contains 11 folders of photographs and ephemera dating 1963 – 2003. Folders 1-7 contain photographs, slides, contact sheets, and reviews that are related to sketches or notes in the notebooks; folders 8-11 contain more photographs, slides, contact sheets, flyers, and reviews, some relating to Bard’s MFA program. The contents include contact sheets with some 70 photographs of Grossberg’s sculptures taken by Bard alum Cinthia [sic] Singleton dated 3/1/1982. Sculptures represented include the 1973 steel sculptures "Solstice” and "Mesabh," and the 1973 mild steel sculpture "Tsadi;” the 1978 welded steel sculptures "Two by Two" and "Diagonal Drop” and the 1985 steel and painted wood sculptures "Joie de Vivre," "Mars," and "Ma Jolie." Reviews and articles are from Arts Magazine, The New York Times, Art News, and Art Forum. Galleries mentioned include the Riverside Museum, the Sculpture Now Gallery, and the Max Hutchinson Gallery. Besides photographs of sculptures there is an undated snapshot of Grossberg and Alan Cote; a 1980s photograph of an early MFA class with Grossberg; and a contact sheet with 24 photographs of the sculpture near the Avery Arts Center at Bard College.</p>
        <arrangement>
                <p>This collection consists of 12 notebooks (Series 1) and 11 folders (Series 2). Series 1 is a selection of 12 of Jake Grossberg’s sketchbooks. These sketchbooks include drawings of sculptures in progress, figure drawings, abstract drawings, and studies of faces including rough self-portraits. There is one polished self-portrait dated November 1986. The drawings are in crosshatch, pen and ink and brush and ink, pencil, and what appears to be marker or felt-tipped pen. The sketchbooks appear to have sometimes functioned as journals and contain Grossberg’s highly personal notes of self-reflection; aphorisms about art and making art; and diary entries.</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>This collection contains a mix of copyright statuses.</p>
        </userestrict>
    
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="908ec4_Jacob_Grossberg_Collection_Container_List.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>