<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nanb">nanb0009</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Bard College Board of Trustees Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Debra Klein</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="1897/1994">1897 - 1994</date>
                <publisher>Bard College Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Stevenson Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>1 Library Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Annandale-on-Hudson, NY 12504</addressline>
                    <addressline>845-758-7396 </addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nanb.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bard College Board of Trustees Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1994" type="inclusive">1897 - 1994</unitdate>
            <abstract>Bard College is a private liberal arts college in Annandale-on-Hudson, New York. The Bard College Board of Trustees Collection includes papers related to the functions of the Board of Trustees, encompassing the early years as St. Stephens to the modern Bard College. The collection shows the financial history of the school through the eyes of the trustees, reflecting the progress of the college, including its social life, curriculum development and many other aspects of the management of this college. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>9 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Bard College</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bard College Archives</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Stevenson Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>1 Library Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Annandale-on-Hudson, NY 12504</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.bard.edu/archives/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection has not been digitized. It may be viewed by appointment in the Special Collections Reading Room of the Stevenson Library, Bard College.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Bard College was founded in 1860 as St. Stephen’s, a school for the education of young men intending to enter the Episcopalian ministry. John Bard and his wife, Margaret Taylor Johnston, were the principal founders. The Bards were devout Christian philanthropists. John Bard was a member of an important local family that had strong connections with the Episcopal Church and Columbia University.  Margaret Johnston’s father was a founder of New York University. In 1919 the college began to broaden its mission, adding secular courses to the catalog. In 1928 Bard College merged with Columbia University, in New York City, took control of the college and it became Columbia’s undergraduate school. Its name was changed to Bard College in 1934. Bard ended its relationship with Columbia in 1944 and that same year began admitting women. This collection was compiled by various hands over the years and offers an overview of the history of the College as seen by those most intimately concerned with its administration.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh 98001887" source="lcsh">Episcopalian college students</subject>
            <occupation authfilenumber="300025881" source="aat">trustees</occupation>
            <function authfilenumber="300141693" source="aat">business records</function>
            <function authfilenumber="300133011" source="aat">administration</function>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection consists of reports and documents associated with the work of the Board of Trustees of St. Stephen's College and after 1934, the Bard College Board of Trustees. This collection includes minutes from the regular meetings of the Board, plus minutes from various committees, such as the Executive Committee and the Committee on Campus and Community Relations. There are also President’s Reports, Publications Schedules, Budget Projections, Warden's Reports, Schedules of Disbursements, financial reports, etc. and correspondence. The bulk of the collection is from 1897 to 1974.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>This material is under copyright.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="496869_BCBoard_Trustees_Collection_Container_List.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>