<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nhycia">nhycia0001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Robert and Margie Petersen collection of Scandia Restaurant materials</titleproper><author>Nicole Semenchuk</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2016-05-26">May 26, 2016</date><address><addressline>Culinary Institute of America</addressline><addressline>1946 Campus Dr, Hyde Park, NY 12538</addressline></address><publisher>Culinary Institute of America</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nhycia.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Robert and Margie Petersen collection of Scandia Restaurant materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1985" type="inclusive">1978 - 1985</unitdate><abstract>Bob and Margie Petersen owned the Scandia Restaurant in Los Angeles, California from 1978 to 1985. During that time they kept a scrapbook and files of magazine and newspaper clippings about the restaurant, along with photographs, menus, and recipes.</abstract><physdesc><extent>c</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="270467115" source="viaf">Petersen, Margie 1935-2011</persname></origination><repository>Archives and Special Collections, Conrad N. Hilton Library, The Culinary Institute of America</repository></did><custodhist><p>Donated to The Culinary Institute of America by the Petersen estate in 2013.</p></custodhist><accessrestrict><p>Open for research by appointment. Contact the Archives and Special Collections in the Conrad N. Hilton Library to inquire about the collection or to schedule an appointment.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>Robert E. Petersen (1926-2007), a native of Los Angeles, was a publishing magnate (particularly of automobile-related magazines, like Hot Rod and Motor Trend). He founded the Petersen Automotive Museum in 1994. Bob and his wife, Margie McNally Petersen (1935-2011), had their wedding reception at Scandia in 1963 and ate there frequently before purchasing the establishment from founder Ken Hansen in 1978. (Hansen had opened Scandia in 1946.) Located on Sunset Boulevard, the restaurant was popular with movie stars and specialized in Scandinavian cuisine.</p></bioghist><controlaccess><subject>Restaurants--California--Los Angeles</subject><corpname>Scandia Restaurant (Los Angeles, Calif.)</corpname><geogname authfilenumber="5368361" source="geonames">Los Angeles (Calif.)</geogname><subject authfilenumber="sh85101195" source="lcsh">Photographs</subject></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>c</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>c</p></userestrict></archdesc></ead>