<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nmbries">nmbries0002</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>TEST Guide to the Cary Institute Archives</titleproper>
                <author>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-09">May 9, 2017</date>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</addressline>
                    <addressline>PO Box AB</addressline>
                    <addressline>Millbrook, New York 12545-0129</addressline>
                </address>
                <publisher>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</publisher>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Guide created by Amy Schuler.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>TEST Cary Institute Archives</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate">1967-2003</unitdate>
            <abstract>Documents and materials that chronicle the history of the Cary Arboretum, Institute of Ecosystem Studies, and the Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies.  Includes some presentations and speeches, awards, committee reports, reports and official documents resulting from other leadership roles within Cary, papers of the Director/President, scientist interviews, Master Plans for the Arboretum and other NYBG materials (1970-1983), Mary Cary oral history project (audio tapes, report, and correspondence from Cary Trust).  Cary photo and slide collection is separate, see _________________.  
</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>103 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname source="viaf" authfilenumber="127083667">Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>PO Box AB</addressline>
                    <addressline>Millbrook, NY 12545-0129</addressline>
                    <addressline>845-677-7600 x164</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.caryinstitute.org "/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <arrangement>
            <p>Most of these boxes were processed during a previous attempt to organize the archives. It appears that boxes of file folders from scientists and staff who left the Cary Arboretum in the 1970s and 1980s were transferred to the archive with minimal processing.  Later boxes (90-103) were processed in 2003.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is closed to the public.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>In 1967, Mary Flagler Cary left her 2,000 acre Millbrook estate to a charitable organization “engaged in the conservation, maintenance, and preservation of natural resources".  In 1971, the Mary Flagler Charitable Trust accepted a proposal from the New York Botanical Garden to establish an arboretum devoted to research and educational activities.  The Mary Flagler Cary Arboretum opened to the public in 1977.  
</p>
            <p>In 1983 the Cary Arboretum became the Institute of Ecosystem Studies (IES), and in 1990 the Institute became an independent, non-profit 501(c)(3) corporation.  The name of the Institute changed to Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies in 2008.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="viaf" authfilenumber="127083667">Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection consists of documents relating to the early history of the Cary Arboretum and IES, and includes founding documents, financial reports, construction plans, administrators' correspondence, reports of research programs and property management, and more.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>All physical files are stored at the Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies in Millbrook, NY. To request access to these files, contact information can be found on www.caryinstitute.org.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="6eb0cd_Archive-box-file-folders.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>