<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nmbries">nmbries0003</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the John Reed Papers</titleproper><author>Isabel Carleton</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2018-07-11">July 11, 2018</date><address><addressline>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</addressline><addressline>PO Box AB</addressline><addressline>Millbrook, New York 12545-0129</addressline></address><publisher>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Isabel Carleton</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>John Reed Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1974" type="inclusive">1971 - 1974</unitdate><abstract>The collection focuses on International Biological Program (IBP), more specifically the work they did and their plans for transferring work to other groups after the IBP ended in 1974. </abstract><physdesc><extent>0.4 cubic feet (2 boxes)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname>Reed, John F., (1911-1997)</persname></origination><repository><corpname>Cary Institute of Ecosystem Studies</corpname><address><addressline>PO Box AB</addressline><addressline>Millbrook, NY 12545-0129</addressline><addressline>845-677-7600 x164</addressline></address><extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.caryinstitute.org "/></repository></did><accessrestrict><p>This collection is open to researchers by appointment only. </p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>John Reed was an environmental scientist who also became the Chairman of the Executive Committee of the US National Committee for the International Biological Program from 1972-1974. He also taught at several universities, ending his career at the University of Wisconsin -Green Bay, where he was a professor during the time period of this collection.</p></bioghist><controlaccess><corpname source="viaf" authfilenumber="125511357">U.S. National Committee for the International Biological Program</corpname><subject authfilenumber="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85040752" source="lcsh">Ecology</subject></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>The collection focuses on International Biological Program (IBP), more specifically the work they did and their plans for transferring work to other groups after the IBP ended in 1974. Includes mostly minutes, letters regarding those minutes, and budgets for IBP (International Biological Program). These papers concern IBP ecology projects, and how they will be continued after the IBP ended in 1974, in the US and internationally. Two folders contains letters regarding content discussed at the 5th IBP General Assembly. Travel records and of IBP scientists attending conferences. Large focus on publishing IBP findings. </p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>The materials in this collection are protected by copyright. </p></userestrict><dsc><c id="c_1ab7da6445576c06fd0fcc66202e37c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes and Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971" type="inclusive">1971</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	Minutes Letters for the United Nations conference on Human environment from various organizations, including the International Council of Scientific Unions (Special/Scientific Committee on Problems of the Environment) and the International Biological Program. Also a speech at the House/Senate Colloquium about the human environment of Latin America. Charts describing the relation of various environmental groups. Environmental grant sheets from USNC/IBP. Includes descriptions of programs these groups implement.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_5e1503052697d5a893224b5ab66b6385" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, Budgets, Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	IBP Minutes concerning establishing and maintaining environmental science programs. Also recent ecological discoveries are brought up.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_bc949bfe3d34694bc1d3a88cd7530955" level="file"><did><unittitle>IBP V General Assembly</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	IBP 5th general assembly agenda, plans for IBP and work they had done. Discussing what should be transferred to other groups. Write-up on the declaration on the human environment.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_6d85224729c24dc9ef596765644551b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>IBP V General Assembly</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	More IBP activities, describing what happened at V General Assembly. Includes descriptions of what happened at different workshops, like one about woodlands. Program of Analysis of World Ecosystems. Desert biome project. SCIBP, International Council of Scientific Unions. Photosynthesis and solar energy discussion, nitrogen fixation. Wetlands working group. Attempts to synthesize events discussed at meeting. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_4efe45433e7368bc54c7e4e3be07854b" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Future of IBP</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	Discussion of programs and how they will be transferred in each involved country, especially the Soviets. Includes what several countries have done. Discussion of man's influence on the environment. Mentions Special Committee on Antarctic Research (SCAR). Also includes IBP budgets and articles. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_fbb20c36472e4dd8d5d1c511c5cc483a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting Agendas, Records, and Correspondences</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="c_b0da5e3b60a363679ddd0f778c39d242" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondences, Budgets, Meeting Agendas, Minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="box">1</container><container type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent><p>Lots of letters from the national research council. Who should take over committees and tasks. More discussion of topics in ecology. Printout of law to protect marine life. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_0f19571c86e202ffa4f6ccc08a9df162" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting Minutes and Agendas</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent><p>Planning for a colloquium with the house science committee. Discussion of what IBP does. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_565854fd5e2c80462642998b1b8e2271" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scientific Future of IBP</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	Focus on scientific logistics of IBP ending. Meeting with IEPC and ICC. Post IBP task force. Plans on publishing IBP biome research in "synthesis volumes". Independent committee to review the IBP. Travel records. Also includes"	Meeting agendas, minutes, appendices, schedules and reports. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_6e493ca72fd33abb1255fd234fe54c75" level="file"><did><unittitle>USNC/IBP Executive Meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent><p>"	A lot of "for USEC only" letters about future plans for IBP. UNESCO is mentioned. Also contains discussions of pricing and logistics for publishing IBP research, as well as discussions of editing the research series. Meeting agenda, attendees, letters, etc
</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_3c1f665218716f9d5172947f989d5645" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting Notes and Agendas</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent><p>Includes"	Meeting notes and agenda, attendees list, and various correspondences. Focuses on specific IBP programs, like aerobiology and research publishing. </p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_33365c63acb13407bfd069c37312fba9" level="file"><did><unittitle>US/IB Executive Committee Meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1973" type="inclusive">1971 - 1973</unitdate><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent><p>Discussions of budget, long term goals, still working on publishing reports, letters about editing report 6, lists committee members, assembly of life sciences, travel budget .</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_007a86968175723ea3d5ce03dec4a926" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting Summaries and Correspondences</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1974" type="inclusive">1972 - 1974</unitdate><container type="box">2</container><container type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent><p>discusses responsibilities of John Reed as head of USNC/IBP, report edits, Development of Studies in Ecosystem Theory, the institute of ecology, ecology study projects, transferring programs, biome studies, travel budget, SRIBP</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_fc0bce500bcb5662c1d7890fc70593cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting Summaries and Correspondences</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate></did><scopecontent><p>More meetings about similar topics, like the human ecosystem interactions project, report 6, SCRIBP. </p></scopecontent></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>