<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysyssf">nysyssf0001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the House Histories of the Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities</titleproper><author>Charlene Martin</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2017-06-14">June 14, 2017</date><publisher>Sisters of St Francis of the Neumann Communities</publisher><address><addressline>960 James Street, Second Floor</addressline><addressline>Syracuse, NY 13203</addressline><addressline>315-634-7085</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Charlene Martin</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="series"><did><unittitle>House Histories of the Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2016" type="inclusive">2003 - 2016</unitdate><abstract>The leadership of the Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities requires members to submit an annual convent/house history.  They provide insight into sisters living in common and complete the historical narrative of the Communities.</abstract><physdesc><extent>3.25 cu. ft. (8 document cases)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><corpname>Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities (Syracuse, N.Y.)</corpname></origination><repository><corpname>Congregational Archives of the Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities</corpname><address><addressline>960 James Street</addressline><addressline>2nd Fl</addressline><addressline>Syracuse, NY</addressline><addressline>315-634-7085</addressline></address></repository></did><accessrestrict><p>Researchers must apply for permission before accessing the collection. Please contact the Congregational Archives of the Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities.
</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>The Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities is a catholic women religious congregation formed between 2004 and 2007 from the consolidation of the following New York and Pennsylvania Franciscan communities: Sisters of St. Francis of the Immaculate Virgin Hastings-on-Hudson N.Y; Sisters of the Third Order Regular Buffalo, N.Y.; and Sisters of St. Francis Pittsburgh, Pa.
</p><p>The primary objective of the order is to sustain the Gospel life of its members and support them while they engage in ministries throughout the world in education, health and social services. The order is known most for providing health care and education for those with Hansen’s disease in Hawaii, and Saint Marianne Cope.
</p><p>Sisters live in groups in houses located near the education, health or social services ministry that they are engaged in. The leadership of the order require these sisters to annually submit a chronicle of their lives in the house, known as house histories.  They provide insight into sisters living in common and complete the historical narrative of the Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities. Historical sketches of missions, photographs, clippings, and house inventories are often submitted along with annual house histories. They are included in this collection.
</p></bioghist><controlaccess><corpname>Sisters of St. Francis of the Neumann Communities (Syracuse, N.Y.)</corpname><subject>Monasticism and religious orders for women--United States--History--20th century.  </subject><subject>Monasticism and religious orders for women--United States--History--21st century.</subject><subject>Nuns--New York (State)--New York--History--20th century.</subject><subject>Nuns--New York (State)--New York--History--21st century.</subject><subject>Nuns--Pennsylvania (State)--Pennsylvania--History--20th century.</subject><subject>Nuns--Pennsylvania (State)--Pennsylvania--History--21st century.</subject><subject authfilenumber="sh2006002576" source="lcsh">Nuns--United States</subject></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>The collection contains one series. The files in the series are arranged first by country, then alphabetically by state and city.
Series I:  Houses
</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>Copyright in some items in the collection may still be held by their respective creator(s). For further information contact the Congregational Archives.</p></userestrict><dsc><c id="c_d0148cf9b2a5926b07c9b659c18e0ddc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Houses</unittitle><unitdate normal="1996/2016">1996 - 2016</unitdate></did></c></dsc><otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload"><bibref><extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="e8adf9_SOSFNCHouse_Histories.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/></bibref></otherfindaid></archdesc></ead>