<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0018</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Chester W. Rice Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2010-06">June, 2010</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        <notestmt>
					<note>
						<p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics</p>
					</note>
				</notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyschmis.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Chester W. Rice Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1906/1964" type="inclusive">1906 - 1964</unitdate>
            <abstract/>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Rice, Chester W.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Museum of Innovation and Science</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Although Chester Rice (1888-1951) was the son of GE executive Edwin W. Rice, Jr., he became known in his own right as a researcher.  Some of the first radar tests in the world were conducted in Rice’s home lab as he targeted trolleys passing by on Rugby Road.  When these tests proved successful, he installed his equipment at the Schenectady County Airport and tested it on passing aircraft.  Rice created several other inventions throughout his career, including a radio loudspeaker and a halogen leak detector for refrigerators.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Rice, Chester W.</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80079757">General Electric Company. Research Laboratory</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Rice Papers contains the working papers of Chester Rice, including correspondence, notes, articles, patents, publications and photographs.  A small amount of the materials is biographical, and some appears to have been inserted into the collection by his family.  There is also a small amount of biographical material about his father, Edwin Rice.</p>
        <p>There is very little about his invention of the radio loudspeaker, but more about his other inventions.  Most of his professional correspondence was collected into letterbooks in chronological order, and this ordering has been maintained.  The collection has been organized alphabetically.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>