<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0017</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the John M. Anderson Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2010-04">April 2010</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        <notestmt>
					<note>
						<p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
					</note>
				</notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyschmis.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>John M. Anderson Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1911/2006" type="inclusive">1911 - 2006</unitdate>
            <abstract/>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>6.6 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Anderson, John M.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Museum of Innovation and Science</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>John M. Anderson was born in Kansas City, Missouri on October 9, 1924.  He joined the Army in 1943 where he was trained in the theory and operations of radio equipment.  He left the Army in 1946 and attended the University of Illinois, earning his PhD in Electrical Engineering in 1955.  That same year he began working in the Research Laboratory at GE in Schenectady.</p>
        <p>Most of his work focused on gaseous electronics and electric discharge lamps. He is remembered for his work on the solenoidal electric field (SEF) lamp, presenting a paper on the topic at the 3rd International Symposium on the Science and Technology of Light Sources in 1983.  The SEF lamp was later marketed under the name Genura. </p>
            <p>Anderson retired in 1987 and began volunteering at the Hall of Electrical History.  When the HoEH merged with the Schenectady Museum, Anderson followed.</p>
            <p>John Anderson died on November 18, 2007.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Anderson, John M.</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80079757">General Electric Company. Research Laboratory</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection contains materials collected by John Anderson during his career at General Electric, as an engineer in the Research Laboratory and as a volunteer in the GE Hall of Electrical History and the Schenectady Museum Archives.  The working papers found here largely consist of correspondence, which makes up the first series.  There is also a series of articles and reports written by Dr. Anderson during his time in the Laboratory</p>
        <p>The rest of the collection consists of materials collected by Dr. Anderson during his historical research with the Hall of History and the Archives.  These mostly consist of articles, clippings, correspondence and notes, as well as transcripts of oral histories, essays and scrapbooks.</p>
            <p>Of particular interest to Dr. Anderson was the Schenectady radio station WGY, the materials for which form their own series.  Anderson was also interested in the work of the engineers William C. White and A. Van Dyck, and the Research Materials series contains copies of their lab notebooks.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <dsc>
            <c id="c_81235a3e1db6208b908d7d9b580baf3d" level="series">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
        <unitdate normal="1952/1988">1952 - 1988</unitdate>
    </did>
</c>
            <c id="c_93d32ced09c9a049698f9887ddf6bd43" level="series">
    <did>
        <unittitle>WGY</unittitle>
        <unitdate normal="1921/2006">1921 - 2006</unitdate>
    </did>
</c>
            <c id="c_5e72568507b7c3a294bcf390d107a380" level="series">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Research Material</unittitle>
        <unitdate normal="1911/2005">1911 - 2005</unitdate>
    </did>
</c>
            <c id="c_045af351b48c1afe884bab7cc79ba6c5" level="series">
    <did>
        <unittitle>Publications</unittitle>
        <unitdate normal="1946/1988">1946 - 1988</unitdate>
    </did>
</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>