<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0010</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Willard Grubb</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-22">December 22, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Joshua Hauck-Whealton</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Willard Grubb Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1986" type="inclusive">1951 - 1986</unitdate>
            <abstract>The papers of Willard Thomas Grubb, a research chemist at General Electric.  Contains a mix of working papers, articles and reports mostly focused on Grubb's work with fuel cells.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.3 cubic ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Grubb, Willard T.</persname>
            </origination>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1986" type="bulk">1964 - 1986</unitdate>
            <note>
                <p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
            </note>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Willard Thomas Grubb received his Masters degree and Ph.D. from Harvard in 1949.  He immediately joined GE's research lab, and spent the next 38 years as a research chemist. Much of his work dealt with organo-silicon compounds.  In the 1950’s he helped to develop the ion-exchange membrane systems that became part of the first hydrogen-oxygen fuel cells.</p>
            <p>These fuel cells, using a proton-conducting solid ion-exchange membrane as electrolyte, were used for power generation in the Gemini Spacecraft.  As a result of his work, Grubb gained a patent on the ion-membrane fuel cell and became known as the expert of fuel cells.  </p>
            <p>Grubb produced or collaborated on over 40 technical papers and received 26 patents during his career.  In 1973, he was elected as a Coolidge Fellow, GE’s highest scientific honor.   </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Grubb, Willard T.</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection mostly consists of technical materials relating to Grubb’s work with fuel cells, though mostly after his famous work with hydrogen-oxygen fuel cells.  These materials include experimental data, notebooks, reports and articles.  </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <dsc>
            <c id="c_bb92897e7d9b59e3765b2c6d529a3e61" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Working Papers,</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1951/1986">1951 - 1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_8486c1b94f9ffb7c016a7cb2ef186284" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Reports</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1955/1986">1955 - 1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_0d488fff92fa1c80c5307a4d2a6ef678" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Articles</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1957/1986">1957 - 1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_1f1d5761c3f3582caf8b1fb92e4577c9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Slides</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1981">1981</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_6c9e756e7091fd19b928fc6962a68936" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Addition #1</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1954/2000">1954 - 2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>A recent addition to the Grubb Papers that will eventually be integrated with the other series.  Mostly Working Papers dealing with fuel cells.  These papers were foldered by Willard Grubb or his family, and this order has been maintained.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>