<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0005</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Roy Anderson Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Joshua Hauck-Whealto.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Roy Anderson Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1951/1990" type="inclusive">1951 - 1990</unitdate>
            <abstract>Documents created and collected by General Electric engineer Roy E. Anderson.  The materials consist of reports, articles and notes, mostly concerned with Anderson's work on satellite communication and positioning.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>6 cubic ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n84131336">Anderson, Roy E.</persname>
            </origination>
            <note>
                <p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics</p>
            </note>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Roy Anderson majored in math and physics at Augustana College.  He graduated during WWII, and began teaching physics at the Army Air Core College Training Program.  After teaching for a year he enlisted in the Navy, which sent him to Bowdoin College and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology to study radar.  With this training he served as an electronics officer about the USS Shelikof.</p>
            <p>After the war, Anderson returned to teaching for a year, then got a job with General Electric in the Corporate Research and Development Center.  He worked there until his retirement in 1983.  After his retirement he founded Mobile Satellite Corporation (Mobilsat), one of the early companies to develop satellite communications.  In 1988 Mobilsat merged with 12 other companies to form the American Mobile Satellite Corporation, where Anderson was a consultant until 1991.</p>
            <p>Much of Roy Anderson's work followed his training in radar and his lifelong interest in ham radio.  He helped pioneer the methods of satellite positioning and navigation, leading to the modern GPS technology.  He produced 125 articles and held 22 patents.  He received a Ralph J. Cordiner Award and a Coolidge Fellowship from GE. He was a fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers; the Institute of Navigation; the American Association for the Advancement of Science; and the Radio Club of America. He also served a term as board president and was a trustee emeritus of Dudley Observatory.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n84131336">Anderson, Roy E.</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Roy Anderson collection consists of reports, articles, notes, correspondence and other materials produced and collected by Roy Anderson during his career at the General Electric Corporate Research and Development Center.  The majority of the material focuses on his work with satellite navigation and positioning, including the reports and articles in the first three series.  The final series consists of notebooks created during Anderson's career, and they contain a variety of subjects.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <dsc>
            <c id="c_f110ad2564bc8cdd9fd67d2b6affe1b9" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>GE Company Reports</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1951/1979">1951 - 1979</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_bdc1a7aea5bec08bace20566c879a000" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Contract Reports</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1959/1994">1959 - 1994</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_657eea2ec1e8fcdf288f049357814d09" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Articles</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1959/1982">1959 - 1982</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_490d8461c118e4ffb74fe1387b86d4f2" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1962/1983">1962 - 1983</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_23a3e1d4ec529647db5646ccb90a4102" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1961/1990">1961 - 1990</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_5de53206b4248387b2b96f3b52c7fc5a" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Notebooks</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1962/1986">1962 - 1986</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="e69cc1_Roy_Anderson_Papers.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>