<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0016</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Arthur Bueche Speeches</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whelaton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2010-06">June 2010</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        <notestmt>
					<note>
						<p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
					</note>
				</notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyschmis.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Arthur Bueche Speeches</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1977/1981" type="inclusive">1977 - 1981</unitdate>
            <abstract/>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Bueche, Arthur</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Museum of Innovation and Science</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Arthur Maynard Bueche (1920-1981) received his Ph.D. in Physical Chemistry from Cornell University in 1947.  He joined the Chemical Research Division of the GE Research Laboratory in 1950, where he helped with GE’s early polymer research.  He was elevated to the head of the Chemical Research division in 1960, and overall head of the Research Laboratory in 1965.</p>
        <p>Shortly thereafter, the Research Laboratory and the Advanced Technology Laboratories were merged into the R&amp;D Center, with Bueche again at the head.  In 1978, Bueche was promoted to senior vice president of corporate technology.</p>
            <p>Bueche believed part of his responsibility as a corporate officer was to act as a spokesman for technology.  As a result, he was in demand as a speaker on issues of technological development, R&amp;D policy and energy policy.  His focus was generally on what he called the “R&amp;D Triangle,” the interaction of academia, government and business that fueled most of America’s research.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Bueche, Arthur</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection consists of materials related to individual speaking engagements for Arthur Bueche.  These folders were created and maintained by Bueche’s secretary.  Each engagement received its own folder, usually containing a draft of the speech as well as related correspondence, notes and the reports from background research. The collection is organized chronologically.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>