<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0012</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Charles Thomas Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-27">December 27, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Joshua Hauck-Whealton</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Charles Thomas Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1947/2007" type="inclusive">1947 - 2007</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Charles Thomas Papers contain documents collected by Charles Thomas in his research on General Electric history for the Hall of History and miSci.  </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3 cubic ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Thomas, Charles E.</persname>
            </origination>
            <note>
                <p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
            </note>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Charles E. Thomas  enlisted in the Army's Reserve Training program in 1944, and through that took engineering courses at Cornell, NYU and Columbia.  After his discharge, he received a B.S. in engineering from Clarkson University in 1948 and began working for the General Electric test program.  He went on to receive his M.S. in engineering in 1964.</p>
            <p>Thomas' work at GE  involved underwater sound techniques, applications of switching theory and ultrasound transducers for medical imaging.  He was part of the permanent staff at the General Engineering Lab.  After his retirement in 1990 he worked with the Elfun Society repairing tape machines for the blind.  He volunteered at the Museum of Innovation and Science and assisted with the integration of the Hall of History with the Museum.  He passed away on October 15, 2006.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Thomas, Charles E.</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Charles Thomas Papers consists mostly of documents collected by Charles Thomas in his research on General Electric history for the Hall of History and miSci.  It contains clippings, publications, articles and notes about General Electric figures and products.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="1fa3f3_Charles_Thomas_Papers_Online.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>