<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Roland Schmitt Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-11-09">November 9, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user Joshua Hauck-Whealton.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Roland Schmitt Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1949/2003" type="inclusive">1949 - 2003</unitdate>
            <abstract>Materials created and collected by Roland Schmitt during his time as the head of the General Electric Research Laboratory and as the president of Rennsselaer Polytechnic Institute.  Mainly consists of article and speeches</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>6 cubic ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85830438">Schmitt, Roland W.</persname>
            </origination>
            <note>
                <p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
            </note>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Roland Schmitt (1923- ) received a masters in Physics from the University of Texas in 1948, and his Ph.D. in Physics from Rice University in 1951. Soon after he began working at the General Electric Research Laboratory as a research associate.  He served as the director of the GE Research &amp; Development Center from 1978 until 1986.</p>
            <p>Upon retiring from General Electric in 1988, Schmitt became president of Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute until 1993.  He has served with a number of science and technology institutions, including being the chairman of the board for the New York State Office Of Science, Technology and Academic Research and being a member of the National Science Board from 1982-1994.</p>
            <p>Throughout his career, Roland Schmitt was in demand as a speaking on issues of science and technology in policy and industry.  He holds numerous awards and honors in the field, including the IEEE Founders Medal, awarded in 1992.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80079760">General Electric Company. Research and Development Center</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n88181601">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute. Center for Science and Technology Policy</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The bulk of the collection consists of articles and speeches written during Schmitt's time as head of the Research Laboratory and during his term as president of Rennsselaer Polytechnic Institute.  There are some working papers created during Schmitt's time at the research laboratory, mostly consisting of meeting notes and materials pertaining to business trips.  There is little personal materials, and few business records.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <dsc>
            <c id="c_533cd92834bbb94f3e10752bce04d128" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Working Papers</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1950/2000">1950 - 2000</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The series contains notes, articles, correspondence and other materials created or collection by Roland Schmitt during his professional life.  Organized by subject, arranged alphabetically.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_8e161f04aa9d34c20a6cbda0769e2b6e" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1964/2001">1964 - 2001</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>This series contains talks, presentations and speeches delivered by Roland Schmitt.  Most speeches and foldered separately, and most folders contain the text of the speech plus related correspondence and research material.  Arranged alphabetically.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_8ed9ea2123a5f55bbccd56eb0b50424e" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Articles</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1949/2001">1949 - 2001</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Papers and articles written by or contributed to by Roland Schmitt.  Foldered by article title.  Most folders contain the text of the article, sometimes the original contributed text and the related research material.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_40e99a6dc6325ef2d9d8efda67e7cb71" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1967/1983">1967 - 1983</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>This series contains small sets of photographs, generally related to trips taken or events attended by Roland Schmitt.  These are generally unlabeled and frequently undated.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="f9b591c1dbcf.xls" xlink:role="application/vnd.ms-excel"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>