<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0011</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Francis Norton Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-22">December 22, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Joshua Hauck-Whealton</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Francis Norton Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1930/1986" type="inclusive">1930 - 1986</unitdate>
            <abstract>The papers of Francis J. Norton contain lab notebooks and binders dealing with Norton's laboratory work in General Electric Atmospheric Sciences Research Center.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.6 cubic ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2009010727">Norton, Francis J., 1899-1994</persname>
            </origination>
            <note>
                <p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
            </note>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Francis Norton was a researcher at GE R&amp;D during World War II who helped develop the mass spectrometer. After retiring form GE, Norton continued his research at the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center at the University of Albany.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2009010727">Norton, Francis J., 1899-1994</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>25 notebooks kept by Francis Norton documenting his research at the General Electric Research Laboratory, 5 notebooks of research from the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center, and 17 additional notebooks maintained by Norton, most of which are likely associated with his work at GE. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>