<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyschmis">nyschmis0007</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Robert Crandell Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-14">December 14, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Museum of Innovation and Science</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline>
                    <addressline>Schenectady, New York 12308</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 382-7890</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Joshua Hauck-Whealton</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Robert Crandell Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1992" type="inclusive">1956 - 1992</unitdate>
            <abstract>Materials collected by Robert B. Crandell in his 37 years as a technician in various General Electric laboratories.  Contains numerous photographs of the labs in the seventies.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.3 cubic ft</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Crandell, Robert B.</persname>
            </origination>
            <note>
                <p>Creation of this finding aid was supported by a grant from the Center for History of Physics, American Institute of Physics.</p>
            </note>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Access to this record group is unrestricted.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Robert Crandell served in the US Navy as a radioman from 1936-1940.  From there he became a Lab Assistant and an Engineering Tech in the GE General Engineering Laboratory.  He would go on to work in the Advanced Technology Lab and Corporate Research and Deasign, retiring in 1978.  His focus was usually on radar engineering and related fields.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Crandell, Robert B.</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Crandell Papers contain materials created by Robert Crandell in his career at General Electric.  The bulk of the materials are photographs, including three unlabeled photograph albums from the 70s.  There are also phone directories and materials related to the Group of Solid-State Applications and Measurements (GOSAM) conferences.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the miSci Archives will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Head of Archives.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="6a57d1_Crandell_Papers.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>