<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0018</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>The Dr. Grace M. Swanner Collection Finding Aid</titleproper>
                <author>Loraine M. Wies, MLS. Librarian, Saratoga Room, Saratoga Springs Public Library, Saratoga Springs, NY. 2004</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-11-16">November 16, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Dr. Grace M. Swanner Collection, 1832-1997 [bulk 1930-1988]</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1832/1997" type="inclusive">1832 - 1997</unitdate>
            <abstract>Grace Maguire Swanner, MD, was the assistant to Walter S. McClellan who was the Medical Directory of the Saratoga Spa. She also authored "Saratoga - Queen of Spas" in 1988. This collection includes items from her professional life as well as the source materials she used to write her book.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3 drawers  plus box of file cards; a box of photographic slides; and a bound volume entitled "Publications of the Saratoga Spa."</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Swanner, Grace Maguire</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <legalstatus>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</legalstatus>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Grace Maguire Swanner was born in Albany, NY on December 5, 1901, the third of four children born to Joseph A. and Mary Margaret Stevens Maguire. Raised in Albany, she graduated from the New York School for Teachers in 1923. When she informed her parents of her desire to become a physician, they initially were very discouraging. She ultimately went on to become the only woman in her class to receive a medical degree, graduating from Albany Medical College in 1933.</p>
            <p>On April 25, 1936, Grace Maguire married Roy O. Swanner, a Sanitary Engineer. Together, they had two children, Roy Steven and Katherine Vaughn.</p>
            <p>In 1936, following the completion of an internship in Albany and her residency in New Jersey, Dr. Swanner began working as an assistant to Dr. Walter S. McClellan, Medical Director of the Saratoga Spa. She was a senior physician on the medical staff of Saratoga Hospital from 1936-1975. For many years, she was the only female physician on staff.</p>
            <p>Following the retirement of Dr. McClellan, Dr. Swanner served as acting Director of the Spa until a permanent replacement was found. She was listed in the “Who’s Who of American Women in 1961 and was a member of the American Association of University Women. In addition, she was a member of the American Medical Association, the Saratoga County Medical Society, the American Academy of General Practice and the New York State Health Officers Association. She served as the Health Officer for the towns of Wilton, NY and Greenfield, NY and was a physician for the Saratoga- Warren BOCES. She was a founding member and instructor at the BOCES Saratoga School of Massage, which operated in the 1960’s.</p>
            <p>A strong advocate in the medical use of hydrotherapy and balneology and a firm believer in the healing properties of the Saratoga waters, she published her book “Saratoga Queen of Spas” in 1988. All royalties from her book are donated to the Saratoga Springs Historical Society. In the 1980’s and 1990’s, she was an active participant in the movement to re-establish the Saratoga Spa as a medical facility.</p>
            <p>Dr. Swanner died on October 13, 2000 in Saratoga Springs, NY.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname>American Medical Association</corpname>
            <persname>Swanner, Grace Maguire</persname>
            <persname>McClellan, Walter Stuart</persname>
            <geogname>Saratoga County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Wilton (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Gansevoort (N. Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Greenfield (N.Y. : Town)</geogname>
            <geogname>New York (State) -- Saratoga Springs. </geogname>
            <geogname>New York (State) -- Saratoga County</geogname>
            <subject>Hydrotherapy </subject>
            <subject>Balneology </subject>
            <subject>Mineral Waters -- therapeutic use</subject>
            <subject>Medicine</subject>
            <corpname>Washington-Saratoga-Warren-Hamilton-Essex BOCES</corpname>
            <corpname>Saratoga County (N.Y) Medical Society </corpname>
            <corpname>Medical Society of the State of New York </corpname>
            <corpname>New York State Association of County Health Officials</corpname>
            <corpname>Historical Society of Saratoga Springs (N. Y.)</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The papers of Dr. Grace Maguire Swanner were donated to the Saratoga Room of the Saratoga Springs Public Library from her estate through her daughter Katherine V. Swanner in Sept. 2001.</p>
            <p>The collection is comprised of approximately 5 linear feet of materials with additional boxes of photographic slides and a box containing file cards with handwritten notes. In addition, the collection contained a full run of the series, “Publications of the Saratoga Spa,” (State of New York, Saratoga Springs Authority, “Publications of the Saratoga Spa”; State of New York, 1935-[1953].) which have been subsequently bound and are housed in the Saratoga Room (call number S615.853 SAR).</p>
            <p>The material has been divided into four series - the Saratoga Spa, Research Materials, “Saratoga - Queen of Spa’s” and Spa Advocacy Activities. The arrangement is chronological within each series. The materials within the collection include photocopies of published materials, news clippings, research notes, lecture notes, photographs and pamphlets and leaflets regarding her research and advocacy activities. In addition, the collection contains several draft manuscripts of her book, “Saratoga - Queen of Spas.” </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="17c101_Swanner_Folder_List.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>