<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0009</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Military Oral History Project Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Saratoga Room Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-01-05">January 5, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Military Oral History Project Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="2007" type="inclusive">2007</unitdate>
            <abstract>This is a collection of the oral military histories and stories of a group of Veterans from Saratoga Springs.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 expanding folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>New York State Military Museum and Veteran's Research Center</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
            <note>
                <p>2013.4</p>
            </note>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Established by the Governor on Veterans' Day, 2000, the New York State Veteran Oral History Program involves professional military historians using the latest digital technology to preserve the story of New York's Veterans - in their own words - now and for all generations to come.</p>
            <p>The program is concentrating on the state's sizable World War II Veteran community also the experiences of veterans of all periods and services.</p>
            <p>Funding and technological assistance are provided by the Governor's Office for Technology. Working together with the Division of Veteran Affairs, these state agencies are dedicated to realizing the Governor's intent to save the thoughts and experiences of the state's veterans, not just because these are important parts of state and national history, but also because they are invaluable lessons in the values that made New York the Empire State.</p>
            <p>Each interview conducted enters an individual veteran's experiences into the permanent public memory of the state and nation, and builds a collection of irreplaceable value that scholars, students, and family members will wish to use for years without end.</p>
            <p>Using the inherent advantages of the digital technology involved to go further than just gathering and storing these memories and prepare visual presentations from the basic materials that brings the veterans' stories directly into the schools and homes of their fellow New Yorkers.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5136334" source="geonames">Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <persname>Corsale, Eugene</persname>
            <persname>Dart, Clarence W.</persname>
            <persname>Jones, Ellsworth</persname>
            <persname>Hunt, Charles</persname>
            <persname>Lindsay, Michelle Renee</persname>
            <persname>Lyons, Kevin Patrick</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2008106349" source="lcsh">Korean War, 1950-1953--Personal narratives, American</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2008113202" source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Personal narratives, American</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2003003059" source="lcsh">Iraq War, 2003-2011</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh99000446" source="lcsh">Kosovo War, 1998-1999</subject>
            <subject>world war II -- personal narratives</subject>
            <subject>Oral History Recordings</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection is part of a larger Oral History project conducted by the NYS Military Museum and includes CD’s of the interviews.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <dsc>
            <c id="c_b851615808d73de782bbde5534c78b71" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Summary</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_8d6dd9e432f59bb0e585333602c9da10" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Personnel Sheets</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c>
            <c id="c_8712f383627b526d8c764be366890175" level="file">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>CD's</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>