<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0020</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Tracy Purcell Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Katherine Federiconi, MSIS Intern</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-12-05">December 5, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Tracy Purcell Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1917/2009" type="inclusive">1917 - 2009</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Tracy Purcell Collection reflects the life of Tracy Purcell, beginning with content on his ancestry from 1917, continuing through his professional life and interests, and concluding with the memorial service celebrating his life in 2009. The collection consists of newspaper articles, personal papers, photocopies of images, ephemera, and a couple of musical CDs.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 Sm. Box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Green, Lynn</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
            <p>Gift of daughter Lynn Green.</p>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Tracy Purcell was born December 6, 1924 in Saratoga Springs, New York. He attended Saratoga Springs High School and later went on to earn a degree in Commercial Agriculture from Cornell University. Purcell served in the Navy during World War II from 1942-1945. He also attended the State Police Academy in Albany, New York, and was a New York State Trooper from 1946-1951. In 1948, Purcell acted as the bodyguard to presidential hopeful Governor Thomas Dewey. Upon completing his service as a Trooper, Purcell became a private investigator for Lincoln Investigations, Inc.. He then pursued careers in management and business. Purcell owned his own recording studio, called Pulse Records, and a private investigation agency. Purcell maintained homes in both New York and St. Petersburg, Florida for a number of years.  On May 16, 2008, Purcell succumbed to esophageal cancer and died at the age of 83 in Florida. </p>
            <p>Purcell was a creative individual and an active musician since the 1930s. In the 1950s, Purcell formed a duo with his new wife, Harriet Purcell, both playing piano. As their six children began to express interest in music, the ensemble grew and changed, taking on the names Tracy Purcell and the Jokers, and the Purcell Family Band. Upon the death of Harriet in 2001, Tracy went on to become the Saltwater Blues Man. </p>
            <p>Biographical History was developed from the contents of the collection. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject>Japan. Finance, Ministry of</subject>
            <subject>Japan Policy Research Institute</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85088762" source="lcsh">Music</subject>
            <subject>Music &amp; Musicians</subject>
            <subject>Music and performing arts</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85140848" source="lcsh">United States. Navy</subject>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2008102094">Archer, Samuel</persname>
            <persname>Archer, Clarence</persname>
            <persname>Purcell, Harriet</persname>
            <persname>Purcell, Tracy E.</persname>
            <geogname>Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Saint Petersburg (Fla.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Tracy Purcell collection consists of newspaper articles, personal papers, photocopies of images, ephemera, and a couple of musical CDs all relating to Tracy Purcell, dating between 1917 and 2009.  The collection contains content on Purcell’s professional and personal life, including his career in the military, state troopers, and musical career; papers for the production of the film Square Heart, a movie that Purcell had invested in during the late 1990s; and research on the political and financial environment in Japan during the turn of the century.  Folders on Clarence and Samuel Archer are also included in this collection because Tracy Purcell is a descendant of the Archer lineage and Samuel Archer was Purcell’s grandfather.</p>
            <arrangement>
                <p>The items of the collection are arranged in folders by subject area.</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="a5a2b2_Purcell_Inventory.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>