<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0015</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>The Lincoln Springs Collection Finding Aid </titleproper>
                <author>Saratoga Springs Public Library</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-11-01">November 1, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Lincoln Springs Collection </unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1834/1932" type="inclusive">1834 - 1932</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Lincoln Springs Collection contains personnel and business dealing of Deyoe Lohnas, owner of the Lincoln Springs Company in Saratoga Springs during the late 19th and early 20th centuries.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Sahlberg, Aldebert Hayden</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
            <note>
                <p>donated in 1998</p>
            </note>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Deyoe Lohnas, President of the Lincoln Springs Co. Inc. was a highly respected business man who lived to the age of 90. He was born in Pittstown, NY on December 15, 1836 to Jacob and Charity Deyoe Lohnas. In November 1869, while a resident of Schuylerville, NY, he married Huldah Farr, daughter of Leonard Farr of Schuylerville.</p>
            <p>In addition to the Lincoln Springs Co., Lohnas was on the Boards of the G.F.Harvey, Co. and General Carbonic Co. of New York as well as the Presbyterian Church. In addition, he was an active member of the Saratoga Club, McGregor Links, Business Men’s Association, the Saratoga Chamber of Commerce, the Knight’s Templar, and the local Board of Education. He was known to be a generous donor to charities.</p>
            <p>Lohnas passed suddenly on July 1, 1926. He was survived by his daughter, Mrs. Adelbert C. Hayden, two granddaughters, and three great grandchildren including the collection donor, Adelbert Hayden Sahlberg.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Callihan, John</persname>
            <persname>Farr, Leonard</persname>
            <persname>Freeman, Romeyn</persname>
            <persname>Lohnas, Deyoe</persname>
            <persname>Haskins, Samuel</persname>
            <persname>Allbright, Jacob</persname>
            <persname>Hathaway, Sherman</persname>
            <persname>Krigger, George</persname>
            <persname>Moon, Andrew</persname>
            <persname>Nelson, Haldah</persname>
            <persname>Scofield, Silas</persname>
            <persname>Swift, Nathan</persname>
            <persname>Thompson, William</persname>
            <persname>Tubbs, Andrew</persname>
            <persname>Vandenburgh, Nicholas</persname>
            <persname>Waring, James</persname>
            <corpname>Carbonic Acid Gas Company</corpname>
            <corpname>Grand Union Hotel</corpname>
            <corpname>Lincoln Springs Company</corpname>
            <geogname>Saratoga County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname>Washington County (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <corpname>Saratoga Spa State Park (N.Y.)</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Lincoln Springs Collection is an artificial collection comprised of several components relating to the personal and business dealings of Deyoe Lohnas, President of the Lincoln Spring Co.</p>
            <p>The first series of records contain 32 volumes of diaries dating from 1900 – 1932. The diaries contain entries of both the personal activities and observations of Mr. Lohnas as well as records of the development of the Lincoln Spring Co. and the conduct of daily business. In addition, information regarding the drilling and production levels of the springs are noted throughout. The diaries are arranged in chronological order. Various notes and news clippings found within the diaries are also included.</p>
            <p>The second series contains the business and personal papers of the Nelson/Farr families. Many are legal papers related to the purchase of various properties in the Saratoga and Washington County areas. The bulk of the papers date from 1834 – 1867 and are arranged in chronological order. </p>
            <p>Copies of the Supreme Court case records filed in 1908 in the case of the People of the State of New York v. the Lincoln Spring Co. and the New York Carbonic Gas Co. comprise the third series. In addition, copies of subsequent judgements handed down in 1909 and appeals briefs are included. The records are also arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="c0a073_Lincoln_Springs_1998.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>