<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0012</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Mark Costello Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Saratoga Room Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-01-30">January 30, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Mark Costello Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1989" type="inclusive">1989</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection of architectural drawings present proposals for renovations for the Saratoga Flat Track and the Reading Room.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 expanded folder</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Costello, Mark</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
            <note>
                <p>2016.43
Gift of Mark Costello</p>
            </note>
        </acqinfo>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Mark F. Costello was the son of the late Mark A. and Cornelia (Miller) Costello of Sea Cliff, NY and was born in Glen Cove, NY on Sept. 4, 193 and was married to the former Jane R. Anderson for 60 years. He and the family resided at various times in Sea Cliff, Glen Head, Floral Park, LI, Saratoga Springs and in Venice, FL. A graduate of Sea Cliff High School, Long Island A &amp; T and Pratt Institute, he took courses at Adelphi College, the Art Student League and AMA. Mark also was a US Navy Seabees veteran of the Korean War. He worked for Sperry Gyroscope as a technical illustrator in 1952-53 and for the Westchester Racing Association in 1953-59 as well as for Kahn &amp; Jacobs Architects from 1955-59. He began working for the New York Racing Association as construction planning assistant from 1955 to 1986 and served as manager of the Saratoga Race Course from 1968 to 1978. He became manager of Belmont Park Race Track in 1978 to 1980 and vice-president of NYRA properties from 1980 to 1986, when he retired. He later provided consulting work for NYRA, Four Winds Hospital, Saratoga Hospital and the Saratoga Golf and Polo Club. </p>
            <p>He was given the additional duty as manager of the Saratoga Race Track in 1968. They all loved Saratoga, considering this their home. In 1978, he was forced to move to Belmont, yet always maintained a home in Saratoga Springs, planning his retirement to here in 1986. He was a member and president of the Saratoga Golf and Polo Club, past president of the Saratoga County Chamber of Commerce, co-chairman of the building committee planning the former downtown YMCA, United Fund campaign volunteer, the Mayor's Committee for the city's convention center, a board member of the Saratoga Holiday Inn and numerous other civic organizations. He was a member and communicant of St. Clement's Roman Catholic Church and served on the first parish council. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5136334" source="geonames">Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <persname>Costello, Mark</persname>
            <persname>Mangano, J.</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n81083578">New York Racing Association</corpname>
            <subject>Saratoga Race Course (Saratoga Springs, N.Y.)</subject>
            <subject>Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</subject>
            <subject>Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)--Pictorial works</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85006611" source="lcsh">Architecture</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection consists of both black and white and colorized drawings of proposals for renovations to areas of the Saratoga Flat Track and the Reading Room. Included are several photographs from the George Bolster Collection of the Reading Room.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="b8a2dc_Costello-_2016.43.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>