<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0034</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Feast of St Michael Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Saratoga Room Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="1914/1999">1914 - 1999</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Feast of St. Michael, Local Legacies Project</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1914/1999" type="inclusive">1914 - 1999</unitdate>
            <abstract>The collection highlights information that was submitted to the Library of Congress for the "Local Legacies Project" featuring the Feast of St. Michael held annually in Saratoga Springs, NY.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 sm box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Fitzgerald, Mary Ann</persname>
                
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
            
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The Local Legacies project was launched by the Librarian of Congress as a major component of the Library of Congress's Bicentennial, which was celebrated on April 24, 2000. The Library invited members of Congress to identify grassroots traditions and activities from every state and congressional district, document them in photographs, sound and video recordings, and manuscripts, and send a portion of that documentation to the Library of Congress for inclusion in the Archive of Folk Culture.</p>
        <p>The Feast of St. Michael, held in Saratoga Springs from 1914-1999, was an annual celebration of the Italian Community and the Principessa Elena Society. The Feast had a Catholic Mass, a parade and lots of food.</p>
            <p>Part of the information brought together for submission was the work of Mary Anne Fitzgerald and Leona Signor in what they called the West Side Oral Narrative Project. Fitzgerald and Signor interviewed people who grew up on the West Side of Saratoga Springs.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            
        <subject>Local Legacies Collection (Library of Congress)</subject>
            <persname>Fitzgerald, Mary Ann</persname>
            <persname>Signor, Leona</persname>
            <persname>Sweeney, John, Congressman</persname>
            <subject>Feast of St.Michael</subject>
            <geogname>Saratoga Springs, NY</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection contains examples of the interviews conducted during the West Side Narrative Project in addition to the documentation and content that was contributed to the Local Legacies Project. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="7b849f_Feast_of_St._Michael_Festival.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>