<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0039</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Congregation Shaara T’Filleh Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Saratoga Room Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="1920/2000">1920 - 2000</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Congregation Shaara T’Filleh Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1920/2000" type="inclusive">1920 - 2000</unitdate>
            <abstract>By the mid 1990’s Congregation Shaara T’Filleh of Saratoga Springs had more than doubled in population. Many of this population were doctors, dentists, lawyers, businessmen, restaurants, grocers and a variety of retail specialists. The Conservative Jewish Community came together and built the first new synagogue and social center on Weibel Ave in Saratoga.
This collection contains photographs, magazine and newspaper articles, information about the families who were members of the congregation.
</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 box</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Siegal, Samuel</persname>
                
                
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
            
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Samuel Siegel was born in Saratoga Springs on March 27, 1918 to Philip and Bessie Siegel. Sam married Vivian “Babe” Globerson on October 7, 1942 and was the former owner of Siegel’s Furniture store in Saratoga.</p>
        <p>Sam was a veteran of the U.S.Army having served in WW ll as an MP. He saw combat in the Battle of the Bulge and the invasion of Utah Beach.</p>
            <p>Upon his return he became an active and dedicated member of Congregation Shaara T’filleh. He served several terms as president, on the board of directors, acted as Rabbi when we were without. Sam was also very active in the Men’s Lodge of B’Nai B’Rith, the religious activities of the shul and a true supporter of the members and the running of Congregation Shaara T’Filleh.</p>
            <p>In the early 50’s , Sam took it upon himself to start collecting his own family pictures and any memorabilia regarding Jewish businesses, professionals, restaurants, events, newspaper articles, invitations, obituaries , virtually any and all information related to the membership families of Congregation Shaara T’Filleh.</p>
            <p>Eventually , in the early 80’s Sam organized this collection into categories and each category (ie. Family, religion, business) had a separate labeled blue plastic binder.  For several years, Sam took it upon himself to hang and display the contents of each binder for the congregation to see and reminisce. Sam , being the convincing salesman that he was and also a known philanthropist arranged to have Allerdice Building Supply  build a wall of beautiful wood and glass showcases for these materials to be displayed. These showcases are still being used today.
</p>
            <p>Sam died on April 28, 2016. All of the people that are a part of Sam’s collection are also deceased. Sam had gifted his collection to Shaara T’filleh. In the fall of 2018, the congregation donated this collection , which was Sam Siegel’s legacy, to the Saratoga Room of the SSPL.













</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            
        <geogname authfilenumber="5136334" source="geonames">Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <corpname>Congregation Shaara T'Filleh</corpname>
            <corpname>B'Nai Brith</corpname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n2015065545">Goldstein, Sophie</persname>
            <subject>Jewish Veterans</subject>
            <subject>World War II</subject>
            <subject>Jewish history, life and culture</subject>
            <persname>Siegal, Sam</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection is comprised of photographs, newspaper articles, synagogue journals, event programs, historical documentation. In addition, materials and information used for wall exhibits and the WW ll Veteran Exhibit.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="87da8f_Shaara_T%27Fille_Folder_List.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>