<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nysspl">nysspl0035</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the McKelvey Family Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Saratoga Room Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2019-02-14">February 14, 2019</date>
                <publisher>Saratoga Springs Public Library</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>49 Henry St.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Saratoga Springs, NY 12866</addressline>
                    <addressline>(518) 584-7860</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nysspl.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>McKelvey Family Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1880/1985" type="inclusive">1880 - 1985</unitdate>
            <abstract>The McKelvey Family were a prominent Saratoga Springs family who were active in the development of several cultural associations. The father, Lawrence was a Judge. One son, Richard, was an academic and author, and another Robert was active in the development of the Saratoga Performing Arts Center and the local YMCA. The third son, William was developmentally disabled and a well-known personality around town.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Bethesda Episcopal Church, Boyd, Gordon</corpname>
                
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Saratoga Springs Public Library</corpname>
                <subarea>Saratoga Room</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="www.sspl.org"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection may be subject to Copyright Laws.</p>
            
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Lawrence McKelvey was a Family Court Judge who married Lillian Purdy in 1908. They eventually settled in Saratoga Springs and raised their three sons in a large home on Lake Ave. None of the sons ever married. </p>
        <p>Robert (1909-1974) became a deputy commissioner for the NYS Commerce Dept. He was actively involved in the founding and development of the Saratoga Performing Arts Center and the local YMCA. </p>
            <p>Richard (1912-1994), was an academic at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor and was an author of the tome, the Middle English Dictionary. He authored several plays and was approached to write for radio programs. Richard was an avid stamp collector. The stamp collection appears to have been liquidated with his estate with the exception of one album, which was retained by the church for future sale.</p>
            <p>William (1915-1985), was the youngest son. Bill was developmentally disabled and a much loved local character.</p>
            <p>The collection was found in the basement of the rectory at Bethesda Episcopal Church. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2010170531">McKelvey, Richard L.</persname>
            <persname>McKelvey, Lawrence B.</persname>
            <persname>McKelvey, Lillian P.</persname>
            <persname>McKelvey, Robert N.</persname>
            <persname>McKelvey, William R.</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n88226409">Villella, Edward, 1936-</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50017594">Balanchine, George</persname>
            <persname>Stoddard, Robert H.</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2005122502">Saratoga Performing Arts Center</corpname>
            <corpname>Young Men’s Christian Association</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50003343">New York City Ballet</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80125008">Philadelphia Orchestra</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5136334" source="geonames">Saratoga Springs (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject>Ballet</subject>
            <subject>Radio Authorship</subject>
        <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79065117">American Pharmaceutical Association</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection was initially sorted through by a church member, Gordon Boyd. A stamp collection album was removed; the sale will benefit the church.</p>
        <p>Following the order that Mr. Boyd had initiated, the collection has been sorted and arranged by individual family member’s name.</p>
            <p>The collection is comprised of letters, photographs, reports, original works and ephemera that were collected by the McKelvey Family and placed in the basement of the Bethesda Church at some point after the death of Richard in 1994. They were discovered in 2012 and donated to the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Items may only be used in the Saratoga Room.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="73a9a1_McKelvey_Family_folder_list.xlsx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>