<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybxlhr">nybxlhr0009</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Papers of Frank Ross Chambers</titleproper>
                <author>Ray Geselbracht</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2019-08-12">August 12, 2019</date>
                <publisher>Bronxville History Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybxlhr.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Papers of Frank Ross Chambers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1866/1964" type="inclusive">1866 - 1964</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Bronxville History Center’s collection of papers of Frank Ross Chambers consists of correspondence, photographs, an autobiographical manuscript, a speech draft, biographical sketches, a passport, printed material, and about 75 photographs—all relating primarily to the lives of Frank Ross Chambers and Kate Waller Chambers, and to their house in Bronxville, called “Crow’s Nest.”  Also included is an essay about the Nondescript Club’s first decade, 1895-1905, written by Margaret Chambers Warshuis.  The correspondence includes eleven letters from Frank Ross Chambers to Kate Waller Chambers, 1869-1888, 1924, and undated, and five letters from Kate Waller Chambers to Frank Ross Chambers, 1866 (or 1867), 1883, and undated; the autobiographical manuscript is by Frank Ross Chambers and covers his life from childhood to the time he married Kate Waller, in 1884.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>About 300 pages</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Frank Ross Chambers</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Open for research</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>When Frank Ross Chambers died on April 30, 1940, his obituary in the Bronxville Review Press called him the “first citizen of Bronxville,” using a phrase that was often heard around Bronxville to describe an extraordinary man.  Chambers lived in Bronxville for fifty-two years, from 1888 until his death.  He played a leading role in incorporating the Village of Bronxville in 1898, and for the next thirty years he served—and shaped—the village in many ways.  In village government, he was at different times village clerk, street commissioner, and president; he served on the Bronxville board of education, the Bronxville Library board of trustees, and on Lawrence Hospital’s board of governors.  He was for many years a deacon and elder and member of the consistory at Bronxville Reformed Church, and he was superintendent of the church’s Sunday school.  
He also gave the Village of Bronxville many gifts, including half the cost of acquiring land for and building a magnificent Village Hall and part of the cost of building a new village school building.  He wanted the village to have a large park on land near his house, and he accumulated sizable holdings of land for the purpose, but eventually most of this land was occupied by Bronxville School.  He made other donations of land to the village as well, including the parcels which became home to the public library and a new village hall.  The outcome of Chambers’ donations of land, and of his dedication to education and public service, was the creation of Bronxville’s civic center at the intersection of Pondfield and Midland Roads.
Frank Ross Chambers during his long life saw Bronxville transformed from a rural hamlet into a suburban village.  “When we came to Bronxville in 1888,” he wrote when he was an old man, “there were less than 300 people living within present Village limits.  Now there are 7,000.”  The village which Chambers left behind at his death in 1940 was in significant measure his creation and his gift to Bronxville’s residents and visitors.
</p>
        </bioghist>
        
        <scopecontent>
            
        <arrangement>
                <p>Subject File, 1866-1964

Box 1
•	Correspondence, 1869-1964
•	Frank Ross Chambers—Autobiographical Manuscript, January 1934
•	Frank Ross Chambers—Biographical Sketches
•	Frank Ross Chambers—Passport (1921) and City of Edinburgh Certificate of Registration
•	Letters—Frank Ross Chambers to Kate Waller Chambers, 1869-1888, 1924, and Undated
•	Letters—Kate Waller Chambers to Frank Ross Chambers, 1866 (or 1867), 1883, and Undated
•	Kate Waller Chambers—Writings, 1923-1924
•	Margaret Chambers Warnshuis—“The Nondescript Club and the Village of Bronxville, 1895-1905”
•	Crow’s Nest Sales Brochure, 1947
•	Photographs
</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Anyone wishing to make copies of the Bronxville History Center’s copies of these materials, or to publish any of the documents and photographs, must obtain permission from the New-York Historical Society.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="4a7a69_ChambersPapersNYHS.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>