<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybxlhr">nybxlhr0012</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Papers of Bertrand G. Burtnett</titleproper>
                <author>Ray Geselbracht and Myrna Geselbracht</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2019-10-07">October 7, 2019</date>
                <publisher>Bronxville History Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybxlhr.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Papers of Bertrand G. Burtnett</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1818/1960" type="inclusive">1818 - 1960</unitdate>
            <abstract>The papers of Bertrand G. Burtnett papers document primarily the history of Bronxville; the life of Bertrand G. Burtnett, including his several careers—as member of the New York State naval national guard, real estate contractor and broker, New York State assemblyman, member and president of the Bronxville Board of Education, business executive, political activist, Mason, member of several hereditary organizations, and Bronxville Village Historian and Eastchester Town Historian; and his family history and the hereditary organizations he belonged to.  </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.2 linear feet--about 4,000 pages</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination/>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>No restrictions on access.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>1874, Nov. 10	Born, 339 Pondfield Road, Bronxville, New York.  The great grandson of Alexander Masterton.
1896-1898	Served in the 1st Naval Battalion, N. Y., 3rd Division.
1899, Oct. 5		Married Frances Lock Lilly
1902			Ran for supervisor in Mount Vernon’s fourth ward
1907, May 5		Birth of daughter, Elizabeth
c. 1912-1920 	Building homes for sale in Bronxville.  Probably lost this business during the recession of 1920-1921
c. 1913-1941	Active in the Progressive and Republican Parties
1913-1925	Served on the Bronxville Board of Education; was president of the board, c. 1922-1925
1916	Placed on the reserve list for non-commissioned officers and enlisted men by the adjutant general of the State of New York
1917	Appointed chairman of the 1917 Independence Day celebration by the president of the board of trustees, Village of Bronxville
1917	Appointed chief registrar of the Committee on Enrollment for Military Service in Westchester County
c. 1917	-1918		Active in the Boy Scouts
1917			Employed by the Gramatan Coal and Supply Company
1917			President of the Union Corners Hose Company	
1918			Member of the American Protective League
1917-1919	Member of the New York State Assembly for the district that included Bronxville
c. 1917-1955	Active in the Masons
1918-?	Employed as Assistant Superintendent for Buildings by the            Y. M. C. A.
1919-1929	Lived at the Hillcrest Apartments, Bronxville
c. 1928	Joined hereditary organizations including the General Society of the War of 1812, Saint Andrew’s Society, Saint Nicholas Society, the Sons of the Revolution, the Society of Colonial Wars.  Withdrew from most of these organizations in 1933, citing personal financial difficulties.
1928-?			Employed at J. C. Penney Co., New York City
1928-1933		Lived at Alden Place, Bronxville
1931-?	President of Eastchester Court Corporation, owner of Meadow Court in Bronxville
1933-?			Worked at Westchester First National Corp., White Plains
c. 1934-1943	Lived at Meadow Court, Bronxville
c. 1935-1943	Worked as a realtor, with partner Montgomery L. Hart, at Hart &amp; Burtnett, Inc., 65 Pondfield Road; name changed to Burtnett and Associates in 1941
c. 1936-1940  	Served as vice president and then president of the Bronxville Realty Board
1936-1955		Served as Bronxville Village Historian and Eastchester Town Historian
1938-1939	Provided advice regarding the subject of mural for the Bronxville Post Office to artist John Sloan
1944-1955		Lived at 96 Kraft Ave., Bronxville
1951, May		Accompanied Bronxville School students on a field trip to the Old 
Marble Schoolhouse in Eastchester; spoke to the students about his student days at the schoolhouse

1952			Death of Frances Lilly Burtnett
1955, Nov. 20		Died, Bronxville

</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess/>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection includes correspondence, photographs, printed material, reports, newspaper clippings, historical articles, survey forms, memorandums, legal documents, programs, minutes and notes of meetings, speeches, scrapbooks, indentures, a travel journal, and other documents and is arranged in two series, a Subject File, and a Family History File.  The Subject File combines material relating to the history of Bronxville and to Burtnett’s life and many careers.  The Family History File includes material relating to the family history of Bertrand G. Burtnett and of his wife, Frances Lilly Burtnett, and to the hereditary organizations to which Burtnett belonged.  
Most of the photographs among Burnett’s papers were long ago transferred to the Bronxville History Center photograph collection.
The Burtnett papers were given to the Bronxville Public Library sometimes after Burtnett’s death in late 1955.  The collection was transferred to the newly organized Eastchester Historical Society in 1964, and was returned to the Bronxville Public Library, and to the custody of Bronxville Village Historian Jean Bartlett, in 1973.  The library placed the collection in the Local History Room (now the Bronxville History Center), which is a department of the Village of Bronxville, in about 1981.
</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The collection is open for research by appointment at the Bronxville History Center, Bronxville Public Library, 201 Pondfield Road, Bronxville, NY 10708. Contact the village historian at geselbracht321@gmail.com.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="0d5363_BurtnettPapers.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>