<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybxlhr">nybxlhr0003</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Bronxville-Related Post Card Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Eloise L. Morgan, Bronxville Village Historian</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-10-13">October 13, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Bronxville History Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>201 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York, U.S.A</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybxlhr.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bronxville-Related Post Cards Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1905/1965" type="inclusive">1905 - 1965</unitdate>
            <abstract>Approximately 500 unique used and unused picture postcards depicting Bronxville scenes, primarily view cards of houses and other structures and some streetscapes and miscellaneous subjects. The collection includes at least one private mailing card, some two dozen undivided-back cards dating from 1906-07, and about three dozen real photograph cards. Many of the early cards were published by three Bronxville businesses: Chambers Pharmacy, Frederick S. Steinman’s Pharmacy, and stationer Thomas J. Lydon. At least 30 other publishers produced Bronxville cards over the years. The collection contains duplicates of many cards, many of which contain a variety of handwritten messages and postal cancellations.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>Approximately 500 unique post card images. With duplicates the collection is approximately two linear feet contained in two standard size postcard boxes.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>No restriction on access</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The collection is comprised of picture post cards collected by Bronxville Village Historians over the years. In the early years, many cards were donated by history-minded residents. In later years, acquisitions at post cards shows and online substantially enlarged the collection.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110269" source="geonames">Bronxville (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The postcards are organized in 21 different alphabetical categories, many of which themselves are divided into sub-categories.</p>
            <arrangement/>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The collection is open by appointment for research at the Bronxville History Center, Bronxville Public Library, 201 Pondfield Road, Bronxville, New York. Images may be scanned and made available to users who give credit to the Bronxville History Center.  Contact the village historian at geselbracht321@gmail.com.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="faca6d_fb5760c44850-1.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>