<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybxlhr">nybxlhr0006</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Louise Lawrence Meigs Photograph Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Ray Geselbracht</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-12-08">December 8, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Bronxville History Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>201 Pondfield Rd. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybxlhr.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Louise Lawrence Meigs Photograph Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate">c. 1887-1916</unitdate>
            <abstract>The collection contains about 1200 photographs which document the personal lives of Louise Lawrence Meigs, her family, and some of her acquaintances.  Meigs and her family were wealthy people, and the photographs in the collection depict their homes and leisure activities, including their movements among their seasonal dwellings and their travels in the United States and to Europe.  Many of the photographs in the collection depict scenes in the Adirondack Mountains, where the Meigs had a home at Big Wolf Lake, and also scenes in Bronxville, New York, where the Meigs primarily home was located, at 42 Prescott Avenue.  The photographs also depict New York City, Washington, DC, rural England, and Meigs's father's home near New Castle, New Hampshire.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>About 1200 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Louise Lawrence Meigs</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>no restrictions on access</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Louise Lawrence Meigs (1871-1965) was the eldest child of William Van Duzer Lawrence, arguably the founder of modern Bronxville, and Sarah Lawrence.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection is arranged in a single series, the Photograph Album File, which includes ten photograph albums and a groups of 31 glass lantern slides.  The photographs relate primarily to the family and friends of Louise lawrence Meigs and the places they lived in and visited, including prominently Bronxville, New York, and the Adirondack Mountains.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The collection is open for research by appointment at the Bronxville History Center, Bronxville Public Library, 201 Pondfield Road, Bronxville, New York 10708.  Contact the village historian at geselbracht321@gmail.com. </p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="e561f5_LouiseLawrenceMeigsPhotographs111317.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>