<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybxlhr">nybxlhr0010</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Records of the Leonard S. Morange Post No. 464, American Legion, Department of New York</titleproper>
                <author>Ray Geselbracht</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2019-08-16">August 16, 2019</date>
                <publisher>Bronxville History Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybxlhr.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Records of the Leonard S. Morange Post No. 464, American Legion, Department of New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1918/1983" type="inclusive">1918 - 1983</unitdate>
            <abstract>The records of the Leonard S. Morange Post No. 464, American Legion, New York Department include minutes of the Post's regular monthly meetings and of the meetings of its executive committee, Post commander reports, correspondence, programs from the events that the Post sponsored in Bronxville, particularly during thye 1920s and 1930s, scrapbooks, membership history cards, a few artifacts, and other materials.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4 linear feet</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination/>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>No access restrictions.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The Leonard S. Morange Post No. 464 was organized in 1919 and became an important part of the civic and social life of Bronxville, establishing two war memorials in the village, leading the Memorial Day parade every year, and sponsoring a considerable number of successful and occasionally glamorous events, especially during the 1920s and 1930s.  The Post was composed initially of World War I veterans and, in its later decades, primarily of World War II veterans.  The Post is defunct.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess/>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The records are currently crudely arranged but described adequately in a preliminary inventory.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>The records are open to research, by appointment, at the Bronxville History Center.  Contact the Village Historian, Ray Geselbracht, at geselbracht321@gmail.com, 914-337-8768.</p>
        </userestrict>
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="" xlink:role=""/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>