<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybxlhr">nybxlhr0011</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Bronxville History Center Printed Materials Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Ray Geselbracht</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2019-08-21">August 21, 2019</date>
                <publisher>Bronxville History Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybxlhr.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Bronxville History Center Printed Materials Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal=""/>
            <abstract>Administrative Information
Title:  Bronxville History Center Printed Materials Collection
Volume (excluding duplicates):  
	Newspapers:  About 100,000 pages
Books:  About 365 items
	Pamphlets, Booklets, Reprints, Reports, Periodicals:  5.3 linear feet
	School Yearbooks (not including Bronxville School):  14 items
	Exhibition and Auction Catalogs:  39 items
	Postcards:  About 510 items
Access:  Open
Processed by Raymond H. Geselbracht

</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>5.3 linear feet, plus 100,000 pages, plus about 930 items </extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center Printed Materials Collection</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Bronxville History Center</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>200 Pondfield Rd.</addressline>
                    <addressline>Bronxville, New York 10708</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Open for research</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess/>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Collection Description
	The Printed Materials Collection is organized in seven series:
	The Newspaper Collection (1902-2009) includes about 100,000 pages of historic newspapers from Bronxville, Tuckahoe, and Eastchester.  They are accessible and fully searchable online at www.news.hrvh.org.   Paper and microfilm copies of some of the newspapers are also available at the History Center.
The Book Collection includes books about Bronxville, its history, people, and institutions; books written by Bronxville residents, including Roy Chapman Andrews, Nardi Reeder Campion, Robert W. Chambers, Elizabeth B. Custer, Tudor Jenks, Charles R. Knight, Will H. Low, Jack Paar, Eddie Rickenbacker, Alice Wellington Rollins, Edmund Clarence Stedman, Kate Douglas Wiggin, and Louise Beebe Wilder; books by and about members of the family of Joseph P. Kennedy; and autobiographies of William Van Duzer Lawrence and Kate Waller Chambers; histories of Eastchester, Westchester County, and New York City; and histories of art and architecture.
	The Pamphlets, Booklets, Reprints, Reports, and Periodicals Collection includes items about the history of Bronxville, surrounding communities such as Yonkers and Mount Vernon and Eastchester, and Westchester County; items about Bronxville’s village government, its neighborhoods, its artists and architects, its schools, churches, civic organizations, veterans and patriotic organizations, and country clubs; its real estate developments; its political parties and campaigns; and about Lawrence Hospital, the Hotel Gramatan, the Bronxville Public Library, and the Bronx River Parkway Reservation.
	The City Directories and Telephone Books Collection (1891-2019) includes two city directories that include Bronxville information, one from 1916 and the other from 1929; several other business and resident directories and extracts from directories (1891-1966, 2000); issues of the Bronxville Guide, published by the Bronxville Chamber of Commerce, 1965-2012, 2019, with a few issues missing; issues of the Bronxville Handi-Book, Including Eastchester, Scarsdale and Tuckahoe, 1979-1985, with 1983 missing; and issues of Directory—Village of Bronxville, published by the Village of Bronxville, 1967-2012, with several issues missing.
	The School Yearbooks Collection (1913-1953) includes yearbooks from Brantwood Hall (1921, 1925, 1928, 1941-1946), Concordia College (1913, 1915, 1919, 1953), and the Edison Vocational and Technical High School of Mount Vernon (1947).  Bronxville School yearbooks are in the Bronxville School Collection.
	The Exhibition and Auction Catalogs (1895, 1977-2010) collection contains items relating to the sale and exhibition of works of art created by people who lived and worked in Bronxville, including auction catalogs from Christie’s New York and exhibition catalogs from the Bronxville Historical Conservancy, the Hudson River Museum, the Musée Municipal A.-G Poulain-Vernon, the Museum of the City of New York, the OSilas Gallery of Concordia College, and the Spanierman Gallery of New York.
	The Postcards Collection (1906-c. 1960s) includes images, often the best images of their subjects in the History Center’s collection, of Bronxville’s public buildings, such as the two Village Halls (1906 and 1942), the Hotel Gramatan and its surrounding commercial buildings, the Bronxville School buildings of 1906 and 1925-30, the Bronxville Public Library, Lawrence Hospital, Concordia College, the five churches (Reformed, Episcopal, Catholic, Lutheran, Christian Scientist), the two railroad stations (1893 and 1916); and also of apartment buildings, residential streets, and houses (especially those in Lawrence Park); and of scenes in the communities surrounding Bronxville.

</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Open for research at the Bronxville History Center, by appointment with the Village Historian, at geselbracht321@gmail.com, 914-337-8768.</p>
        </userestrict>
    
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="e2d61d_BHCPrintedMaterialsFindingAid81519.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>