<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyamcfi">nyamcfi0002</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>False Memory Syndrome Foundation Collection</titleproper><author>Center for Inquiry Libraries / Shane Stephenson, Archives in the Buff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2018-10-30">October 30, 2018</date><publisher>Center for Inquiry Libraries</publisher><address><addressline>PO Box 741</addressline><addressline>Amherst, New York 14226-0741</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyamcfi.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>The False Memory Syndrome Foundation Collection</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate">1992 -present</unitdate><abstract>This collection was accumulated over the course of the False Memory 		 	               Syndrome Foundation’s existence, 1992 – 2017. It is broken into three series: FMSF Records, Correspondence, and Family Surveys. </abstract><physdesc><extent>Approx. 187.5 cu ft</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><corpname source="viaf" authfilenumber="126315530">False Memory Syndrome Foundation</corpname></origination><repository><corpname>Center for Inquiry Libraries</corpname><address><addressline>PO Box 741</addressline><addressline>Amherst, New York 14226-0741</addressline></address></repository><repository/></did><accessrestrict><p>This collection can be used by appointment only by serious researchers to be determined on a case-by-case basis.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>The False Memory Syndrome Foundation was established in 1992 by Pamela and Peter Freyd after their daughter accused her father, Peter, of sexual abuse when she was a child. The purpose of the foundation is to examine the concept of false memory syndrome and recovered memory therapy, to seek out the reasons for the spread of false memories, and work for ways to prevent it. The foundation advocates on behalf of individuals believed to be falsely accused of child sexual abuse. In addition, they assist with families healing process through education, reconciliation, and coping techniques. The foundation became heavily involved with the Institute for Experimental Psychiatry at the University of Pennsylvania, and Johns Hopkins Medical Institution in Baltimore, MD, and these entities combined knowledge, resources, and expertise. They were frequently called to testify, give depositions to various cases in the court system, and got involved with false memory cases around the world. As of 2018, the foundation is still in existence, but it is slowly winding down its work. </p></bioghist><controlaccess><corpname source="viaf" authfilenumber="126315530">False Memory Syndrome Foundation</corpname><subject authfilenumber="93005727" source="lcsh">False memory syndrome</subject></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>This collection includes, binders, file folders, DVD’s, books, and other paper material. The bulk of the collection spans the years, 1992 – 2012, while there is also content from the 1980s – 2017. 
The False Memory Syndrome Foundation is one of the best archival 	collections regarding the study of “False Memory.” This collection 	explores what False Memory is, it contains real world samples through correspondence with families that have suffered both real and imagined abuse, surveys scientific and psychological journal articles, legal cases, 	news articles, and work with other agencies that address childhood abuse

</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>A non-disclosure form will be given to the researcher, and any publications or media created by using this collection will require a copy be given to the Center for Inquiry libraries. In addition, confidentiality is paramount; some records have been cleared of names, especially the family correspondence to protect the family members, both adults and children. Each family has been assigned a number, and the Center for Inquiry librarian will retrieve the proper records for you. </p></userestrict><otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload"><bibref><extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="fee9b9_The_FMSF_Collection.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/></bibref></otherfindaid></archdesc></ead>