<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0007</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Ivan Mikhailovich Andreev (Andreevskii) Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-15">May 15, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Ivan Mikhailovich Andreev (Andreevskii) Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1944/1998" type="inclusive">1944 - 1998</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collections contains the correspondence and somewritings of Ivan Mikhailovich Andreevskii, who wrote under the pseudonym I. M. Andreev.  </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w61v8pnk">Andreev, I. M. (Ivan Mikhailovich), 1894-1976</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Ivan Mikhailovich Andreevksii was born in Saint Petersburg, Russia in 1894. Andreevskii was incarcerated in the Solovestkii concentration camp from 1927 to 1932. In 1950 he emigrated to the United States, where he taught at Holy Trinity Seminary in Jordanville, New York until 1971. He wrote many books over the course of his career, using the pen name I. M. Andreev. He died in Jordanville, New York in 1976. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w61v8pnk">Andreev, I. M. (Ivan Mikhailovich), 1894-1976</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5122926" source="geonames">Jordanville (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain the correspondence and some writings of Ivan Mikhailovich Andreevskii (pen-name: I. M. Andreev), a prominent writer in the Russian emigration in the U.S., and formerly interred in the Solovetsk concentration camp from 1927-1932. In emigration, Andreevskii settled in the U.S., teaching various subjects at Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary and editing several publications. These papers reflect only a fragment of Andreevskii’s activities and writings. Among his SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, included in this collection, are writings on pedagogy and psychology, as well as catacomb Orthodox communities in the U.S.S.R.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="10f6a0_Andreevskii.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>