<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0010</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Konstantin Stavrovich Cherkassov (Lagoridov) Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir  von Tsurkiov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-16">May 16, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Konstantin Stavrovich Cherkassov (Lagoridov) Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1984" type="inclusive">1984</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the manuscript of Cherkassov's novel "Mezhdu dvukh ognei," along with related correspondence.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.4 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6md277b">Cherkassov, Konstantin</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Konstantin Stavrovich Cherkassov was born Konstantin Stavrovich Lagoridov in Taganrog, Russia in 1921. During the Second World War, Cherkassov served in Andrei Vlasov's Rossiiskaia osvoboditel’naia armiia (ROA), holding the rank of Captain in the 5th Cossack Division. After the war, Cherkassov lived in a displaced persons camp in Parsch, Austria, before emigrating to Australia in 1949. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6md277b">Cherkassov, Konstantin</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain Konstantin Stavrovich Cherkassov’s novel “Mezhdu dvukh ognei” in manuscript form. As a former member of General Andrei Vlasov’s Rossiiskaia osvoboditel’naia armiia, Cherkassov wrote this work of historical fiction drawing on facts experienced first-hand. Cherkassov was born Lagoridov, but adopted his new name after World War II. He was a captain in the 5th Cossack Division under the command of General Ivan Kononov, and later served as reconnaissance officer. After World War II, Cherkassov first assumed the last name Dulshers. Cherkassov lived in a displaced persons camp in Parsch, Austria, until 1949, when he emigrated to Australia, where he worked as a gardener. Included are his letters to Archbishop Laurus, to whom he submitted his manuscript for consideration for publication by Holy Trinity Monastery’s printshop of St. Job of Pochaev.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="39d7a3_Cherkassov.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>