<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0037</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A register of the Archpriest Mikhail Pol'skii Papers</titleproper>
                <author>James Volmensky</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-08-18">August 18, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Archpriest Mikhail Pol'skii Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1924/1959" type="inclusive">1924 - 1959</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the correspondence of Archpriest Mikhail Pol’skii, particularly with Grand Duchess Kseniia Aleksandrovna Romanova and her family.  </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no89002462">Polʹskīĭ, M. (Mikhail)</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Archpriest Mikhail Pol'skii was born in Novotroitsk in Kuban Oblast in 1891. Pol'skii graduated from Stavropol' Theological Seminary in 1914, and in 1920 he was ordained a priest. In 1923 he was arrested and imprisoned in Solovki concentration camp, being released in 1929. In 1930, Pol'skii  escaped the Soviet Union and emigrated to British Palestine, and from there to London, England. There, he served as a rector at a Russian Orthodox parish from 1938-1948, and in this capacity came into contact with Grand Duchess Kseniia Aleksandrovna who was living in exile in England. In 1948 Pol'skii emigrated to the United States, settling in the city of San Francisco and serving at the Russian cathedral there until his retirement in 1959. Pol'skii died in San Francisco on May 21, 1960.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no89002462">Polʹskīĭ, M. (Mikhail)</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85118939">Marīi︠a︡ Ḟeodorovna, Empress, consort of Alexander III, Emperor of Russia, 1847-1928</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="nb2002065404">Ksenii︠a︡ Aleksandrovna, Grand Duchess, daughter of Alexander III, Emperor of Russia, 1875-1960</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n81107824">Alexander III, Emperor of Russia, 1845-1894</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection contains the correspondence of Archpriest Mikhail Pol’skii. The bulk of the collection is in the correspondence file. The largest file contains correspondence between Pol’skii and Grand Duchess Kseniia Aleksandrovna Romanova. Other files contain correspondence between Pol’skii and Kseniia Aleksandrovna’s family and household. The artworks series contains watercolors created by Kseniia Aleksandrovna. The photograph series contains prints of Kseniia Aleksandrovna at her home, Wilderness House.</p>
            <p>This collection was previously misidentified as the “Kseniia Aleksandrovna Romanova Papers.” </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="ca475c_Polskii_finding_aid.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>