<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0019</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Natal'ia Apollinarievna Logunova Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-18">May 18, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Natal'ia Apollinarievna Logunova Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1943/1978" type="inclusive">1943 - 1978</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the correspondence and writings of Natal'ia Apollinarievna  Logunova, a writer in the White Russian diaspora.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3.2 cubic feet (8 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6tb573v">Logunova, Natalii︠a︡ Apollinarievna, d. 1972?.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Natal'ia Apollinarievna Logunova was born in Odessa, Russia in 1903. In 1920, Logunova fled to Romania. In 1944 she was deported to Germany and later lived in displaced persons camps. She emigrated to the United States in 1952. Logunova died in 1972.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6tb573v">Logunova, Natalii︠a︡ Apollinarievna, d. 1972?.</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85115953" source="lcsh">Russian American literature</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85023660" source="lcsh">Children's literature, Russian</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain the correspondence and writings of Natal’ia Logunova, a Russian journalist and writer, who emigrated to the United States, and also used the pen-names Nataliia Snarskaia, Nikolai Tallin, and NETLI. Logunova’s CORRESPONDENCE includes letters to publishers and writers. Among her SPEECHES AND WRITINGS are two published novels, Irina and Olen’ka Bell, as well as numerous articles, unpublished novels, plays, and short stories. A recurring theme in her writings is the fate of Russian émigrés, particular in the Displaced Persons camps. Of particular interest is her unpublished memoir “Tri epokhi.” </p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="9cc221_Logunova.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>