<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0038</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A guide to the Viacheslav Grigor'evich Naumenko Papers</titleproper>
                <author>James Volmensky</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-08-18">August 18, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Viacheslav Grigor'evich Naumenko Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1949/1961" type="inclusive">1949 - 1961</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the correspondence of Viacheslave Grigor’evich Naumenko, pertaining to the forced repatriation of the Cossacks from Lienz, Austria during Operation Keelhaul.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.5 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no95034967">Naumenko, Vi︠a︡cheslav Grigorʹevich, 1883-</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Viacheslav Grigor'evich Naumenko was born in Petrovskaia, Kuban Oblast in 1883. In 1901 he graduated from the Mikhailovskii Kadetskii Korpus in Voronezh, and in 1903 he completed the Nikolaevskii Cavalry School in Saint Petersburg. He saw action with Kuban Cossack forces during the First World War in Galicia, and later during the Russian Revolution where he participated in the First Kuban Campaign. in 1919 Naumenko was elected Ataman of the Kuban Cossacks, and in 1920 he evacuated the Crimean Peninsula with his forces, heading first to the island of Lemnos and finally settling in Serbia. In 1944 Naumenko evacuated to Northern Italy with fellow Cossacks, and after the war he was resettled in the Bavarian city of Kempten. In 1949 he immigrated to the United States. Naumenko died in Valley Cottage, New York in 1979.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no95034967">Naumenko, Vi︠a︡cheslav Grigorʹevich, 1883-</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148273" source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148389" source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945--Cossacks</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2009122069" source="lcsh">Cossacks--History--20th century</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148414" source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945--Forced repatriation</subject>
            <geogname authfilenumber="2772505" source="geonames">Lienz (Austria)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection contains the correspondence of General Viacheslav Grigor’evich Naumenko, a commander of Cossack forces during the First World War, the Russian Civil War, and the Second World War. The bulk of this collection pertains to Operation Keelhaul and the forced repatriation of Cossacks at Lienz, Austria in 1945. </p>
            <p>Efforts were made during processing to retain the original order of the collection. The correspondence was arranged by the country of residence of the correspondent, as is reflected in the following finding aid. The correspondence pertaining to the events the transpired at Lienz was organized alphabetically by correspondent in two folders, labelled 2 and 3; the first folder was not in this collection of documents.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="683a7b_Naumenko_finding_aid.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>