<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0033</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Registry of the Raissa G. Zemmering Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-24">May 24, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Raissa G. Zemmering Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1933/1957" type="inclusive">1933 - 1957</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the correspondence of Raissa G. Zemmering, most notably her correspondence with the writer Ivan Sergeevich Shmelev. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.4 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6c32cmn">Zemmering, Raissa Gavrilovna, 1892-1988.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6c32cmn">Zemmering, Raissa Gavrilovna, 1892-1988.</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w68w3nsk">Shmelev, I. S. (Ivan Sergeevich), 1873-1950</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers consist primarily of letters and postcards from Ivan Sergeevich Shmelev to Raissa Gavriilovna Zemmering. Most letters have been copied and typed by Raissa Zemmering after Shmelev’s death. Included are also five letters from different individuals addressed to Raissa Zemmering. The IVAN SHMELEV FILE include undated notes, and an undated typescript, “Ugodniki solovetskie.”</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="1557ab_Zemmering.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>