<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0015</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register/Inventory of the  Vladimir Sergeevich Khitrovo Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-16">May 16, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Vladimir Sergeevich Khitrovo Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1910/1967" type="inclusive">1910 - 1967</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers contain the correspondence and writings of Vladimir Sergeevich Khitrovo, a graduate of the Pazheskii korpus and participant of World War I and member of the White Army</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.8 cubic feet (2 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
                <language langcode="fre">French</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6tm8pkd">Khitrovo, Vladimir Sergeevich, 1891-1968.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Vladimir Sergeevich Khitrovo was born in Russia in 1891, graduating from the Pazheskii korpus in 1910. In 1918 he served as an officer in General Kirpichev’s Kievskaia dobrovol’cheskaia druzhina, and in 1920 he worked as the chief of the Russian press bureau in Constantinople. Khitrovo died in Paris, France in 1968.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6tm8pkd">Khitrovo, Vladimir Sergeevich, 1891-1968.</persname>
            <subject>Soiuz pazhei</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148236" source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain the correspondence and writings of Vladimir Sergeevich Khitrovo, a graduate of the Pazheskii korpus and participant of World War I and member of the White Army. In emigration, Khitrovo was active in the alumni association of the Pazheskii korpus, the Soiuz pazhei, which is reflected in a number of organizational files of this association, including bylaws, correspondence, and lists of members within the Subject file. Of particular interest is Khitrovo’s unpublished memoir of World War I, “Vospominaniia i materialy dlia istorii. Leib-gvardii konnaia artilleriia. Chast’ II-aia. Voina 1914-1917. Pokhod v vostochnuiu Prussiiu,” which include numerous original photographs. </p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="a4f2fa_Khitrovo.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>