<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0034</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A guide to the Leonid Mikhailovich Savelov Papers </titleproper>
                <author>Andrey Lyubimov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-07-13">July 13, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Leonid Mikhailovich Savelov Papers </unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1894/1992" type="inclusive">1894 - 1992</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the writings of Leonid Mikhailovich Savelov, an historian and genealogist. Included within this collection is a memoir penned by Savelov, and poetry written by his daughters.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.4 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n82240889">Savelov, L. M. (Leonid Mikhaĭlovich), 1868-1947</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Leonid Mikhailovich Savelov was born in Warsaw on April 30, 1868. He graduated from the Orel Cadet Corps in 1886. From 1892 to 1903 Savelov was the district nobility leader in Voronezh Province. In 1904 he moved to Moscow to work at the Ministry of Internal Affairs, and in 1908 he became the head of the Archive of the Ministry of the Imperial Court. From 1916-1917 he served as Governor of the Kholmsk Province, but following the Russian Revolution and Civil War he emigrated abroad, arriving in Greece in 1920, and in Yugolsavia in 1923. In 1926 Savelov returned to Greece, settling for a time in Athens. He arrived in the United States in 1937, and died in Ann Arbor, Michigan on October 19, 1947.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n82240889">Savelov, L. M. (Leonid Mikhaĭlovich), 1868-1947</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="264371" source="geonames">Athens (Greece)</geogname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2004109491">Ioakim, Patriarch of Russia, 1620-1690</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85053742" source="lcsh">Genealogy</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection contains the select papers of Leonid Mikhailovich Savelov, a Russian statesman, historian, and genealogist, and represents a broad sample of his writings. The biographical series contains the poetry and writings of Savelov’s daughters, Elena Leonidovna and Vera Leonidovna, as well as an obituary of Savelov. The speeches and writings series contains holograph and typescript manuscripts by Savelov, including a holograph memoir. The subject file contains an essay on Patriarch Ioakim (Savelov), an ancestor of Leonid Mikhailovich. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="17be76_Savelov_finding_aid.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>