<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0022</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka Records</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-19">May 19, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka Records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1917/1984" type="inclusive">1917 - 1984</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the records of the Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka, the Union of Kornilov Shock Regiment Veterans, a unit of the White Army during the Russian Civil War.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.2 cubic feet (3 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6jt4w9c">Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Formed in May, 1917, the Kornilov Shock Regiment was named after General Lavr Georgievich Kornilov, and saw action in the Kerenksy Offensive of July 1917, and later during Lavr Kornilov's failed counterrevolutionary putsch in August of 1917. During the Russian Civil War, the Kornilov Shock Regiment took part in campaigns along the Don River, joining the Volunteer Army led by General Kornilov. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6jt4w9c">Ob"edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka.</corpname>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w62f8jk6">Kornilov, Lavr Georgievich, 1870-1918</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148236" source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85125808" source="lcsh">Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers consist of select records of the Ob”edinenie chinov Kornilovskogo udarnogo polka, the Union of Kornilov Shock Regiment Veterans, one of the units of the White Army during the Russian Civil War. The records relate to the fate of the regiment’s members in the emigration, dating from 1921 to 1980, and relating to their presence in Bulgaria, Serbia, France, Belgium and other European countries. Included among the documents are correspondence, financial records, membership lists, orders, photographs, and reports.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="37d696_Obedinienie_chinov_Kornilovskogo.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>