<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0004</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovikii Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-10">May 10, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1916/1961" type="inclusive">1916 - 1961</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection consists of materials collected by Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii for an exhibit titled "Zarubezhnaia Rus,'" which displayed the life of the Russian emigre community from 1916 to 1961.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>24 cubic feet (60 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6np3gqz">Abdank-Kossovskii, Vladimir Konkordovich, d. 1962</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Born in Vitebsk Guberniia in the Russian Empire in 1885, Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii was educated at the Lazarevskii institut vostochnykh iazykov, the Aleksandrovskoe voennoe uchilishche, the Ofitserskaia elektrotekhnicheskaia shkola, and the Istoriko-filologichskii fakul’tet Novorossiiskii University. In 1922, following the Russian Civil War, Abdank-Kossovskii emigrated to Paris, France via Tunis, Tunisia. In France, he worked as a reporter for the Russian emigre press from 1922 to 1962, and during this time he organized the exhibit whose materials comprise this collection. Abdank-Kossovskii died in Grasse, France in 1962.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6np3gqz">Abdank-Kossovskii, Vladimir Konkordovich, d. 1962</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6bp0s7g">Kolchak, Aleksandr Vasiliyevich, 1873-1920</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6b28159">Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1868-1918</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh97004371" source="lcsh">Exhibition catalogs</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85112309" source="lcsh">Political refugees</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sj96005546" source="lcsh">France. Army. Foreign Legion</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85007878" source="lcsh">Art, Russian</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers consist primarily of materials collected by Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii for the exhibit “Zarubezhnaia Rus’,” which chronicled the fate and life of Russian émigrés beginning in 1916 up to 1961. 
Vladimir Konkordovich Abdank-Kossovskii was a graduate of the Lazarevskii institut vostochnykh iazykov, the Aleksandrovskoe voennoe uchilishche, the Ofitserskaia elektrotekhnicheskaia shkola, and the Istoriko-filologichskii fakul’tet Novorossiiskii University.
</p>
            <p>Within the ZARUBEZHNAIA RUS’ FILE, the chronological file includes clippings, original documents, photographs, and print materials, providing information on the Russian diaspora in different countries, arranged by V. K. Abdank-Kossovskii himself, and pasted to album sheets. These materials were exhibited by Abdank-Kossovskii regularly in Paris. The subject file of the ZARUBEZHNAIA RUS’ FILE includes materials prepared by Abdank-Kossovskii for inclusion in the “Zarubezhnaia Rus’” exhibit, but categorized only by subject and not pasted for exhibit. These papers focus on all aspects of émigré existence, including Russian military and veteran organizations, Russian Orthodoxy, cultural, political and social organizations, literary life, and performing arts. </p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="888a5f_Abdank-Kossovskii.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>