<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0012</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the  Agnes M. Diterichs Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-16">May 16, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Agnes M. Diterichs Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1919/1922" type="inclusive">1919 - 1922</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers contain the detailed investigative report of the assassination of the last Tsar of Russia, Nicholas II, and his family. The report was prepared by Nikolai Alekseevich Sokolov, and includes the typescript of “Dielo ob ubiestvie tsarskoi sem’i v Ekaterinburgie,” and related documents, including correspondence, illustrations, and minutes.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.4 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6g47zcq">Diterichs, Agnes M.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>These papers contain the detailed investigative report of Nikolai Alekseevich Sokolov on the assassination of the Romanov Family in Ekaterinburg. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6b28159">Nicholas II, Emperor of Russia, 1868-1918</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2015001443" source="lcsh">Dom Ipatʹeva (Ekaterinburg, Russia)</subject>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w633230s">Romanov, House of</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="1486209" source="geonames">Yekaterinburg (Russia)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain the detailed investigative report of the assassination of the last Tsar of Russia, Nicholas II, and his family. The report was prepared by Nikolai Alekseevich Sokolov, and includes the typescript of “Dielo ob ubiestvie tsarskoi sem’i v Ekaterinburgie,” and related documents, including correspondence, illustrations, and minutes. Also included is P. A. Severnyi’s unpublished manuscript “Poslednie dni imperatora Nikolaia vtorogo.”</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="e70de4_Diterikhs.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>