<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0016</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-17">May 17, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1884/1969" type="inclusive">1884 - 1969</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection reflects the literary activities of General Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov, and contain his correspondence and writings.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2 cubic feet (5 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w60d2c42">Krasnov, P. N. (Petr Nikolaevich), 1869-1947</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov was born in Saint Petersburg, Russia in 1869. Krasnov graduated from the Pavlovskoe voennoe uchilishche in 1888 and embarked on a military career spanning three decades, commanding various Cossack units in the Russian Imperial Army. In 1918 he was elected Ataman of the Don Cossacks. During the interwar years Krasnov devoted himself to writing, penning six works. In 1943 Krasnov became the head of the Cossack units in the German army. In 1945 he was repatriated to the Soviet Union from Lienz, Austria, along with thousands of fellow Cossacks. Krasnov was executed in Moscow in 1947.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w60d2c42">Krasnov, P. N. (Petr Nikolaevich), 1869-1947</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh93007587" source="lcsh">Don Cossacks</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148273" source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148236" source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85125808" source="lcsh">Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers reflect the literary activities of General Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov, Don Cossack Ataman, writer and historian. Most of his writings in emigration focus on the events leading up to the Russian revolution, as well as on the revolution and its aftermath themselves. Krasnov also focused on the history of the Don Cossacks. His writings have been published in translation in English, German and other languages. This collection consists of detailed correspondence mainly related to his writings and personal matters, and also reviews of his published works. The SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE consists mainly of correspondence related to and reviews of his writings.</p>
            <p>The SUBJECT FILE consists of various materials on the Don Cossacks, including minutes of meetings, reports, official documents and publications, dating from 1917 to 1944.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="93f5c2_Krasnov.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>