<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0025</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the  Russkii Obshche-voinskii soiuz (ROVS) Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-23">May 23, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Russkii Obshche-voinskii soiuz (ROVS) Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1919/1986" type="inclusive">1919 - 1986</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers consist of select records of the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, ROVS, the Russian All-military union. Formed by General Petr N. Vrangel’ in 1924, ROVS managed to preserve the military structure of the demilitarized White Army in exile, while integrating its members into civilian life. ROVS played an important role in redefining the White Army’s ideology, and provided essential support to its members in emigration.
These records include detailed lists of ROVS members, correspondence, circulars, orders, and reports.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.5 cubic feet (10 manuscript boxes, 8 index card boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
                <language langcode="fre">French</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6vj44gj">Russkiĭ Obshche-Voinskiĭ Soi︠u︡z.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>These papers consist of select records of the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, ROVS, the Russian All-military union. Formed by General Petr N. Vrangel’ in 1924, ROVS managed to preserve the military structure of the demilitarized White Army in exile, while integrating its members into civilian life. ROVS played an important role in redefining the White Army’s ideology, and provided essential support to its members in emigration</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6vj44gj">Russkiĭ Obshche-Voinskiĭ Soi︠u︡z.</corpname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85289371">Vrangelʹ, Petr Nikolaevich, Baron, 1878-1928</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50035923">Denikin, Anton Ivanovich, 1872-1947</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148236" source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These records include detailed lists of ROVS members, correspondence, circulars, orders, and reports.
Included are documents that predate the formation of the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, such as circulars and orders of the White Army under General Denikin, and orders of the Russian Army under General Vrangel’s command.
Of particular importance is a collection of eight boxes of index cards, dating to 1924-1925, which provides personal information of members of the Gallipoli veteran’s association, included the numbers of distributed commemorative Gallipoli crosses. </p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="cf798a_ROVS.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>