<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0029</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the  Aleksandr Kallinikovich Svitich PapersA Register of the  Aleksandr Kallinikovich Svitich Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-24">May 24, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Aleksandr Kallinikovich Svitich Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1921/1965" type="inclusive">1921 - 1965</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers provide insight into the life of the Orthodox Church in Poland in the Interwar period. Aleksander K. Svitich, a theologian and member of the faculty of the Vilno Theological Seminary, served on the editorial board of Za svobodu, a Russian émigré newspapers, which he contributed numerous articles to, at times using his pen name Tuberozov. Reflected in these papers are also Svitich’s research interests.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.8 cubic feet (2 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="pol">Polish</language>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w61g8ddb">Svitich, Aleksandr Kallinikovich, 1890-1963.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Aleksandr Kallinikovich Svitich was born in Vilno, Russia in 1890. In 1930, Svitich graduated from the Theological Faculty of Warsaw University, and proceeded to teach at the Vilno Theological Seminary. In 1937 he emigrated from Poland to Serbia, settling in Belgrade and becoming a legal advisor to the Russian Orthodox Church Outside of Russia. In 1945 he emigrated to Germany, living in displaced persons camps until arriving in the United States in 1950. Svitich died in Denver, Colorado in 1963.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w61g8ddb">Svitich, Aleksandr Kallinikovich, 1890-1963.</persname>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6zw7k05">Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov zagranitsei.</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers provide insight into the life of the Orthodox Church in Poland in the Interwar period. Aleksander K. Svitich, a theologian and member of the faculty of the Vilno Theological Seminary, served on the editorial board of Za svobodu, a Russian émigré newspapers, which he contributed numerous articles to, at times using his pen name Tuberozov. Reflected in these papers are also Svitich’s research interests. </p>
            <p>The Subject file contains documents pertaining to the activities of the Orthodox Church in the Unites States. Noteworthy are the correspondence of Archbishop Arsenii (Chakhovtsev), and Archbishop Irinei (Bekish), and documents relating to the Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov’ zagranitsei.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="3f8c38_Svitich.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>