<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0028</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Papers of the  Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-24">May 24, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus  Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1899/1972" type="inclusive">1899 - 1972</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers consist of select records of the Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus (Suvorov cadet corps), located in Moscow, whose members were active in emigration in its alumni association. The records relate to the history of the cadet corps as well as the fate of the corps’ alumni in the diaspora.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>2.5 cubic feet (6 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6258mtd">Suvorovskiĭ kadetskiĭ korpus.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus was a military school located in Moscow whose members were active in emigration in its alumni association. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6258mtd">Suvorovskiĭ kadetskiĭ korpus.</corpname>
            <persname authfilenumber="n2010063202" source="lcnaf">Vera Konstantinovna, kni͡azhna, 1906-2001</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="n82019621" source="lcnaf">Suvorov, Aleksandr Vasilʹevich, kni͡azʹ Italiĭskiĭ, 1730-1800</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh92003827" source="lcsh">Military cadets</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers consist of select records of the Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus (Suvorov cadet corps). The records relate to the history of the cadet corps as well as the fate of the corps’ alumni in the diaspora. Included among the documents are correspondence, memoirs, and photographs. Of special interest are records pertaining to the annual celebration of the corps’ feast day, October 14th. The rich collection of prints, dating from 1899-1964 and totaling five hundred and sixty nine provides a rich source of information, as most prints are described in detail.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="4f7a61_SuvorovskiiKK.doc" xlink:role="application/msword"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>