<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0030</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Nikolai Dmitrievich Tal'berg Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-24">May 24, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Nikolai Dmitrievich Tal'berg Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1918/1967" type="inclusive">1918 - 1967</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers reflect the writings and research interests of Nikolai Talberg, a government official in pre-Revolutionary Russia and historian, writer, and professor in emigration. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7.4 cubic feet (18 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w67j3rfk">Tal'berg, N. D.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Nikolai Dmitrievich Tal'berg was born in Korostyshev, Kiev guberniia, Russia in 1886. He graduated from the Imperial School of Jurisprudence in 1907, and served the next years at a post with the Ministry of Internal Affairs. Following the Russian Revolution in 1917, Tal'berg became involved with an underground monarchist movement. In 1919 he left Russia, settling in Berlin in 1920. Following the Second World War, he emigrated to the United States, settling in Jordanville, New York, where he worked as a professor at Holy Trinity Seminary. Tal'berg died in Jordanville in 1967.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n87867189">Vitaliĭ, Archbishop</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w67j3rfk">Tal'berg, N. D.</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sj96006394" source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945--Refugees</subject>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6840zgj">Holy Trinity Monastery (Jordanville, N.Y.)</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers reflect the writings and research interests of Nikolai Talberg, a government official in pre-Revolutionary Russia and historian, writer, and professor in emigration. Among his writings are works related to late 19th and early 20th century history, partially based on his own reminiscences and others. Major themes include the history of the Russian Orthodox Church, politics and contemporary issues of the Russian diaspora.</p>
            <p>The SUBJECT FILE includes materials on the history of the Russian Orthodox Church and especially on the various jurisdictional conflicts that affected the Church in emigration. Particularly important are the documents dating from 1945 onwards relating to such conflicts in the United States. Of special significance is the correspondence of Archbishop Vitalii Maksimenko with representatives of different dioceses, parishes and organizations.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="1b25cd_Talberg.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>