<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0018</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the Reverend Stefan Liashevskii Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-18">May 18, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Reverend Stefan Liashevskii Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1935/1982" type="inclusive">1935 - 1982</unitdate>
            <abstract>This collection contains the correspondence and writings of Stefan Liashevskii, an geologist in the Soviet Union, an archpriest in the Russian Orthodox Church, a biblical scholar, and historian. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.2 cubic feet (3 manuscript boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6k481j3">Liashevskii, Stefan.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Stefan Liashevskii was born in Taganrog, Russian in 1899. He taught at the Novocherkassk Tekhnikum until 1934, when  he became the senior geologist at the Azov-Black Sea Trust in Rostov-on-Don. He served a term in a Siberian labor camp from 1936 to 1939, and upon his release he again worked as a senior geologist in Krasnodar', USSR. In 1943, Liashevskii was ordained to the priesthood in Taganrog. Following the Second World War, Liashevskii emigrated to the West, finally arriving in the United States. He died in Augusta, Maine in 1986.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6k481j3">Liashevskii, Stefan.</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50015060">Sofroniĭ, Archimandrite, 1896-1993</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85344792">Aleksiĭ, Patriarch of Moscow and All Russia, 1877-1970</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="542420" source="geonames">Krasnodar (Russia)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="484907" source="geonames">Taganrog (Russia)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="501175" source="geonames">Rostov-on-Don (Russia)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="518970" source="geonames">Novocherkassk (Russia)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="4957003" source="geonames">Augusta (Maine)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers reflect the writings, papers and research interests of Stefan Liashevskii, a geologist in the USSR, archpriest of the Russian Orthodox Church, biblical scholar, and historian in emigration. Stefan Liashevskii had close relations with a number of Russian Orthodox hierarchs, which is reflected in his CORRESPONDENCE FILE. Among his correspondents were Patriarch Aleksii (Simanskii), Metropolitan Iosif (Chernov) and Metropolitan Nikolai (Eremin).</p>
            <p>The SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE includes several historical essays and articles dedicated to ecclesiastical figures known personally by Liashevskii in Russia and in emigration, such as Patriarch Tikhon (Belavin), Metropolitan Serafim (Lade), Hieromonk Sofronii (Sakharov) and others. </p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="629ab2_Liashevskii.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>