<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0011</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the  Sviatoslav Varlaamovich Denisov Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-16">May 16, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Sviatoslav Varlaamovich Denisov Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1900/1966" type="inclusive">1900 - 1966</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers contain the correspondence and writings of Sviatoslav V. Denisov, Major General of the Don Cossack Army and participant in the Don Cossack uprising of 1918. In emigration, Denisov was president of the Cossack Union in the United States, and an active member of various Cossack organizations, especially the All-Cossack Union.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>13.6 cubic feet (32 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6wn3mkn">Denisov, S. V. (Sviatoslav Varlaamovich)</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Sviatoslav Varlaamovich Denisov was born in Stanitsa Piatiizbianskaia, Luganskaia oblast’, Russia in 1878. In 1896, Denisov graduated from the Donskoi kadetskii korpus, and in 1898 he completed his studies at the Mikhailovskoe artilleriiskoe uchilishche. From 1898 to 1905 he served in the 21st Don Cossack battery. In 1908 he graduated from the Nikolaevskaia akademiia general’nogo shtaba. From 1916 to 1918 he served as the commanding officer of the 11th Don Cossack regiment, and in 1918 he participated in the Don Cossack Uprising, becoming the leader of the Don Cossack Army. In 1919, Denisov emigrated to Constantinople, and from there to Berlin, Germany. Denisov arrived in the United States in 1923, where he was elected chair of the Cossack Union in the United States. Denisov died in Stratford, Connecticut in 1957.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6wn3mkn">Denisov, S. V. (Sviatoslav Varlaamovich)</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh93007587" source="lcsh">Don Cossacks</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85148236" source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh92004044" source="lcsh">Russia--History</subject>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6pk4k81">Denikin, Anton Ivanovich, 1872-1947</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain the correspondence and writings of Sviatoslav V. Denisov, major general in the Don Cossack Army and participant in the Don Cossack uprising of 1918. In emigration, Denisov was chair of the Cossack Union in the United States, and an active member of various Cossack organizations, especially the All-Cossack Union.</p>
            <p>The Correspondence file includes extensive correspondence with leading Russian émigré military and social leaders, providing a rich source of information on the activities of Cossack activities in the diaspora.</p>
            <p>Denisov’s Speeches and writings consist mainly of materials relating to his history of the White Army, Belyi Al’bom, as well as research materials and articles on Cossack history.</p>
            <p>The Subject file includes materials on the history of the Don Cossacks, the White Army, as well as Russian émigré organizations. Particularly important are the documents dating from 1917 onwards relating to the Don Cossack Army. Of special significance are the materials relating to the All-Cossack Union in the United States, as well as documents relating to the Don Cossack ataman elections.</p>
            <p>Printed matter includes appeals and circulars from the civil war period, 1919-1920, published in territories occupied by the White Army, Soobshcheniia Donskoi Armii (1919), issues of Vol’naia kuban’, and Velikaia Rossiia.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="959a6d_Denisov.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>