<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0031</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>An Inventory of the  Soiuz leib-gvardii tsarskosel’skikh strelkov Records</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-24">May 24, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Soiuz leib-gvardii tsarskosel’skikh strelkov Records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1929/1938" type="inclusive">1929 - 1938</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers consist of select records of the Soiuz leib-gvardii tsarskosel’skikh strelkov, formerly known as the Leib-gvardii 2-oi tsarskosel’skii strelkovyi polk.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>0.4 cubic feet (1 manuscript box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6479h03">Soiuz leib-gvardiĭ tsarskosel'skikh strelkov.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The Leib-gvardii 2-oi tsarskosel’skii strelkovyi polk (2nd Life Guard Infantry Regiment) was formed in 1856. This unit participated in the Russo-Turkish War of 1877-1878, as well as in the First World War. The regiment was disbanded in 1918, but then reformed as part of the Volunteer Army that same year, taking part in the Russian Civil War on the side of the White forces. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6479h03">Soiuz leib-gvardiĭ tsarskosel'skikh strelkov.</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers consist of select records of the Soiuz leib-gvardii tsarskosel’skikh strelkov, formerly known as the Leib-gvardii 2-oi tsarskosel’skii strelkovyi polk, but liquidated in 1918. These records relate to the fate of the regiment’s members in the emigration, dating from 1929 to 1938. Included among the documents are statutes, lists of members, and reports.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="1265fd_Tsarskos.Strelki.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>