<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhdu">nyhdu0017</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>A Register of the  Georgii Pavlovich Larin Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Vladimir von Tsurikov</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2017-05-17">May 17, 2017</date>
                <publisher>Foundation of Russian History</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                    <addressline>(315) 858-2468</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhdu.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The  Georgii Pavlovich Larin Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1922/1975" type="inclusive">1922 - 1975</unitdate>
            <abstract>These papers contain the correspondence of Georgii Pavlovich Larin, a Russian émigré and Cossack, who was active in China, and later emigrated to Australia. Included are various materials relating to the activities of the Bratstvo russkoi pravdy in China, a Russian émigré anti-communist secret society, such as correspondence, circulars, orders, reports, and printed matter. Of interest are also documents relating to the Russkoe obshchestvo vzaimnogo kredita (Russian Mutual Credit Corporation)</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1.4 cubic feet (3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
                <language langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6fk00tg">Larin, Georgiĭ Pavlovich, 1900-1992.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Foundation of Russian History</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>1407 Robinson Road </addressline>
                    <addressline>Jordanville, NY 13361</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://foundationrh.org/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Georgii Pavlovich Larin was born in Orenburg, Russian in 1900. In 1922 he left the city of Vladivostok with the evacuating White Army, settling in Shanghai, China. In 1933 he founded the Russian Mutual Credit Corporation. Following the fall of Shanghai to communist Chinese forces in 1949, he lived in a displaced persons camp on the island of Tubabao in the Philippines, before settling in Sydney, Australia. Larin died in Sydney in 1992. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6fk00tg">Larin, Georgiĭ Pavlovich, 1900-1992.</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="1681267" source="geonames">Tubabao Island (Philippines)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="515003" source="geonames">Orenburg (Russia)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="1796236" source="geonames">Shanghai (China)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="2147714" source="geonames">Sydney (N.S.W.)</geogname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85121107" source="lcsh">Shanghai (China)--History</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>These papers contain the correspondence of Georgii Pavlovich Larin, a Russian émigré and Cossack, who was active in China, and later emigrated to Australia. Included are various materials relating to the activities of the Bratstvo russkoi pravdy in China, a Russian émigré anti-communist secret society, such as correspondence, circulars, orders, reports, and printed matter. Of interest are also documents relating to the Russkoe obshchestvo vzaimnogo kredita (Russian Mutual Credit Corporation), on whose board of trustees Larin served from 1933 to 1943. This collection provides a valuable insight into the life of the Russian emigration in Shanghai, China.</p>
            <p>Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register.  Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the regulations of the Foundation of Russian History.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="eb88c0_Larin.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>