<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nald">nald0001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the James H. Armsby Papers</titleproper><author>Joshua Hauck-Whealton</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2016-10-03">October 3, 2016</date><publisher>Dudley Observatory</publisher><address><addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline><addressline>Schenectady, NY 12308</addressline><addressline>(518) 382-7890 ex. 259</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user Josh Hauck-Whealton.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Dr. James H. Armsby Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1851/1857" type="inclusive">1851 - 1857</unitdate><abstract>The papers of Dr. James Armsby contain correspondence relating to a few of Armsby's many booster projects.  Specifically it contains letters relating to the construction of the Dudley Observatory, the founding of the university that Dudely was supposed to be a part of, and some of Armsby's correspondence with attendee of the Army relief bazaar of 1864.</abstract><physdesc><extent>.6 cubic feet</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="nr97013203">Armsby, James H. (James Harvey), 1809-1875</persname></origination><unitdate normal="1864" type="inclusive">1864</unitdate><repository><corpname>Dudley Observatory</corpname><address><addressline>15 Nott Terrace Heights</addressline><addressline>Schenectady, NY 12308</addressline></address></repository></did><accessrestrict><p>Access to this collection is unrestricted.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>Born in Sutton, Massachusetts and trained at the Vermont Academy of Medicine, James H. Armsby arrived in Albany in 1932. He followed his brother-in-law, Dr. Alden March, to the Capital Region to help combat the Cholera epidemic that swept New York during the summer.</p><p>Armsby became a resident the next year.  Albany got a glimpse of what it could expect from the new citizen when he began campaigning to establish a new medical school, hospital and YMCA chapter in the city.  Like Mitchel, Armsby turned to the lecture circuit to raise money and support.  Those lectures, along with come public dissections, eventually founded the Albany Medical College.</p><p>Until his death by heart disease in 1875, Armby worked to build educational institutions.  Through another series of lectures, he raised enough money to save Albany Law School during a financial crisis.  He helped organize the Albany Army Relief Bazaar which supported the US Sanitary Commission. Armsby appears to have been the first person to suggest that an observatory be added to the plans for a university in Albany.  Even after the idea of the university faded, he remained a booster of the Observatory.   He served as the secretary of the board during the early years, but realistically was far more important to the budding institution. </p><p>For forty years, Dr. James Armsby was an institution builder in the booming city of Albany.  While he is laregly forgotten, intellectual life in the city would have been much poorer without him.</p></bioghist><controlaccess><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="nr97013203">Armsby, James H. (James Harvey), 1809-1875</persname></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>The papers of Dr. James H. Armsby contain incoming correspondence, newspapers and a few pamphlets that were included in five letterbooks. Dr. Armsby was Secretary of the Dudley Observatory Board of Trustees and kept incoming correspondence addressed to other members of the Board, including Thomas Olcott and Robert H. Pruyn. The contents of the letterbooks were removed from the acidic and deteriorating bindings and placed in acid-free folders. Before removal, each item was numbered in pencil on the verso. These numbers appear in the notes field of the container listing.
</p><p>The first book (Box # 1 Folders #1-20) held incoming correspondence regarding a bazaar that was held in Albany in 1865 to raise money to support the United States Sanitary Fund which provided aid for sick and wounded Union soldiers. Various photographs, autographs and works of art were sold or raffled off. One item included in the sale was a draft of the Emancipation Proclamation in Abraham Lincoln’s handwriting. Most of the correspondence is comprised of simple requests for raffle tickets. There is a small number of requests for donations and replies from donors.</p><p>The second letterbook (Box # 1 Folders # 21-30) was labeled “University Letters” and contained incoming correspondence (1850 -1856) from Ormsby M. Mitchell about the directorship of Dudley Observatory. Other correspondence in this letterbook concerns the meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the establishment of a National University in Albany. The selection of foreign guests and the solicitation of free transportation for them filled one section of the letterbook.</p><p>The third letterbook (Box # 1 Folders #31-48) contained correspondence addressed to several members of the Dudley Observatory Board of Trustees in 1856 and 1857.</p><p>The fourth letterbook (Box #1 Folders #49-66) contained correspondence about the establishment in Albany, NY of a National University, 1851-1853.</p><p>The last letterbook (Box # 2) contained correspondence from Benjamin Apthrop Gould, Jr. to Dr. Armsby and Thomas Olcott about the Dudley Observatory, 1855 to 1858; from Benjamin Pierce, 1858; from A.D. Bache, 1856 to 1857; and from Joseph Henry, 1857.</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>The researcher assumes full responsibility for conforming with the laws of copyright. Whenever possible, the Dudley Observatory will provide information about copyright owners and other restrictions, but the legal determination ultimately rests with the researcher. Requests for permission to publish material from this collection should be discussed with the Archivist.</p></userestrict><dsc><c id="c_389f510fba1f54d4851c87bbf7532bbb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Army relief bazaar, Correspondence,</unittitle><unitdate normal="1864">1864</unitdate></did></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>