<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuuar">nbuuar0001</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Patricia Ann Manuele Camp Fire Girls Uniform</titleproper><author>Sarah Pinard</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2016-05-02">May 2, 2016</date><address><addressline>420 Capen Hall </addressline><addressline>Buffalo, New York 14260-1674</addressline><addressline>http://library.buffalo.edu/archives</addressline><addressline>lib-archives@buffalo.edu</addressline><addressline>(716) 645-2916</addressline></address><publisher>State University of New York at Buffalo. University Archives</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user spinard.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Patricia Ann Manuele Camp Fire Girls Uniform</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950 - 1960</unitdate><abstract>A collection of clothing items worn by Patricia Ann Manuele during her time in the Camp Fire Girls. Each item features specific elements and decorations that carry meaning within the organization.</abstract><physdesc><extent>3.17 linear feet (2 oversize boxes)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname source="viaf" authfilenumber="">Manuele, Patricia Ann</persname></origination><unitid>MS 237</unitid></did><accessrestrict><p>The Patricia Manuele Camp Fire Girls Uniform, circa 1950-1960s is open to researchers.</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>Born in 1951, Patricia Ann Manuele was a Buffalo, NY native and member of the Camp Fire Girls organization. She attended various universities around the nation before settling in Oregon. In 2007 she passed away after battling leukemia. The Camp Fire Girls organization was founded in 1910 and incorporated in 1912. Concerned with providing recreational opportunities for girls comparable to those existing for boys, the founders aimed "to train girls for their responsibilities as distinct from those of boys." A 1915 Camp Fire Girls manual proclaims: "Camp Fire Girls is an organization of girls and women to develop the home spirit and make it dominate the entire community." Prominent among the founders were Dr. and Mrs. (Charlotte) Luther Hasley Gulick who worked out much of the early program of the Camp Fire Girls at Wohelo, their summer camp in Sebago, Maine. The name of the Gulick's camp, Wohelo, became the motto of the Camp Fire Girls, symbolizing the goals of "Work, Health, and Love."</p></bioghist><controlaccess><genreform authfilenumber="300210387" source="aat">ceremonial costume</genreform><subject authfilenumber="sh85055022" source="lcsh">Girls--Societies and clubs</subject><corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w60915c9">State University of New York at Buffalo. Archives.</corpname><persname source="viaf" authfilenumber="">Manuele, Patricia Ann</persname><corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6hs0h0m">Camp Fire Girls Inc.</corpname></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>This collection contains a Camp Fire Girls ceremonial uniform and moccasins that were customized by the wearer and reflected the rank and acheivements they had attained. Each patch and bead's color, shape, and size has a meaning for members in the organization and reflect their ability.</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>Copyright of papers in the collection may be held by their authors, or the authors' heirs or assigns. Researchers must obtain the written permission of the holder(s) of copyright and University Archives before requesting photocopies and/or publishing quotations from materials in the collection. Once permission is obtained, most papers may be copied in accordance with the library's usual procedures unless otherwise specified.</p></userestrict><dsc><c id="c_e6ea00f64e933de159435f0d4741613e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Camp Fire Girls Ceremonial Collar</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950 - 1960</unitdate><container type="">Oversize-box 1.1+</container></did><scopecontent><p>Attached to this ceremonial collar are patches and beads that indicate rank and personal achievements within the Camp Fire Girls organization. The shape, size, and color of each item is representative of some accomplishment.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_c5950398cd3d45ad98272ad68e63a48b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Camp Fire Girls Ceremonial Gown</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950 - 1960</unitdate><container type="">Oversize-box 1.2+</container></did><scopecontent><p>Attached to this ceremonial gown are beads personal achievements within the Camp Fire Girls organization.  The shape, size, and color of each item is representative of some accomplishment.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c_40492d97eb47125457ef76c146b3a5da" level="item"><did><unittitle>Camp Fire Girls Ceremonial Moccasins</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950 - 1960</unitdate><container type="">Oversize-box 2+</container></did><scopecontent><p>Moccasins were customized and decorated individually within the Camp Fire Girls organization.</p></scopecontent></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>