<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0012</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Fraser Drew/Langston Hughes Correspondence Collection </titleproper>
                <author>Lauren Thompson</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-07">December 7, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Fraser Drew/Langston Hughes Correspondence Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1950/1967" type="inclusive">1950 - 1967</unitdate>
            <abstract>Fraser Drew had the opportunity to keep in contact with Langston Hughes during the peak of his career.  Dr. Drew was a professor of English at SUNY Buffalo State for decades; he retired in 1983.  He received his Ph.D. in English Literature from the University at Buffalo in 1952.  His interest in African American literature motivated him to follow Langston Hughes’ career closely, and this led him to reach out to Hughes directly.  Hughes responded by keeping open communication with Drew for a number of years.  </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 folder; .25 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6q66fsc">Drew, Fraser</persname>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80014956">Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Fraser Drew/Langston Hughes Correspondence Collection is open for research. </p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/drew-hughes-correspondence</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Langston Hughes was born on 1 February 1902 in Joplin, Missouri, and died on 22 May 1967.  His maternal grandmother raised him in Lawrence, Kansas.  According to Hughes, his grandmother inspired him to write, as she was a natural orator of black traditions. After his grandmother’s death, Hughes returned to his mother in Cleveland, Ohio, until he graduated from high school in 1920.  In 1921, Hughes enrolled in an engineering program at Columbia University, but left after one year.  For a few years, Hughes worked various blue- and white-collar jobs while he spent most of his time writing, as that was his passion.  Langston Hughes began to publish numerous poems, and by 1926, he published his first book of poems, The Weary Blues.  In 1929, he graduated from Lincoln University with a Bachelor of Arts degree.  Conscious of the importance of race relations and politics, Hughes published The Way of White Folks in 1934.  The spectrum of Hughes’ writing grew as the years went by.  He began to write many politically inspired poems, plays (such as Mulatto and Don’t You Want to Be Free?), and autobiographies.  Hughes also wrote books that supported his consciousness of race relations like Jim Crow’s Last Stand and Montage of a Dream Deferred. Writing was Hughes’ main contribution to black history, though he also served as a social activist.  He traveled the world, expanding his horizons on black issues and became well-known as a radical democrat.  Langston Hughes faced many obstacles during the prime years of his publications as his critics viewed him as being too extreme.  He was able to hurdle these obstacles as he persevered.  Today, Hughes is remembered as an essential figure in black history.  He had the ability of writing the relevant problems within that community at a time when the American public consciously ignored such issues.  Langston Hughes devoted his time to writing poems, novels, dramas, and numerous articles.  </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6q66fsc">Drew, Fraser</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80014956">Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79062912">State University College at Buffalo</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Fraser Drew had the opportunity to keep in contact with Langston Hughes during the peak of his career.  Dr. Drew was a professor of English at SUNY Buffalo State for decades; he retired in 1983.  He received his Ph.D. in English Literature from the University at Buffalo in 1952.  His interest in African American literature motivated him to follow Langston Hughes’ career closely, and this led him to reach out to Hughes directly.  Hughes responded by keeping open communication with Drew for a number of years.  </p>
            <p>10 letters; 6 postcards; 4 Christmas cards</p>
            <p>Letters arranged chronologically</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="da0a0d_c3def4f274c2.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>