<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0006</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Buffalo Courier-Express Photograph Morgue Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-07">December 7, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E.H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Courier-Express Photograph Morgue Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1960/1982" type="bulk">1960 - 1982</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Courier-Express Photograph Collection spans from the early 1960s to the mid to late 1980s. The collection contains over 100,000 print images used to complement published and unpublished articles. In addition, most photo files contain the associated article. Topics can range from the Buffalo Bills to photos of elementary schools in WNY. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>62,000 folders; 69 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50048616">Buffalo Courier Express, inc.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The Courier-Express Photograph Morgue Collection is open for research.</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/courier-express-photo</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The Courier-Express newspaper was born in 1926, with the merger of the Buffalo Courier and the Buffalo Express to form the Buffalo Courier-Express. William J. Conners, owner of the Buffalo Courier, was the person instrumental in bringing the two papers together. During the 19th century numerous newspapers existed. The Buffalo Courier-Express merger can trace its roots back to 1828. From 1828 to 1926, twelve separate newspapers merged during those years, ending with the formation of the Buffalo Courier-Express; quite a chronology for the history of this newspaper.</p>
            <p>The Courier and then the Courier-Express took a liberal position on all issues. In the late 1970s, the Courier-Express was sold to Cowles-Media, an out of state publisher. Cowles Media decided to close the paper in 1982. The September 19, 1982 issue was the last one for this very popular Buffalo newspaper. Cowles Media donated the library to the Buffalo and Erie County Historical Society and Buffalo State College.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50048616">Buffalo Courier Express, inc.</corpname>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300134989" source="aat">news photographs</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300026867" source="aat">clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Courier-Express Photograph Collection spans from the early 1960s to the mid to late 1980s. It is subdivided into two categories alphabetically: topic and name of individual. The collection contains over 100,000 print images used to complement published and unpublished articles. In addition, most photo files contain the associated article. Topics can range from the Buffalo Bills to photos of elementary schools in WNY. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>