<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0025</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the William Schmidt Commercial Art Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-12">December 12, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The William Schmidt Commercial Art Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1936/1975" type="inclusive">1936 - 1975</unitdate>
            <abstract>Mr. William Schmidt (Buffalo State, Art Education, 1950), the creator of art designs on plastic covers for commercial products contained in plastic, requested that his special art work be deposited in the Buffalo State College E. H. Butler Library's Special Collections. He helped to set up the Schmidt and Eckert Award, offering several scholarships annually to Art Education majors at State University of New York at Buffalo. The William Schmidt Collection in boxes one and two includes samples of plastic pieces that he did as freelance designer and information about many of the accounts that he worked on. They also contain many sketches and drawings of his designs. The collection also includes original artwork by Mr. Schmidt, including sketches and paper and ink drawings depicting his experiences during the Second World War. Articles, biographical information, and memorabilia can be found in boxes three and four.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>5 boxes; 8 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Schmidt, William</persname>
            </origination>
            <unitdate normal="1958/1974" type="bulk">1958 - 1974</unitdate>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The William Schmidt Commercial Art Collection is open for research. </p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/schmidt</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Mr. William Schmidt (Buffalo State, Art Education, 1950), the creator of art designs on plastic covers for commercial products contained in plastic, requested that his special art work be deposited in the Buffalo State College E. H. Butler Library's Special Collections. He helped to set up the Schmidt and Eckert Award, offering several scholarships annually to Art Education majors at State University of New York at Buffalo.</p>
            <p>William Schmidt was drawn to art all his life, beginning his path as an artist as a young child. He was a World War II veteran, serving in the Pacific theater. His powerful and often harrowing artwork depicted the experiences of GI's and Japanese prisoners. Many of his pencil sketches and ink drawings are of the battle of Iwo Jima. He also attended the Art Institute of Buffalo, where much of his work would take on an abstract quality.</p>
            <p>After the war, he became a freelance designer working under Mr. Sidney Schulman of the Transparent Bag Company of Buffalo. Together, they handled many of the Western New York area's most important plastic bag accounts, and was one of the most successful businesses of its kind during the 1950's and 1960's. Although Mr. Schulman sold the Transparent Bag Company in December of 1981, the legacy of the company lives on in the William Schmidt Collection.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>William, Schmidt</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85103176" source="lcsh">Plastics as art material</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85007461" source="lcsh">Art</subject>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79062912">State University College at Buffalo</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Mr. William Schmidt (Buffalo State, Art Education, 1950), the creator of art designs on plastic covers for commercial products contained in plastic, requested that his special art work be deposited in the Buffalo State College E. H. Butler Library's Special Collections. He helped to set up the Schmidt and Eckert Award, offering several scholarships annually to Art Education majors at State University of New York at Buffalo.The William Schmidt Collection in boxes one and two includes samples of plastic pieces that he did as freelance designer and information about many of the accounts that he worked on. They also contain many sketches and drawings of his designs. The collection also includes original artwork by Mr. Schmidt, including sketches and paper and ink drawings depicting his experiences during the Second World War. Articles, biographical information, and memorabilia can be found in boxes three and four.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>