<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0017</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the David Lampe Poetry Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-08">December 8, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The David Lampe Poetry Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1960/2011" type="inclusive">1960 - 2011</unitdate>
            <abstract>The David Lampe Collection of archival and book material represents the first holdings obtained under the E. H. Butler Library's "Special Collections of Special Professors" initiative. Dr. Lampe, a native Iowan, earned his PhD from the University of Nebraska, and taught at Buffalo State College for over 35 years. His areas of interest and research range from Medieval to modern poetry. Dr. Lampe's subject expertise is reflected in his donation to E. H. Butler Library. The collection is comprised of two parts, representing Dr. Lampe’s collection of monographs as well as correspondence/subject files.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>Archival: 3 boxes; 4.5 linear ft.—Monographic: 1800+ books; 41 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no91025878">Lampe, David, 1941-</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The David Lampe Poetry Collection is open for research. The monographic (book) collection is still growing; Archivists can provide updated lists of materials.</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/lampe</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The David Lampe Collection of archival and book material represents the first holdings obtained under the E. H. Butler Library's "Special Collections of Special Professors" initiative. Dr. Lampe, a native Iowan, earned his PhD from the University of Nebraska, and taught at Buffalo State College for over 35 years. His areas of interest and research range from Medieval to modern poetry. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no91025878">Lampe, David, 1941-</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79062912">State University College at Buffalo</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85103722" source="lcsh">Poetry, Modern</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85103721" source="lcsh">Poetry, Medieval</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The David Lampe Collection of archival and book material represents the first holdings obtained under the E. H. Butler Library's "Special Collections of Special Professors" initiative. Dr. Lampe, a native Iowan, earned his PhD from the University of Nebraska, and taught at Buffalo State College for over 35 years. His areas of interest and research range from Medieval to modern poetry. Dr. Lampe's subject expertise is reflected in his donation to E. H. Butler Library. The collection is comprised of two parts, representing Dr. Lampe’s collection of monographs as well as correspondence/subject files.</p>
            <p>Monographic Material: The David Lampe Collection is partially comprised of 940+ books of research materials, general interest, and poetry texts, written by American, Australian, Canadian, English, and Irish authors. Many of these books are rare, first editions, and/or signed by the authors. A complete catalogue of holdings maintained by Buffalo State College can be accessed through the catalog. </p>
            <p>Archival Material: Also included in the donation are over 85 correspondence and subject files, representing Dr. Lampe's work with and study of various local, national, and global poets. These files contain background information, poems and copies of poems and other works, correspondence, as well as notice of the poets' lectures and Dr. Lampe's notes and written introductions of the authors.</p>
            <arrangement>
                <p>These files have been reprocessed in alphabetic order by poet; multiple files have remained distinct, in original order.</p>
                <p>Additionally, the collection contains audio and visual recordings of over 100 poets and writers Dr. Lampe invited to Buffalo State College. These recordings are currently being migrated to more stable and usable formats.</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="2bd26d_9e052d24687c.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>