<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0002</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the George Arthur Political Papers Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-07">December 7, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The George Arthur Political Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1961/2010" type="inclusive">1961 - 2010</unitdate>
            <abstract>Buffalo native George K. Arthur has been active on the local political scene for nearly half a century. Notably, he served on the Erie County Board of Supervisors from 1964-1967, as Ellicott District Councilman from 1970-1978, and then as Councilman-at-Large in 1978, eventually serving as Common Council President from 1984 until his retirement in 1996. Along the way, he ran for mayor in 1985 as the unendorsed Democratic candidate, narrowly losing to incumbent Jimmy Griffin. In 2010, he served as Secretary of the Buffalo Fiscal Stability Authority. The collection contains a wealth of information concerning politics in the Buffalo and Western New York region.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>115 boxes; 13 scrapbooks; 152 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Arthur, George K., 1934-</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The George Arthur Political Papers Collection is open for research.</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/arthur</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Buffalo native George K. Arthur has been active on the local political scene for nearly half a century. Notably, he served on the Erie County Board of Supervisors from 1964-1967, as Ellicott District Councilman from 1970-1978, and then as Councilman-at-Large in 1978, eventually serving as Common Council President from 1984 until his retirement in 1996. Along the way, he ran for mayor in 1985 as the unendorsed Democratic candidate, narrowly losing to incumbent Jimmy Griffin. In 2010, he served as Secretary of the Buffalo Fiscal Stability Authority. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <persname>Arthur, George K., 1934-</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh93008666" source="lcsh">Political candidates</subject>
            <occupation authfilenumber="300025474" source="aat">politicians</occupation>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n88236273">Erie County (N.Y.). Board of Supervisors</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n90630271">Buffalo (N.Y.). Common Council</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2014039236">Buffalo Fiscal Stability Authority (N.Y.)</corpname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85091463" source="lcsh">New York (State)--Politics and government</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The collection contains a wealth of information concerning politics in the Buffalo and Western New York region. The collection includes: scrapbooks; certificates; plaques; photographs; videotapes; badges; newspapers; invitations; brochures; ephemera; and correspondence. Some of the topics include: the buffalo waterfront (guide to specific materials available upon request); campaign materials for his several offices; newspaper scrapbooks detailing political activity; the African American Cultural Center; various organizations (see keyword/subject guide for specific organization lists).</p>
            <arrangement>
                <p>The papers are arranged into three series based on acquisition dates. Each series is then broken down into topics and arranged in alphabetical order for ease of access. Keyword findings aids are also available upon request. Series III is currently searchable by note field and keyword only.</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="0568ad_9cf1e830e0df.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>