<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0024</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Paul G. Reilly Indian Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-12">December 12, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Paul G. Reilly Indian Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1800/1980" type="inclusive">1800 - 1980</unitdate>
            <abstract>Paul G. Reilly served as attorney of record for the land claims initiated by the Seneca Nation of Indians and the Tonawanda Band of Seneca before the Indian Land Commission between 1948 and 1976. This collection is unique because it is the most complete collection of primary source materials on the Iroquois/Seneca Indians treaties and agreements found in one location. It contains materials culled from primary and secondary sources by Reilly, Fleming and Reilly, Counselors at Law between 1948 and 1970.
The collection originally contained 48 boxes when delivered to SUNY Buffalo State. During reprocessing these 48 boxes became 14 containers; the items were rehoused and retain all original documents. A guide to boxes and container contents can be found in the front of the collection inventory. The vast majority of documents in the collection are photoduplications/photocopies of original documents located in other repositories throughout the United States.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>Original 48 boxes currently stored in 14 containers; 16 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85389268">Reilly, Paul G.</persname>
            </origination>
            <unitdate normal="1948/1976" type="bulk">1948 - 1976</unitdate>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The Paul G. Reilly Indian Collection is open for research with pre-approval and restrictions. </p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/reilly</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Paul G. Reilly served as attorney of record for the land claims initiated by the Seneca Nation of Indians and the Tonawanda Band of Seneca before the Indian Land Commission between 1948 and 1976. This collection is unique because it is the most complete collection of primary source materials on the Iroquois/Seneca Indians treaties and agreements found in one location. It contains materials culled from primary and secondary sources by Reilly, Fleming and Reilly, Counselors at Law between 1948 and 1970.</p>
            <p>Mr. Reilly in preparing for these legal cases, over a period of forty years, collected a great volume of photocopies of treaties between various Indian nations and the Various Indian nations and the United States Government, chapters from history books, maps and other supporting materials. These photocopies were made from the original materials held at the National Archives, libraries and other depositories across the United States. Some of the materials that were collected and cited in the briefs for the Seneca Indian Land case of 1971 are not included in this collection. All those documents cited in the case can be found at the National Archives. </p>
            <p>Professors Eric Brunger and John Aiken, members of the History Department at Buffalo State College and both experts in western New York history, were requested by Paul Reilly to assist him in evaluating the lands involved in the Seneca Indian land claims case. Their work entitled "The Big Tree Cession of 1794" was presented as part of the Senecas’ brief before the Indian Claims Commission in September of 1970. </p>
            <p>As a result of their work which also included testifying before the Indian Claims Commission, Mr. Reilly upon his retirement from the law, after the conclusion of the case in 1971, offered the papers to the two professors. They accepted the papers in 1973 for the college and requested that the papers be housed in E. H. Butler Library. The papers were transferred to the Archives &amp; Special Collections Department in 1982 for use and preservation.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85389268">Reilly, Paul G.</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85119991" source="lcsh">Seneca Indians--Land tenure</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85119994" source="lcsh">Seneca Indians--Treaties</subject>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6jh700m">Reilly, Paul G.</persname>
            <corpname authfilenumber="n80066192" source="lcnaf">United States. Indian Claims Commission</corpname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85119990" source="lcsh">Seneca Indians</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Paul G. Reilly served as attorney of record for the land claims initiated by the Seneca Nation of Indians and the Tonawanda Band of Seneca before the Indian Land Commission between 1948 and 1976. This collection is unique because it is the most complete collection of primary source materials on the Iroquois/Seneca Indians treaties and agreements found in one location. It contains materials culled from primary and secondary sources by Reilly, Fleming and Reilly, Counselors at Law between 1948 and 1970.
The collection originally contained 48 boxes when delivered to SUNY Buffalo State. During reprocessing these 48 boxes became 14 containers; the items were rehoused and retain all original documents. A guide to boxes and container contents can be found in the front of the collection inventory. The vast majority of documents in the collection are photoduplications/photocopies of original documents located in other repositories throughout the United States.</p>
            <arrangement>
                <p>Please contact an archivist to access an inventory for content listings.</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>