<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0004</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Andrew Brown Choral Arts Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-07">December 7, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Andrew Brown Choral Arts Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1991" type="inclusive">1968 - 1991</unitdate>
            <abstract>A tenor soloist at St. John Baptist Church, Andrew Brown (1929-1977) became the church's minister of music in 1955. There, he organized a hundred-voice choir and personally established concert series as well as composing popular and renowned spiritual songs such as "My Prayer to Thee," "In Jesus' Name," "Come and Go with Me to My Father's House" and "Lord, Lord." A native of Buffalo, NY, Brown was also involved locally and elsewhere in organizing, establishing and conducting church choirs while promoting his love of gospel music.

Installed as an instructor of music at Buffalo State College (then State University College at Buffalo), Brown became the director of the Pilot Musical Experiment Program in Gospel Music in 1967. Collection contains a large collection of mounted photographs, programs, and materials from the Alumni Association.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname>Brown, Andrew. 1929-1977.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The Andrew Brown Choral Arts Collection is open for research. </p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/brown</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>A tenor soloist at St. John Baptist Church, Andrew Brown (1929-1977) became the church's minister of music in 1955. There, he organized a hundred-voice choir and personally established concert series as well as composing popular and renowned spiritual songs such as "My Prayer to Thee," "In Jesus' Name," "Come and Go with Me to My Father's House" and "Lord, Lord." A native of Buffalo, NY, Brown was also involved locally and elsewhere in organizing, establishing and conducting church choirs while promoting his love of gospel music.</p>
            <p>Installed as an instructor of music at Buffalo State College (then State University College at Buffalo), Brown became the director of the Pilot Musical Experiment Program in Gospel Music in 1967. Due to the program's success, it was instituted into the College's curriculum the following year. He directed the annual "Gospel Festival Comes to College" and remained active in teaching and community groups until his death in 1977.</p>
            <p>In 1978, a Memorial Scholarship Fund was established in memory of Andrew Brown, the first director of Buffalo State College All-College Choir, by Dr. Joseph Wincenc, Distinguished Teaching Professor Emeritus, of the Buffalo State College Performing Arts Department.</p>
            <p>Since 1978, scholarships and awards have been given annually to outstanding students who participate in Choral Arts at Buffalo State. With encouragement and support from Dr. Joseph Wincenc and Miss Rosalie Turton, former director of the Buffalo State Alumni Association, an Andrew Brown Chapter was established in 1987 by Reather Walker Diamond (BSC '76), coordinator of the Buffalo State All-College Gospel Choir, 1973-1982. The main object of this Chapter is to provide educational enrichment and assistance for people who have little or no background in music or singing. The Chapter's future goal is to maintain an Archives and Music Library to preserve the tradition, legacy, and ideals of African-American Choral Arts directors and accompanists in the educational process of learning, searching, and serving mankind.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Brown, Andrew. 1929-1977.</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79062912">State University College at Buffalo</corpname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85024628" source="lcsh">Choirs (Music)</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010014493" source="lcsh">African American choirs</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Collection contains a large collection of mounted photographs, programs, and materials from the Alumni Association.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="53e57f_91b425775b4e.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>