<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0007</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Edward H. Butler Family Papers Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Sister Martin Joseph Jones</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-07">December 7, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Edward H. Butler Family Papers Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1880/1956" type="inclusive">1880 - 1956</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Edward H. Butler Family played a prominent role in the development of the Niagara Frontier for nearly 100 years (1880 - 1976). Edward H. Butler, Senior published the first edition the Buffalo Evening News on October 11, 1880. Upon his death in 1914, his son, Edward, assumed the role of editor and publisher of the paper. At his death in 1956, his widow, Kate Robinson Butler ran the paper. Shortly after her death in 1975, the paper was sold to Blue Chips Stamps. 
 
Buffalo State College has enjoyed a long relationship with the Butler family. Three generations of members of the Butler Family served as Presidents of the College Council. E. H. Butler Library was named after Edward H. Butler, Senior. Collection includes personal correspondence; photographs; business records; financial statements; business files and personnel for the Buffalo Evening News; editorials; news clippings, and some miscellaneous ephemera. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>250 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2008010777">Butler, Edward H. (Edward Hubert), 1883-1956</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The Edward H. Butler Family Paper Collection is open for research. Due to the size and nature of the collection, inventories of material are made available only within the Archives &amp; Special Collections Department. Please contact an Archivist for specific materials or subjects.</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/ehbutler</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The Edward H. Butler Family played a prominent role in the development of the Niagara Frontier for nearly 100 years (1880 - 1976). Edward H. Butler, Senior published the first edition the Buffalo Evening News on October 11, 1880. Upon his death in 1914, his son, Edward, assumed the role of editor and publisher of the paper. At his death in 1956, his widow, Kate Robinson Butler ran the paper. Shortly after her death in 1975, the paper was sold to Blue Chips Stamps. </p>
            <p>Buffalo State College has enjoyed a long relationship with the Butler family. Three generations of members of the Butler Family served as Presidents of the College Council. E. H. Butler Library was named after Edward H. Butler, Senior. </p>
            <p>Kate Butler Wickham, daughter of Edward H. Butler, Junior donated her mother's personal correspondence to the library in 1977. In 1976, she donated all correspondence of her grandfather and father covering the period 1880-1956. In 1985, the Buffalo News donated all business correspondence of the Butler Senior and Junior connected to the Buffalo Evening News. In 1987, The Buffalo News donated the "Kirchhofer Papers". Kirchhofer, editor of the News, was in the process of writing a history of the paper when he died suddenly. His research materials and the papers he had taken from the Butler family files (1880-1976) were kept together as a collection.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2008010777">Butler, Edward H. (Edward Hubert), 1883-1956</persname>
            <persname>Wickham, Kate (Butler). </persname>
            <occupation authfilenumber="300025574" source="aat">publishers</occupation>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85091588" source="lcsh">Newspapers</subject>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w61p6g20">Buffalo Evening News (N.Y.).</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Collection includes personal correspondence; photographs; business records; financial statements; business files and personnel for the Buffalo Evening News; editorials; news clippings, and some miscellaneous ephemera. </p>
            <arrangement>
                <p>The collection is arranged into four sections. Please see original inventory for more in-depth information on subgroups and individual foldering. </p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>