<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0020</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the New York Geographical Association Records</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-08">December 8, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The New York Geographical Association Records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1935/1947" type="inclusive">1935 - 1947</unitdate>
            <abstract>The New York State Geographical Association Collections includes correspondence; meeting minutes, organizational data and papers presented; photographs; and miscellanea from its meetings between 1935 and 1947 as well as historical information and material relating to NYSGA's association with other organizations, such as the New York State Association of Teachers Colleges and Normal School Faculties, Geography Group, and the New York State Department of Education. Notably, several of Dr. Katheryne Whittemore's original papers are included; and additional data, interviews and reminiscences of hers are available in the Archives' administrative and biographical files. All NYSGA collection material dates 1935-1947.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 box; .5 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2005034440">New York State Geographical Association</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The New York Geographical Association Records is open for research. </p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/nysgeoassociation</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The New York State Geographical Association Collection was donated to Buffalo State College by the estate of Dr. Katheryne T. Whittemore. Dr. Whittemore (1899-1981) was an instructor and administrator at the College for thirty-seven years, serving specifically as a professor of geography from 1925-1962 and having been appointed to the newly-created post of director of the Division of Arts and Sciences in 1957. She was an active member of the New York State Geographical Association, of which she often assumed a leadership role in its meetings.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2005034440">New York State Geographical Association</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <persname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w68055mb">Whittemore, Katheryne Colvin Thomas, 1899-1981.</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85053998" source="lcsh">Geography--Research</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85101554" source="lcsh">Physical geography--Research</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85031255" source="lcsh">Conservation of natural resources</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The New York State Geographical Association (NYSGA) first met in 1935, beginning as an informal organization of interested geographers, educators and students, with open membership. The stated "original purpose of the group was to promote research in the geography of New York State" (from folder 1-11). The NYSGA developed ties with state educational systems as well as the New York State Department of Education. Papers presented at the annual meetings highlighted the organization's scope and purpose, including scholarly and research topics and roundtables on local and state geography, settlement, conservation, soils, land utilization, water supply, weather, climate, economic geography, impressions of teaching through the world and travelogues. The collection reflects the academic interests and the socio-political atmosphere of the 1930s through the 1940s. Notably, no meetings were held during the War Years of 1943-1946.</p>
            <p>The New York State Geographical Association remains an active organization; information that post-dates this collection as well as other data on NYSGA can be found at http://www.nysgaonline.org/.</p>
            <p>The New York State Geographical Association Collections includes correspondence; meeting minutes, organizational data and papers presented; photographs; and miscellanea from its meetings between 1935 and 1947 as well as historical information and material relating to NYSGA's association with other organizations, such as the New York State Association of Teachers Colleges and Normal School Faculties, Geography Group, and the New York State Department of Education. Notably, several of Dr. Katheryne Whittemore's original papers are included; and additional data, interviews and reminiscences of hers are available in the Archives' administrative and biographical files. All NYSGA collection material dates 1935-1947.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="f0d685_bb56a33fcc5f.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>