<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Dr. Madeline Davis LGBTQ Archive of Western New York</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-06">December 6, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Dr. Madeline Davis LGBTQ Archive of Western New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1920/2015" type="inclusive">1920 - 2015</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Dr. Madeline Davis LGBTQ Archive of Western New York was founded in 2001 to collect, safeguard, and provide access to archive and manuscript materials that document the gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender communities of Western New York and Southern Ontario. Since its founding, many additional individual members of the LGBTQ community in Western New York and Niagara have donated their personal materials. The archives house records of more than fifty diverse organizations and the manuscript collections of many individuals who have had a significant impact on the history of the region.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>150 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n92112163">Davis, Madeline D., 1940-</persname>
            </origination>
            <unitdate normal="1970/2015" type="bulk">1970 - 2015</unitdate>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
                <subarea>Archives &amp; Special Collections</subarea>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E.H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://library.buffalostate.edu/archives"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The Dr. Madeline Davis LGBTQ Archive of Western New York is open for research. Parts of the collection may be in processing; please contact an Archivist for additional information on particular sections of the collection.</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting
</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/LGBTQ</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Dr. Madeline Davis  is a noted gay rights activist. In 1970 she was a founding member of the Mattachine Society of the Niagara Frontier, the first gay rights organization in Western New York. In 1972, Davis taught the first course on lesbianism in the United States. She was also a founding member of HAG Theater, the first all-lesbian theater company in the US. </p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh94009215" source="lcsh">Gay rights</subject>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n92112163">Davis, Madeline D., 1940-</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh93000860" source="lcsh">Gay Pride Day</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh95001341" source="lcsh">Gay and lesbian studies</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85053577" source="lcsh">Gay bars</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh93002979" source="lcsh">Gay activists</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh91003435" source="lcsh">Gay community</subject>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Dr. Madeline Davis LGBTQ Archive of Western New York was founded in 2001 to collect, safeguard, and provide access to archive and manuscript materials that document the gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender communities of Western New York and Southern Ontario. Since its founding, many additional individual members of the LGBTQ community in Western New York and Niagara have donated their personal materials. The archives house records of more than fifty diverse organizations and the manuscript collections of many individuals who have had a significant impact on the history of the region. </p>
            <p>The collection contains: abstracts; albums; articles; audio cassette; awards; booklets; brochures; buttons; calendars; CDs; community service pamphlets; correspondence; count documents; ephemera/memorabilia; essays; family trees; financial reports; interviews; letters; magazines; mini cassettes; needlepoints; negatives; newsletters; obituaries; organizational business records; photos; plaques; playbills; poems; posters; publications; pulp fiction/romance; screenplays; scripts; textile artifacts; transcripts; VHS; and year books.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
            <p>Even though all reasonable and customary best-practices have been pursued, this collection may contain materials with confidential information that is protected under federal or state right to privacy laws and regulations. Researchers are advised that the disclosure of certain information pertaining to identifiable living individuals represented in this collection without the consent of those individuals may have legal ramifications (e.g., a cause of action under common law for invasion of privacy may arise if facts are published that would be deemed highly offensive to a reasonable person) for which the SUNY Buffalo State assumes no responsibility.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="99b068_b7a184ecdc79.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>