<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbuc">nbuc0016</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Great Lakes United Environmental and Ecological Issues Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Hope Dunbar</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-08">December 8, 2016</date>
                <publisher>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>E. H. Butler Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Room 214</addressline>
                    <addressline>1300 Elmwood Ave. </addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                    <addressline>(716) 878-6304</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbuc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>The Great Lakes United Environmental and Ecological Issues Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1984-2004</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Great Lakes United collection includes published reports, programs, journals, newsletters, handbooks, fact sheets, pamphlets and video tapes obtained from the organization’s Buffalo, NY, offices. The information gathered in this collection covers issues relevant to both the United States and Canada on the topic of the Great Lakes ecosystem and its environment. The bulk of the collection highlights concerns from and regarding the United States, but there also exists a significant amount of material collected from Canada and the International Joint Commission. Significant topics covered within the materials are issues ranging from water quality reports and protection agendas to environmental awareness publications; the bulk of the collection consists of information regarding the Great Lakes’ total ecosystem. The data spans the approximate years from 1984 to 2004.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>7 boxes; 10.5 linear ft.</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85157987">Great Lakes United (Organization)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York, College at Buffalo</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>The Great Lakes United Environmental and Ecological Issues Collection is open for research. </p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/visiting</p>
            <p>http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/greatlakesunited</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>After their website, http://www.glu.org, Great Lakes United “organizational members were brought together by the awareness that the world’s largest fresh water ecosystem was under very serious threat. These concerns attracted the attention of individual members who recognized the need for an integrated approach to recovery. The Basin contains twenty per cent of the world’s available surface water and is home to a broad variety of natural habitats. GLU members saw, on the one hand, a basin with abundant water resources and aquatic habitats, with biologically rich coastal waters, blue ribbon trout streams, and sparkling inland lakes. On the other hand, members were keenly aware that over two-thirds of the Basin’s original wetlands had been lost, thousands of miles of rivers had been impaired, and miles of shoreline had been degraded.” Great Lakes United works to preserve and protect the Great Lakes, the St. Lawrence Seaway and their surrounding ecosystems. Their research material focuses on the eight U.S. Great Lakes states as well as the Canadian provinces of Ontario and Quebec, and underscores the organization’s work in collecting relevant resources and petitioning the ruling bodies of the Canada, the United States, and First Nations.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85157987">Great Lakes United (Organization)</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5110629" source="geonames">Buffalo (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85121794" source="lcsh">Shore protection</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010118289" source="lcsh">Water quality management--Great Lakes (North America)</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010118258" source="lcsh">Water resources development--United States</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh91001664" source="lcsh">Great Lakes Region (North America)</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Great Lakes United collection includes published reports, programs, journals, newsletters, handbooks, fact sheets, pamphlets and video tapes obtained from the organization’s Buffalo, NY, offices. The information gathered in this collection covers issues relevant to both the United States and Canada on the topic of the Great Lakes ecosystem and its environment. The bulk of the collection highlights concerns from and regarding the United States, but there also exists a significant amount of material collected from Canada and the International Joint Commission. Significant topics covered within the materials are issues ranging from water quality reports and protection agendas to environmental awareness publications; the bulk of the collection consists of information regarding the Great Lakes’ total ecosystem. The data spans the approximate years from 1984 to 2004.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Please visit our Policies page for additional restrictions and copyright information: http://library.buffalostate.edu/archives/policies</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="a257c4_5c47c28efc55.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>