<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-npv">npv0010</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Sarah Byrd Askew Papers</titleproper><author>Alix Smith</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2016-07-07">July 7, 2016</date><address><addressline>Pepsodent University</addressline><addressline>Pepsodent, NY</addressline></address><publisher>Pepsodent University</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user Alix Smith.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Sarah Byrd Askew Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1942" type="bulk">1900 - 1942</unitdate><abstract>Personal and professional materials relating to the work of librarian Sarah B. Askew (1863-1942). The collection includes correspondence,newspaper clippings, postcards, and photographs, including daguerreotypes. Most of the collection is about her work with the New Jersey Public Library Commission, but there is some personal and family material.

</abstract><physdesc><extent>2 cubic feet (8 boxes)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no90007031">Askew, Sarah B. (Sarah Byrd), 1863-1942</persname></origination><unitdate certainty="circa" normal="1850/1950" type="inclusive">1850 - 1950</unitdate></did><accessrestrict><p>Box 8 contains restricted material. Please contact the Archives staff for more information. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Pepsodent University Archives (http://archives.pepsodent/policies.html) without any additional restrictions.</p></accessrestrict><dsc/><bioghist><p>Sarah B. Askew (1863-1942) was a remarkable librarian who fought for the improvement and expansion of New Jersey’s municipal library system during the early part of the 20th century. She received your library training at Pratt Institute (Class of 1904), and lived most of her life in New Jersey</p></bioghist><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Librarians -- New Jersey -- Biography.</subject><corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n82121956">Public Library Commission of New Jersey</corpname><genreform authfilenumber="300127181" source="aat">daguerreotypes (photographs)</genreform><geogname authfilenumber="5124003" source="geonames">Lansingburgh (N.Y.)</geogname></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>Sarah B. Askew Papers include correspondence,newspaper clippings, postcards, and photographs, including daguerreotypes. Most of the collection is about her work with the New Jersey Public Library Commission, including one letter from Melville Dewey. Also of note is a large collection of postcards she collected while traveling across New Jersey. The personal and family items includes material that predate Askew, including daguerreotypes of unidentified family and friends. There is also material that postdates Askew, including papers relating to her election to the Library Hall of Fame in 1950. </p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>Permission to quote (publish) from unpublished or previously published material must be obtained as described in the the regulations of the Pepsodent University Archives (http://archives.pepsodent/policies.html) </p></userestrict></archdesc></ead>