<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nyhutca">nyhutca0001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Paul Fulton Kelly Collection</titleproper>
                <author>Pamela Griffin-Hansen</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-12-15">December 15, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Huntington Town Clerk Archives</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Town Hall</addressline>
                    <addressline>100 Main Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>Huntington, NY 11743-6991</addressline>
                    <addressline>(631) 351-3035</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nyhutca.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="series">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Paul Fulton Kelly Collection</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1957/2003" type="inclusive">1957 - 2003</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Paul Fulton Kelly Collection relates to the Huntington Town Division of Veterans Affairs. The records described in this finding aid are arranged in chronological order and cover the years 1957-2003. This single level series of Record Group 21- Accessions has a total length of 5 1/2 linear inches.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>5 1/2 linear inches</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Huntington Town Clerk's Archives</corpname>
                <persname>Paul Fulton Kelly</persname>
                <persname>Rex Metcalf</persname>
                <corpname> Vietnam War Memorial Committee</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Huntington Town Clerk's Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
            <container type="box">2016-1</container>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>APPOINTMENT REQUIRED FOR VIEWING MATERIALS ONSITE. Inquire at the Huntington Town Clerk's Archives (email: amattheou@huntingtonNY.gov)</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Paul Fulton Kelly was born August 13, 1943, in Flushing Queens, New York, to parents Patrick and Viola Kelly. Paul spent his younger years in the unincorporated village of Great Neck with his three siblings their widowed mother. After completing St. Mary’s High School in Manhasset, Paul attended the College of Santa Fe, New Mexico, where he received his undergraduate degree in education in 1966, and then attended Northern Arizona University where he obtained a Masters in elementary education, with a minor in history. Paul also attended Hofstra University, and received a professional diploma in the field of teaching reading. He then attended St. John’s University, where he earned a professional diploma in administration and supervision.
 
After college, Paul taught for two years, and then enlisted in the Regular US Army. After military training, Paul was deployed to the Republic of South Vietnam. In 1969, Paul was assigned to Company "C" (Charlie Company), 1/52nd 198th Light Infantry Brigade, Americal Division (23rd Infantry Division), which fought the Japanese in the Pacific during WWII. He engaged in active combat and was awarded the bronze star for his meritorious service in a war zone. On February 4, 1970, right before Paul was to return home, he was assigned to Headquarters Company, 1st Battalion, 52nd Infantry, 198th Light Infantry Brigade, and was awarded the bronze star medal with “V Device for Valor” for his display of heroism in connection with ground operations against a hostile force in the Republic of South Vietnam. The Bronze Star medal with “V” Device award was announced in a letter dated February 16, 1970 to Paul Fulton Kelly from Colonel T. H. Tackaberry:
 
On [February 4, 1970], sergeant, Kelly was leading the patrol along the crest of a ridgeline near Lending Zone Bayonet when he spotted several enemy soldiers. Reacting immediately, Sergeant Kelly, engaged the insurgents with effective suppressive fire. When the friendly element came under enemy automatic weapons fire, Sergeant Kelly, disregarding the danger involved, remained in his exposed position as he threw a hand grenade into the enemy placement and then directed his men to form a tight defensive perimeter. After suppressing the hostile fire, Sergeant Kelly led a sweep of the area which resulted in the capture of valuable enemy documents, weapons, and equipment. His timely and courageous actions prevented the enemy force from attempting to attach the fire support base. Sergeant Kelly’s personal heroism, professional competence, and devotion to duty are in keeping with the highest traditions of the military service, and reflect great credit upon himself, the Americal division, and the United States Army. (pers. comm. to Paul Fulton Kelly).
 
On [February 4, 1970], sergeant, Kelly was leading the patrol along the crest of a ridgeline near Lending Zone Bayonet when he spotted several enemy soldiers. Reacting immediately, Sergeant Kelly, engaged the insurgents with effective suppressive fire. When the friendly element came under enemy automatic weapons fire, Sergeant Kelly, disregarding the danger involved, remained in his exposed position as he threw a hand grenade into the enemy placement and then directed his men to form a tight defensive perimeter. After suppressing the hostile fire, Sergeant Kelly led a sweep of the area which resulted in the capture of valuable enemy documents, weapons, and equipment. His timely and courageous actions prevented the enemy force from attempting to attach the fire support base. Sergeant Kelly’s personal heroism, professional competence, and devotion to duty are in keeping with the highest traditions of the military service, and reflect great credit upon himself, the Americal division, and the United States Army. (pers. comm. to Paul Fulton Kelly).
 
In the spring of 1970, after his heroic service in Vietnam, Paul accepted an elementary school teaching position at the Garden City Public School District in New York, where he taught until his retirement. Paul spent most of his career as an elementary school Science Specialist/Consultant at Stratford Avenue and Homestead Schools on the West Side of Garden City. On September 30, 1972, Paul married his elementary school sweetheart, Catherine Mary Scanlan, at St. Aloysius Catholic Church, Great Neck. The newlyweds moved to Huntington Station where they have now live for over 44 years. Paul and Catherine are the proud parents of three children and two grandchildren.
 
Paul is active in the veterans’ community. He is currently the Vice President of the Board of Directors, Nathan Hale Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 1469, as well as a member of several other veterans groups including the Combat Infantrymen's Association, American Legion Post 360, and the Vietnam Veterans of America. Paul is also the chairman of the Vietnam Committee, and the Town of Huntington Veterans Advisory Board. Paul serves as the liaison between the Town of Huntington Veterans Advisory Board and the Huntington Town Supervisor.
 
Paul was also a board member of the Huntington Vietnam War Memorial Committee, with his friend and fellow Vietnam Veteran Rex Metcalf, the board chairman. Paul became chairman of the board, after Rex resigned as the chairman, just prior to the dedication of the Town of Huntington Vietnam Wall. The majority of the collection held by the Huntington Vietnam War Memorial Committee is composed of materials that were given to Paul by Rex’s wife, Patricia, after Rex passed away.
 
 
 
</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname>Paul Fulton Kelly</persname>
            <corpname>Huntington Vietnam War Memorial Committee</corpname>
            <persname>Rex Metcalf</persname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Paul Fulton Kelly Collection relates to the Huntington Town Division of Veterans Affairs. The records described in this finding aid are arranged in chronological order and span the years 1957 to 2003. The total length of this collection is 5 1/2 linear inches. The Paul Fulton Kelly Collection is the history of the work of the Huntington Vietnam War Memorial Committee. This single series collection of subject files contains correspondence, loose papers, steering documents, photographs, newspaper clippings, blueprints, and a bound oral history project. The collection also includes a history and the combined efforts of the Huntington Vietnam War Memorial Committee and the "Huntington Women In Support of Our Men In Vietnam." Paul mentioned that a weather resistant container of sealed veterans’ names are buried at the Tree Memorial, located at the Village Green on the intersection of Route 25A and Park Avenue. The box is buried in front of a boulder that includes a memorial bronze plaque.
 
Notable items in the collection include the Vietnam Order of Battle by Shelby L. Stanton; a list of women in support of Vietnam and a few that passed away; a list of US military personnel who died (included missing, captured, or declared dead) as a result of the Vietnam conflict, 1957-1994; a New York Times Article dated January 19, 1997 by Diane Ketcham; a record dated September 1970, Long Islander article (Opinion) dated June 12, 1997; perspectives article by Joy Wellman; addendums 1-4, Suffolk County Vietnam Memorial Commission Guidelines for Competition-Philosophy and Purpose, Project costs; Suffolk County Vietnam Veterans Memorial Commission correspondence; handwritten rough drafts by Paul F. Kelly (on behalf of the Vietnam War Memorial Committee) to Vietnam Veterans about upcoming fundraisers with an interest in starting a Huntington annual tradition; steering documents with handwritten notes by Paul F. Kelly; Rex Metcalf and Paul F. Kelly photographs; steering document of the committee that include authorization date, revision date, objectives, task list, telephone list, mailing list of organizations, committee members, and interested Vietnam veterans; handwritten notes and attendance sheets with the steering documents; handwritten attendance sheets and donations lists of local businesses that gave donations in the vicinity of Huntington Village; and an oral history project.
 
</p>
            <dao xlink:label="" xlink:href="http://cdm16694.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/singleitem/collection/p16373coll130/id/903/rec/1">
                <daodesc xmlns:xforms="http://www.w3.org/2002/xforms" xmlns:xbl="http://www.w3.org/ns/xbl" xmlns:xxf="http://orbeon.org/oxf/xml/xforms" xmlns:xxi="http://orbeon.org/oxf/xml/xinclude" xmlns:ead="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:saxon="http://saxon.sf.net/" xmlns:fr="http://orbeon.org/oxf/xml/form-runner" xmlns:xxforms="http://orbeon.org/oxf/xml/xforms" xmlns:xf="http://www.w3.org/2002/xforms" xmlns:xh="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:exist="http://exist.sourceforge.net/NS/exist" xmlns:ev="http://www.w3.org/2001/xml-events" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xxbl="http://orbeon.org/oxf/xml/xbl" xmlns:exf="http://www.exforms.org/exf/1-0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:eaditor="https://github.com/ewg118/eaditor" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:oxf="http://www.orbeon.com/oxf/processors" xxforms:exclude-result-prefixes="#all">
                    <p>Rex Metcalf
Vietnam Veteran
2003
</p>
                </daodesc>
            </dao>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>……Town of Huntington Department of the Town Clerk and they are open for research under the conditions of the Records Access Policy. Copyright has been assigned to the Huntington Town Clerk’s Archives and permission to quote and publish should be submitted in writing to the Huntington Town Clerk’s Archives or by email to the archivist.  </p>
        </userestrict>
        <dsc>
            <c id="c_1a07f714861fdd2fe410a88bf63ac902" level="recordgrp" audience="external">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Paul Fulton Kelly Collection</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1957/2003">1957 - 2003</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c>
        </dsc>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="b56431_COLLECTION INVENTORY Paul Fulton Kelly Collection.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>