<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nybubpa">nybubpa0001</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>The Margaret M. Martin Archival Collection </titleproper>
								<author>Heather Gring, 2013</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2019-05-13">May 13, 2019</date>
								<publisher>Burchfield Penney Art Center</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>1300 Elmwood Avenue</addressline>
								<addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nybubpa.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>The Margaret M. Martin Archival Collection </unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1969-01-01/2012-12-31" type="inclusive">January 1, 1969 - December 31, 2012</unitdate>
							<abstract/>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>66 7/16 linear inches</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n98071368">Martin, Margaret M., 1940-</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Burchfield Penney Art Center</corpname>
                <address>
                  <addressline>1300 Elmwood Avenue</addressline>
								<addressline>Buffalo, NY 14222</addressline>
                </address>
            <subarea>Archives</subarea>
            </repository>
						</did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>See archivist for details</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Margaret M. Martin was born on August 15, 1940 in Buffalo, New York to artistically-minded parents—her father worked as an architect and her mother was interested in the fine arts. Before graduating from Boston University and receiving a Bachelor of Fine Arts degree in Advertising Design, she attended Buffalo Seminary. After completing her years at university, Martin worked both as an art director and in the graphic design field.
</p>
            <p>Martin eventually became fascinated with working in watercolor and took lessons from other artists, improving her skills and deepening her interest. In time, she shifted to becoming a watercolorist, art instructor, and exhibition judge. In addition, Martin participated in and became a valued member of clubs such as the Women’s Group, the Buffalo Society of Artists, and the Niagara Frontier Water Color Society. Her work has won several honors and been featured in numerous publications, as well as in the 2003 Universal Studios film Bruce Almighty. Her book, No More Wishy-Washy Watercolor, was published in 1999 as an aid to those wishing to improve their watercolor skills.
</p>
            <p>Floral, nautical, and architectural themes are most commonly found in Martin’s art. When speaking of her work, Martin often noted that she was stirred by seemingly common and ordinary subjects. Exaggerating aspects of subjects in her work allowed for a more profound and vibrant connection to them. Understandably, her studio on Elmwood Avenue in Buffalo was often recognized by bright floral décor.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <occupation audience="external" authfilenumber="300025157" source="aat">watercolorists</occupation>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>Margaret M. Martin’s Archival Collection contains primary source materials relating to her art, sales, workshops and exhibitions. A large portion of this collection consists of sketchbooks, sketches, watercolors, and prints of Martin’s work as well as financial accounts of sales of her artwork. Textual records include correspondence between Martin’s friends, family, patrons, and various organizations. This collection also contains various exhibition catalogues that are housed in the special exhibition catalogue library. Watercolor publications include magazines and books in which Martin was featured or had acquired. A certificate from D’Youville is also included in this collection. Martin’s archival collection is housed in eleven containers and in both the general library and the special exhibition catalogue library.</p>
            <p>This collection has been broken into the following series: Series 1: Sketchbooks and Fine Art; Series 2: Materials Relating to Artwork Creation, Promotion, and Sales; Series 3: Exhibition Catalogues; Series 4: Watercolor Publications
Series 5: Awards and Certificates
</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>See archivist for details</p>
						</userestrict>
					<otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="" xlink:role=""/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>