<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-npkmc">npkmc0005</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Clove Spring Iron Works</titleproper>
                <author>Lynnie Marina</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2018-04-06">April 6, 2018</date>
                <publisher>Marist College</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Archives &amp; Special Collections</addressline>
                    <addressline>James A. Cannavino Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>3399 North Road</addressline>
                    <addressline> Poughkeepsie, NY 12601</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user npkmc.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Clove Spring Iron Works</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1870/1904" type="inclusive">1870 - 1904</unitdate>
            <abstract>The Clove Spring Iron Works papers cover the day to day business operations of the company between the years 1870-1904. The papers include a variety of materials including business correspondence, telegraphs, contracts, legal documents, bills, receipts, checks, vouchers, deposit slips, balance sheets, payments, postcards, construction blueprints, paychecks, order records, invitations, tax receipts, weights of coal, price lists, account statements, lease agreements, insurance, and annual reports.
</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>3 lf</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Clove Spring Iron Works</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Marist College</corpname>
                <subarea>Archives &amp; Special Collections</subarea>
                <address>
                    <addressline>James A. Cannavino Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>3399 North Road</addressline>
                    <addressline>Poughkeepsie, NY 12601</addressline>
                </address>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://library.marist.edu/archives/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>"The Clove Spring Iron Works was a company founded in the late 1800s in Dutchess County, New York. The general manager of the company was John S. Schultze, who oversaw smaller companies that ran under the authority of the Clove Spring Iron Works including Sylvan Lake, the Clove Branch Railroad, and Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad Company. 

The Clove Spring Iron Works was also managed by members of the Brown Family: George Brown (President) and Sam Brown (Treasurer). Other employees include William Reid (Secretary/Treasurer), Charles A. Taylor (Cashier), and H.B. Willits, an assistant to Schultze. The company also conducted its operations--mainly its orders--through the company store. Crocker Brothers, a manufacturing company, frequently ordered materials from Clove Spring Iron Works to produce metals. 

The Sylvan Lake mines were where the company extracted coal and ore which were used to manufacture iron products. Important employees at Sylvan Lake were Normal J Plass and C.A. Stephens who both served as treasurer, and E.W. Plass and Oliver Davidson who were both agents. Oliver Davidson also managed the East Fishkill Mills with Silvanus Davidson. 
 
The company transported coal and iron materials by the Newburgh, Dutchess, and Connecticut Railroad Company, which John S. Schultze managed until John Crosby Brown became the President in 1902. William Wells served as secretary/treasurer until H.H. Reed became the treasurer in 1902.The Newburgh, Dutchess and Connecticut Railroad Company worked with the president of the Philadelphia Reading and New England Railroad Company, John Brock, to transport to materials outside of the tri-state area."
</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5115580" source="geonames">Dutchess County (N.Y.)</geogname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The Clove Spring Iron Works papers cover the day to day business operations of the company between the years 1870-1904. The papers include a variety of materials including business correspondence, telegraphs, contracts, legal documents, bills, receipts, checks, vouchers, deposit slips, balance sheets, payments, postcards, construction blueprints, paychecks, order records, invitations, tax receipts, weights of coal, price lists, account statements, lease agreements, insurance, and annual reports.
</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Individuals requesting reproductions expressly assume the responsibility for compliance with all pertinent provisions of the Copyright Act, 17 U.S.C. ss101 et seq. Patrons further agree to indemnify and hold harmless the Marist College Archives &amp; Special Collections and its staff in connection with any disputes arising from the Copyright Act, over the reproduction of material at the request of patrons. For more information please visit the following website: http://www.loc.gov/copyright/title17/.
</p>
        </userestrict>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="531c41_test.csv" xlink:role="application/vnd.ms-excel"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>