<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nelmc">MTA.007</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Tom Tenney Collection of Mark Twain News Clippings, undated</titleproper><author>Elmira College</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date certainty="approximate">undated</date><publisher>Elmira College</publisher><address><addressline>One Park Place, </addressline><addressline>Elmira, New York 14901</addressline><addressline>(607) 735-1869</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nelmc.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Tom Tenney Collection of Mark Twain News Clippings, undated</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate><abstract>The collection is comprised of news clippings of Mark Twain from 1872-1912.  The bulk of the materials concerns Mark Twain’s later years, primarily documenting the coverage of Twain’s death in U.S. and British newspapers in 1910.   </abstract><physdesc><extent>1.25 linear ft. (3 boxes)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n91027876">Tenney, Thomas Asa</persname></origination><repository><corpname>Mark Twain Archive, Gannett-Tripp Library, Elmira College, Elmira, N.Y. . </corpname></repository></did><accessrestrict><p>unrestricted </p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>Thomas Asa Tenney, internationally known as a Mark Twain Scholar… was born on June 20, 1931 in New York City, the son of Asa Clifford Tenney and Eleanor Milton Tenney. Dr. Tenney received his undergraduate degree from the University of South Carolina, his MA from Columbia University, and his PhD in English from University of Pennsylvania. Tom began his teaching career in science at Storm King School, Cornwall on Hudson, New York and Moorestown Friends School, Moorestown, New Jersey. Dr. Tenney taught English at Rutgers University - Camden, College of Charleston, Charleston Southern University, and The Citadel. For a short time he taught on naval vessels in the Mideast and Far East. </p><p>Throughout Dr. Tenney's adult life, Mark Twain was a central character in his academic studies and dining room conversations. He published Mark Twain a Reference Guide with subsequent updates, continuing his work on Mark Twain bibliography throughout his life. He was coeditor of Satire and Evasion? Black Perspectives on Huckleberry Finn. Dr. Tenney also helped to launch The Mark Twain Circular. He took over the Mark Twain Journal in 1984. Through the Journal, he provided a forum for well-known scholars and an opportunity for rising scholars to discuss all aspects of Mark Twain's life and works. Within the Mark Twain community Dr. Tenney was admired for the generous giving of his knowledge, time, and expertise. He encouraged Mark Twain scholarship whenever possible, helping well known scholars, emerging scholars, and anyone with an interest in Mark Twain. </p><p>Dr. Tenney was honored at The Fifth International Mark Twain Conference on the State of Mark Twain Studies in 2005 at Elmira, New York. He was the first to receive the John Tuckey Award in recognition of lifetime achievements and contributions to Mark Twain studies and the Elmira College Center for Mark Twain Studies. He also was given The Mark Twain Circle of America Award for Service in recognition for outstanding service to the study of Mark Twain and his work. </p><p>Published in Charleston Post &amp; Courier on Feb. 7, 2012</p></bioghist><controlaccess><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79021164">Twain, Mark, 1835-1910</persname><genreform authfilenumber="gf2014026099" source="lcgft">Facsimiles</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>The collection is comprised of news clippings of Mark Twain from 1872-1912.  The bulk of the materials concerns Mark Twain’s later years, primarily documenting the coverage of Twain’s death in U.S. and British newspapers in 1910.   </p><p>The British news clippings focus on two events: the honorary doctorate of letters awarded to Twain from Oxford University in 1907 and the death of Twain in 1910.  The clippings from U.S. newspapers document Twain in New York newspapers from 1901-1910 as well as national coverage of his death in 1910.   Also included in the collection is one notebook of annotated clippings that was used in Tenney’s, Mark Twain: A Reference Guide.</p><p>This collection is entirely comprised of clippings.  No scholarship or original documents are included.  </p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>unrestricted </p></userestrict><dsc><c id="c_9606b4ebbd7cc946bf6cea63e04e804b" level="collection"><did><unittitle>Tom Tenney Collection of Mark Twain News Clippings, undated</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate><note><p>This collection is organized alphabetically by folder title. </p></note></did><c id="c_80fb3e43616bd69bba3d4f46b90cf3b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>British News Clippings -- copies of 1872-1900 clippings </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8ed48e613b9969440fd84062feb73d36" level="file"><did><unittitle>British News Clippings -- copies of 1907 clippings, loosely arranged by publisher </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_de7b778db00412abfdcee661a122f51e" level="file"><did><unittitle>British News Clippings -- copies of 1907 clippings, loosely arranged by publisher </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b0bfde0bf2ff91c206d2d7928f69ce09" level="file"><did><unittitle>British News Clippings -- copies of 1910 clippings </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e947fe2c5bfe635dc6c8950506534adc" level="file"><did><unittitle>British News Clippings -- unsorted duplicate copies </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_878f612287ba56a162f29b8b12b7e8a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>British News Clippings -- unsorted duplicate copies </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1aee7f1b5ccfabc0c6011be2aff7273a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebook -- 1910 clippings from U.S. newspapers concerning Twain's death, p. 1-116 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_93b6a1aa1a9f913248b467fcdc8c7383" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebook -- 1910 clippings from U.S. newspapers concerning Twain's death, p. 117-242</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_83f4ba4da53c2e3ad03c4253636a1ad7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebook -- 1910 clippings from U.S. newspapers concerning Twain's death, p. 1-274 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_38f959d93b650b932e6bfe5d74b2a33a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebook -- 1910 clippings from U.S. newspapers concerning Twain's death, articles are annotated for use in Mark Twain: A Reference Guide </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9ef1287f1124c3345c087e7480d07f1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebook: Miscellaneous Clippings -- copies from Twain related clippings from New York newspapers, 1901-1908 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6161005a634c036f0e62657ac7dfd195" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notebook: Miscellaneous Clippings  -- Contents used for creation of "Mark Twain: A Reference Guide"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>