<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nelmc">MTA.004</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Louis J. Budd Papers and compilation of Mark Twain Resources,  1980-2008, undated</titleproper><author>Elmira College</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="1980/2008">1980 - 2008</date><publisher>Elmira College</publisher><address><addressline>One Park Place, </addressline><addressline>Elmira, New York 14901</addressline><addressline>(607) 735-1869</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nelmc.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Louis J. Budd Papers and compilation of Mark Twain Resources,  1980-2008, undated</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2008" type="inclusive">1980 - 2008</unitdate><abstract>The bulk of the papers are comprised of Lou Budd’s collection of Mark Twain caricatures,
interviews and reviews. Correspondence and materials related to his tenure as trustee at the Mark
Twain Memorial for the years 1992-1999 are the extent of materials in the collection related to
Budd’s professional life. The collection contains the manuscript and research for one scholarly
article, Seeing Double Can be Twice as Clear: Mark Twain’s Impersonators.</abstract><physdesc><extent>6.42 Linear ft. (6 Cartons, 1 Hollinger Box)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n81125454">Budd, Louis J.</persname></origination><repository><corpname>Mark Twain Archive, Gannett-Tripp Library, Elmira College, Elmira, N.Y.</corpname></repository></did><accessrestrict><p>unrestricted</p></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>Budd was born August 26, 1921 in St. Louis, Missouri, the last of three children in his family.
His father Vincent Budrewicz, a Polish immigrant from Lithuania, had served in the army of
Czarist Russia.</p><p>When discharged as a reservist, Vincent Budrewicz emigrated, arriving in America in 1910.
Louis&amp;#39;s mother Zofia Kajszo, a devout Catholic, emigrated from Lithuania to America in 1911.
In 1930 Vincent Budrewicz was a laborer in a shoe factory and his wife Zofia worked at a bakery
a half a block from the family home. Following the lead of his older brother, Louis would later
change his surname to Budd.</p><p>After graduating from high school at age fifteen, Budd attended the University of Missouri
majoring in English literature and was elected to Phi Beta Kappa. Budd received his B.A. there
in 1941 and his M.A. in 1942.</p><p>After serving in World War II, in 1945 he married Isabelle Amelia Marx-it was a marriage that
produced two children and lasted more than 60 years, until her death in 2006. Budd entered the
University of Wisconsin under the GI Bill and obtained his Ph.D. in American literature in 1949. Budd's doctoral thesis was titled "William Dean Howells's Relations with Political Parties."</p><p>From 1949 to 1952, Budd taught at the University of Kentucky at Lexington. In 1952 he
relocated to Duke University and remained with Duke until his retirement. Budd's first book
titled "Mark Twain: Social Philosopher" was published by Indiana University Press in 1962. The book traced the development of Mark Twain's social commitments and changing political attitudes.</p><p>Budd received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1965. He lectured in India in May 1966 as a
Fulbright scholar and returned to lecture in India again in October and November of 1972.</p><p>From 1968-70 he chaired the Afro-American Studies program at Duke. In 1973 he became
chairman of the English department and served in that capacity until 1979. In June of 1978 Budd
traveled to the University of Damascus as a visiting lecturer. He was awarded a NEH Senior
Fellowship in 1979-80. In 1979 he became managing editor of the journal American Literature. Budd became a prolific editor with Duke University Press, publishing numerous literary collections taken from back issues of American Literature.</p><p>He served on editorial and advisory boards of numerous publications including Studies in
American Humor, South Atlantic Review, Mississippi Studies in English, and American Literary Realism.</p><p>Throughout his career, Budd used his archival research skills to compile data on Mark Twain. In
1983, Budd published "Our Mark Twain: The Making of His Public Personality," which included rare caricatures and cartoons of Twain gathered from scarce 19th  century publications.</p><p>Budd was the recipient of numerous awards for outstanding scholarship, including several
honorary degrees. In 1991 Budd received one of the first Mark Twain Circle Awards.</p><p>Budd formally retired from Duke University in 1991 although he continued to teach there until
1996. In 1992 he arranged and annotated a two-volume edition "Mark Twain: Collected Tales,
Sketches, Speeches, &amp; Essays" for Library of America. In 1999 Budd published "Mark Twain:
The Contemporary Reviews" with Cambridge University Press which provided hard-to- obtain
texts of early magazine and newspaper reviews of Mark Twain's works. In 2005 he and Peter
Messent co-edited "A Companion to Mark Twain."</p></bioghist><controlaccess><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n81125454">Budd, Louis J.</persname><subject authfilenumber="sh85020312" source="lcsh">Caricatures and cartoons</subject><genreform authfilenumber="gf2014026099" source="lcgft">Facsimiles</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="gf2011026362" source="lcgft">Legislative materials</genreform><subject authfilenumber="sh85101237" source="lcsh">Photography--Negatives</subject><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79021164">Twain, Mark, 1835-1910</persname><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n93099439">Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910</persname><genreform authfilenumber="gf2014026141" source="lcgft">Personal correspondence</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>The collection is primarily a compilation of resources compiled by Lou Budd regarding Mark
Twain caricatures, interviews and reviews. The caricatures, interviews and reviews are
secondary sources consisting of reproductions, transcriptions, negatives and prints.</p><p>The collection contains research and manuscript drafts for one article titled, “Seeing Double Can
Be Twice as Clear: Mark Twain Impersonators.” Budd’s affiliation with the Mark Twain
Memorial as Trustee is represented in the collection through board minutes, agendas and
correspondence, including news clippings, articles and promotional materials regarding Mark Twain’s Hartford house.</p><p>Absent from the collection are personal papers or documents pertinent to Lou Budd’s
scholarship.</p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>unrestricted</p></userestrict><dsc><c id="c_9051718a24a0c20c173c066d9dac4cbb" level="series"><did><unittitle>SERIES 1: PROFESSIONAL PAPERS</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1999">1979 - 1999</unitdate></did><c id="c_c3988c40da5dd1a0c834ce6ffd7123b8" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>SUB-SERIES 1: MARK TWAIN MEMORIAL TRUSTEES MATERIALS</unittitle><unitdate normal="1992/1999">1992 - 1999</unitdate><note><p>This sub-series contains information gathered by Louis Budd as a trustee of the Mark Twain Memorial.  The bulk of the material pertains to board related activities, including newsletters, clippings and promotional materials.  This series is organized alphabetically and chronologically by folder title. </p></note></did><c id="c_3d8a6f4d5559ac056cbb6574a023905e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Trustees -- Correspondence, agendas, minutes, etc. </unittitle><unitdate normal="1992/1993">1992 - 1993</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_25c8e8289b5b11d3ab3dbec069bea850" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Trustees -- Correspondence, agendas, minutes, clippings,  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1994/1995">1994 - 1995</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f49193551ab08f2d02ba205f57e3921e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Trustees -- Louis Budd Comments [manuscript</unittitle><unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6303222ccca428d3c455e7e766c8e6cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Trustees -- Reports </unittitle><unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_83f27c7a99840c7884f0a05104d60faa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Board of Trustees -- Correspondence, agendas, minutes, </unittitle><unitdate normal="1996/1998">1996 - 1998</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1111a467acae671d9c2a6f5cda8b5d2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>News articles </unittitle><unitdate normal="1989/1996">1989 - 1996</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_947a67d1ee0d262ddc14d4638d485521" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newsletters -- Mark Twain News </unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/1999">1993 - 1999</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a6389fc4302daa170445e03021b4975a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Promotional Materials </unittitle><unitdate normal="1992/1997">1992 - 1997</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="c_f43602c5f00d8982b29673382531d28d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>SUB-SERIES 2: MANUSCRIPT MATERIALS</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1997">1982 - 1997</unitdate><note><p>This sub-series contains research, correspondence and drafts for a paper titled, “Seeing Double Can Be Twice as Clear: Mark Twain Impersonators.”  These folders remain in original order. </p></note></did><c id="c_fcedffbf3d77c9df8f6a31232da45161" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Doubles (1) -- Edited manuscript, "Seeing Double Can Be Twice as Clear: Mark Twain's Impersonators," clippings, correspondence </unittitle><unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_624bef1819881e76ff14728df98392a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Doubles (2) -- Edited manuscript, "Seeing Double Can be Twice as Clear: Mark Twain's Impersonators," clippings, correspondence, offprint </unittitle><unitdate normal="1995/1996">1995 - 1996</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2443e1611ff2688d496c5c186b58b94e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Doubles (3) -- Research materials on Twain impersonators, includes clippings, correspondence, photograph </unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/1994">1990 - 1994</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0af59ad048ffac71058be5e476c77fa0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Doubles (4) -- Research materials on Twain impersonators, includes clippings, articles, correspondence  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1989">1983 - 1989</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_36cfeaf87f9f61f0099f140b05caed88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Doubles (5) -- Research materials on Twain impersonators, includes clippings, articles, correspondence  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1983">1982 - 1983</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="c_76e9a8e01a3750762c6049b6816231c2" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>SUB-SERIES 3: PROPOSALS AND PAPERS</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1999">1979 - 1999</unitdate><note><p>This sub-series contains no works by Lou Budd and is primarily comprised of proposals for Mark Twain related programming, particularly for television, that were sent to Budd. The scripts for Samuel Clemens and Mark Twain a film project by Sandra Bradley and Mark Twain and Mark Twain and the Laughing River by Jim Post are the only materials in this sub-series that contain correspondence whereby Budd offers an opinion on the work.  All other files only contain the article and/or project proposal. This series is organized alphabetically by title. </p></note></did><c id="c_d805e2980c9557b318d14b657560d594" level="file"><did><unittitle>Life on the Mississippi -- TV script by Philip Reisman </unittitle><unitdate normal="1979">1979</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_206fddf841ce407e14427093681be286" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain: Beneath the Laughter: A Discussion Leader's Guide </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b38530ff202b6558020d5ecb86834b18" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain: Cradle Skeptic ---Wesley Britton typescript </unittitle><unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a101ab03063ea6c1446f13e210b769ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain and the Laughing River -- Includes photographs, correspondence between Budd and Post about the review of the play </unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/1999">1997 - 1999</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3bf77409ea0e904960c8e08262d8d46c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain and Me -- Article by Barry Crimmins from the Cleveland Plain Dealer </unittitle><unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4cdb96c3c541b5becd4f20be05454316" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Series -- NEH proposal </unittitle><unitdate normal="1979">1979</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e39542f5c8d56efbfa30c6133338cb5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain's Adventures of Huckleberry Finn: Humor and Race, A Callback Session on Teaching the Novel in High Schools -- By David E. E. Sloane </unittitle><unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_82ba4c3bd197f86d834c12ccf9c9d300" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain's Bizarre Shorts -- Pandora's Players script </unittitle><unitdate normal="1983">1983</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9a15a812c30f467c05bcbee4197143c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Private History of A Campaign that Failed and The War Prayer -- TV script by Philip Reisman </unittitle><unitdate normal="1980">1980</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9051fc71876b9da9c8d6a879e2c1a616" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sam Clemens and Mark Twain -- Film proposal by Sandra Bradley </unittitle><unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b6df01b4ad4cb8e1a8a9f89638c16d58" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sam Clemens: Inventing Mark Twain -- Treatment and Script </unittitle><unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_954df3c33ff056880df89a151361f0cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sam Clemens: Inventing Mark Twain -- Correspondence, includes part III script </unittitle><unitdate normal="1993/1995">1993 - 1995</unitdate></did></c></c></c><c id="c_45f4571b80df9cff50911265b45d8bc7" level="series"><did><unittitle>SERIES 2: CARICATURES</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/2008">1980 - 2008</unitdate><note><p>The series primarily consists of reproductions, negatives and prints of Mark Twain caricatures.
Louis Budd states in a letter to the National Portrait Gallery in 1989, “For some years I have

been gathering caricatures of Mark Twain, especially those done during his lifetime. Eventually,
of course, I plan some kind of publication though I am still primarily concerned with gathering
and analyzing the materials” (Box 2 Folder 182). Caricatures from later dates, though present,
are not as thoroughly documented.</p><p>The collection contains few original materials and is almost exclusively comprised of prints and negatives of reproductions. Dates from the limited correspondence and from Budd’s online
resources, including the statement above, indicate Budd was actively collecting caricatures for an eventual publication up until his death in 2006. The collection is primarily focused on caricatures created in Twain’s own time; caricatures from later dates, though present, are not as thoroughly documented. This series represents Budd’s twenty plus year research commitment to collecting Mark Twain caricatures.</p><p>The collection of Mark Twain caricatures remains in original order, primarily organized by date of publication (the first three folders are miscellaneous). Original folder headings are used whenever possible.</p></note></did><c id="c_e46d3dcd6f4c612adcd5da88e3afcac6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Association -- photocopied articles and notes about the  association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997/1999">1997 - 1999</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_922cde2230a079ec352ea0d05923bf76" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memo on Tom Quirk -- Inventory of cartoon folders sent to Tom Quirk</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_809476e110b019347b152743cf5ed9b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Innocents Abroad -- Letter and photocopied title page; Mark Twain with  tomahawk</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981">1981</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3dfa5e0a40b3dc1a9cf85253b217d220" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain "Funny Baby"; caricature, 1870's with letter</unittitle><unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1bc962d0312b40620d8e9f7b3cfd4551" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Once a Week", 14 December, 1872 : Mark Twain astride a frog</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_00450167e31b051808fa785efdd2f5dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Mark Twain's Funniest Fiction Fully Illustrated", early 1870's: Mark Twain as Jester </unittitle><unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e1a8e5ae4c7d4f7fadfdb2117ce60b42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Illustrations for Roughing It / Mark Twain Lecturing </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ad46ab4a68de95114e18e63546f27d12" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper," 26 July, 1873 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8752246f478690c6d03c073572bae5b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 15 November, 1873 : Mark Twain Cap and Bells, "The Lyceum Committeeman's Dream" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7035ae4feaeaaaf3888d8c773f6c5a30" level="file"><did><unittitle>"American Publisher" : Mark Twain at Tomb of Adam </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_db4aa8f34d1e3058bfdedfdf9810f5e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain lecturing in England 1873? </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_59693b9ee8311dac49bdde823ab1132b" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Hoppin -- C. d. Warren, "Backlog Studies" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ca7f54dd9cb8875ae124f92df97f4ec6" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York, 26 October, 1874 and 1876 : Theodore Wust illustration of Mark Twain platform pose </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_25e7ecdf45a13f9045de59a99595dc64" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain weeping at Tomb of Adam [transparency] </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0586e9d6ee6507c358082e61c4d99914" level="file"><did><unittitle>F. D. Millet Portrait c. 1896 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ec1402439f60837f05c5187de48eda2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Suggestions about Work" 1880's? </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b45d927a11bf1feb7dde300900820f3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain attends Ingersoll Lecture, "Chic," May 1881 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a5cfdfdd3404d7be711ff965d889831b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harper's Weekly, 21 January 1882, Thomas Nast, Mark Twain in Canada in search of Copyright </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_aadd31623eb51d87a480c60f4bd7f487" level="file"><did><unittitle>Life, 22 March 1883 : Mark Twain holding skull </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b24eb55c987e8183b9d89d6ee27bfcbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Life, 9 August 1883 : Mark Twain sleeping in chair </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dc0afdeef48153a314854d1c7f611d8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clover Club, 9 April 1885 -- profile portrait, with correspondence </unittitle><unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f821f91eccfacfe6686c46dc9e774bdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Commercial Gazette, Cincinnati, 26 September 1885 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8cd32e06c05338912910dde41e8cd699" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Mark Twain's Funniest Fiction Fully Illustrated" -- Cap and Bells, c. 1885 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e36d45b88ce1ca4f049e89e03c0aab8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 16 December 1885 -- Artist Joseph Keppler : Mark Twain on Platform  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ecbf2128720ef99ea15dd3d7defd2d30" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 24 February 1886 -- International Copyright, Mark Twain in Chorus of British Authors </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ea54366aa93f23ce2d042d19fbbb1ca1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Boston Sunday Globe," 3 July 1887  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d3d922b6811c4942456b2cd6bf535448" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Post-Dispatch," 11 December 1887 -- caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_81ce071ba3355305f6d4196f27352909" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 11 November 1888 : Mark Twain and Browning (Bill Rye's Column)  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9ca1c8beca262ed134c94aa4e9442938" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 9 April 1889 : Baseball cartoon </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a4ccf6192a971966816d349dac2be27f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Post-Dispatch," 19 May 1889 -- "Mark Twain Writing Under Difficulties" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6d5f146802cbba29ae36566430a2aca0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 16 June 1889 :  "Mark Twain at Work" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f43acb3f91591298fc0aabee535bf46b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 16 June 1889 :  "Mark Twain at Work" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_78c8bd09e1116bf599ffe0a2168292cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Critic, 45," 4 October 1890 -- Mark Twain self-portrait with Laurence Hutton </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b65e06f0c80ab7c1950407edda651954" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 27 February 1890 : Twain wearing dress and holding cat [transparency</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_388632158886c6e6615a89825a0ddb17" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Idler," February 1892 : Mark Twain blowing soap bubbles </unittitle><unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d91de871ef8c244e9775cdea1b2002a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Theodore Wust -- Correspondence about "The Interrupted Siesta," 1890's </unittitle><unitdate normal="1980">1980</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_86b016664791625a6bf54e72c06dda5f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Idler," October, 1892 " : Mark Twain in Quaker City </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9f94a687b4486fce58486c12a506cba6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," three faked photographs, February 1895</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b3662ba3c3dd19c369d6f09ec52373b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notecards containing information about published caricatures of Mark Twain</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7e2ab2de8223324bca965076711facae" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 10 July 1895 : "Great Speech by McKinley" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_525179638f65e02ea15d376d008512b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 12 July 1895 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_bf162087821bf38f3d21c335dd998b96" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Lifetime with Mark Twain; the memories of Katy Leary..." : "Mark Twain at Home"[</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_baaf508614d6450b4ff0f403e30a01e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (Australia) Bulletin, 28 September 1895 : Mark Twain and Henry Parkes </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1564f5ff7f30166a944e3267777c63f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Five cartoons copied from Shillingsburg MS, "Abroad : Mark Twain in Australasia,"  1895 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ad036938cd90a573015cc1a32060f885" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (NSW) Bulletin, 5 October 1895 -- Tom Burkin Sketch  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5e0f5b02610cf63912f605d8e73d2997" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne Australia, October 1895 : Mark Twain Smoke Night </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5f2fcd5d3bf12f1a631bcbc107838c9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Sketch, 27 November 1895 : Mark Twain on Platform </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c371dfe586baedd8c50ea1973765b02c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 28 May 1896 : Mark Twain as Joan of Arc by F. T. Richards  -- transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_51253d79c7fab5cb2aec582c20308860" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Book Buyer," February 1897 " : Mark Twain with Puppet Characters </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_819f3109e4db9a3068dbf748ddc8debc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 4 February 1897, NYC newspaper scene ; "Life's School of Journalism</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_736bd9d16f22b5f14309dd2f122b5a8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 27 May 1897 : Mark Twain on Boat  -- Transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8dbe099c00500a3f38d8d8f04542e5a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vienna Erfloh : Mark Twain as Diogenes and other Dolmetsch cartoons, 1897 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1794f38ecad2091c7cf5f5084b6fd651" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Journal and Advertiser," 21 November 1897 : Mark Twain at Vienna Press Club, includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7fa10368ac0d3758e7442eede3b053bf" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 13 December 1897, Mark Twain Addressing Vienna Press Club</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b7debdfda170a5ded491faed7ce72b79" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 1 March 1898 : Mark Twain speaking German verse, includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5a738269036db577ec066f94e422dfe4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 26 May 1898 : Mark Twain caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_212642b836572f66a29b76e79ee8787e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 18 August 1898 : Portrait caricature, "Eyes that 'lack only the nictating membrane of the eagle'</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_17143b75315bf49877ccd2d70d8aa538" level="file"><did><unittitle>Book illustration, 1898 : "The boy chieftain knelt and kissed the hem of the maiden's robe," American Literary Realism, vol. 8 no. 2, 1975 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_51efcad0b7eafff31af23dc53c879a22" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Criterion," 18 February 1899 : unconventional statues-V </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3911759e2fdc6146bb5b1cedc5c0e08a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 2 March 1899 : Twain caricature, "The American Humorist" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f9789f122ceab23ff652adcaff1de542" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Criterion," 18 February 1899 : Mark Twain : unconventional statues-V : Mark Twain could make a sphinx laugh </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_425a68f1fa849d1745b907811b72368d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Boston Herald," 15 June 1899 : Mark Twain as Internal Raconteur -- photograph and transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_10291256856260381f007a637da6c07f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 6 August 1899 : "Mark Twain before Breakfast" -- photograph and transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fdf1987adf43482bd2cf5747af85ee7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 10 December 1899 : Mark Twain looking through binoculars, includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d8d33b7c30059092a62a6760d59d05c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"An Alphabet of Celebrities" by Oliver Herford, 1899 : caricature, includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d79aa91e1eec0c1446183d1ccb1ee565" level="file"><did><unittitle>"An impromptu by Phil May," June 1900, "The Savage Club" by Aaron Watson </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d50f176d1b178cc08cd90a2e5de2283e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Metropolitan Magazine," 12 July 1900 " -- Twentieth Century Cartoons," by Will Hudson </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_879ebcbc29822102168dcd3d4f7ac208" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 21 October 1900 : "A First Impression of Mark Twain" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1c0d6abce32d3cd3c28288bd54050ae8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Independent," 25 October 1900 by P. Bigelow : "Mark Twain Addressing a Committee of the House of Lords on International Copyright </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_03c2ed9f380a08322cc752541bf60fa5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald," 23 November 1900 : "Mark Twain Talks of Cabmen to Mayor's Marshal Roch," includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e722c30700832c09e9e7e1149e1959b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 5 December 1900, Frank Nankivell : Caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0f667ae3336c62fc8a22c5f167c7eb9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Louisville Times," 14 December 1900 : Caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4986f9978cd6b7a72749ec69be5e9ea4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Commercial Advertisers," 22 December 1900 : "Mark Twain and His Empire -- A Laughing World" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c6371de872bdbb17b391dcff427984fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>F. C. Gould, 1901-1903? : Caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e7f089c6a2bfdc50586c80a0a24f8411" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 5 February 1901, by F. Opper, Mark Twain and McKinley </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_894f032ff6cdf0a9abb0b2d1a80738ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Syracuse Herald," 5 February 1901 : "The Kicking Joker" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8b7583956926bd022e77aa1bfe041226" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis Tribune, 14 February 1901 -- "Better quit your foolin', Mark, and go back and work at your trade -- Twain holding elephants tail with 'politics' written on its side </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9034bb7a876cb70afec5a9ecbf798325" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 23 February 1901 : "Having the Time of His Life" -- Twain getting hit by snowballs </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_466a8dfae53965140103218fabd26c37" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 28 February 1901 : "The American Lion CF St. Mark's," : Twain caricature as lion, includes letter for permission to copy </unittitle><unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_43638c62f5865d31cffa28e99ad2115c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Minneapolis Tribune," 20 March 1901 -- "The Best Joke Yet" --includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_65e55ed2ab39473fbb14a8b11ed15bd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Minneapolis Journal," 23 March 1901 : "Can the Missionary Reach This Old Savage" -- Twain caricature as savage </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_668deac70ec2e99ce20870bd21657ca0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 25 March 1901 : "With Poets as Policemen Mark Twain Would Purify the City," transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_57e694886e1758b8be8e52823aa33475" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Kansas City Journal," 29 April 1901 : Mark Twain pulled in cart by N.Y. Clerical Union </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_27c6ef6258d8197f72cd6247b00bb8e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Judge," 11 May 1901 --includes transparency and photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_85eafb92fe0feafa7167a296856c6785" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Bookman," September 1901, by Tim Murphy : "A Man of Mark" caricature -- includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2ba2e53c98e7c7de7b3ff5fad0bd1d8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Republic," 16 October 1901 : "Mark Twain will fight Tammany [Tiger]" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6deffa820c547b55544004b6c65fc022" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain as Yachtsman(?) by Harry Furness, 1902? </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d55fed4c2b8a2a78165c5b5fd8a936e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Pastel," by Everett Shinn, 1902 : Mark Twain sitting, "Portrait of Mark Twain</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6a275781d80a66532f7225acfb8d83af" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald," 23 February 1902 : Mark Twain sitting at desk writing, "Mark Twain in an Engrossing Moment" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b54947b69829f39639d864984e9d00f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Republic," 2 June 1902 : "Mark Twain at Hannibal" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_80edb719cd443e3d7d4e2fb28d6f80e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Republic," 7 June 1902 : "Mark Twain as Pilot on Mississippi's Bosom" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8f7316d894241b09494f2b33b7283ea3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Republic," 8 June 1902 " Mark Twain in St. Louis </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a26b2fdfd0789c422894e726bcb67b9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Advertisement for Alfred Houghton Clark pastel portraits, including Mark Twain, November 1902 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9691c260cc12e590cc2b542bed1a8e20" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World" 23 November 1902 : Mark Twain self-portrait and "The audience broke into uncontrollable laughter" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1c18076daece0f112571488748db0d09" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 20 December 1902 : "Homer Davenport's Impressions of Twain" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3787b294d5b3d6e991094f558b63d149" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 7 February 1903 : "The Man Who Corrupted Eddyville</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ebff46c1807ded6925a38fbd70888f4f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Booklovers Magazine," March 1903 : Mark Twain with Halo "Fame"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7c498c6f1c9e16c66ede3ba6f73334b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Strand," May 1903 :  Mark Twain Speaking </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f4136a13d2e2a5631c1275188957ae18" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Booklovers Magazine," June 1903 : Mark Twain Lecturing </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_91738140e3bac067dc8a79b5fb4dfe14" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Bookman," July 1903 : "Our artist makes two farewell sketches of Mark Twain," include transparency </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903">1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2a8041c9dc8da3e8e8c73facaea4383e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Nicholas," September 1903 : caricature, with transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_66da49c339b5cfde320d164dc3b0e284" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 1903 : "Mark Twain retranslating the jumping frog from French" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e71d178c666811ce3e4e0e966eda6c70" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 24 December 1903 : "The Brave Sir Mark : A Yankee Writer at King Arthur's Court," transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4d3ab685941dcc2e5865ccc409619749" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain illustration for "Esquimau Maiden's Romance," in Autograph Edition, 1903 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2f1b5cf77a1b44b5050bfef9e8dc7f06" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Art of Caricature," 1904  --transparency, photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_997408e6da88f7d100a7b939394b92a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Bystander," by Thus. Downey, 17 February 1904 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_705b34ff50ab1a590e1f9461b11b5f6d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Mark Twain and Max O'Rell"  by Harry Furness, 1904 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8e85c562922d84ff536daab49f8fc78e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 1 March 1905 : Mark Twain as Newfoundland Dog, includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8a93db39903dad3ac1da546fcb5aa6a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 13 July 1905 : "Mark Twain Pilot" transparency  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c0a28b28868d3969b5793a78772a7c46" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Tribune," 6 December 1905 ; caricature by John T. McCutcheon </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dd3686592e49311652febad5dc4b3328" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World" 6 December 1905 : "Honored Humorist with Incidents in His Career, From Youth up to Threescore Years and Ten" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3a8ddbe1d665766cbdae58b637f1eddc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain with Halo by Robert Reid, 6 December 1905 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_81584a11052f70b5c81901be54830a90" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Spokane Spokesman Review,"8 December 1905 by Morris : "Here's Hoping He'll Make the Hundred Mark" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fb43f4bd5cd21914b2b461fec5550e41" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald," 10 December 1905, Third Section, Page 4 : "When Author's Passed in Proud Review" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7fec5d314c8ccd22002136c8a0e9dc08" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cass Gilbert, 1905 or else latter [sic]</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6c3d1401219a2408dcd964997f84b655" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 21 December 1905  : "His 70th Birthday" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_48051c67de0f9ec754204db960604860" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 22 December 1905 : A Bradshaw caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fa85b4aa755c3d9c1c959dc4abc84235" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 4 February 1906 -- "The Press Club will send a wheelbarrow for Mark Twain," includes transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e14c9d404da1dfa3b954f0d3bce75699" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 9 March 1906 : A Bradshaw caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_30f36ea045274594a25dee5beef3e84c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 13 April 1906 : Dethroning Czar </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7c3cd360d7f48f88391fbb90e5b9bb6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 5 July 1906 -- Transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9b160d7c19078053d73776f773e5069c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," 2 September 1906 -- "The Caricature of Himself that Mark Twain Liked Best" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_945337926da9d5e5bfaa4cc30cb8295b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 20 September 1906 -- Includes transparencies and photographs of two caricatures </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cee32b47c9c0374575e2f20920c0b56d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," 20 September 1906 -- Caricature as infant </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_24534b9dae1eb56b37a575d6c2ea1486" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 25 November 1906 -- Twain at party, includes transparency and photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b751956b563bc0b7f78fa37e9181ed75" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 8 December 1906 -- "Mark Twain in that Cream Colored Suit," includes transparency and photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a7c6c43b6954454843441263ae3121c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 22 December 1906 : Writing his Autobiography </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d38843e700d68cc406f606988fe197d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frederic Remington, c. 1906 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d6a6ed624cf15eea10a65d4d327290b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 31 January 1907 -- Transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_62c72ebbdd573ed7ce6c258607394d89" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald," 15 February 1907 -- "Mark Twain has suit of white for evening wear" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_100c62de8f7135b1e91cac43e140ff1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Paul Pioneer Press," 17 February 1907 -- "Mark Twain in evening dress; sketched from telegraphic description" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5e51ac7d45e278165d82a417e4e53657" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Saturday Evening Mail," 23 February 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_722c713d948df521825bbea00be18c8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Boston Post," 24 February 1907, p. 33 -- "Mark Twain in his Suit of White</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a57f8c28e641d33422e7b8879103c2d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 24 March 1907 -- no image </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e46d8d253b92ca006d68a1f943fb243e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 7 May 1907 --" Persons prominent at Fair for the Benefit of Actors' Fund -- World Booth"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d0de5541df4b778bea1e79cab834de76" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 7 May 1907 -- "Mark Twain in His Justly Celebrated White Flannel Suite made the Opening Speech" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_69dad112a2a65699e8aff0ee1eb3613f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Baltimore News," 11 May 1907, p. 9 : "Sketches of Mark Twain" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b46258df565b236e6026578b6bae6036" level="file"><did><unittitle>"London Daily Chronicle," 19 June 1907 : P. Richards -- "Mark Twain on Board the Minneapolis" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_75133565a64a81106a8a2b7bd9590868" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Puck," 19 June 1907 -- "The way he will get it: Oxford University will confer an honorary degree on Mark Twain next week" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5166ad3b9143063fee53b0dd1b182a9d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"London Chronicle," 20 June 1907 : D. Watson, "Mr Clemens and the Marked Twain" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_616c61258a3f1ac1840649246cad2edf" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 20 June 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0c2c1388ed1bb9b4b9e47b7250bfa533" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Minneapolis Journal," 21 June 1907 : "The Connecticut Yankee in King Edwards Court" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fdfae06222a2f1dfadbf9d76f25d8b2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Globe and Commercial Advertiser," 21 June 1907 : Mark Twain in Bathrobe </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_00d160b1548bf953be7f4488439d565b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 22 June 1907 : Mark Twain in Bathrobe </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_38251b5f7574301ce2f5826feec585f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Paul Pioneer Press," 22 June 1907 : "King Full on Deuces" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_708ae3a962fbde9af61ddd285beec3f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 24 June 1907 : Mark Twain and Fedinck and King </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cddf391a9364a4c0988a6094ad2970f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Democrat," 24 June 1907 -- King Edward had a hearty laugh over a joke Mark Twain made 35 years ago" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_866df26aa989328e6bd2d6cf4446c9e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Columbus (Ohio) Evening Dispatch," 25 June 1907 : Mark Twain jokes with Queen of England </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2fa6caf8a3024bfcf577db3e34b0dfd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pilgrims Luncheon, 25 June 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0129a305f3240ffe9277b7bf71e36a9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"London Daily Graphic," 26 June 1907 -- "Honouring the Greatest Living Author" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a5f47104dfc5782ab9356b0f13e66dea" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 26 June 1907 -- "A Surgical Operation" drawn by Phil May </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2d4f4da4a86122950880157c2faa4047" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald," 26 June 1907 : RE: Punch Cartoon -- "England's Homage to Mark Twain; Notables at Pilgrims' Luncheon" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7014458005f7869334cc251a24e4b5c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 27 June 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0b3017ba8e4ec0f27b0c3c913f52383b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Daily Tribune," 28 June 1907 : A Good Story by Briggs </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_552ab36b7e5cb2d94509f25d898ea886" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Onlooker," 29 June 1907 -- "More Tramps Abroad"  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_31ff144f9888a91939cb48e0d9d4bf60" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Washington Evening Star," 29 June 1907 -- By Berryman </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0af6980dbf78085f7ca5047826d034ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," 30 June 1907 -- "Mark Twain in London" by Hy. Mayer </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a1b62f536895b742cdfc113de8f70038" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Yankee in Court of King Edward," Seattle Spokesman Review, July-August, 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ccff90afc290eed8c9ce731b249e605d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Press," 5 July 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ff3614e2651bf70c93175d4e4d5bf266" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Jabberwock," 6 July 1907 : Winning Post </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5e0ab7b61884a1860e8ffeab121332e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Savage Club House Dinner," 6 July 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1b2de7976aa85ee370ef6312046d1f41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Westminster Gazette, 8 July 1907 : "Mark Twain's Real Jumping Frog" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cd4978d0d0c6fa82b190053c0f617881" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pilgrims Luncheon/Bystander, 10 July 1907 -- "Mark Twain's Visit: The veteran humorist amuses the pilgrims' club with some new jokes at the savoy luncheon held in his honour" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6c000e117f6b1f19188b942171fc0dd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"London Tribune," 10 July 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_21c9c0e0b471537a99a9567c09231207" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Liverpool Daily Post and Mercury," 11 July 1907 -- "John Bull and the vanishing cups" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c58dbfc2d0685939f20b1d9708f3b87d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Inter-Ocean," 13 July 1907, p. 1 -- "Mark Twain Leaves England--and the Ascot cup is still missing" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f92368b0fefadf111a3e80ac74ebc4d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 20 July 1907 : Mark Twain, Mrs. Eddy, King Leopold </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_23d3064d3125ee5bf5598d9a5ee504b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Judge," 27 July 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_02f7d73d545a2691fbf04e97e4430ab3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Christian Advocate," 1 August 1907 -- "Doctor's all or more innocents abroad" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1c66fd7c24da469a06e8958a9e463f5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 1 August 1907 --"England Likes Mark Twain" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5b31d993ff5d85fd16bc43c760a7411d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 29 August 1907 -- T. S. Tousey caricature</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4939b0a003b402b20bb09713f468432f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Success Magazine," September 1907 : Yankee in King Edwards Court -- "Impressions by 'Dwig'" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f953d41ec6530f96210a3e1909f87b86" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening Journal," 20 September 1907 : Mark Twain and H. H. Rogers by T. E. Powers, "Two Eminent Humorists" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1c938c7b639235bb1761c3847e80c5ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Harper's Weekly," 12 October 1907 : Mark Rockefeller -- "From the Nature-Fakers' Gallery"  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c8b74a8c8a846ca88b87c4191ab8c85b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Literary Digest," 19 October 1907 : Oxford procession </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_eac4748f2d3aa4f5fccc512261c7a7cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 24 November 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a7404dfcd38950365ec3af08e1c21597" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 28 November 1907 --Transparency </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_75c372f26d18a5a92640b1966d1eee7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 1 December 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d646cb3d0c27f1a05842491962ada4b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 10 December 1907 ; Also 24 April 1910 -- "Mark Twain in After Dinner Speech at His Best, as Cesare Saw Him" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1cddb5d477ead473da266ce4001df108" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 15 December 1907 -- "The most remarkable seen in New York this season"  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f4b0a8c298b213de1582359dae63ebcc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Pleiades Club,"  22 December 1907 by Anderson </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_75ee868c4515f02b51f668473687c79f" level="file"><did><unittitle>James A. Shepperd, 1907 -- Correspondence seeking caricature from the National Portrait Gallery </unittitle><unitdate normal="1989">1989</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0e13c7001f1a4cbcf10ecf4f88bec06c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," 19 January 1908 -- "Mark and Mary a Novel Gyroscopic Toy--Combines Science and Laughter</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_409ba06126450f975fabe00f16765d04" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Saturday Evening Post," 15 February 1908 : Re: Stewart -- "I am Just Back from the Holy Land" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_efc300e1676f9df59f40c011bfc1d49f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 20 February 1908 -- "Some Distinguished New Yorkers Who Attended the Pilgrims Dinner" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e8badbe83ca78694a7e81ff64429c46e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," 1 March 1908 -- "Mark Twain prefers to be put at the end of the programme" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b22d02b4d06d7449cf8874eeba140feb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Collier's," 10 April 1909 -- "Indoor America" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1bdd8bdc63131ba751b41a65afa67a7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 19 April 1908 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1013f2e7e261a93537fcb13d5387e8db" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Vanity Fair," 13 May 1908 : Spy caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a53eebb19d0d23e208eb75500d6c038a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 19 September 1908 -- "Mark Twain's home, the two burglars, their captor and the Twain kittens" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7f860f351491dcda5d0d338d0c5356fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 26 December 1908 -- "Malefactors of Great Wealth Club" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cea96bd5e22522f372b8d533c8ee4216" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald," 29 December 1908 : "Mark Twain has 'Elephant' on his Hands" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_414dfccdd9547138e9ac36509884e6ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Max Beerbohm, c. 1908 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_16cd1f2c36eb37353c78fd086205f70b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The New Planet/Harper's Weekly," 30 January 1909, p. 13 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7cb3c72dc7e67767291c8a87683afd20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook, January 1909 by Mark Fenderson -- "good natured portraits" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a8f3e4addb0d6c361ab9cdab2a361431" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 28 February 1909 -- "The World's Championship Belt" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4d86f62bb2ca685efd2e4c55b225852f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Norfolk (Va.) Ledger Dispatch," 5 April 1909 -- Text of article, no image </unittitle><unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3de9d7c1dae3f975ecab0e162aee5ce9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Current Literature," June 1909 -- "Cloud effects" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_da0d8a1b0169aecae0a10f3798ff7b26" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Coburn Negatives, late 1908-1909 -- Two twain portrait color negatives </unittitle><unitdate normal="1980">1980</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_622f65d0870b9ba9ab6ac31bd3e412e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Art young : Mark Twain walking on Fifth Avenue </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f88782fc87a09c3019efef1762e82ea2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," 6 February 1910 -- Mark Twain chased by Denmark </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9f3e86579756cb03d86dcb698efe8261" level="file"><did><unittitle>Red Lewis : Mark Twain as Huck Finn </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a24a938652fdd0c5a846ce42a4c27063" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," : Mark Twain and Dickens by Anderson </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ee53c8c99a02e3f99cb66997ef32806e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain as a Notorious Smoker -- photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_60837806d60d79e34c8daf8ac4c2a262" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fudge caricature </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_beb2568b8892ea799e086212faae9507" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carlo de Fornaro? -- Notecards and article, no image </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_124896418c4ad3e70e2bb5f9182e0c83" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Daily News," 22 April 1910 -- "The Magic River" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6a01d677991b7b9ee2e9900711e86f60" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Record-Herald," 22 April 1910 -- "The Babies; They Comfort Us in Our Sorrows, Let us not Forget Them in Our Festivities" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ee239efc199e1980a1a54c391d27d894" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Tribune," 22 April 1910 -- Caricature by Briggs </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_969500c94a2045239d67e1527bf4320b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 22 April 1910 : R. Carter/also 2d item </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a3f2c357232b3817fdd0f2aee2804143" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Lewiston Evening Journal," 22 April 1910 -- "Hall of Fame" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_313b2ffaf53444ada86e990aa4c53527" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Post-Dispatch," 22 April 1910 -- "Pilot" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c53bc2a705a64fb41d2235ebc435f163" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Republic," 22 April 1910 -- "Humorist whose eventful career has been closed by death" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dc7959791349fa19b7b1806ce019215c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Springfield Illinois State Journal," 22 April 1910  -- "Stayed is the Hand that made world laugh and weep" by Grue </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2348c2d16aae5a17360d4b1b9a29485a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Wheeling (W. Va) Register," 22 April 1910 -- "Mark Twain, Most Picturesque Figure in Literature, is Dead" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_812b61ebf05a01000075a34c40ebcbfd" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Atlanta Journal," 23 April 1910 -- "Uncle Sam Mourns" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_637ecf242ce683c97e97b7f56c5bea95" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Baltimore American," 23 April 1910 : Thorndike -- "There is a Time to Laugh and There is a Time to Weep" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e39085386332310d32d26e1fabc8d89f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Cleveland Plain Dealer," 23 April 1910 -- "Down the River" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9ab8c119d8721b820f985fa6f2bf86cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Denver (Rocky Mountains) News," 23 April 1910 -- "The Old Pilot's Last Voyage" by Gilbert </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6f0f9c0fd11699af89352759685040f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Knoxville Journal and Tribune," 23 April 1910 --"The Vacant Chair" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dadf1dabc626c33815a63bfa26c34a22" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Los Angeles Times," 23 April 1910 -- "Among the Immortals" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c6267ba3f152806214e93b82367034d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Nashville American," 23 April 1910 -- Wetterau </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_592bd48d9a5b7f0867a052b35bb13dc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York World," 23 April 1910 : Obituary Cartoon -- "The Last Voyage" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e7719c5a9a2557ab0cfe1b810cf0f5cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Republic," 23 April 1910 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d844e7fc6548d360ec9835f7d8e44b0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"San Francisco Call," 23 April 1910 -- "Finis" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a06849a2c6c27108c74e3b3fbc367bb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Spokane Spokesman Review," 23 April 1910 -- "The Vacant Chair at Stormfield" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9bc58f1324a70e69fc1adef7cc12008a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Washington (D.C.) Evening Star," 23 April 1910</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c6ec69f293fbdce3450d572554fa148e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Denver (Col.) Post," 24 April 1910 -- "gone" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_20967455134eaf75e6be83a4a06034f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Inter-Ocean," 24 April 1910  -- "At a great man's tomb today</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2735c4132874e122c3cc59600c82196a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Record-Herald," 24 April 1910 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_51d4c5afe32cf2a32038a21528fc6e6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Ohio State Journal," 24 April 1910 -- "Death makes no conquest of this conqueror" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_404633568e79c648a0f4424634bd4aa2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Washington (D.C.) Herald," 24 April 1910 -- "Works of cheer still live" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_51f3dbda3430d91e782933474dfcf7c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Evening World, 25 April 1910</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4264145666781ec2b23c4fe8b2f5e908" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zim, 1910? Obit Cartoon? --Elmira's Honored Son </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5c91139ed2b2d64ec35b31a6042fce2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zim : After 1910? </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_188bf98174bcf9d66623fbba6d5ac9dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York American," 1 May 1910 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8c93818146bb8d24727198ee677ef489" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statuette by Amici in Rome Café </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_648ffe9fe1bb039efea6c108b14d617d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merle Johnson's drawing, c. 1910 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2436eeb57df29ba98543d79cb8f5fc8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Webster, "The boy whose mother read Tom Sawyer" (before 1915)</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_bad3c159e6a765e761630016e30b5d95" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Life," 9 December 1920</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d3e8ba3b623c31cd313c5063680dfead" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Mentor," May 1924 : C. Fornaro -- Twain with umbrella </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a04c62f38d428bc992a72dd55caee41c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Saturday Evening Post," Campbell Soup Ad, 1934 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6d22cdfcb3b967ac27d129bfdeaceec0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Photoplay Magazine," October 1934 -- Budweiser ad </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_22b1ef7183f93477d0dc67a3f553154f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Believe it or Not," 1 November 1935 -- "St. Louis Post-Dispatch" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7d1c5141c110f36224965063890dc1b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Caleb Catlum's America, 1936 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7231d2f4d1a7d0bc36338338e17838d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Fortune," February 1937 : Old Taylor advertisement, includes color photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d4f3d5fa242922986a452f25ff078a7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>In Danish Edition of Stolen White Elephant </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d0a19fee4234a768199a148971dd6643" level="file"><did><unittitle>On Willard Hotel Menu -- Sold in 1943 </unittitle><unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dd295e39477eb42db9a906603c0e0241" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Horizon," 23 December, 1945, p. 8, 9 December 1945 p. 18 -- German </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0c734a411f05f0fffd27d65ce26d8663" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald Tribune," 20 March 1948 : Webster, Mark Twain "Chair" -- "The thrill that comes once in a lifetime" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_709ed50f1486f43785519757f1f3098f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Los Angeles Times," 4 November, 1948 -- "As Mark Twain Would Put It"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_acc300e112f99f0ba6bbbd978f20447c" level="file"><did><unittitle>James Montgomery Flagg sketch, 12 January 1949 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_edf69cebed53964118ab8e9a682d1620" level="file"><did><unittitle>"St. Louis Globe-Democrat," 25 January 1949 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c9909be74bdf0488b70250ac556ce96d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Everett Shinn : Mark Twain in Library, 1951 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_047379cceeb528604b834bd2d03733e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dutch Quarterly Review, 1981 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d955dce0a0b6025dbe16ca1472e2d119" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Herald Tribune," 9 May 1952 : Old Typesetter </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_92cfdbc6448d7e95d1c778e656fc8737" level="file"><did><unittitle>David Levine : Three drawings, 1960's </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e18d556154a6c97a4b875bcc2cb6a542" level="file"><did><unittitle>H. Lauritzen, Mark Twain's Humor </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_56572eea4b6ff841194fbb55d6f59525" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carl Rose for Bennet Cerf </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4076d2e60201daffd401a2056e6c6e39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Art Young </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cd2e332568c74e5303d0b535ed7869d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Old Crow Ad, "TIME," 5 October 1962</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b5f4ba124f8b28c0c8fd564a1c9366ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>From "Other Voices (Elmira College)," June 1969</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_039b8bdb43d682acea675a366cb2da4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Broom-Hilda, 20 July 1971 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d19360c0c5935ffbc4ecd78dcbc0dac0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"They'll Do It Everytime," 17 November 1974</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_221397d234719a0234d5202003cc0312" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gersten, c. 1980 for Quality Paper Backs </unittitle><unitdate normal="1980">1980</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cfd981a279139d7b8959533185d8235c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Washington Post" Parade Section, 5 April 1981 : Mark Twain and His Publisher</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6cb086e6c480278b2b67ab0804fd926f" level="file"><did><unittitle>1984 Wordcut/Elmira Flier </unittitle><unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_be062e1b3b569895d1dad98a64ea8af1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paul Pitcher 1980s? 1990s? </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5224188e31a9a663fd86d003936505c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Times," Gordon Connell, 21 April 1985 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_827a34749a92e6885c953db8f527924a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Rocky Mountain News," 20 October 1985 -- Win, Lose and Drew </unittitle><unitdate normal="1985">1985</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ca00126edcedab6ec20c6e63243098a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dave Kelley, Essays in Literature, Fall 1985 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_bf8a61e75bb5104a7b90cfe4d545bb31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain on a Jumping Frog, 1985 </unittitle><unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7c0a0dbc0a3848a8e9e15ad8861d8c6c" level="file"><did><unittitle>V. Courtlandt Johnson, Harper's Magazine, January 1986 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e34765477fd95ca1f7756b6d791566ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ronald Searle : Mark Twain, Steamboat, Tom and Fence, Huck </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b4df20e0406c0dab4952253a6a7f6e62" level="file"><did><unittitle>U &amp; LC (Upper and Lower Case) February 1987</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0a472e9506ded014a99d20f45e77a7fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Daytona Beach News Journal," 11/8/87  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d4e746ece4f600bbfad857a4331d402c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain Shirt, c. 1988 -- photograph </unittitle><unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b4194abe0b77aedadf51760080c1deb8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"San Francisco Chronicle," 10 February 1991 by Val B. Mina </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6a295c28e4e8afe447ef7570aa20baae" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Metropolitan Home," 1991 by Frederick Hart </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_88dc1829ba123191dddf0eb79711fbaf" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Chicago Tribune," 18 October 1992 </unittitle><unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_daaebbdf87609922ea8e89dec6399b06" level="file"><did><unittitle>1993 Item -- Will Sleazak </unittitle><unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8ad77012fa255eaf9a56451e02e58776" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drawings for Mark Twain Festival, Birmingham ALA, March 1993 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6d94d87f8f1847503023fa5fd81bbc78" level="file"><did><unittitle>David Tomlinson handout, May 1993 </unittitle><unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e0a14ea54feb52b6d5a8c3fb833c50bb" level="file"><did><unittitle>"North Carolina Independent," June 30-July 6, 1993 </unittitle><unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_027b4a1e5bc3e8c79817b352ec7a6856" level="file"><did><unittitle>Peanuts, 25 July 1995 -- Twain reference </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_047316cf8fecd65985ff3a801db63959" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nancy Ohanian, Los Angeles Times, 26 Jan 1997 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_267741d0d4bf7060444dd1b9ae41144c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"New York Weekly Standard," 5 May 1997 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a863fe05495d9fae3dedd96939ca62ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elmira 1999 for McAvoy Lane Poster </unittitle><unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_266f14541fdda1de93f821b93bd05494" level="file"><did><unittitle>Atlantic Monthly, July-August 2001 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_bd76e275e51a727d56607315d1888191" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mike Burrell </unittitle><unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3081d72e529ba951191ae1f4aacd919e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mike Burrell </unittitle><unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_49cc3332396a53d4a227dca611621179" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mizzou (mag.), Summer 2006 </unittitle><unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_afeeb664a12a45426a78aa716ab8d363" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain in blackface (and color) 2007 or earlier </unittitle><unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f01e5748185e2db96986d29aecc3ee98" level="file"><did><unittitle>From K. MacDonnell, bought in 2008 -- watercolor </unittitle><unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="c_3582fc626e7680a36deefcc7566b728d" level="series"><did><unittitle> SERIES 3: MARK TWAIN INTERVIEWS</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate><note><p>This series compiled by Louis J. Budd contains photocopies and transcriptions of Mark Twain interviews.  Dates reflect the date of the original article and not the date of reproduction. This series contains Budd’s original folder headings and is arranged chronologically</p></note></did><c id="c_ac3b8abf5c6b9de0f99c6c4e6623e19b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington National Republican -- "Mark Twain Takes Out a Patent" -- "Probably an authentic summary of Clemens's drolling about his "patent suspenders" and Horace Greeley; No Direct Quotation" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1871-09-21">September 21, 1871</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_01c927beff39a29ab3e7ff7b2fb683c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Evening Traveler -- "New Publications" (Hard to Read</unittitle><unitdate normal="1874-01-06">January 6, 1874</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e9161f78fccd2ddeb3a8fba719b6637c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Evening Transcript -- "Soliciting Twain's Subscription" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1874-05-29">May 29, 1874</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7c84a53264f95cad38be1443aaa9985f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Evening Journal/Boston Times -- "Mark Twain's Recent Walking Feat"," "Mark Twain as a Pedestrian" -- "Clemens gives details on his abortive walking tour with J.H. Twichell"" (With Notes) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1874-11-14">November 14, 1874</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_07eaa8e6e0def24dde64b768718db539" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN and Boston Evening Transcript -- "Mark Twain: An Extract from a  Private Letter to a Gentleman of This City," "The Growth of New York: Up Town and Down Town" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1876-10-22">October 22, 1876</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_25fe3101288eeaa2bc23ad8f1a5bcd3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elmira Daily Advertiser -- Mark Twain and Politics -- "Clemens gives his reasons for supporting Rutherford B. Hayes for the presidency" (No Title) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1876-12-29">December 29, 1876</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_724c049d1394c8b7c42ec3b84ca20539" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Not Quite and Editor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1878-01-26">January 26, 1878</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_eadcd8bc717d87a456a907183b5eaed0" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times, World --MT Sails to Germany, "The Start for Germany"-- "Very long, jocular item as Clemens family embarks; Bayard Taylor gets the most space; though mostly in a joking mood, Clemens indicates that the new travel book will not echo 'Innocents Abroad'" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1878-04-12">April 12, 1878</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_86d2e7e1fa010aea11f6cd73fbbd2eda" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Interviewed: About New Book on Travel" -- "Rich item dealing mainly with copyright law and with Clemens's conclusions that faults in British were no worse than American ones"  (With Notes) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1879-05-11">May 11, 1879</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1e3c343a943501feb954f054a03de15d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain's Return/The Great Humorist Delighted to Be Home--How He Passed His Time in Europe" -- "Fairly brief; remarks on forthcoming book and casual remarks about the British aristocracy" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1879-09-03">September 3, 1879</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b0aba5984613a4773ba140f9ca3d30e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Mark Twain Back Again/Freely Expresses His Opinion About Various Things/His View on the English Language, the Danger of the Elevated Railroads, Prunes as a Sea-Going Diet, and Lord Dunraven" -- "Light-weight but amusing; besides topics listed Clemens comments on his forthcoming book" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1879-09-03">September 3, 1879</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0b6dd42b6792fadd53f8edf2cae3a74f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain Home Again/What He Says About the New Book He Has Written" -- "A jocular account; Clemens makes practical remarks about how much of the new travel book he has written and how he heavily he expects to revise it" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1879-09-03">September 3, 1879</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7a8a1e31de63e4eafcd3f85901240149" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mr. Twain Again with Us/A Wonderful Book in His Luggage and Much Wonderful Sea-Lore in His Head" -- "After much joking about the sea voyage, nature, and Clemens discusses the progress of his projected travel book" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1979-09-03">September 3, 1979</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1b99847e77ea6c26192191aead80e7c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hartford Post --"On Sentimental Poetry," "Mark Twain Unfolds a Few Striking Specimens," "A Few Epitaphs" (With Notes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1880">1880</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6deeac67d593cb4d5889a1d6835c7e5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Herald -- "Mark Twain/Samuel L. Clemens' Home in Hartford/The Artistic Surroundings of a Sterling Humorist" -- No direct quotations; seemingly another of the "Mark Twain at Home" pieces; but is based on overnight visit by the reporter (Sylvester Baxter); facts and opinions (as on copyright) come from Clemens--see H.N. Smith and W.M. Gibson, eds., "The Mark Twain-Howells Letter" (Cambridge, Mass., 1960), pp. 311-312, 314-316/ </unittitle><unitdate normal="1880-06-20">June 20, 1880</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2fd046d8ed42f6478d1dbc9bf784adcd" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN, Knoxville Daily Chronicle -- "The Lookout of the World/Mark Twain's Preparations for a Possible Encounter with a Comet" -- "Most probably spurious; Mark Twain is sitting near Hartford, the roof of his house with a pole, ready to fend of a visible comet if it gets too close to the earth" (With Correspondence)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1881-06-27/1881-06-28">June 27, 1881 - June 28, 1881</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2fa9d7db3093f77881b326d1dd193e5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Montreal (Canada) Gazette -- "An Innocent Abroad" -- "Comments on his lecturing; reminisces about the legislature in the Sandwich Islands</unittitle><unitdate normal="1881-11-28">November 28, 1881</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_960ad6df62465fee7319d9542131b7a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Evening Traveler -- "New Publications- The Prince and the Pauper" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1882-01-06">January 6, 1882</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_01e7458c7595f3e8fa6cf99876d2a918" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- "An 'Innocent' Interviewed, Mark Twain Pays a Visit to St. Louis" -- "Rails at interviewers; discusses his projected travel book about the Mississippi; develops a fantasy about an expedition to fix location of Hell" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1882-05-12">May 12, 1882</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ab31876aa9134c2c83b3c02ec5b19c92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Globe-Democrat -- "Mark Twain Travels, The Famous Humorist Pay a Flying Visit to St Louis/A Round Trip to Mississippi in Search of Book Material" -- "Clemens recalls "Babies" speech; discusses his planned book on the river trip" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1882-05-13">May 13, 1882</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_514903110bfde5a9bc257ee8cc08d08d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Keokuk Daily Constitution, Muscatine Daily Journal -- "Mark Twain Spends a Few Hours in Keokuk, and is Entertained by Some of His Old Friends Here," "Mark Twain: A Short Chat with the Gentleman," "Mark Twain in Muscatine" -- "Gives practical details of his current trip" -- "Brief, no direct quotations; mentions that Clemens recently told anecdote about reciting same certain number of Bible verses for five years" -- "Clemens brief layover; no quotations or summary of significant opinions" (With Correspondence) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1882-05-18/1882-05-19">May 18, 1882 - May 19, 1882</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_adac16f3072940ca5e76f0d24dce1aff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Paul and Minneapolis Pioneer Press -- "Mark Twain Not Misrepresented" -- "Brief item; no direct quotations; Clemens on mistrust of interviewers and on reasons for current trip" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1882-05-22">May 22, 1882</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8d74a3d8f683397437971de5feb2531a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rollingpin's Humorous Illustrated Annual -- "A Day with Mark Twain" (With Correspondence) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1882-05">May, 1882</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ea41de32af17b0c3f60c4bd7de41c0c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mr. Mark Twain Excited/On Seeing the Name of Capt. C. C. Duncan in Print" -- "A blistering but funny tirade, technically an interview; mostly disavowed later by Clemens in New York SUN on August 24, 1883" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1883-06-10">June 10, 1883</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_24068462e45fee31f5469ab960ba619b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Herald -- "Mark Twain and the Police/The Humorist's Experience in a Boston Station House" -- "Not quite an interview but long quotation from Clemens describing his reception at the police station after helping to prevent a suicide" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-11-16">November 16, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_de0930467b26f235bed9e3acf18015b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain as a Lecturer/How He Feels When He Gets on the Stage Before an Audience" -- "Clemens discusses how he watches, quakes, and adjusts to the reactions of his audiences" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-11-20">November 20, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a3e5b416d30e7304f1e122ffd19a5aa3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore (Md.) American -- "Mark Twain Ideas" -- "Complains mildly about traveling as a lecturer; discusses psychology of audiences and Americanisms of speech" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-11-29">November 29, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_59e216777d16b0f00cec7fc2a8ba4388" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rochester (New York) Herald -- "Mark Twain Encountered" -- "Clemens described as loafing the day away; comments on various subjects, such as partnership with G.W. Cable and architecture of his Hartford house" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-12-08">December 8, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dfbf9cfa2f3c675e0b1be24cc93d266a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Toronto Globe -- "An Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Brief, casual; Clemens explains why he went back on his vow never to lecture again" (With Notes) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-12-09">December 9, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_802bcf377bd6c799afa9372c5f1a28c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Detroit Post -- "The Funny Men in Bed/A Post Reporter Disturbs Twain and Interviews Cable" -- "Clemens comments briefly on defects of copyright law, applauds the growing popularity of American humor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-12-17">December 17, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cede48859d0905adf4a08c84dd3043cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pittsburgh Chronicle Telegraph -- "A Talk with Mark Twain/His Comments on Authors, Magazines and General Literature" -- "Coherent and cogent; Clemens on a new syndicate for literary materials, his limited taste for fiction (even Hawthorne's), and the social accuracy of Howells' Bartley Hubbard and of "Daisy Miller" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-12-29">December 29, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_20ecafeae78487be6df531f1fddc544a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pittsburgh Penny Press -- "Mark Twain Gets Shaved…and Talks to a Reporter at the Same Time" -- "Clemens jokingly describes himself as the level of a murderer of the English language, asserts seriously that magazine writing is much superior to that of the past"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-12-29">December 29, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4e570a0a078cff7cb472321fae4c1996" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pittsburgh Post -- "Mark Twain Gives His Own Experiences with an Interviewer and Jokes at His Own Expense" -- "A lightweight item probably meant to generate free publicity for Twain-Cable tour" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1884-12-29">December 29, 1884</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1aa82812e4187d7f6c018543f9adaa49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cincinnati Enquirer -- "Twain and Cable," "The Humorist Interviewed" -- "Clemens does most of the talking; discusses interviews, his days on Territorial Enterprise, Bret Hare"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-03">January 3, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d37ebeb168ea2d9e3a416bc61ae3b283" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louisville (KY) Post -- "A Great Humorist/Mark Twain Gives Some Information Concerning Himself and Partner--How He Met the Reporter and the Instructions He Gave" -- "Clemens casually discusses his reception in the South, his fight for copyright, his treatment by interviewers" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-05">January 5, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3e75a27fff32fe9592356e2972197726" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- "Cable and Twain/The Author and the Humorist Arrive in the City To-Day" -- "Clemens in joking mood; does about all the talking, mostly about a rough ride across the Mississippi" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-09">January 9, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7dc54a66a0288338e17d90e5d4370909" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Evening Chronicle -- "Two of a Kind: Samuel Clemens and George W. Cable" -- "Clemens does almost all the talking; he compares Canadian, Northern, Southern, and British audiences and discusses sales of his books" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-09">January 9, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_00315099d50db20d9b2e4cfbb88fb365" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Daily News -- "Mark Twain and George Cable Loaded with Enjoyment" -- "Brief but amusing; Clemens jokes about being tired and hungry" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-16">January 16, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7c0be3e55374ed9ca27486060a88ab68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fort Madison Democrat -- "Mark Twain in Iowa" -- "Long introductory remarks and details, then brief summary of what may have been a long interview; Clemens show interest in Indians" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-21">January 21, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_725c37deb00ced5d1c1b6ee9ffb82726" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis Tribune -- "An Interesting Chat with Samuel Clemens and George Cable Upon Their Work" -- "Clemens on origin of joint lecture tour and a general sources of Huckleberry Finn; Cable does a good share of talking" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-25">January 25, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0232d82131899289bed2b4c3fc238b3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Milwaukee Evening Wisconsin -- "Talk with Mark Twain" -- "Clemens discusses his efforts to get Canadian copyright, the faulty illustration in Huckleberry Finn, and borrowing his pen name from a Mississippi boatman. This may be an interview described in W.J. Anderson, "Tells an Interview He Once Had with Great Humorist," Wisconsin State Journal, April 22, 1910, p. 1" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-01-29">January 29, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_92ca70af3448ed7634fb8638ecdad18b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lafayette Daily Courier -- "Mark Twain Interviewed/His Views Upon Subjects of Interest" -- "After that familiar version of the origins of reading tour, Clemens joke vigorously about the malodorous local canal, the courthouse, and Cable's soporific effect on audiences" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-02-06">February 6, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6f98a3611e1286e2fb02475f9e172f98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Detroit Free Press -- "The Re-Mark-Able Twain" -- "Quoted passages are few; much recounting of backstage remarks by Clemens and Cable while the other is performing</unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-02-15">February 15, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fc2006a82056afd8bef05a75f6a573f0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Montreal Daily Star -- "Moments of Samuel Clemens and George Cable" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1885-02-20">February 20, 1885</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0d8d0f7aa0c2f496d2d0d779af2f08c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis Tribune -- "Mark Twain in Saint Paul" -- "Brief; Clemens family on way to Kobuk, Iowa; Clemens discusses his habit of working on several books intermittently" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1886-06-30">June 30, 1886</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5cc141df433c38dd5995718a87003bd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Paul and Minneapolis Pioneer Press -- "Mark Twain Abroad" -- "Clemens comments on modern journalism; brief" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1886-06-30">June 30, 1886</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b517a5327112fab10b5217672a33e740" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Tribune -- "Amusing the Children/Thus Does Mark Twain Kill Time While in Chicago" -- "Clemens discusses recent visit to Keokuk, scenery of upper Mississippi River, and neglect of the area by travel writers and social commentators; praises steamboat travel" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1886-07-09">July 9, 1886</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a498ec47940ad8d788de9d7e1770cf9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Tribune -- "A Day with Mark Twain/The Genial Humorist at His Summer Home" -- "Edwin J. Park wrote; many small details on the Quarry Farm setting; Clemens has done no writing there during the past summer" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1886-09-19">September 19, 1886</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_bec384c20b05ed5675e9b1e0c6964348" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "The Insolence of Office" -- "Marginal item; congressional doorkeeper keeps Mark Twain (for a while) from seeing Sunset Cox; Clemens protests that he was once a 'mighty good' reporter in V.A. City" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1888-03-23">March 23, 1888</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_73fc27d23baa85e653e475f8fe03a010" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "An Interview with the Famous Humorist/He Chats of Past and Present/His Life as a Reporter" -- "In Washington, D.C. Clemens reminisces about 1867-1868" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1889-05-19">May 19, 1889</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_44d9ecb1c27f2d453a231ddaf4bf2e1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Journal (Supplement) -- "Mark Twain Speaks His Mind on Interviews/A Pungent Letter from the Great Humorist" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1889-07-13">July 13, 1889</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_56e0e2fec3eb2ae7e63d060a1f31aeaf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tacoma (WA) Globe -- "Mark Twain's Latest"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1889-12-29">December 29, 1889</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9266d42f1ea4aec66bcebc012d6cbcb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times, Pall Mall Gazette -- "Mark Twain and His Book/The Humorist on the Copyright Question/The Spread of Foreign Notions Not to His Liking--What His English Publisher Dared Not Print" -- "Important comments about Connecticut Yankee" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">1889-12-10 &amp; 1889-12-23</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_67a7d98ea4ca26301ad8c71449bcb601" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain at Home/An Interesting Visit to the Humorist's Workshop/Talks of His Funny Books/How He Does His Work and Reminiscences of His Most Popular Books--He Labors But Three Months a Year--Replying to Accusations of Plagiarism" -- "Very long item, though reporter is obtrusive; Clemens answers charge that basic idea of Connecticut Yankee was taken from Max Adeler" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1890-01-12">January 12, 1890</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ba3e631c38c0fb145f176c195a5626ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hartford Current -- "Mark Twain's Lawsuit/Dramatization of the 'Prince and the Pauper'" -- "Clemens gives his side of dispute with Edward H. House</unittitle><unitdate normal="1890-01-18">January 18, 1890</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6796ad61aba3b076633cfcfce28ab35a" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Rudyard Kipling on Mark Twain" -- "Bibliog in July-September 1993 MT Circular states that item also ran in Lahore CIVIL AND MILITARY GAZETTE, 23 September 1890; cites article "Kipling and Mark Twain" in Kipling Journal 66, No. 263 (September 1992)" (With Notes) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1890-08-17">August 17, 1890</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5262be75d6944071871f152f7df07d99" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain on Kipling" -- "Fairly long item; deals with Kipling's visit and work, "Diary of Shem," habit of waiting for tank to fill up, and Prince and Pauper lawsuit" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1890-08-24">August 24, 1890</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9060f56b1d88ee7c46ee31402c189b9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edward Bob -- "Literary Leaves" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1991-05-12/1991-05-15">May 12, 1991 - May 15, 1991</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f2e611d3a091da5de6d2374bee948571" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain on Humor/T.B. Aldrich the Wittiest Man" -- "Long item with much talk about humor, especially; also on definitions of reverence vs. irreverence" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1891-05-31">May 31, 1891</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_df47ee705f444fab000185c2e8c327d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Berlin National-Zeitung -- "Mark Twain in Berlin" -- "Clemens praises Belen and, unlike hasty visitors to U.S., doubts he will write book about Germany; is relieved to find he is not subject to German taxes and complains about having his royalties taxed in England" (With Correspondence) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1891-11-15">November 15, 1891</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_37a8317d42da6a87d1a9541d58f37c48" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain's Little Joke/He Registers as 'Mr. Jones, of Gibraltar' To Hide Himself" -- "Brief, with no direct quotation; Clemens claims he wanted to see how long he could remain incognito in New York City"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1893-04-05">April 5, 1893</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3f3898827a59a8d0c70cfb72c2601ff7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Inter-Ocean -- "Colony of Mermaids/Mark Twain to Exhibit a lot of Fish-Tailed Girls" -- "Not much quotation; Clemens was trying to get unnoticed by the press; registered as from East Chicago; explains that he has gathered some mermaids during his ocean voyages and will exhibit them in Chicago; item interesting only in showing how the press joked with Mark Twain through Orion writing to Mollie Clemens on 15 April 1893 (From Chicago) called it an interview" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1893-04-15">April 15, 1893</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_806f1a3e3bef3248876cf6b4e17ca772" level="file"><did><unittitle>Illustrated Buffalo Express, Saint Louis Republic -- "Mark Twain and the Reporter/Mark Twain Came Abroad" -- "Clemens in garrulous and joking mood; mentions his working habits, tells the glass-eye story, discusses his after-dinner speaking" (With Notes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1894-04-01">April 1, 1894</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_52a6a8db6424381bb3c96ebd7c9854e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Paris Figaro  -- "Gabriel Random, Mark Twain" -- Much background commentary; Clemens names his favorite authors, and especially his French favorites; he tells an anecdote contrasting French and American character" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1894-04-05">April 5, 1894</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1c495db351e71ff345ac046c063361ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Mark Twain is Back in Town/Has Been Abroad to See His Wife, Who Was Ill in Paris" -- "Brief; Clemens discusses his wife's health and sea voyage" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1894-04-15">April 15, 1894</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8fcabe15c4ea177fa3ae1d1fcd45795c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Mark Twain Goes Abroad" -- "Clemens jokes about whether he is on passenger list; briefly discusses his wife's health and European doctors"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1894-08-16">August 16, 1894</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ae783dc8f06259799d30290550f330be" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Sun -- "Mark Twain in Paris" -- "Clemens on French character and culture, especially French reputation for wit" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-01-27">January 27, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ee1cc0342affe87be68387e766c262ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cleveland Plain Dealer -- "Mark Twain/His Scheme for Regeneration of Human Race/He Makes a Startling Confession/He Says That in His Plan of Regeneration He Has Passed Through Two-Thirds of the Crimes of Which the Human Race is Capable" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-16">July 16, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8a371c71ab13e30f877c88a5f0be4e35" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cleveland, Sydney Australian Star -- "A Trip Around the World" -- "Clemens on duel in Nevada and SF CALL days" (With Correspondence) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-16">July 16, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ff2b60f3e0f1f85668eb6a3f1426ffd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Petoskey Restorer -- "Mark Twain on Yachting/Something Concerning the Great Humorist" -- "Clemens much prefers yachting on the lakes rather than the ocean" -- "Clemens discusses how he borrowed his pen name, evades question of authorship of 'Joan' book, reacts to a local newspaper" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-21">July 21, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d535561de73e5640c3d39443880ba06a" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Next Stop Detroit: A City's Views of Mark Twain's Evolution as a Literary Hero 1868-1895 </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-18">July 18, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2e2df7486a24f0b77027554755a2fd73" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis Journal -- "Not Roughing it Now/Mark Twain Reaches Minneapolis on His 'World Belting' Trip/He Tells of His Recent Life" -- "Clemens comments on his wife and Howells as editors of his work" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-23">July 23, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_62f98667d5a1a1f0fbf1e5e6cf80bf14" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis Penny Press -- "Mark Twain/The Celebrated Humorist Arrives in the City Today" -- "Discusses his wife and daughters as editors, praises Kipling, and generalizes about what kind of humor will endure" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-23">July 23, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_316f4057e6bbe011c69084b9349a6d32" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minneapolis Times -- "In Private Life" -- "No direct quotations; Clemens praises Kipling, Bill Nye, and James Whitcomb Riley, and names 'Huckleberry Finn' as his favorite among his own books" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-24">July 24, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9835d30db3fdf654980659abc812bfe2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manitoba Evening Free Press -- "A Chat with Clemens/Mark Twain Talks About Himself, His Books, and His Aggravating Carbuncle" -- "Clemens prefers Huckleberry Finn over Tom Sawyer and squelches Max O'Rell; routine, almost brief" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-27">July 27, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_bd8c025f91a7e81c9f1cd0b48be12f29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Winnipeg (Canada) Nor-Western -- "An Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Clemens praises Hartford, Conn., calls for better copyright laws, reminisces about Artemus Ward, and recalls some tributes in Germany" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-27">July 27, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_87137166c76cdd4599500b99241366ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Winnipeg (Canada) Tribune -- "Mark Twain's Lecture" -- "Clemens comments on lecturing and on his feeling that river life on the Mississippi was his 'field of work'" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-27">July 27, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_781d6c486c06c6e54d738ffc8e3aaaa8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grand Forks (N. Dakota) Herald -- "Mark Twain Talks" -- "Not important; somewhat brief; Clemens comments on the way the grass prairies look like a mighty ocean; asks many questions, reportedly, about Grand Forks" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-07-30">July 30, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5e12ebc9a511a1d728b775ad4488fb2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Helena (Montana) Herald -- "Mark Twain is Here/The Eminent Humorist, Author and Lecturer on His First Trip to Montana's Capital" -- "Quoted passages reproduce (without credit) material from Minneapolis Journal July 23, 1895" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-03">August 3, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_884c40c98b84ad73517665540f978149" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tacoma (Wash) Morning Union -- "He Lost His Trunk Keys/Mark Twain is Seriously Embarrassed for Clean Clothes" -- "Paraphrase of superficial remarks about scenery" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-09">August 9, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b24bf9a0fffa2fdab17c8a9706d4ad36" level="file"><did><unittitle>Toronto Globe -- "Mark Twain Interviewed" -- "Not consequential though it shows Mark Twain quiet, informal mood before he rises into mock-oration over a broken bottle of whiskey" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-10">August 10, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_84862dd17ee6b1b4a51c698007e51e83" level="file"><did><unittitle>Portland Sunday Oregonian -- "Mark Twain Talks/The Famous Story-Teller Discusses Characters/Says That No Author Creates, but Merely Copies--How to Write a Guide Book" -- "Clemens also discusses monopolies and travel books (Clemens praised this interview)" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-11">August 11, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0ae01d9f50e944c846a582073c6af868" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seattle Post-Intelligence -- "The Same Old Twain" -- "Clemens praises the vistas of scenery and discusses tricks played by visual perspective; long anecdote about choosing his pen name; details on first publication of jumping frog story" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-11">August 11, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f20ac27247068ffd8a70269da61fe036" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tacoma (Washington) Morning Union -- "Mark Twain and Major Pond/They Talk about Each Other and Discusses Everything save Humorists" -- "Much space devoted to Pond as Clemens keeps drifting in and out of the interview; he says most about palmistry"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-11">August 11, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cd28a97e40e7f5e5599b940b80656034" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seattle Post-Intelligence -- "Mark Twain Brands a Fake/But It Does Not Irritate Him--Talk of Cable and Lecturing" --"Clemens repudiates a faked interview about mortuary poetry; denies that Cable and he broke up their lecture tour in a quarrel"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-14">August 14, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d937876f5695219c3bc7050dd8dfa645" level="file"><did><unittitle>San Francisco Examiner -- "Mark Twain to Pay All" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-17">August 17, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d0c31e0aff01396ca480d22eb4e5dc8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Whatcom Blade -- "Mark Twain Seriously Embarrassed for Clean Clothes/Mark Twain Unsuited" -- "Brief comment on poor visibility in area because of smoke" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-17">August 17, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b77825491f6019f109cb1fbc929b329f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times, New York Tribune -- "Mark Twain Plan of Settlement/Why Mark Twain Lectures" -- "A detailed, prepared statement" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-17">August 17, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2b92248d095c861641a255a08a3e4461" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vancouver (B. C.) Daily News Advertiser -- "Mark Twain Talks/About Lecturing and Lectures--Pleasant Half Hour in the Company of the Great Humorist" -- "Long comment on attitudes and psychology of audiences; diatribe against hotel keepers who are stingy about lighting"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-20">August 20, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_164853478ed1cee5045e4939d71102d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>San Francisco Examiner -- "Twain's Programme" -- "Greater detail on his bankruptcy and his plans for paying the debt; Clemens speaks warmly of his reception so far and exudes cheerfulness (perhaps Clemens wrote the text</unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-24">August 24, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_63b2a78fac51a64882674e2e85ddaf99" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vancouver or Victoria (B.C.) -- "Mark Twain Very Ill/Ruined at 60, He Starts 'round the World/But Talks in His Usual Vein Before He Goes/Where His Head Where His Feet Ought to Be, Twain Tells a Good Story on Saint Louis--Discusses Hotel Lights, Bell Boys and National Politics Until His Agent Makes Him Stop the Conversation" -- "Highly similar to item in Vancouver Daily New-Advertiser, 20 August 1895"  (With Correspondence) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-08-24">August 24, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d0aab5759abe3a3ebe8f8736d4484a82" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Australian Star - Saturday Evening "Very Much Abroad Mr. Clemens on Tour A Trip Around the World" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-14">September 14, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a8fdaead6eff9496a007ce47fb6a78e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne (Australia) Argus -- "Mark Twain at Sydney" -- "Clemens briefly discusses his literary quarrel with Max O'Rell" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-16">September 16, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5c5508260b467a42999843c3dd2957e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (Australia) Daily Telegraph -- "A Ramble with Mark Twain/His View on Men and Things" -- "Clemens defends free trade and Henry George's ideas on ownership of land; tells story of plagiarizing from Oliver Wendell Holmes; comments on Scotts and his style; declares he is humorous rather than witty" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-17">September 17, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9a614c0bd93c06a4f1801688dd764c9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (Australia) Morning Herald -- "Visit of Mark Twain/Wit and Humor" -- "Long discussion of humor and its relation to pathos and wit; judgments of W.S. Gilbert, Dickens, Pope, Ulysses Grant, Kipling, Harte' Clemens explains need for "third party" in politics" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-17">September 17, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_19e1916085ddf3fc1cf7aa18fc5ee487" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne (Australia) Argus -- "Mark Twain at Sydney" -- "Comments on seriousness of life, his reputed laziness, Ulysses Grant, Bret Harte, Kipling, and Hawthorne" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-16">September 16, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_808884da7076be5a1b7f1b45388fc454" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney Australian Star -- "An Interview with Mark Twain" (With Correspondence) </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-21">September 21, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_367f4614712e0d1e4cf5471f8ff60ee1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (Sunday) Truth -- "Our American Cousin" -- "A very playful item; hard to tell whether it is authentic; Clemens explains of having been hounded by reporters" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-22">September 22, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c2e44399925c294345702a23eda7f303" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (Australia) Sunday Times -- "A Chat with Mark Twain/Impressions of Public Men/Australian and American Audiences/Criticism of Bret Harte--What He Thinks of Interviewing--Lecturing v Authorship--His Favorite Work" -- "Long item; mostly direct quotation" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-22">September 22, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1f317089fa3c069424dfd82701289c7a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney Truth (Australia) -- "Mark Twain" -- "Long but unimportant because highly fanciful and quite possibly a total fabrication" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-22">September 22, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6fd84cd91387ec4743e40b794c766179" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne Evening News -- "Mark Twain in the Sydney Express" -- "Clemens, in a general mood, diplomatically praises the landscape and the Australian writer Marcus Clarke; briefly comments on Dickens and on 'Prince and Pauper'" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-26">September 26, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_09fd7f04546078febb5cacc645cca38e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne Herald -- "The Tramp in Melbourne/A Morning with Mark Twain/Jokes and Jottings" -- Clemens chats genially, praises Marcus Clarke's Novel" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-26/1895-09-27">September 26, 1895 - September 27, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8add5c8d9c33891536871c974a1698a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne (Australia) Age -- "Mark Twain/Arrival in Melbourne" -- "Clemens praises both progress and preserving some relics of past; suggests that purely humorous books do not last; describes his writing habits; decries hasty judgments by travelers" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09-27">September 27, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d89a39cbea57cd82c9f9fe65fe50a8af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Melbourne (Australia) Age -- "Mark Twain/Arrival in Melbourne" -- "Clemens praises both progress and preserving some relics of past; suggests that purely humorous books do not last; describes his writing habits; decries hasty judgments by travelers" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-10-14">October 14, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6378b52568afc562b8f7e94a2761784f" level="file"><did><unittitle>South Australian Register -- "Mark Twain Put to the Question" -- "Clemens discusses interviews, Kipling poetry, false notions about Americans and Southern violence, racial minorities, the "Jumping Frog" story"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-10-14">October 14, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7070cd320a97d2ca2a804936031e3c62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Licensing (?) Guardian (New South Wales) -- "Mark Twain on Prohibition" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-09/1895-12">September, 1895 - December, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ebd26a1021289afee43851195abae8fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Balart Courier -- "A Chat with Mark Twain: Impression of Australia" -- "No direct quotation; Mark Twain diplomatic; main Australian cities, scenery,  (?), and character which is highly similar of American character, especially in frankness" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-10-21">October 21, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fa667146af4c9de09a8353b0179ed992" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hobart (Australia) Tasmanian News -- "Mark Twain/Arrival in Hobart" -- "Probably in most part a pastiche of earlier interviews, especially that in Sydney Herald, 17 September 1895" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-11-02">November 2, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c1ac6c6b7a8b28b3b3afb550203a65a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hobart (Tasmania) Mercury -- "Mark Twain in Hobart/Save Impressions and a Interview" -- "Diplomatic remarks about Australian people and scenery" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-11-04">November 4, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b1b505f76fd68608c1fcc6a43fbb5b01" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dandier  (New Zealand) Otego Daily Times -- "M. Ross: A Chat with Mark Twain" -- "Long item with few quotations; Clemens discusses habit of working intermittently on a manuscript" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-11-06">November 6, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dfad8b95bae95283c34c401e68f50ad3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christchurch (New Zealand) Press -- "Mark Twain Home/A Chat with Mr. Clemens" -- "Clemens declines to make quick judgments on Australia and New Zealand, praises the scenery, compares American and "colonial audiences, praises Zew Zealand journalism" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-11-13">November 13, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_da1b1d86cb001099b3d599d52caa7b08" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christchurch (New Zealand) Canterbury Times/The Lyttelton Times -- "Mark Twain/A Talk with the Famous Humorist" -- "Brief reference to many subjects: Knights of Labor, habit of laying manuscripts aside for a while, superficial travel books, and lecture audiences" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-11-13">November 13, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f8cc7404f95265c897cb6453cda452e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Auekland New Zealand Herald -- "Mark Twain/Arrival in Auekland" -- "Prolonged discussion of American versus British humor and of Americanisms in speech" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-11-21">November 21, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8c047776f692556912359046847621b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wellington New Zealand Mail -- "A Chat with Mark Twain" -- "Clemens reminisces about Territorial Enterprise, Civil War (Service), publication of Jumping Frog story, the Holy Land trip, the Prince and the Pauper, and writing his own obituary" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-12-12">December 12, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_043a72bdeb29eaeba36c27bcf789aecb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (Australia) Daily Telegraph -- "Mark Twain/His Tour Through New Zealand" -- Clemens refuses to give impressions of Zew Zealand since he went through so little of it so hurriedly; criticizes, briefly, hasty travelers who express opinions on the United States" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1895-12-20">December 20, 1895</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9721b1f22ee02547c2107fd1184793f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Overland Times of Ceylon, Ceylon Observer -- "Mark Twain in Colombo</unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-01-14">January 14, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_991f675ead376a0c187087d63538110e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sydney (N. S. W.) Bulletin -- "Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Solid item; Clemens discusses his books, tastes in reading, writing habits, and dreams" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-01-04">January 4, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7499e45f4d67db5a0adfc3d39654a49a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ceylon Independent -- "Mark Twain in Ceylon/He Will Return to Lecture" -- "Summary of an extended, casual talk with Clemens, who compares public buildings in Ceylon and U.S."  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-01-15">January 15, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a4b4aaa6b312363a727ee8af18438f7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bombay Gazette -- "Mark Twain on His Methods of Work" -- "Detailed comments on when he works, how long, where, and how much he turns out; also comments lengthily on how much he prepares for his readings" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-01-23">January 23, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2e44e0d4cc778998e8d92ca44c729853" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bombay Times of India -- "Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Clemens sums up his journalistic career from Virginia City to Innocents Abroad; discusses Kipling, his new working habits, and interviewing" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-01-23">January 23, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4f869887fd34449f1e1f61bc07901970" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bombay India Gazette -- Mark Twain Relations Between England and America/Americans Not Unfriendly" -- "Clemens praises vigor and modernity of English-speaking peoples; strongly decries and idea of war over Venezuela question; insists that majority of Americans do not share anti-British feelings of their newspapers; defends British copyright law" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-01-24">January 24, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_794b030db0f9f3f87a6a05f85b8e779a" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Asian (Calcutta) -- "Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Clemens discusses scenery, gives anecdotes about his faux pas at a diner party and a clerk who failed to recognize his pen name" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-02-07">February 7, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a527dd57a4f7de672f2eb2a97c7806c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Calcutta Englishmen -- "Mark Twain Interviewed/First Impressions of India" -- "Comments on Indian scenery, visit to a holy recluse, caste system. British rule of India, treatment of red Indians in Canada and United States, and the Negro question in United States" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-02-08">February 8, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_41a8b81cd86fa241ee3797189f1d18dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Calcutta Statesman -- "Mark Twain in Calcutta" -- Clemens gives impressions of Indian scenery and railways" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-02-08">February 8, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3534ad0891d7d1b6a0f9bb6bbb536826" level="file"><did><unittitle>Calcutta Indian Daily News -- "Mark Twain in Calcutta" -- "Clemens comments on value of copyright of his books" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-03-26">March 26, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d5eb11c53b3d842f6d258bb995d9669f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reis and Ragget (Calcutta) -- "Mark Twain in Madras/An Interview in the Harbor--His Opinion on Mr. Skrine's book An Indian Journalist" -- "Detailed comments on publishing contracts, poverty in India, and England and United States as sources of inventions" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-04-11">April 11, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_27110083d15c084e5d13859f22a5710b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Durban (S.A.) Natal Mercury -- "Mark Twain in Durban/A Bedside Chat with the Humorist" -- "Clemens says much on Venezuela crisis, copyright, current (?), and Portugal as imperial power" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-05-08">May 8, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1519a2b1bbd488ac62301334a4cf66c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johannesburg Standard and Deggers' News -- "Mark Twain: The Humorist at Home/How He Tackled a New York Irishman/A Mark Twain Yarn"  -- "Table talk rather than interview; most space given to Clemens's anecdote of how he got past Daly's Irish doorkeeper; he jokingly mentions the criticism of Standard Oil Co., praises the sunsets in Florence, Italy, and comments on the local locust plague" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-05-18">May 18, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f109989d26ce9a6c3d9092fee353b483" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johannesburg (S.A.) Star -- "A Chat with Mark Twain/English and Americans/Some Authors He Knows/The Sense of Humor" -- "On the British-American relations, current Presidential election in United States, his books, W.D. Howells, and Edward Bellamy" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-05-18">May 18, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5fd60ae4327e111c6faad438dd28ca37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johannesburg (S.A.) Times -- "Mark Twain on the Rand/He Gives a Few Opinions/A Chat with the Humorist" -- "Clemens comments on complexity of current politics in Union of South Africa and on his curiosity about Cecil Rhodes; discusses Story of an American Farm" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-05-18">May 18, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_95ce1bb1ee0fda522e9f31c72fe28a2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pretoria (South Africa) Press -- "A Chat at the Hotel" -- "Few quotations; summary of Clemens  Jameson Raiders and Johannesburg" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-05-25">May 25, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b541ad0c669d9bd20cc38fd8941ac470" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kimberley (S.A.) Deamond Fields Advertiser -- "Mark Twain at Queenstown" -- "Brief, but Clemens comments on problems of having a reputation as a humorous writer" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-06-10">June 10, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6c6f396f610b79b1bccc9a3510742cfe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eastern Province Herald (S.A.) -- "Mark Twain/In Port Elizabeth" -- "On Jameson Raiders, railway travel, Venezuela crisis with stress on Anglo-American rapprochement" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-06-19">June 19, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7eab25dbfdf20cd24598f09c045bb6ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>London  African Critic -- "Stage and Sport/The Sketch/Critique and Causerie" -- "Clemens on Shriner, copyright, and pernicious French novels repeated from interviews in NATAL WITNESS, 8 May, and Johannesburg TIMES, 18 May, with F.L. Austin's criticism in London SKETCH" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-06-20">June 20, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_da6c3bc6926351ed54bb408e722631c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Midland News and Karroo Farmer (S.A.) -- "Mark Twain" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1896-06-30">June 30, 1896</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_240f6f4ae252832f8f0b6907dc48f099" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Journal -- "Mark Twain Amused/Humorist Says He Even Heard on Good Authority that He was Dead/Cousin, Not, Sick/New Book Just Finished, and It Will Be Called 'Another Innocent Abroad'" -- "One long quotation, which includes the famous, "The report of my death is an exaggeration" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-06-02">June 2, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_405c754a7791f45d8d5f590985fdf3da" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain Smiling Through His Tears, but in Sore Straits/Celebrated American Humorist Tells of His Affairs, and the Herald Starts a Subscription for Him" -- "Clemens discusses his health and his forthcoming travel book, criticizes French courts and severe punishments, tell anecdote about donating to charity" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-06-13">June 13, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6927c1bc5a3c4ae7def738d7b8ff8a3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Springfield Sunday Republican -- "A Recent Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Two long paragraphs quote the account of a London correspondent of a New York paper; differs in interesting details from interview in New York Herald (item 132)" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-07-25">July 25, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0c93c50799d31a350e9ee80d91976594" level="file"><did><unittitle>Review of Reviews -- "Mark Twain Character Sketch" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-08">August, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1430207d4b0253dd29ec7af351cf592a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vienna News Freie Press -- "Ein Besuch Fei Mark Twain" -- "Clemens expresses his interest in Austria, declares he will be slow to make judgments about it, and discusses the naming of his book of travel" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-10-01">October 1, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_46fcc62a9fbda49cdd2a331e0b6d62a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Russian Interview with Mark Twain -- Odesski Novosti </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-10-09">October 9, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7f2a50ddce93217739700e95caf1e1be" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain in Vienna" -- "Basically a story on Clemens personal popularity in Vienna, a quoted comment on the uproar in the Reichsrath" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-12-13">December 13, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_441db2b8593f88a5535c64179ddc4250" level="file"><did><unittitle>Illustrated Zeitung -- "Mark Twain" -- " J.B.C. Kinch calls this an interview; but her precis makes this sound like an article and my own rough-reading indicates a non-interview" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1897-12-23">December 23, 1897</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f12f496c6ff90cedb1af0c517a2205e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Proud and Happy/That's the way it Feels, He Says, to Be out of Debt--Longing for Home" -- "Brief; Clemens insists he is not a bad businessman" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1898-03-13">March 13, 1898</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_985483f43fc3fc1160d5c5c6f1787e52" level="file"><did><unittitle>(Budapest) Magyar Hirlap -- "S.H. in Budapest" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-03-24">March 24, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5a21b9fd18202a89d52ba7a4b7dddcfa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Budapest Pesti Naplo -- "With Mark Twain from Galatia to Budapest" (With Negatives</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-03-24">March 24, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ff3c8aab334b8067a3e0bef569151d57" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Times -- "Mark Twain Bequest" -- "Clemens discusses his work on a book of portraits of persons he has known: candid and not primarily humorous, it will not be published for a hundred years" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-05-23">May 23, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8fd317f42aa1c035c424a0461f8ec145" level="file"><did><unittitle>Visit with Emperor </unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-05-25">May 25, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4a650713ca312fa20cf4eb347c5c5a07" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mark Twain and Vienna -- "Farewell" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-05-26/1899-05-27">May 26, 1899 - May 27, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_409dfc810d1a775bb40e9f240a842c29" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Chronicle -- "Mark Twain in London/He Talks of His Visit and His Doomsday Book/Vienna and the Emperor/The Tragedy of the Speech Done in German/Anglo-American Union" -- "Clemens discusses the collected edition of his his writings, in preparation, and his current writing (the autobiography, perhaps); ends with friendly comments on British-American solidarity</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-06-03">June 3, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_56b8adb42f628c6a8a001035cb4dc752" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stenholm Aftonbladet -- "Mark Twain" -- "Clemens at Sana; Clemens jokes about the climate, Cook's mismanagement of his baggage, his excellent health, his indefinite literary plans, the curious abundance of American flies in Sweden, and Anglo-American friendship as the bulwark against Russian expansionism" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-07-13">July 13, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a928cd8e663827d35cea9543a9052b3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Buffalo Express -- "Mark Twain Talks: That Book for Year 1999" -- "Long, solid item; Clemens says much about his book of portraits of contemporaries that he will withhold from publication in his lifetime" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1899-07-30">July 30, 1899</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_36c3da33fddba82ff506cfaf5b8d94d9" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Says He's Discouraged/Every Sort of Crank except Himself Has a Presidential Following/Is Advised to Withdraw But He Thinks it Unnecessary..." -- "Clemens jokes about running for the presidency; declares that when he returns home, he will stay" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-06-17">June 17, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f885b1ae0ae6197fbf0b6a2bfd81421b" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain Returns After Nine Years" -- "Clemens berates the beds in British hotels but makes firm statement for Anglo-American unity" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-04">October 4, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_334c2afacf7dfe2629182e9e25b65ce1" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Twain on the Sea, Glad to Start Home/At Work on Reminiscences to Be Published One Hundred Years After He Dies, He Writes Freely/Imperialism Stumps Him/Doesn't Understand How it is That We Are Fighting the Filipinos, Whom We Were to Set Free, He Supposed" -- "Essentially a shorter version of interview in New York World of 14 October 1900" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-07">October 7, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1d081a3b053f3f3addfd71865e9d4412" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain, the Greatest American Humorist,  Returning Home, Talks at Length to the World/He Likes to Dine Out/For That Reason London Has Proved a Delightful Place of Residence/We've No Business in China/Nor Can He Understand on Just what Principles We Are Proceeding in the Philippines" -- "Clemens comments on Holy Land trip and on working for San Francisco Call" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-14">October 14, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7b82812a3625af39df1954e6c5a56800" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Tribune -- "Mark Twain in America Again/Humorist Home After His Nine Years of Wandering in Distant Lands/Talks of the Future/Although an Anti-Imperialist He Says He Prefers McKinley to W.J. Bryan/Important Work Ahead" -- "One of the more compact interviews on this occasion" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5dd9a7eb1eabc6459fe2d12b4b40fc01" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening Seen -- "Mark Twain Home Again/Hale and Happy at 65--His Book of 100 Years After" -- "Touches on several subjects, none in more detail than in other interviews of same date" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_805d869c6a26c8fd4f1a89826b96ffe2" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald and Evening Telegram -- "Mark Twain Home, An Anti-Imperialist/Views of the Author Changed During His Long Travels in Foreign Elands, but He Will Not Support Bryan/Notes of the Author's Trip Around the Globe" -- "Very long item; Clemens comments on his reputation for truth, world and domestic politics, experiences during his world tour, and plans for writing" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8bcb5e3bbbed9a34fa3af634727d2394" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Press -- "Mark Twain Wants to be President/Humorist Arrives Home After Nine Years Abroad" -- "Stress on political opinions" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f14d11e234b8f2def9505a7979bf49c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Mark Twain Home Again/He Went Away with a Load of Debt Which He Voluntarily Assumed, and Has Paid It all Off--He Will Not Lecture Again, He Says, Unless He Is Compelled To" -- "Clemens announces his anti-imperialism, discusses paying off his creditors" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_be3fdf8a8bb3b1f254209c7b01027d40" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Tribune -- "Mark Twain Home/Arrives in Minnehaha with Wife and Daughters" -- "One of better versions, both for substance and coherence; Clemens discusses current politics, his literary plans, and his immediate future, and reviews his travels since 1891" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fc1b964e8b9b13eed995241273e82dc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Home Again Hale and Happy at 65/After Nine Years Abroad, He Declares That He Will Break Both Legs, So That He Cannot Leave America Again--To Winter in New York" -- "Shorter, much less political than other interviews" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f22c54d856878e77d32a97cf716141b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Mail and Express -- "Mark Twain Talks/Says His Chief Desire Is Not to Be Told to Move On" -- "Clemens says most about being a mugwump" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1aaf7ec2442c35fd2148f57dcac702c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain Home Again/Talks Freely of His Travels, His Experiences, and His Triumphs--In the Best of Health" -- "Clemens has much to say on politics and gives details of his visit to Jameson Raiders" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-16">October 16, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_79b8101c2d6eec55a1f9d081425c957b" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "My Impressions of America/And Kate Carew's Impressions of the Great Humorist/An Interview in Which He Refuses to Be Interviewed/Eluding the Subject Proposed, He Talks About Almost Everything Else, Including Truth, Waiters, Early breakfasts, Wisdom and Noise" -- Clemens was submitting to being sketched rather than interviewed and said little of consequence" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-21">October 21, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e3feec9a88317cf93f5674fe87abd617" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Wouldn't Work 30 Minutes for 500 Dollars/Declares That He Only Does Work When It Is an Absolute Necessity" -- "Clemens declines to cover a Bryan mass meeting for the WORLD" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-21">October 21, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_03252ed5a82204d9e4b2d73a4c1f683c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hartford Current -- "What Mr. Clemens Said/His Grief at News of Mr. Warner's Death/Old Days Recalled/Humorist's Plans" -- "Clemens also praises Plasmon and asks about Connecticut politics" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-10-26">October 26, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9defa54a672d91feddaa4e0aea4f9c17" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Journal and Advertiser -- "A Day with Mark Twain/Funniest Man in the World/Pictorially Told by Vivid Snap Shots at America's Famous Humorist" -- "Clemens explains why he has decided to shun serious interviews; comments on unrelated matters, with most about his visit to the jail in Pretoria (possibly a pastiche of other interviews)" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-11-11">November 11, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7c5a9d68eafdc92ecfac887c3deb79fd" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Sure Mark Twain is in a Crooked Game/Housekeeper who did No. 14 East on Tenth Street Annoyed by Inquiries for Him/He's at No. 14 West" -- "Clemens, while commenting on a housekeeper who did not recognize either of his names, insists that he cannot afford to talk to the press free of charge" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-11-12">November 12, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0746c16bd454a70221b052e70eae00d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain at Football Game" -- "Clemens attends Yale-Princeton game and makes a few spectator's remarks" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-11-18">November 18, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_01e7105a538927a7b1af9d2a5f2206e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times Sun, Tribune, World -- "Mark Twain is Avenged/One False/Cabby Learns the Power of His Wrath" -- "Not an interview but a long and interesting report of Clemens appearing in magistrate's court in New York City to press a complaint against a cabman who had overcharged his housekeeper" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1900-11-23">November 23, 1900</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6604c2b1aa87a1e90ea7e2f567a7f226" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain in His New York Den" -- "A combination feature-story interview, with many photographs; Clemens comments mostly on persons appealing for money criticizes grand opera" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-01-20">January 20, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dd1906ae6ebba57a03f097ead1c7ddfc" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain Hazing/Calls West Point Cadets Who Indulge in It Cowards" -- "Clemens speaks out briefly against hazing and adds a reminiscence about his boyhood fights" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-01-20">January 20, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1537ae393ecb73af6e3f17b2c934cfc4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Journal and Advertiser, New York Times -- "Mark Twain/Expert on Trade Marks/Has Fun/Says They Won't Let Me talk, He Testifies in a Suit of Rudyard Kipling's about Copyright" -- "Clemens answers some questions on copyrights as an expert, in a hearing before a United States Commissioner" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-03-14">March 14, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2c348bf7c0e714b93a22afd999d7b248" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain in the Woods" -- "Clemens at Lake Saranac, refuses to be quoted on any serious subject; much description and photographs of his summer house" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-07-21">July 21, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5a2783f75cdc040b2f861a825c94f5a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Journal and Advertiser -- "Mark Twain Offers to Vote for Satin" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-10-09">October 9, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1502e96f5c56b441f73b31e386a4b73d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN, New York Journal -- "Mark Twain will Warmly Great Robbers/Riverdale Burglar-Ridden" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-10-11">October 11, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8383ceec38892804531294553de4caea" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald, Baltimore SUN -- "Sh-hhh Says Mark Twain" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">1901-10-14 &amp;1901-10-19</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_73b4df96e9749f7793f59b46bda5077c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Tribune , New York SUN -- "Mark Twain Would Be a Bill Poster" -- "Actually a news story, quite possibly planted; Clemens appears at anti-Tammany headquarters and wants to go out pasting up political posters; he jeers at Tammany tactics and candidates" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1901-10-31">October 31, 1901</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f733f36feb587d9f050f58cc15d4ae63" level="file"><did><unittitle>San Francisco Examiner -- "Mark Twain Says it's All Rubbish/College Education is Not Essential to the Making of a Gentleman" -- "Actually a statement or press release; Clemens rejects view that the new millionaires, if they have not been to college, can be gentlemen"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-03-10">March 10, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_74b159d55b47ed87a546c1ea09df9d41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Charleston Sunday News -- "Tom Reed and Mark Twain/Mark Twain in Town/ Mark Twain with a Julep" -- "No direct quotation but extensive summary on Mark Twain's remark: praise for Charleston Exploration" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-04-06">April 6, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f84b1c16777a3a98c32b3577d785c704" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- "Mark Twain Here as Saint Louis' Guest for the First Time Since 1861" -- "Long, loose item; Clemens comments on Bret Harte and on piloting career, recalls in detail the Punch, Brothers, Punch jingle and the heap pipe presented to him in Virginia City" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-05-29">May 29, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_81eccab2b63ae1ed7871cdbc2a4770d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Star -- "Mark Twain Laughs in Grain Pits" -- "Clemens speaks at Merchants Exchange, then chats in hotel lobby about his health and laziness and discusses river traffic with Horace Bixby" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-05-29">May 29, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_106213741b93af898cd0d4c4ab4a90f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- "Mark Twain's Visit to Hannibal" -- "Part feature story, part interview; Clemens reminisces about old friends on the river and other Missourians" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-05-30/1902-05-31">May 30, 1902 - May 31, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fb488d2172e4dfd8b453370109cda16b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Republic -- "Mark Twain Comes Back to Missouri/Affection of Old Friends Brings Mark Twain to Tears/Reminiscences of Humorist/Mark Twain Visits His Old Sweetheart/Mark Twain Guest of President Jesse/Mark Twain's Reunion/Mark Twain at Pilot Wheel;  Bids Farewell to Mississippi </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">May 30-31, 1902 &amp; June 8-9, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_169ebf721087134d4df6f59108e45353" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- "Mark Twain Takes a Drive/Tom Sawyer Character in Hannibal" -- "Clemens comments to old acquaintances and reminisces casually; comments on local traditions about who were the originals for some of his characters" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-06-02">June 2, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_af890dc9ff38131a04da293f8adcbaa0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- "Mark Twain Takes a Drive/Tom Sawyer Character in Hannibal" -- "Clemens comments to old acquaintances and reminisces casually; comments on local traditions about who were the originals for some of his characters" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-06-03">June 3, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_16978c52136fece85e0b7e21b8fa4596" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hannibal Morning Journal -- "Mark Twain Going Home" -- "Mostly news story but summarizes a 30 minute conversation when the reporter found Mark Twain lying in bed puffing away on a black cigar and with a book in his hand" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-06-03">June 3, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_95fd2e165e33ca88e08a8790fa83078a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Star, Saint Louis Globe-Democrat -- "Mark Twain at Wheel Again" -- "Clemens chats casually about river traffic, past and present</unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-06-06/1902-06-07">June 6, 1902 - June 7, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fb05b57f1f5dd1092dffcd9d5c0f8e25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Saint Louis Post-Dispatch -- Mark Twain at Smoke Talk/Twain at Helm of Harbor Book/Mark Twain's Visit Over" -- "Clemens comments casually on events of current visit, and his taste in cigars, and he tells an anecdote about his and W.D. Howells' interest in a pretty pedestrian" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-06-06/1902-06-08">June 6, 1902 - June 8, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2d0cb41b10bf2dae0c72a52db1d5e23c" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Hannibal Evening Courier-Post -- "Mark Twain" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-06-06">June 6, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a71fadf6cca0f222890ca34d010c6c26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cassell's Magazine -- "A Day with Mark Twain" -- "Not identical with piece in New York World, 21 July 1901, but based on same visit; really a feature story with no quotations of consequence" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-07">July, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_57e58c1bc306ecf187a89ae1d81f0162" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "My First Vacation and My Last" -- "Free ranging item; some yarn-spinning reminiscences; Clemens mentions his work on a new novel" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-09-07">September 7, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_71f80895d8cd1e77959b59f74be8e82d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening Journal -- "Mark Twain: Study of an American Who Has Interested and Amused 50,000,000 People by His Wit/Mark Twain: His Wit and Humor" -- "Reporter comes along with Homer Davenport, for a full page spread of words and pictures; Mark Twain makes some interesting comments about fossils and about Monte Carlo" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1902-12-20">December 20, 1902</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_646362c9371106c722f83a570773cd9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Men of To-Day Who Make the World Laugh" -- "Mark Twain repudiates the interview that accompanied the Homer Davenport visit of December 1902; that is, he says he had not expected a report on the conversation to appear; refuses to be interviewed, commenting at some length on idea that writers, unlike politicians, should be paid for interviews, which use up their stock in trade" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-04-13">April 13, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f54a57c8251c112e8f7d4da300cee0e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain's Door Open to Burglars" -- "Frothy comment on his respect for successful burglars" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-06-15">June 15, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9053fc9b793cd0e428bdefaff98c6bd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain on the Yacht Races" -- "Actually written by Clemens; he clowns about his knowledge of yachting and about how he has adapted his style to being paid by the word" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-08-30">August 30, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7ef2a763eb6e11b7c0a978aa89765966" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening Journal -- "Mark Twain Off Shooting Shafts of Humor" -- "By far the longest of the items for this occasion; reporter picked up Mark Twain at the hotel and stayed close; Mark Twain talks about Dowie and also about Henry Lucy--OBITUARY scheme; also comments on the comparison of him to Aristophanes and Rabelais" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-10-24">October 24, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_075257302ec26456fe7b47209b7bad2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald, SUN, Times, Review -- "Mark Twain Makes Some Parting Remarks/Comments on Aristophanes, Rabelais, Dowse, and Mrs. Eddy"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-10-25">October 25, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ff91ad5ab1c38c43cd3da83c97e85daf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ladies Home Journal -- "Mark Twain's Pictures/Three Famous Authors" -- "Mark Twain, W.D. Howells, and Henry Van Dyke; three photos of Mark Twain with a sentence or two commentary each; two of the photos get further, quoted commentary, photos taken at Quarry Farm; not really an interview but list because of R. Willis comment""</unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-11">November, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e150b0a26ebacfecc2747e1ae5221e42" level="file"><did><unittitle>Courier Della Sera -- "Italian Accounts of Mark Twain Aboard and at Home: An Interview and a Visit" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1903-11-12">November 12, 1903</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_74485e03222c204386fb1120dccc3215" level="file"><did><unittitle>Metropolitan Magazine -- "An Interview with Mark Twain" -- "Author is very obtrusive and indeed features her own opinions and anecdotes; item is finally of no consequence" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1904-03">March, 1904</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2fd32263c46b7b9afe908bd0e03ef2f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Sketch -- "Mark Twain on the Law of Copyright" -- "Clemens also comments, briefly, on Italians, Mary Baker Eddy, and mass opinion" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1904-03-30">March 30, 1904</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_feeae2b9aadca6fd2a11ac1b883a7c92" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain to Reform the Language of Italy" -- "A very coherent; covers Italy and Italian, Clemens's reading" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1904-04-10">April 10, 1904</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2c54f95835fc980aaa8d2bcb5011f085" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "A Talk with Mark Twain's Cat/The Owner Himself Being Invisible" -- "Reporter fails to get to see Clemens" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-04-09">April 9, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_827985f7d4787261ddb37cc7bf300d86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Herald -- "The Same Old Mark Twain" -- "Long and coherent; but stresses copyright and color of Mark Twain's personality while recording same main subjects as other accounts" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-06">November 6, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_75dd96daecd63c40a5ce9f1b09c22ff6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Globe -- "In Genial Mood/Mark Twain Talks on Various Topics" -- "Long, coherent item; main subjects are copyright, political and business corruption in United States, Imperialism in the Congo and South Africa, and Czarist Tyranny"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-06">November 6, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_419da9302a3beeb6345d106e381502c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Evening Transcript -- "Mark Twain Talks on 'Graft'" -- "After remarks on copyright and imperialism in South Africa, Clemens talks at length about current corruption and places its source in post-bellum speculation"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-06">November 6, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_73a6e976b26708c48743430c6040975f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Journal -- "Mark Twain, Between Puffs, Talks Some" -- "Relaxed commentary by Clemens on copyright law, atrocities in the Congo, tyranny in czarist Russia, and the insurance scandal" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-06">November 6, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e205c45a84e6b013bb92e4ec0acdd960" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hartford Courant -- "Mark Twain at 70/He discusses Summer Homes and His Work" -- "Clemens wrote out the quoted parts; he details his liking for Dublin, New Hampshire, as a summer retreat and briefly mentions what pieces of writing he has worked on lately" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-25">November 25, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6fb5d022ef86798efc84dd40bcc139b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain on Summer Homes" -- "Quoted parts identical with Hartford Courant of 25 November and New York American and Journal of 26 November" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-26">November 26, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_535bfa057cb351ee06eff55dffe56ca7" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World Sunday Magazine -- "What I am Thankful For" -- "Prearranged interview; long; dependable; Clemens discusses his dyspepsia, his habit of non-exercise, his self-editing, and (briefly) the use of humor; then launches into long, rehearsed diatribe against Leopold" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-26">November 26, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_acb45c65946ca073ce8c1b94b68fe748" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain: A Humorist's Confession/On the Eve of His 70th Birth Anniversary, He Admits He Never Did a Day's Work" -- "Clemens discusses play v. work, his reputation and seriousness as a humorist, and national differences in humor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-26">November 26, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_680c248b1f0b0f8295af1fff752bab5f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Seattle (Washington) Star -- "Samuel L. Clemens Interviews the Great Humorist, Mark Twain" -- "Clemens humorously discusses photographs and other representations of himself, wishes them to be kinder; plugs Peter Pan" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1905-11-30">November 30, 1905</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8147375e182c67136e977a70319cc306" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Samuel Clemens's in Washington, D.C./Congress Admires Mark Twain's Hair" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-01-30">January 30, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_28cd3afc267765145a7639bbc995741c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain in Moving Pictures" -- "Comic photographs of Clemens with some captions presumably suggested by him" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-02-04">February 4, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f7464b3112c2a8af34c79bd2f3e2268c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hartford Courant -- "Mark Twain Pays Tribute to Servant" -- "Series of laudatory remarks about the deceased" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-02-28">February 28, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7669bbd22a80a08c74c00c7cd089a2c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain Too Lazy for a United States Senator" -- "Clemens humorously rejects notion that he might be a senator; feels he would not be taken seriously" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-03-11">March 11, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a90fb431395bc6d02b210a234b394103" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American and Journal -- "Huckleberry Finn's End Disappoints Mark Twain" -- "Clemens comments quizzically on the many persons over the years who have claimed to be the models for Tom and Huck" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-03-18">March 18, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fa4bd5dc89519c65c188e748abfc0f6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN, Tribune, World -- "Mark Twain on Gorky Affair/Gorky Visit/Hotels Turn Gorky Away" -- "In part or whole, probably written answers by Clemens to reporters' questions about Maxim Gorky scandal" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-04-15">April 15, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_386c81b712809c177d2e9f61d49a5a1d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times and Tribune -- "Mark Twain Appeal for San Francisco/Mark Twain's Memories of the City" -- "After appeal from platform for aid to victims of San Francisco earthquake, Clemens gives reporters an anecdote about a small quake he once experienced" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-04-20">April 20, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1c8205e78d486a4ac4c8448ac8bb762a" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening Journal -- "Mark Twain Helps to Open the Day and Night Bank in NYC" -- "Mark Twain is among those who make deposits in the new Day and Night Bank, Mark Twain said he could deposit money there if he felt like it, but he decided not to do it for fear of exciting the envy of other authors. Mark Twain said it was a fine sign of prosperity when the town had to keep a bank going night and day" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-05-01">May 1, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e674612e1de7901446a5e3c07415eb37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Human Life -- "Mark Twain Dean of Our Humorists" -- "Evidently talked with Clemens lately, when he returned for funeral of Patrick McAleer; has a few brief quoted comments; also has some local anecdotes and reminiscence of his own" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-05">May, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_773dbee28ad0f980c4d4f0c65669ace3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Sunday Post -- "Walks Around the Hudson" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-05-20">May 20, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7981da0ad2c8d9b8bcf5da695c91f022" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Chattanooga Times -- "Polk Miller's Visit to Mark Twain" -- "Entertainer famous for his Old Times Down South program reports recent session of reminiscence with Clemens about antebellum and plantation days" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-07-07">July 7, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d31192daa10681ba271fcd646f585027" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American -- "Twain Would Like to Dress Like Adam" -- "Clemens jokes at length about men's clothing and fashions" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-08">December 8, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e67b6d3fe89236f1a88d351fba30f4e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "An Advocate of Dress Reform" -- "Clemens drolls on at length about clothing" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-08">December 8, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f29fb99e2520e10bab1ef636a271b536" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington (D.C.) Post -- "Twain's Fancy Suit" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-08">December 8, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b72d62531781db6116c5e45d4e1225c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington Evening Star, Washington Herald -- 'Mark Twain in White/Twain Awes Capitol" -- "Much joking about clothes; Clemens is sardonic about a library banning 'Eve's Diary'; brief comment on several current political matters; firm plea for renewal of copyrights" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-08">December 8, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_542f80c0e62bc6ccda1f2412f75bfa5d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN, Tribune, World, Herald -- "Dress Uniform and Copyright" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-08">December 8, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a2c0145cb394b1b85396738f20c3484a" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Twain's Plan to Beat Copyright Law" -- "Solid interesting item, though Clemens must have stipulated there be no quoting; gives details of his intention to renew in effect the copyright of his books by adding relevant portions of autobiography to them" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-12">December 12, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c70f96c99f39c9104ee65fcb33f114e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington (D.C.) Post -- "Heard at the Capitol" -- "Clemens offers departing judgments on how the fight for extending the term of copyright should be conducted" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-12">December 12, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_412ebf3f89fd9bdbe30ce66a3e9b49a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Actually in Earnest" -- "A statement obtained by Ervin Justice; Clemens feels that his white suit and his joking detracted from the serious point of his visit to Washington; argues against 42-year limit for copyright" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-16">December 16, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2d7898b958da52ba326c6a844510a102" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Twain and the Telephone" -- "Clemens praises the telharmonium and reminisces about his early use of the telephone and his habit of using profanity" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1906-12-23">December 23, 1906</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5b0010bf116ebbb508a014ca48cb20e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, Herald, Times, Tribune, World: Bermuda Colonist -- "New Year’s Eve Party" -- "Comments on New York State politics" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-01-01">January 1, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c7dd36e5c79674b428e6c9cc951a3899" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald, New York Tribune, New York Times -- "Mark Twain Back from Bermuda" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-01-10">January 10, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_33255081334cfb346573921fbab4bc7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "For the Longfellow Century/Tributes to Poet by Men of Letters/Mark Twain Tells of His Visits" -- "Clemens recalls contacts with him in 1870s" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-02-24">February 24, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ebcf7648f1370ebb937e49bf11b5ec50" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Mark Twain Sails South" -- "Brief; Clemens gives humorous reasons for going to Bermuda" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-03-17">March 17, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a011e1553da3054c483ab5df747c1c68" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain's Wanderings at an End" -- "Long item; mostly history by the reporter but has some quotation; Mark Twain comments on some of his homes briefly; more unimportant, amends three or four famous anecdotes about him" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-03-31">March 31, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_703aa7880d47c0c2636a82d6e9c7396b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Elmira Daily Advertiser -- "Mark Twain in Elmira" -- "Not a substantial item; Clemens resists being interviewed but finally relents to help out cub reporter; then he gives a boost to the progress for Elmira talk going around and especially to the organ manufacturing company" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-04-04">April 4, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f3168cb49933d54b59ddef2770a329bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American -- "Mark Twain is Going to be a Buccaneer" -- "Interesting item; Mark Twain defends his plan to go down to Jamestown for a naval review, along with Rogers; comments cynically on the Peace Congress just completed at Carnegie Hall, i.e., is not very sanguine about the prospects for peace and pacifism" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-04-23">April 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a85eef48a3a3136a758eeae32589d2e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Norfolk Ledger-Dispatch -- "Marooned Mark Twain" -- "Clemens explains why he is waiting to go back to New York City alone by yacht rather than by train" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-01">May 1, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d4f4069fb1348710dd57afd7546e64fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, SUN, Times, Tribune, World -- "Twain Hesitates to Admit He's Dead" -- "Clemens chaffs about report that he has been drown at sea" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-05">May 5, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0318ebb7909bdbb7ff7c11d18fcd5a2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore American -- "Mark Twain at Annapolis/Mark Twain an Honored Guest" -- "Clemens chatted ten minutes between trains about recent report he had drowned, praised Southern cooking, joked about wearing ribbon of Legion of Honor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-10">May 10, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_58d9b8e84343b1c9209e26acc68821ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore News -- "Mark Twain Tells His Literary Secret and Many Other Things" -- "Fine item; long and much quotation; on his autobiography in progress; on seriousness of his work; on paying off the Webster debt; on his five works that he will leave unfinished; long attack on German, American, and British imperialism" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-10">May 10, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_18f56ab70a7e68cf7558d9ff1ff6d148" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore SUN -- "Mark Twain in Clover" -- "Reporters on hand at railroad station; long, useful item; mixture of superficiality and comments on purchase of Philippine Islands, the Belgian Congo, his autobiography, disfranchising the Negara, and his white suit" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-10">May 10, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d33090220f5a94900d5216ada8522a53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore American -- "As Mark Twain Watched the Drill" -- "Reporter followed Clemens around and got his opinions on interviewing, on his smoking, on mugwumps, and on Peace Congress; technically not an interview but worthwhile and appropriate" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-11">May 11, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9baffe427b5602e4088c0ed77779de55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore SUN, New York Tribune -- "Mark Twain Departs/Mark Twain at Annapolis" -- "Clemens comments on his background as a journalist, how characters such as Huck and Tom are created, 'Eve's Diary', and an admitting poem about his serious side" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-12">May 12, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c677e704f5e0aa6c9ed9600dc1b826e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mighty Mark Twain Over-Awes Marines" -- "Datelined Annapolis; probably report of a lecture; filled with familiar anecdotes" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-12">May 12, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_843ebcdf9f7fe860c7abaa7def3dd11f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American -- "Mark Twain Tells the Secrets of Novelists" -- "Clemens contends that books and characters tend to find their own line of development once the author has conceived them and started to write" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-05-26">May 26, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a6a14845fb61a4db5ec37a20ce428103" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, Times -- "Mark Twain Sails/Shiest Man Aboard/Humorist Takes His Last Trip to London from this Sphere" -- "Clemens discusses the autobiography he is writing but will hold back from publication; chats at length about his autobiography, which will create a sensation when it is eventually published after his death" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-09">June 9, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_93daac704b7920b3e2f89a7a5e716739" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Evening News -- "Arrival of Mark Twain/Collecting Hints for His Funeral Procession" -- "Clemens chaffs a great deal on minor matters" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-18">June 18, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2d9967e35bc5a45c16beeb5be46e41d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Westminster Gazette -- "Mark Twain in London" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-18">June 18, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_28d8c0f124a39ec9099778b1dfc89483" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily Chronicle -- "Mark Twain/Mr. Clemens's Arrives in England" -- "Clemens jokes about many subjects including himself" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_49bc621315d171388cdc3a3ad223e9f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>London -- "G.B.S. and Mark Twain: First Greeting of Two Great Men/Mark Twain in London/Mark Twain Arrives from America/The American Humorist in London" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-18/1907-06-19">June 18, 1907 - June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c9bbb3152affaea54b53fdc5701db5ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily Express -- "Mark Twain in London/Wants Hints for his Funeral from Oxford Pageant/A Bright Lad" -- Interviewer lists twelve subjects that Clemens touched on and then mentions others, especially the funeral" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b9e0803477e9622edd6e8cd3a86c7637" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily Mail -- "Edgar Wallace/Mark Twain in London" -- "Attempts jocosity in Clemens's vein of humor about his funeral, his use of Italian, and his white suits" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_f582d40d8b9c1f4f81c6a5912c85854b" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily Mirror -- "Mark Twain Reaches England" -- "Clemens jokes about his funeral and Kipling" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b9beb201b8b56f0e140d3fcf4e8cf494" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Morning Leader -- "Mark Twain an the Secrets of Youth/In England to Receive Oxford Honor/Chaffs Interview and Himself" -- "Much joking , especially about his funeral, his ancestry, and his white suits" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8f144fdea725f727e78f5cfb6e238fbd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manchester Dispatch -- "Mark Twain's Quest/Looking for Ideas for His Funerals/Meeting with G.B.S." -- "May be by W.B. Northrop; nothing unusual in the content; relative to the many other accounts of the occasion</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2391734dad08e95ff1941849701f3dce" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN and New York Times, Chicago Inter-Ocean -- "Mark Twain Tells Sea Tales" -- "Clemens jokes in high spirits about the voyage over to England" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b1bd834809b31723335ba98b5b773540" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald, World, Saint Louis Globe-Democrat -- "Mark Twain in London/Meets Mr. Bernard Shaw" -- "Mark Twain jokes with G.B. Shaw and winks at reporters; then comically outlines his daily routine" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-19">June 19, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_003537d10e37b15a505308f56d33fa4f" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Evening News -- "Mark Twain at Windsor/To Be One of the Guests of the King" -- "Clemens gives anecdote about the King; outlines his social schedule" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-20">June 20, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cda7bd8214a60f916354053e2a31ee44" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily Mail -- E.W. "Mark Twain's Plans/To Meet the King To-Morrow" -- "Summary of a drifting conversation with banquets and Clemens's funeral as the uppermost subjects" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-21">June 21, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_eab1325585ebafb67fe29e1d029b96d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American -- "Mark Twain Again Meets His Former Chum Edward/Renew Acquaintance with the King, Which He Started Years Ago on a Bus" -- "Clemens reminisces about meeting King Edward ten years ago at Hamburg; makes statement after the garden party at Windsor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-23">June 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6fc3064f216a3fc9c17d25e7fbaa2daf" level="file"><did><unittitle>London -- "Mark Twain's Statement in Windsor Garden Party" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-24">June 24, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e66a92f8191b9f6979ff8124185881ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Evening News -- "Mark's 'Mots'/Plans and Patents a Joke for the 'Punch' Dinner" -- "No direct quotations; Clemens muses about his immediate engagements" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-24">June 24, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d4ef7963351e1a1fb345e0e8f6653552" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Leader -- "Mark Twain Meets King Edward/And Describes the Royal Garden Party" -- "Clemens jokes about heaven, bright clothes, napping, and his white bathrobe" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-24">June 24, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_072d845223c474895ce09748e1df9734" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily News -- "Oxford Pageant/What Mark Twain Thought" -- "Clemens praises the pageants" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-28">June 28, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d508076a9480b36f56f742afba9e9ddf" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain Living Up to His Degree/Honor Conferred upon Him/By Oxford Seems to Have Sobered Him/Is Excessively Solemn/Says England's Welcome Has Impressed Him Greatly--Calls Ceremony at Oxford Beautiful" -- "Clemens is on these good behavior" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-06-30">June 30, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a3d6319b1e2ddc78f915f9581017b95a" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Mark Twain for Penny Post" -- "A long, genuine item that Clemens probably planned for;  is for lower international postal rates; introduces humorous, probably fanciful autobiography about how he used to embezzle money that father gave him for stamps" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-02">July 2, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8403def49f1773504dc4a6020cef2ea4" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily Chronicle -- "Mark Twain/Confession Made by His Own Fireside"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-02">July 2, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2789f9b34dfb9851ac0bf6a89d00505d" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Daily News -- "Sleepy, But Happy/Mark Twain's Regretful Farewell" -- "Mark Twain makes  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-12">July 12, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3a91675811fadc31fea30688b712a368" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World, New York Times -- "Mark Twain  Moved to Postpone Funeral/Younger Now By 7 Years, He Says, and Changes Mind about Dying" -- "Clemens briefly waxes enthusiastic about his current visit to England" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-13">July 13, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_996b4bc1d4cb45e683648fd0315d7153" level="file"><did><unittitle>London Morning Leader, London Tribune -- "Two Mark Twains/One of them Leave England/Mark Twain's Farewell" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-13/1907-07-16">July 13, 1907 - July 16, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e552c36b14e3d6712ab5bfa1921399a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening World -- "English Know a Joke/Mark Twain's Wireless Message from the Sea/Reports that His Ship Tore Off the Bowsprit of an Unknown Bark in the Fog" -- "Clemens comments briefly on a number of topics including the British sense of humor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-22">July 22, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_57f90b9b98ae1592aa4a019aa2cbcfb8" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American -- "Twain Home with English Jokes at 30 Cents a Word" -- "Much chaffing about the Ascot cup; Clemens defends British sense of humor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_50fc2775e4d1d379f4852337d1a7998a" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald -- "Dr. Mark Twain, Pelted, Home Again" -- "Clemens jokes about his visit to England and the return voyage" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b33983bbf370da71f5b7280e0a6e615e" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York SUN -- "Mark Twain Comes in White" -- "Clemens comments on recent stories about his English visit; chaffs about old age and his new rate for 'stories and jokes'" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2d0c9448f67f4cbb1269a4a2eba35e01" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Times -- "Mark Twain Home in Good Humor" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2c4819beda47fea8929d1079e4a34f78" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Tribune -- "Twain Glad He's Back" -- "Somewhat fewer quotations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ff8eb14ece94ec25ec2961a9e20d4d2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening World -- "Mark Twain Recalls Happy Days in Fresco" -- "Clemens briefly recalls 'dear, dead Bohemian days of long ago'" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e34e44e631e5db0f00e4c315c7c1149c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Home, Captive of Little Girl" -- "Story devotes much space to young fellow-passenger Dorothy Quick" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-07-23">July 23, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6d00828993837c01e9e5cb12558dcf75" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "My Hand Interviews with Mark Twain and Thomas Edison"  -- "Clemens submits to having his palm read; in a mellow mood he comments on current situation and age" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-08-25">August 25, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dd47c098ec025f5c414c8da268b32bd0" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Press -- "Mark Twain's Ideal Pipe" -- "Quoted from 'an interview the other day' seems genuine; not important but characteristic"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-09-15">September 15, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_940da19d1932f9de57005e36735c5d2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Great Thoughts -- "A Prince of Humorists" -- "Long with much padding, many passages that may well come from Mark Twain's writings and commentary"  </unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-10-05">October 5, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cce99869c7aec71d36d96f6b0c777b67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brooklyn Daily Eagle -- "Mark Twain on the Scope of the Children's Theater/What it Means to American Citizenship and Education" -- "Besides praising East Side theater for children, Clemens talks about the importance of enunciation, and of raising esthetic taste among immigrants; he also discourses on responsible citizenship vs. jingoistic patriotism</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907-11-24">November 24, 1907</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2dad1443e4389152b0c49b0d7b271e44" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, SUN, Times, World, Tribune -- "Rogers is Busted--Twain" -- "Clemens jokes broadly about supposed poverty of H.H. Rogers" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1908-02-23">February 23, 1908</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c3dc6f07606077a3b7ece03b8c582b18" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, New York Herald, SUN, Times, World -- "Return from Bermuda/Mark Twain Faced Two Perils/Going to Make Less Noise/Mark Twain Gets a Sea Souse/Back from Bermuda with H.H. Rogers/Big Wave Loan to Rogers" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1908-04-14">April 14, 1908</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b88994e9bb89f23fe43d465e1e5eb3ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American -- "Twain Says He Told Her 'Book a Mistake Twain's Daughter Talks About Him'" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">1908-09-27, 1908-06-03</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_93730dc955194ab31d3a10f99ce00ec1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Boston Herald -- "Death of Roger/Mark Twain, Rockefeller, and Others Pay Tribute to Dead" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-05-19/1909-05-20">May 19, 1909 - May 20, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6539d462d73736f0e7940db484ae6077" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore News -- "Twain Puts Blame  on the Typesetter" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-06-10">June 10, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e6a0e042b6a088367abaa6245dd1ac0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore Star -- "Twain Pokes Fun at Union Station and Pities City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-06-11">June 11, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d33d282c84b8bf7ed433d9deaf0ad57c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baltimore American -- "Why Not Baltimore?" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-06-12">June 12, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a9defa96ad27c5dae3cf6058cb07685f" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, Danbury News(?) -- "Mark Twain Has a Tobacco Heart/Mark Twain Cited for Awful Tobacco Habit/Mark Twain Smokes/The Psychology of the Tobacco Habit/Two Uncollected Twain Writings Found in British-Authored Books" -- "Clemens grumbles a little about interviewers but talks almost solely about his doctor's orders to reduce smoking and about the criticism of his having smoking while waiting for the Oxford ceremony" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-08-03">August 3, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3b752810c3fbd26c1d8706b7306ea9a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World , New York Tribune -- "Samuel Clemens Interviews Himself at Clara's Wedding/Mark Twain Prepares Interview and Sketches Guest </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-10">October, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_5a0a206d1776d79c88991a0d54915206" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Lounger -- "Clara's Wedding" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-12-07">December 7, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_68c8c1ba0b17afdb62a33921f5b77b05" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York American, SUN, Times, Tribune, Herald, World -- Mark Twain Returns from Bermuda" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1909-12-21">December 21, 1909</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4eb85e68d38befae6817ec3fffb79693" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Herald, SUN, Times, Tribune, Evening World -- "Mark Twain Leaves NYC for Bermuda" -- "Several brief indirect quotations on Clemens's health" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1910-01-06">January 6, 1910</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_de4057649520962472dbeb8970a748c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York World -- "Mark Twain Returns Hastily to Bermuda" -- "Clemens Comments on his health and his solace in smoking cigars" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1910-01-06">January 6, 1910</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_dfe8fc2afc4422bd33a8d92129884014" level="file"><did><unittitle>Human Life -- "Mark Twain Back in Feeble Health/Mark Twain at Bermuda/The Venerable Prince of Humorists Who Has Been Seeking Rest and Seclusion in the British Isles" -- "Mark Twain staying with the Allens; visitor is slow to get to main business and is gushy; nothing of consequence gets said, but this may be the last interview with a very sick man" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1910-05">May, 1910</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3b1d6132a0dc031bcdaedea6c1663c1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Inter-Ocean -- "Mark Twain's Boyhood (Jane Clemens)" -- "Mrs. Clemens lay the foundation for two legends about the boyhood of Clemens: his promises in the prescience of his father's coffin and his later promise never to drink intoxicants" </unittitle><unitdate normal="1911-04-05">April 5, 1911</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c90d96dd665586f88e236a151c85ad11" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Evening Post , Parade Magazine -- "Mark Twain's Daughter" </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">1931-01, 1960-04-24</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="c_529c0d91300304363964e735ef5b2ffd" level="series"><did><unittitle>SERIES 4: MARK TWAIN REVIEWS</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate><note><p>This series is a compilation of reviews of Mark Twain’s works compiled by Lou Budd and is arranged alphabetically by title</p></note></did><c id="c_3c497adf7f946a099fabf530dd9b19d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adam's Diary -- 1904 review copies </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8c0e54d23a576a2d847d02091ec6b8ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adventures of Huckleberry Finn -- photocopies and transcripts from 1884-1896 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1a3995832e501e7ba3074c9f128347cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adventures of Tom Sawyer -- photocopies and transcripts from 1876-1877 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_2ec182cf06a82843928cccdb589606b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Claimant -- review photocopies from 1892-1897 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6389dbfcc9beb85fcedab04657bc3273" level="file"><did><unittitle>Burlesque Autobiography -- photocopies and transcripts from 1871 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c31db50210f215b2f4a45887cd989495" level="file"><did><unittitle>Captain Stormfield's Visit to Heaven -- photocopies from 1909 and 1910 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_9d58df843dbc74854e7ef0b7ce9063fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Christian Science -- photocopies and transcriptions from 1907 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_82c3fe702757c6ef5468835422b4aa35" level="file"><did><unittitle>Connecticut Yankee in King Author's Court -- photocopies and transcripts from 1889-1896 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_99b680f9048434bc74a2b50e94713b6d" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Dog's Tale -- photocopies from 1904-1905, contains an unrelated photograph </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_858ead47b9021fd767e7eaf9695579ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>Double-Barreled Detective -- photocopies and transcriptions from 1902 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_c6f8631b65e75e2f42f3dd4f34af2275" level="file"><did><unittitle>Editorial: Wild Oats -- photocopies from 1905 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_59d7ae5d51ec4efcd43aa4b8bf3bca38" level="file"><did><unittitle>English as She Taught It -- photocopies from 1887 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_6a81bdf41764cfec2fb28dac6b4e9262" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eve's Diary -- photocopies from 1906 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_abd2e2a3dedfeedd9de40e4dd9130234" level="file"><did><unittitle>Following the Equator -- photocopies from 1897-1898 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_108199903dca710023566ebde892bb72" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Gilded Age -- photocopies from 1874 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_546fee3b0dfcfe4e9723c6098709a6a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hadleyburg-American -- photocopies from 1900 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_56264e586db5fc6b35bdf929d022894f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hadleyburg-British -- photocopies from 1900  reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a1353b03b0b79f83356e550872077d13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Horse's Tale -- photocopies from 1907-1908 reviews  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_888fd0c14aa06fa291303cc3a7132e14" level="file"><did><unittitle>How to Tell a Story -- photocopies from 1897 and 1907 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_398b88b5208fdc6298c012aa53021869" level="file"><did><unittitle>Innocents Abroad (1) -- photocopies and transcripts from 1889-1890 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_16aa571795bf05f5a0b1b03ad7fc939e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Innocents Abroad (2) -- photocopies and transcripts from 1889-1890 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_ddc191fb99a60e8e75c28a5dfeb445e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Joan of Arc -- photocopies from 1896-1897 reviews  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_85fcb1d9678decbf7eb31a73067c5ed3" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Jumping Frog of Calaveres County -- photocopies from 1867  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_522d943c788f5943e782a3217a71bb76" level="file"><did><unittitle>King Leopold's Soliloquy -- photocopies from 1905-1907 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3015d5923e9265a97174f1168dff6057" level="file"><did><unittitle>Life on the Mississippi -- photocopies from 1883-1886  reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_04d4f4c4feea14d522d4e7a418d11bca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Merry Tales -- photocopies from 1892 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_7676a733be9e5c0b45b0b48cb075f0c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mysterious Stranger -- photocopies from 1916-1917 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_e6ef7a181874bbe0fe3a65e5b5f2cc1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Prince and the Pauper -- photocopies from 1881-1897 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_a0a314ca740259516ef49d7e67de3509" level="file"><did><unittitle>Puddin' Head Wilson -- photocopies from 1894-1895 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0f7d2c17af37f01dcfcf0a8f7437a8dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Punch, Brothers, Punch -- Photocopies from 1878 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_cafc51fc6e2d620c424ebb37416d3d2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Roughing It -- photocopies from 1872-1873 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3b9e4e10644f8a8320a7b0d9d3551763" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrap-Book -- photocopies from 1877 and 1879 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_fc3e4ee9be620ff1fb4627aa8301cd37" level="file"><did><unittitle>Screamers/A Curious Dream -- photocopies from 1872 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_17eb4ce880a88859c2411e351f174779" level="file"><did><unittitle>Is Shakespeare Dead? -- photocopies from 1909 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_8f7208325ccb392a74d7bc95cd82a252" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sketches, New and Old -- photocopies from 1875-1875 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_b2ecda8734373d8b248b82329f22fff7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches [1910 Edition] -- photocopies and transcriptions from 1910 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_89fdea3584faa2449a5966047ccd3538" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stolen White Elephant -- photocopies from 1882 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_3355c02f6f321d764176d906643db4fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tom Sawyer  Abroad -- photocopies from 1894 and 1897 reviews  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_d9dad4b090b9792f0b1c8d54f4d14d8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tom Sawyer Detective -- photocopies from 1896-1897 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_606908bbf8087105f4273b6ed2f693b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Tramp Abroad -- photocopies from 1879-1898 reviews  </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_91900166e9827fc9ebc30a3f4d35e757" level="file"><did><unittitle>A True Story Repeated Word for Word as I Heard It -- photocopies from 1877 </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_0c1656d9e3eaa3e88b43b9aa2ed056af" level="file"><did><unittitle>What is Man? -- photocopies from 1910-1918 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_90a48776217ce32fad817b42a6fb070f" level="file"><did><unittitle>$30,000 Bequest -- photocopies from 1906-1907 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_1f0597120675729cace7cf47a61d8b92" level="file"><did><unittitle>$1,000,000 Banknote -- photocopies from 1893 reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_01847fb62f396c45ad100235b1f9a8ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bibliographic cards for reviews </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c><c id="c_4aa62049398e7e08fc8484ab02c5b979" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bibliographic cards for reviews (2) </unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate">undated</unitdate></did></c></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>