<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nelmc">nelmc0002</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Howard Baetzhold Papers, 1952-2005 </titleproper><author>Elmira College Archives</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="2017-03-06">March 6, 2017</date><publisher>Elmira College</publisher><address><addressline>One Park Place, </addressline><addressline>Elmira, New York 14901</addressline><addressline>(607) 735-1869</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nelmc.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Howard Baetzhold Papers, 1952-2005 </unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/2005" type="inclusive">1952 - 2005</unitdate><abstract>The bulk of the Howard Baetzhold papers are comprised of correspondence with members of the Mark Twain community.  The majority of the letters, though touching on Twain topics, are of a personal nature.  The collection contains little documentation of Baetzhold’s academic contributions in the field of Mark Twain studies and primarily documents the Twain scholarly community.</abstract><physdesc><extent>.83 linear ft.</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n93110953">Baetzhold, Howard G., 1923-</persname></origination><repository><corpname>Mark Twain Archive, Elmira College, Elmira, N.Y.</corpname></repository></did><accessrestrict><legalstatus>Unrestricted</legalstatus></accessrestrict><bioghist><p>“[Howard Baetzhold] was born January 1, 1923 in Buffalo, New York to Howard K. and Harriet H. Baetzhold.</p><p>After graduating from Brown University and serving in the U.S. Air Force in World War II, Howard returned to Brown where he met his wife, Nancy M. Cheesman, and soon after began their loving and supportive 60-year marriage. They moved to Madison Wisconsin, where Howard earned his PhD at the University of Wisconsin Madison.</p><p>Indianapolis became their home in 1953 when Howard accepted a position in the Butler University English Department and began his tenured academic career. From 1981 to 1985 Howard served as head of the English Department and was named the Rebecca Clifton Reade Professor of English Emeritus. He retired from Butler University in 1988.</p><p>Howard was a nationally recognized Mark Twain scholar, writing and editing publications for over 40 years. He authored Mark Twain and John Bull: The British Connection (Indiana, 1970) and co-authored The Bible According to Mark Twain: Writing of Heaven, Eden and the Flood (University of Georgia Press, 1995). He was a generous supporter and advisor to the Center for Mark Twain Studies at Elmira College. Howard shared his expertise with the University of California's Mark Twain Papers and Project where he was one of the original editors of the Works of Mark Twain. He was one of the world's true experts on the contents of the archive of Mark Twain's papers at Berkeley. In 2001 at The Fourth International Conference on the State of Mark Twain Studies, Howard received the Henry Nash Smith Award recognizing his lasting contributions to Mark Twain Studies.</p><p>During his whole life, Howard fostered a love of water and was a competitive swimmer in high school and college. He was a member of the British Sub-Aqua Club of Indiana and for a time, taught scuba diving at the Jordan YMCA. Howard continued swimming through the U.S. Masters Swimming Program well into his 70's.”</p><p>Howard Baetzhold died on July 7, 2012.
</p><p>http://www.legacy.com/obituaries/indystar/obituary.aspx?pid=159405986#sthash.W0nTKIZC.dpuf</p></bioghist><controlaccess><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80054060">Hirst, Robert H.</persname><persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n93110953">Baetzhold, Howard G., 1923-</persname></controlaccess><scopecontent><p>The Howard Baetzhold papers are comprised of correspondence, NEH grant materials and materials concerning the Mark Twain Papers held by the University of California at Berkeley. The materials related to the Mark Twain Papers at the UC Berkeley, where Howard Baetzhold was a contributor and writer, are the materials most concentrated on Twain scholarship. </p><p>However, the majority of the collection are letters, though touching on Twain topics, are of a personal nature.  </p><p>The collection contains little documentation of Baetzhold’s academic contributions in the field of Mark Twain studies.  </p></scopecontent><userestrict><p>unrestricted</p></userestrict><otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload"><bibref><extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="755dfc_Baetzhold_Container_List.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/></bibref></otherfindaid></archdesc></ead>