<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nbum">nbum0001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Medaille College Office of the President Newsletter</titleproper>
                <author>Chad Taylor</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2018-04-17">April 17, 2018</date>
                <publisher>Medaille College</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Buffalo Campus Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>Huber Hall</addressline>
                    <addressline>18 Agassiz Circle</addressline>
                    <addressline>Buffalo, New York 14214</addressline>
                    <addressline>716-880-2283</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nbum.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Medaille College Presidential Communications </unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="2010-01-01/2018-02-01" type="inclusive">January 1, 2010 - February 1, 2018</unitdate>
            <abstract>Official internal communications to the campus community from the presidents of Medaille College.  </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>1 cubic foot</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname>Medaille College.</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Medaille College Libraries Archives</corpname>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>Archival materials in the Medaille College Libraries are available by appointment usually M-F Noon-5 pm.  Please contact Chad Taylor (716) 880-2283.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Dr. Kenneth M. Macur became Medaille College’s seventh President on June 1, 2015. He has a B.S. in Accountancy, an MBA in Finance and a Ph.D. in Accountancy, all from the University of Illinois at Urbana/Champaign. In addition, he is a licensed CPA (Wisconsin). Dr. Macur previously served as Provost and Dean of Bethany College (KS) and Associate Vice President for Academic Affairs and Online Learning at Edgewood College (Madison, WI). He was a tenured full professor in Accounting and Information Systems at Edgewood College and at the University of Wisconsin – Whitewater. </p>
            <p>Dr. Richard T. Jurasek, Ph.D. was employed at Medaille College in the position of the President between June 2007 and June 2015. He was previously the executive vice president of Antioch College in Yellow Springs, Ohio. At Antioch College, Dr. Jurasek served as the chief operations officer with direct responsibility for admissions, financial aid, academic affairs, student affairs and auxiliary services. Dr. Jurasek originally joined Antioch in 2003 as the college's vice president and dean of faculty. He served as the Antioch's interim president from July 2004-February 2006 and was promoted to executive vice president in March 2006. Before joining Antioch College, Dr. Jurasek served as the dean of faculty at Augustana College in Rock Island, and as Professor of German at Earlham College in Richmond. Dr. Jurasek earned both his Ph.D. and master's degrees in German from The Ohio State University and his bachelor's degree in German from Ohio University.</p>
            <p>Makur's Mark Newsletter written by Kenneth Macur and donated by Chad Taylor.</p>
            <p>President's Message written by Richard Jurasek and donated by Thomas Orrange.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n84058066">Jurasek, Richard T.</persname>
            <persname>Macur, Kenneth</persname>
            <subject>Medaille College (Buffalo, N.Y.)</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>Newsletter type communications from the Office of the President of Medaille College sent to the campus community.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Physical copies are available for on-site review.  Duplication or publication is prohibited.</p>
        </userestrict>
    </archdesc>
</ead>