<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="baird_sf">baird_sf</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Spencer Fullerton Baird Collection</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        the collection 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">KM</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>&su_address;
                           <date normal="1989-04-18" encodinganalog="Date">18 Apr 1989</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>12 Mar 2007 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name; <lb/>&su_address;
               </repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Baird, Spencer Fullerton,1823-1887.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Spencer Fullerton Baird Collection</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1858-1882</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">8 items (SC)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">
                    Papers of the American zoologist, naturalist, ornithologist; Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.</abstract>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Seven outgoing letters to A. Bolmar, J.C. Green, I.I. Hayes, and Thomas Louis Ogier. Also a memorandum for Dr. Hayes concerning the collection of polar zoological specimens.</abstract>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="US" repositorycode="NSyU">149370</unitid>
      <langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Spencer Fullerton Baird was born in Reading, Pennsylvania in 1823 and graduated from Dickinson College in Carlisle, Pennsylvania in 1840.  The next year Baird made an ornithological excursion through the mountains of Pennsylvania, walking (says one of his biographers) 400 miles in 21 days. While still in college Baird met noted naturalist John James Audubon, who gave part of his own collection of birds to the young man and inspired in him a lifelong interest in ornithological studies.</p>
<p>Baird became professor of natural history at Dickinson College in 1845; he was also chair of the chemistry department and taught physiology and mathematics. In 1850 he was appointed assistant-secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, in Washington, D.C., where he encouraged the work of the young naturalists in the Megatherium Club. On the death of Joseph Henry in 1878 he became secretary of the Institution, and from 1871 until his death he was also U.S. Commissioner of Fish and Fisheries.</p>
<p>Baird's studies and publication topics include iconography, geology, mineralogy, botany, anthropology, general zoology, and, in particular, ornithology.  For several years he edited an annual volume summarizing progress in all scientific lines of investigation, and between 1850 and 1860 he supervised a number of government scientific explorations of the western territories of the United States, preparing for them a manual of Instructions to Collectors.</p>
<p>According to a bibliography by George Brown Goode, from 1843 to 1882 Baird published over a thousand pieces of writing, 775 of them being short articles in his <emph render="italic">Annual Record</emph>. Among the most significant works were his <emph render="italic">Catalog of North American Reptiles</emph> (1853, with Charles Frederic Girard); <emph render="italic">Birds</emph> (1858); <emph render="italic">Mammals of North America: Descriptions based on Collections in the Smithsonian Institution</emph> (Philadelphia, 1859); and the impressive <emph render="italic">History of North American Birds</emph> (Boston, 1875-1884; 5 vols, with Thomas Mayo Brewer and Robert Ridgway).</p>
<p>Baird died in 1887 at the Marine Biological Laboratory at Woods Hole, Massachusetts, an institution which was largely the result of his own efforts and which continues to play an important role in ochthyology today.</p>
<p>[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from "Spencer Fullerton Baird" Wikipedia article.]</p>
  </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The Spencer Fullerton Baird Collection consists of seven outgoing letters and a single item of writing, "Natural History Memoranda for Dr. Hayes," all of which were generated during the zoologist's tenure at the Smithsonian Institution.</p>

<p>The letters are arranged chronologically from 1858 to 1882, and an index of correspondents is also included.  Some of the lettesr (A. Bolmar, J.C. Green, Thomas Louis Ogier) contain answers to, or requests for, various publications; however the most interesting letters in the collection are those to American explorer and physicist I.I. Hayes in reference to his 1860 Arctic expedition.  
The second letter to Hayes (24 June 1860) indicates that several instruments for the collection of specimens were also sent, including "drills for perforating eggs" and a blow pipe.  An enclosure to this letter, a copy of "Natural History Memoranda for Dr. Hayes," filed with Writings, reflects the Smithsonian Institution's interest in obtaining Arctic zoological specimens for its collections, and the particular ornithological predilection of its secretary:</p>

<blockquote><p>All zoological collections from the Arctic regions are of interest, especiallyin view of the fact that very few or any of the specimens collected in the high north are in the museums of the United States.</p>

<p>Shells, crustaceans and fishes will throw much light upon questions in regard to currents of the ocean, etc.</p>

<p>Eggs of Arctic birds, sparrows, hawks, owls, ducks, gulls, etc will be of particular interest to the Smithsonian Institution in connection with its work on biology.  No occasion should be unimproved to collect eggs of all land birds that may be met with, as also of plovers, snipe, curlew, sand pipers, etc.  Some of these specimens can be sold at a high price.</p>

<p>Of all the gulls and ducks, a good series ofeggs should be secured.</p>

<p>Among the species of birds to which particular attention should be paid are:<blockquote><p>1.  All land birds.  Many of these are stragglers from the United States, the goegraphical distribution of which it is very desirable to ascertain.</p>
<p>2.  Any unusual or rare dovekies or species of that group.</p>
<p>3.  The small gull with black ring around the neck, and a wedge-shaped bill.  Also pure white gulls.</p>
<p>4.  The great auk...This is a very large sea bird considerably larger than a domestic duck.  Something like a murre in appearance but with a high bill and a square white patch at its base.  The wings are rudimentary.  Good skins and eggs of this bird will realize $50.00 each and perhaps more.</p></blockquote></p>


<p>It will be best to attempt the collection of a full series of all the birds met with in Greenland.</p>

<p>The mammals of chief interest are the different kinds of lemmings, mice &amp; rats.  Next to these any marmots &amp; ground squirrels.  Also, hares in both winter and summer dress.  Also, any bears, seals, foxes, wolves, weasels, etc that appear to be unusual or peculiar, although it will not be worth while to collect such as may be found in more southern latitudes.</p>

<p>Any marine mammals from the open polar sea will be of much interest as illustrating points of physical geography.  Note as fully as possible all facts relating to the habits, migrations, numbers, reproduction, etc. of all animals met with.

</p>
</blockquote>

    </scopecontent>
    <!-- <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 351$a)</p>
    </arrangement> -->
    <!-- <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 1)</p>
    </relatedmaterial> -->
    <!-- <separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
    </separatedmaterial> -->
    <!-- <otherfindaid encodinganalog="555"><head>Other Related Finding Aids</head><p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p></otherfindaid>
            -->
<controlaccess>
<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Science and medicine</subject><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Bolmar, Antoine.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Green, J. C. (Jesse Cope), 1817-1920.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Hayes, I. I. (Isaac Israel), 1832-1881.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Ogier, Thomas Louis.</persname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Smithsonian Institution.</corpname>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Arctic regions -- Discovery and exploration.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Natural history museums -- United States.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Zoological museums -- United States.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Zoological specimens -- Collection and preservation.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Zoologists -- United States.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Zoology -- Arctic regions.</subject>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Zoologists.</occupation>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Scientists.</occupation>
</controlaccess>

<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p></accessrestrict>

<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
                       all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
                       materials in this collection. </p></userestrict><prefercite encodinganalog="524"><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p><p>Spencer Fullerton Baird Collection<lb/>&su_name;
                  </p></prefercite>

<!--
            <appraisal encodinganalog="583">
<head>Appraisal Information</head>
<p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       -->
<!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584">
<head>Accruals</head
><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->

      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>Inventory</head>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle><unitdate normal="1858/1882" type="inclusive">1858/1882</unitdate></unittitle>
                  <physdesc><extent>7 items</extent></physdesc>
                  <container type="SC">92</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Natural History Memoranda for Dr. Hayes"</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1855/1860" type="inclusive">Sent as enclosure to letter of 24 June 1860</unitdate>
                  <container type="SC">92</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         
      </dsc>
   <index id="sic"><head>Index to correspondence</head><indexentry><name>Bolmer, Antoine</name><ref>9 Apr 1858</ref></indexentry><indexentry><name>Green, Jesse Cope</name><ptrgrp><ref>7 Nov 1878</ref><ref>7 Mar 1882</ref></ptrgrp><indexentry><name>Hayes, Isaac Israel</name><ptrgrp><ref>16 Jun 1860</ref><ref>24 Jun 1860</ref></ptrgrp><indexentry><name>Ogier, Thomas Louis</name><ref>6 Jul 1882</ref></indexentry></indexentry></indexentry></index></archdesc>
</ead>
