<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
<!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->
<eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid countrycode="us" identifier="galloway_e" mainagencycode="NSyU">galloway_e</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Ewing Galloway Collection of Photographs</titleproper>
<subtitle>An inventory of the collection at Syracuse University</subtitle>
<author encodinganalog="Creator">-</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
<lb/>
</publisher>&su_address;
<date encodinganalog="Date" normal="0000">unknown</date>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>AMCon
			<date normal="2006-09-25">25 Sep 2006</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
<language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
<revisiondesc>
<list>
<item>25 Sep 2006 - converted to EAD (AMCon)</item><item>8 May 2007 - added creator (MRC)</item>
    <item>12 Jan 2012 - box numbers revised (MBD)</item><item>15 Mar 2012 - adds (MRC)</item>
    <item>26 Oct 2012 - extent revised (MBD)</item><item>25 Sep 2015 - Fox gift (MRC)</item>
</list>
</revisiondesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
<did>
<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
<repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
<lb/>&su_address;</repository>
<origination label="Creator: ">
<persname encodinganalog="100">Galloway, Ewing</persname>
</origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Ewing Galloway Collection of Photographs</unittitle>
<unitdate calendar="gregorian" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1900/1930" type="inclusive">1900-1930(?)</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
<extent>18 linear ft.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Reproduction of early 20th century photographs from the Ewing Galloway Agency.   Urban street scenes (New York, Chicago, Detroit), Asia and Europe, Native Americans, human interest.</abstract>
<unitid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">2472501</unitid>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
<language langcode="eng">English</language>
</langmaterial>
</did>
<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
<head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Ewing Galloway (1881-1953) was an American journalist and photo editor, and ran the Ewing Galloway 
Agency in New York City.  He began his working life as a lawyer in Henderson County, Kentucky working 
in his spare time for <emph render="italic">The Gleaner</emph>, a county newspaper.  Gradually 
journalism drew more and more of his interest, and after a journalism course at Columbia University 
in New York he took a series of newspaper jobs that led him to the Midwest, to California, and 
eventually to Hawaii before he returned home to Kentucky to work again for 
<emph render="italic">The Gleaner</emph>.    After completing his internship there, he returned to 
New York where he worked as assistant editor for <emph render="italic">Literary Digest</emph> and 
freelanced on the side.  He became photo editor for <emph render="italic">Collier's</emph> and then 
worked for Underwood and Underwood.</p>

<p>In 1920 he opened his own photographic agency on 28th St. in New York.  Although he had relatively 
few photographs at first, he soon expanded his stock and in 1925 purchased a collection of 8000 images of 
Africa and Asia.  By 1928 the agency was successful enough to expand; in the following years Ewing 
Galloway branches opened in Chicago, Detroit, Los Angeles, Boston, London, Berlin, and Amsterdam.  By 
handling only general topics as opposed to time-sensitive news photographs, Galloway established a 
profitable market niche while pioneering the photographic interpretation of industry, transportation, and
commerce. He also provided trained photographers for hire for studio or location work.
One of these was Maclean Dameron, a respected photographer from Henderson County,
Kentucky whom Galloway hired as a full-time associate in 1941.</p>

<p>The "Ewing Galloway" byline that appears under many photographs reproduced in books, 
magazines, schoolbooks, and encyclopedias, refers to the agency and not to Galloway
himself, who learned to operate a camera only
later in life. The caption was an advertising device: it could be left off, but the
photograph would cost more without it.  The lack of records from the company makes it 
impossible to identify the actual photographers.   Nevertheless, the images that survive from
the early years of Galloway's agency preserve striking historical glimpses into everyday life,
familiar locations, and means of employment. Though produced for journalistic purposes,
their fine qualities of composition and execution suggest that a skilled photographer with
an artistic eye was standing behind the lens. Though the men -- and perhaps women -- who
clicked the shutter remain anonymous, we enter easily into what they saw, at the moment
they saw it.</p>

<p>The agency's holdings amounted to some four hundred thousand images 
by the time of Galloway's death.  Today, Ewing
Galloway, Inc. manages and markets a portion of the photographic assets of the original
agency.</p>








</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
<head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
<p>The <emph render="bold">Ewing Galloway Collection of Photographs</emph> consists of more than 150 large-format photographs taken by the American photographer.  The collection is divided topically.   Galloway's own identification number is given in parentheses following each item title.</p><p><emph render="bold">City scenes</emph> includes photographs from New York, Chicago, Detroit, Indianapolis, Little Rock and other urban areas.  Most are street scenes (Michigan Boulevard in Chicago, Bagley Avenue in Detroit) though there are a few river and skyline shots.  <emph render="bold">Industry</emph> comprises images of American business, including manufacturing, mining, railroad, dairy, refining and steel, among others.  </p><p><emph render="bold">Native American</emph> contains individual and group photographs, primarily from the Southwest and Alaska, while <emph render="bold">Asia</emph>  contains images from China, Formosa (Taiwan), Japan, Korea, Siam (Thailand), and the Philippines.  <emph render="bold">Foreign</emph> covers most of Europe (Austria, Belgium, England, France, Germany, Holland, Russia, Spain and Tunis) and Central/South America (Argentina and Mexico).  </p><p>The most varied selection is found in <emph render="bold">Human interest</emph>: from a superstitious aviatrix with her two dolls to a horse-drawn wagon in Brooklyn, from a prison tower at Sing Sing Correctional Facility to a chemist in his laboratory.</p><p>There is also a small series of nine <emph render="bold">Unnumbered photographs</emph>, smaller in dimension and acquired separately at a later date.   These represent a variety of the above topics, including New York Harbor, a full-rigger tall ship, a Philippine Islander in traditional dress, St. Gudula's Cathedral in Brussels, and more.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
			<head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
			<p>Divided topically.  The topics, and the photographs within each topic, are in no particular order.</p>
		</arrangement>
<!--<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
			<head>Related Material</head>
			<p>## (MARC 544 1)</p>
		</relatedmaterial>-->
<!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
			<head>Separated Material</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
		</separatedmaterial>-->
<!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
			<head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
		</otherfindaid>-->
<controlaccess>
<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Photography</subject>
<!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc).  
Some have defaults set in the template.-->
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Galloway, Ewing</persname>

<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Photographs.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Street life -- Photographs.</subject><geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Germany -- Pictorial works.</geogname><geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Japan -- Pictorial works.</geogname><geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Korea -- Pictorial works.</geogname><geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- History and culture.</geogname><geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.</geogname><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>

<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Photographers.</occupation></controlaccess>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
<p>Ewing Galloway Collection of Photographs, <lb/> &scrc_name;</p>
</prefercite><acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Gift of <persname role="donor">Mark Jacobson</persname>, 1997.</p><p>Unnumbered photographs, gift of <corpname role="donor">Ricker Library of Architecture and Art, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</corpname>, 2010; <persname role="donor">Margaret Fox</persname>, 2015.</p>
</acqinfo><!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
			<head>Appraisal Information</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
		</appraisal>--><!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
			<head>Accruals</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
		</accruals>-->
<dsc type="combined">
<head>Inventory</head>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>City scenes</unittitle>
</did>
<note><p>Galloway's own identification numbers appear in parentheses following each item title.</p></note><c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Trolley on Trolley Track Going Down Main Street (54)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Alaska: A Village and River Front Located in Alaska (172)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Buffalo, New York: Main Street Located in Buffalo, New York (166)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Chicago, Illinois: Michigan Boulevard During 1920 Located in Chicago, Illinois (83)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Cleveland, Ohio: Public Square Located in Cleveland, Ohio (95)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Cleveland, Ohio: Cleveland Car System in the Public Square Looking Towards Euclid Avenue (111)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Cleveland, Ohio: A Municipal Center in Cuyahoga County Court House and City All in Cleveland (177)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Dayton, Ohio: Looking Down 4th Street in Dayton, Ohio (69)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Detroit, Michigan: Sight Seeing Boats Along the Detroit Water Front (122)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Detroit, Michigan: Parking Autos on Bagley Avenue in Detroit, Michigan (156)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Detroit, Michigan: Along the Detroit River Front Reflecting Pleasure and Passenger Boats (170)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hot Springs, Arkansas: Central Avenue and Bath House Row in Hot Springs, Arkansas (76)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Indianapolis, Indiana: A Typical Street scene in Indianapolis, Indiana During the Early 10th Century (15)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Little Rock, Arkansas: Capital Avenue Viewed From Main Street Located in Little Rock, Arkansas (75)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: Night View of Times Square in New York City During the 1930's (two copies) (6)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: Looking East Over 42nd Street From 6th Avenue, New York City. An Early Version Showing the Trolley in Motion (9)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: A Photo Reflecting Orchard Street in New York City Viewed From Grand Street. It Shows The Atypical Shoppers and the Push Carts(two copies) (21)</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1925/1935">ca. 1930</unitdate>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: Skyline of New York City Taken From the Brooklyn Bridge in the Early Part of the 20th Century (two copies) (33)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: The Soldiers Monument in the Center of Midtown (70)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: Hotel Madison in New York City Located on Madison Avenue (88)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: New York City Skyline Viewed From a Ferry (two copies) (120)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: New York City Skyline Viewed from Brooklyn, New York (127)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: View of 5th Avenue and 42nd Street Reflecting Heavy Pedestrian Traffic (157)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: Hoisting of a Bell to the Tower in the Riverside Church Located in New York City (161)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: A Ship Coaling at the Dock in Brooklyn with the New York Skyline in the Background (175)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York City: The New York Skyline Seen From The Manhattan Bridge (195)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Toledo, Ohio: Lucas County Court House on Adams Street Located in Toledo, Ohio (84)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Industry</unittitle>
</did>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Borroughs Adding Machine Company: Switchboard in Engine Room of Borroughs Adding Machine Company (51)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Borroughs Adding Machine Company: Safety Device on a Joiner Machine at the Borroughs Adding Machine Company (117)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Borroughs Adding Machine Company: Employment Office of the Bourroughs Company in Detroit (145)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Calumet Hecla: A Michigan Mine Reflecting Securing Loose Ground at the Calumet Hecla Mine (22)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Calumet Hecla Mines: Forging Molten Copper Into Molds at Calumet Hecla Mines (146)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Coal: Vessel Being Loaded With Coal in Toledo, Ohio (118)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Cobbler: A Cobbler Sewing Shoes with a Shoe Machine (28)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Corn Harvest: Corn Harvest Utilizing Modern Corn Cutting Machinery (27)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Curtis Oriole Airplane: Assembling a Wing of a Curtis Oriole Airplane 1920 Model (176)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Curtis Oriole Airplane: Grinding the Cam Shaft of a Curtis Motor for the 1920 Model of an Oriole Airplane (185)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Curtis Oriole Airplane: Installing Motors in the Curtis Oriole Airplane 1920 Model (192)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Erie Railroad: Erie Railroad Camps, Depicting One of the Largest Passenger Engines (125)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Erie Railroad: Largest Freight Engines on the Euro Erie Railroad Lines (181)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Factory - Hats: Interior of a Hat and Cap Factory (48)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Factory - Hats: Manufacturing Soft and Stiff Fur Hats (81)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Factory - Hats: Manufacturing Hats Using Hard Wood Blocks and Electric Iron (184)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Gravel Tug: Unloading a Gravel Tug, Docked at Toledo, Ohio (82)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hydraulic Press Steel Company: Press Room of the Hydraulic Press Steel Company at Cleveland, Ohio (85)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hydraulic Press Steel Company: Oil Burning Furnace at the Hydraulic Press Steel Company in Cleveland, Ohio (110)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Libby Glass Works: Forming A The Stand For Use At Libby Glass Works (36)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">3</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Locomotive: Locomotive Early Train Twenty Four Wheel Drive (41)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Locomotive: An Engineer Oiling the Locomotive Before a Run in the Railroad Yard in Baltimore, Maryland (72)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Machine Company Employees: A Pastry Kitchen Being Utilized For Borroughs Adding Machine Company Employees (126)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: A New York City Inspector Checking Tag on Milk Cans (35)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: New York Department of Health Inspector Examining for Bacteria in Milk Before Being Sent to Dealers for Consumption (47)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: Taking samples of Milk From a Tank for Bacteria Testing (49)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: Taking the Temperature of Bottles of Milk in New York City (53)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: Inspecting Milk Before Delivery in a Borden Horse Drawn Milk wagon in New York City (56)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: Inspecting a Milk Tanker Truck, Being Unloaded at a Bottling Plant in New York City (113)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Milk: Reading Milk Tags on the Tank Car to Establish Origin of the Milk (114)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Copper: Copper Mine and Crushing Plant in Miami, Arizona (55)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Copper: A View of the Rails in a Copper Mine in Michigan (187)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Klondike Gold: Gold Mining in Klondike, Yukon Territory. This scene in the district where gold was discovered in 1896, two years before the gold rush of 1888. (20)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Klondike Gold: Men Mining For Gold in Klondike Region in Canada (141)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Salt: A Salt Mine Located 960 Feet Deep (164)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, US Bureau: Rescue Crew Employed by the United States Bureau of Mines (162)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mine, Wilkes-Barre Coal: Starting Early as a Mascot of Coal Miners in Wilkes-Barre, PA (1)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mosquitoes: A Power Pump Attached to the Moret of an Oil Truck Utilized by the New York City Health Department to Destroy Mosquitoes (13)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mosquitoes: New York Inspector From Board of Health Collecting Mosquito Larvae for Examination (39)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mosquitoes: War on Mosquitoes with Crude Oil in Marshes Located in New York City (180)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York Globe Newspaper: The Telegraph Room At The New York Globe Newspaper in New York City (148)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">4</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York Globe Newspaper: Make Up Alley in the Newspaper (152)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New York Globe Newspaper: Stereotype Room Showing Plates Being Made (154)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Niagra Falls, New York: Building Underwater in Niagra Falls, New York in Eleven Mile Current (150)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Packard Motor Car Company Drilling the Crank Case 65 Holes at One Time. Factory Located in Detroit, Michigan (74)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Packard Motor Car Company Located in Detroit, Michigan (97)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Another Picture of the Packard Motor Car Company of Detroit, Michigan (98)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Testing A Motor with a stethoscope for the Packard Motor Car Company (104)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Automatic Screw Machine Department at the Packard Motor Car Company (108)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: A Roller Conveyor at the Packard Motor Car Company Used for Handling Heavy Parts (109)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Aluminum Melting Furnace At the Packard Motor Car Company (128)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Packard Motor Car Company: Oil Burning Furnace at the Packard Motor Car Company in Detroit, Michigan (147)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pneumatic Tool Company: Chipping With a Compressed Air Tool, Built By the Chicago Pneumatic Tool Company of Cleveland, Ohio (16)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pneumatic Tool Company: Grinding Gear Housing For Auto truck With Pneumatic Tool Company (151)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Railroad Grain Elevators: Ten Railroad Grain Elevators in Baltimore, Maryland (190)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Railroad Lamps: Blowing Lamp Cylinders for Railroad Lamps (37)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Railroad Yard: A Car Shop and Railroad Yard Located in Toledo, Ohio (73)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>S.S. Brennan: A Wireless Radio Operation Aboard the S.S. Brennan (46)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Sheet Copper: Stripping and Straightening Sheet Copper in Hubble, Michigan (198)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Shredded Wheat Company: A Female Restroom at the Shredded Wheat Company of Niagra Falls, New York State in the Early 20th Century (3)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Shredded Wheat Company: A Production Line of the Shredded Wheat Company of Niagra Falls in New York State (10)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Shredded Wheat Company: Packing Shredded Wheat in Niagra Falls, New York (183)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Sinclair Refinery: Rear View of Stills Showing Piping at Sinclair Refinery in East Chicago (57)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Sinclair Refinery: Light Oil Receiving House at the Sinclair Refinery in east Chicago, Illinois (94)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Sinclair Refinery: Loading Rack of the Sinclair Refinery in East Chicago, Illinois (106)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Sinclair Refinery: A Close up of the Loading Rack at the Sinclair Refinery (107)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Steel Beams: Loading Steel Beams on a Vessel in Cleveland Harbor For Canada (87)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Tank Gasoline Station: A Converted Railroad Tank Car into an Office for the Gasoline Filling Station Reflecting Autos Getting Gas Located in Charlottesville, Virginia (17)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Tank Gasoline Station: Another View of the Converted Railroad Tank Car in Charlottesville, Virginia (18)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Glen L. Martin Company: Adjusting the Motor and Checking Parts after a Final Test is Made on an Airplane (2)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Glen L. Martin Company: Drafting Room of the Engineering Department of the Glen L. Martin Company of Cleveland, Ohio (5)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Glen L. Martin Company: Assembling Wings for Martin Planes Located at the Glen L. Martin Company in Cleveland, Ohio (96)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Glen L. Martin Company: Covering an Airplane Wing With Linen Cloth. Located at the Glen L. Martin Company in Cleveland, Ohio (105)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Glen L. Martin Company: A Side View of a Martin Naval Plane (112)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Glen L. Martin Company: Assembling Rib For the Martin Plane at The Glen L. Martin Company of Cleveland, Ohio (196)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Train, Commuter: A Commuter Train and It's Occupants Leaving to go to Their Daily Jobs in Chicago, Illinois (64)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Tripping Device: Two Handle tripping Device To Curb Accidents in Detroit (124)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Upson Steel Mills: Upson Steel Mills Located in Cleveland, Ohio (178)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Van Tassel Tanning Comp.: Soaking Hides in the Van Tassel Tanning Company of Stoneham, Massachusetts (66)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Van Tassel Tanning Comp.: Photographing Story of Leather Making Taken in Van Tassel Tannery (153)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Van Tassel Tanning Comp.: Van Tassel Tanning Company Hides are Stored in Respective Bins According to Kind, Grade, and Weight (155)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Van Tassel Tanning Comp.: A Leather Tanning Plant in Stoneham, Massachusetts (197)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Whaling: Whalers at Work, Notice Whale in Shallow Waters (90)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">6</container>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Native American</unittitle>
</did>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Indians Making Ceramics (77)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>An Indian Mother Nursing Her Baby (80)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Albuquerque, New Mexico: Exhibition at the Indian Buildings in Albuquerque, New Mexico (101)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Albuquerque, New Mexico: Basket Weaving By Indian Child In Albuquerque, New Mexico (189)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Blackfeet Tribe, Montana: American Indian Close Up Photo. This is the photo of the man appearing on the Nickel Coin. This Indian is a member of the Blackfeet tribe of Montana. (19)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Blackfoot Indians: Blackfoot Indians in Montana (168)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Dawson, Alaska: Indian Women Hanging Up Salmon to Dry in Mosse Head Village Near Dawson, Alaska (121)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Juger: Juger Women Weaving (135)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mexico: Making Tortillas In Mexico (179)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Navajo of New Mexico: A 10 Year Old Navajo Indian Child of New Mexico, Weaving and Simultaneously Attempting to reflect Stories of Their Tribe in the Weave (11)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New Mexico: Two Indians From New Mexico (133)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Point Oak, Alaska: Eskimo Mother and Her Baby From Point Oak, Alaska (92)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pueblo Indians: Pueblo Indians of Islets, New Mexico (4)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pueblo Indians: A Group of Pueblo Indians on a Roof Top in Isleta, New Mexico (8)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pueblo Indians: Pueblo Indians Crossing a Stream in New Mexico (143)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pueblo, Laguna, New Mexico: A Scene From Pueblo, Laguna of New Mexico (100)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Pueblo, New Mexico: An Indian Wrapped in a Blanket in Pueblo, New Mexico (99)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">7</container>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Asian</unittitle>
</did>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Children Being Prepared to Have Photos Taken of Themselves (134)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>China: Chinese Oriental Fishing From a Small Boat (40)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Formosa: A Group of Formosan Girls Dressed in Colorful Costumes Taken During 1951 (12)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Formosa: A Group of Aborigines Parading In Formosa (167)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Japan: A Bus made By the Ford Motor Company Utilized For Passenger Service In Tokyo, Japan (30)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Japan: A Japanese Girl Taking a Bath in a Barrel With a Wood Burning Heating Device (32)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Japan: Japanese Lady With a Little Girl Riding in a Rickshaw (132)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Japan: Crater Of A Volcano In Northern Japan (163)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Korea: A Korean Carrying a Load of Baskets, Brooms, etc. in a Gigi Used By Thousands of Porters For Toting Burdens in Korea (29)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Korea: A Gentleman Pulling a Rickshaw in Korea (131)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Korea: Farmers Children on the Road in Seoul, Korea (136)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Korea: Salvation Army Van in Seoul, Korea (138)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Korea: Koreans In Seoul In Their Homes With Children (144)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Philippines: A Scene Of Nipa Shacks Located in the Philippines (139)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Philippines: A Women In The Philippines Selling Fruits and Vegetables (142)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Siam: A Woman Working In A Rice Field In Siam (199)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">8</container>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Foreign</unittitle>
</did>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Small Boys Twisting Cotton With Hands and Toes (137)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Argentina: Shipping at the Docks of Buenos Aires, Argentina (171)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Argentina: Storage Bins and Warehouse for Cotton and Wheat in Buenos Aires, Argentina (200)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Austria: A Portrait of an Austrian Mother and Child (63)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Belgium: A Busy Market Scene in a Locale in Belgium (45)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>England: A Fishing Village in Clovelly, England (169)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>France: German Prisoners of War Located in France (188)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Germany: The Wreck of a Tank Captured by the Germans and Used by Them Against the French (34)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Germany: A View of a Medieval Town in Germany (79)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Germany: A Cathedral in Nuremberg, Germany (129)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Holland: Scenic View of Several Windmills in Holland Within the City of Zaandyke (67)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Holland: A Typical Farm Cart Traveling on a Cobble Stone Road in Holland (173)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Mexico: A Scene Depicting Men Being Executed By a Firing Squad in Mexico. One of the Men is a Priest. (182)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Russia: A Russian Church Located in Moscow Called "Vassely Blajenni" (159)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Spain: Date Gatherers In Hide Palms in Alicante, Spain (165)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Tunis: Musicians in Tunis (193)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">9</container>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Human interest</unittitle>
</did>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>An Early Photograph of a Typical Patrolman in His Rain Gear Accompanied by a Crying Child (two copies) (7)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Fire During the 1920's at the Edmonds' Elevator Company, Note the Spectators in Their Summer Straws (two copies) (14)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Spectator Viewing the Springs at Hot Springs, Arkansas (23)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Scene Reflecting Destitute Children Picking Up Coal From Waste Piles to Insure Coal Supply for Their Respective Homes in Anticipation of Winter (24)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Tractor Moving a House on Rollers (25)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Two Circus elephants Getting Ready to Leave Town Via Locomotive (31)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Modern Sanitation Truck During the Early 1930's (38)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Two Hobo's on Top of a Caboose (42)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Hobo Catching A Ride on a Caboose (43)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Newark, New Jersey Public Library (Interior) (44)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hobo Walking the Railroad Track (50)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Photo of a Grandma Madonna and Two Young Children (52)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Chaos in the Financial District At the Height of the Depression (58)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Two Little Boys Playing in a Gutter Located in New York City (59)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Baby Giving a Piece of His Chocolate Bar to His Family's Pet Dog (60)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Portrait of an Immigrant Mother and Her Baby Daughter (61)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Group of Immigrants Applying For Their First papers in Quest of United States Citizenship (62)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A View of a Prisoner Listening to His Radio (Note Earphones) to Stifle Noise (65)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Horse Drawn Wagon of Scrap Metal in Brooklyn, New York (68)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>An Auto Wreck Being Observed By a Group of New York Onlookers (71)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Superstitious Aviatrix Accompanied By Two Little Dolls When Flying (78)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">10</container>
</did>
</c02><c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Portrait of a Musician Holding His Bow and Violin (86)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Children Getting Inoculated Against Scarlet Fever (89)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Hobo Sewing Warm Clothes in His Woodland Home (91)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Chemist in His Washington, D.C. Laboratory (93)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Father, Mother and Child (Family Pose Early 20th Century) (102)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Application For Naturalization Taken Under Oath (103)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">11</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Man Getting Oysters Out of the Water at the Oyster Beds in New Jersey (115)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Orphan Children's Outing Given by the Cleveland Automobile Club (116)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Portrait of Mr. Munson Havens the Secretary of the Chamber of Commerce of Cleveland, Ohio (119)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>An Employees Cooperative Store in Detroit, Michigan (123)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Group of Veteran Gold Miners (130)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Cardiac Class For Women Suffering From Cardiac Disease in New York City (140)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Postman Delivering Mail, His Uniform of Fifty Years or More Are Still Being Utilized (149)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Free Public Tennis Courts Located in Cleveland, Ohio (158)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Protest Against Non-Employment and Discrimination Against Minorities (160)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A Concrete Bridge Over a Niagra River Above Niagra Falls, New York (174)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>The Old Style, Free Delivery Postman with Horse and Buggy (186)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Excavating in Quest of Archeological Finds (191)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>A View of a Guard Manning the Tower Overlooking the Sing Sing Prison in New York State (194)</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">12</container>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Unnumbered later additions</unittitle></did>
<c02><did><unittitle>Postcard with photograph of City Hall in New York</unittitle><container type="Oversize">1</container></did><acqinfo><p>Gift of Margaret Fox, 2015.</p></acqinfo></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><physdesc><extent>9 items</extent></physdesc><container type="Oversize">1</container></did><acqinfo><p>Gift of the Ricker Library of Architecture and Art, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2010.</p></acqinfo><scopecontent><p>Places and subjects include New York City, Kansas City, St. Gudula Cathedral in Brussels, Niagara Falls, New York Harbor, a full-rigger "tall ship," turtle fishing in Abyssinia, and a Bagobo youth in the Philippines.  Dates are unknown.  All photos are 8x10" black and white originals.</p></scopecontent></c02>
</c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
