<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../ead_dtd/ead_oxygen.css"?>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="gallo_b" mainagencycode="NSyU">gallo_b</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Bill Gallo Papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        his papers 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">WHL/CAD</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
          <lb/></publisher>&su_address;
        <date encodinganalog="Date" normal="1984-08">Aug 1984</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           
        
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>13 Nov 2007 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item>
        <item>8 Dec 2009 - expanded  bio, scope and inventory (SK)</item>
                                                  <item>3 Jun 2011 - updated bio (AM)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
        <lb/>&su_address;</repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Gallo, Bill.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Bill Gallo Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1960/1970" type="inclusive">1960-1970</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">12 linear ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Nearly 900 original sports cartoons from the New York 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph>, sketches, correspondence and two newspapers.</abstract>
      <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">148996</unitid>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Bill Gallo (1922-2011) was an award-winning American sports cartoonist. </p><p>Born December 28, 1922 in New York City and raised in Astoria, Queens, William "Bill" Gallo grew up wanting to work for a newspaper. His father, an immigrant from the Basque region of Spain, worked at the  the Spanish-language paper 
        
        <emph render="italic">La Prensa</emph>. Gallo acquired his art education through Columbia University and  what is now the School of Visual Arts through the GI Bill. </p>
      <p>In 1941, he joined the staff of the New York 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph> and worked as a reporter, caption writer and staff artist.  He left in 1942 to serve with the United States Marine Corps but returned in 1945 after a tour of duty that included  Iwo Jima. In 1954 his first cartoon was published in the <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph>  and he became the paper's sports cartoonist in 1960,  after the death of cartoonist Leo O'Melia.   Not only did Gallo depict many figures in the sports world, he has  also met and befriended many prominent athletes including Muhammad Ali and baseball's Joe Dimaggio. </p>
      <p>Gallo has been an active member of the National Cartoonists Society. He served two terms as  NCS president and won many of their awards including best sports cartoonist (1968-1970, 1972-1973, 1983-1985, 1987-1988), the Silver T-Square Award (1978), and the Elzie Segar Award (1976). In 1998 NCS recognized him with the  Milton Caniff Lifetime Achievement Award. Gallo's work has also won several Page One Awards from the
New York Newspaper Guild.  Gallo has been a member of the New York Boxing Writers (serving as president), the Baseball Writers Association, Professional Football Writers, Turf Writers and The New York Press Association. His work is represented in the permanent collections of the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, New York.</p>
      <p>An estimated 15,000 cartoons by Gallo have appeared in the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph> and in 2000, Gallo published 
        
        <emph render="italic">Drawing a Crowd: Bill Gallo's Greatest Sports Moments</emph>. As of 2009, Gallo was still writing a weekly sports column for the 
          
          <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph>.</p>
                                          <p>Gallo died in May 2011 of complications of
                                                  pneumonia.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The 
        
        <emph render="bold">Bill Gallo Papers</emph>, consist of four series. The main series, <emph render="bold">Cartoons</emph> contains almost 900 original sports cartoons drawn by Gallo for the New York 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph> during the 1960s. Gallo covered all sports but professional baseball, professional football and boxing are heavily represented in this particular collection. Only a handful of cartoons focus on college sports with particular attention given to the National Invitation Tournament.</p>
      <p>Aside from regular depictions of the New York Mets, Yankees, Rangers, Giants and Jets and their star players, coaches and managers, Gallo commented on rivalries (such as that between the New York Yankees and the Boston "Rob" Sox as Gallo dubbed them) and the standings within particular leagues and divisions. Outside of the New York area, Gallo gave particular attention to the Los Angeles Dodgers (formerly of Brooklyn). Gallo also utilized several recurring characters including Basement Bertha and Denny Deflator as well as the "three and a half guys" who were fans of basketball and the "half of a guy" who like hockey. </p>
      <p>Providing more than simply a caricature of a particular team or event, Gallo frequently presented analysis of a sporting event as if it were a short sports story and even explained the  history of particular teams or figures such as the Southern Illinois University's mascot, the Saluki.  A handful of  cartoons in this vein are referred to by Gallo as "columntoons". Gallo also depicted the life of sportswriters who according to him, practically lived at Madison Square Garden as well as the process he went through in producing a daily cartoon. Also worth noting is Gallo's running gag depicting conflict between husbands who like to watch sports on television and their wives, with the wives typically drawn as being locked in the closet for the duration of Sunday afternoon's televised games. </p>
      <p>Almost all of the cartoons are undated and therefore have been arranged in alphabetical order by caption. Gallo drew the cartoons on illustration board with pen and ink and dot screening. Captions appear in pencil. The cartoons vary in size, with most measuring approximately 11 1/4" x 14 ½". There are 13 cartoons without captions and 25 oversize cartoons which can be found at the end of the series.  </p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Sketches</emph> contains 17 undated items by Gallo drawn primarily in blue pencil on paper. The sketches  measure 8 ½" x 11 and  many contain written ideas for cartoons.   </p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph> includes incoming correspondence (1960-1967, almost all typed), primarily from individuals thanking Gallo for original cartoons. Correspondents include William Shea, New York Giants coach Allie Sherman, Robert O. Fishel of  the New York Yankees, and Soupy Sales as well as representatives from the Chicago Cubs,  the Pro Football Hall of Fame and the Baseball Hall of Fame and Museum.  Also of interest are a few pieces of fan mail. </p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Newspapers</emph> is comprised of two issues (final and night owl editions) of the January 17, 1970  New York 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph> in which a cartoon by Gallo appeared. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The cartoons are arranged alphabetically by caption with oversize cartoons located at the end of the collection. Correspondence is arranged in chronological order.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>See also the 
        
        <archref href="../k/king_w.htm">Warren King Papers</archref> for additional cartoons (editorial) from the New York 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph> from this time period. </p>
      <p>&scrc_name; has collections of over one hundred cartoonists.  Please refer to &subjindex; for a complete listing.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Art -- Cartoonists</subject>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Ali, Muhammad, 1942-  -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Berra, Yogi, 1925- -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Durocher, Leo, 1906-1991 -- Caricatures and cartoons.  </persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Ewbank, Weeb -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Francis, Emile -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Frazier, Joe, 1944- -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Gallo, Bill.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Griffith, Emile -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Houk, Ralph, 1919- -- Caricatures and cartoons. </persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Lombardi, Vince -- Caricatures and cartoons. </persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Mantle, Mickey, 1931-1995 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Namath, Joe Willie, 1943- -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Sherman, Allie -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">Stengel, Casey -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">Los Angeles Dodgers (Baseball team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">New York Giants (Football team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">New York Jets (Football team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">New York Knickerbockers (Basketball team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">New York Mets (Baseball team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">New York Rangers (Hockey team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">New York Yankees (Baseball team) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf">Daily news (New York, N.Y. : 1920)</title>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">American wit and humor, Pictorial.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Baseball -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Basketball -- Caricatures and cartoons. </subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Boxing -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Caricatures and cartoons -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cartoonists -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cartoonists -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Coaches (Athletics) -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Football -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Hockey -- Caricatures and cartoons. </subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Horse racing -- Caricatures and cartoons. </subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Sports -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Sports general managers -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Sportswriters -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Cartoons (humorous images)</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Newspapers.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Preliminary sketches.</genreform>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Cartoonists.</occupation>
    </controlaccess>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
                       all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
                       materials in this collection. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Bill Gallo Papers,
        
        <lb/>&su_name;</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Gift of 
        
        <persname role="donor">Bill Gallo</persname>, 1966-1967, 1969-1970.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <!--
            <appraisal encodinganalog="583"><head>Appraisal Information</head><p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       --><!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584"><head>Accruals</head><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Inventory</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Cartoons</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1960/1969" type="inclusive">1960-1969</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>A-Ben </unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
About Face:  Leo Durocher, Chicago Cubs
              
              <lb/>Acrobatics: Chicago Cubs
              
              <lb/>
 
Advance Publicity: Jim Brown, New York Giants, Cleveland Browns
              
              <lb/>
 Advice to the Glovelorn (2 cartoons): boxing
              
              <lb/>
After the Brawl is Over: boxing, Joey Archer, Holley Mims 
              
              <lb/>Again, Again and Again: baseball, Solly Hemus
              
              <lb/>
The Agony and the Agony: New York Giants, Cleveland Browns
              
              <lb/>
Ah, but there was this one day in N.Y....: Don Larsen, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Ali Cat: Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
All alone, by the...: Casey Stengel, Jimmy Wynn
              
              <lb/>
All About Those Guys in the Middle: boxing
              
              <lb/>
All Our Eggs in One Basket All Together: New York Knicks, Dave Debusschere, Frank McGuire
              
              <lb/>
All Together Now!: NY News sports staff
              
              <lb/>All Together: Casey Stengel
              
              <lb/>
Allie's Burden: Allie Sherman, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
... and a Happy New Year: Weeb Ewbank, Hank Stram, Kansas City Chiefs
              
              <lb/>
And Now, A Commercial...: New York Yankees, Minnesota Twins, Cal Griffin
              
              <lb/>
And Protect Yourselves At All Times: Astrodome
              
              <lb/>
And the winner is...: Kentucky Derby
              
              <lb/>
Angel on Their Shoulder: Al Kaline, Carl Yastrzemski, Albie Pearson, American League, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Another season, another reason: holidays and regional sports teams
              
              <lb/>
Answered: Mets, Tommie Agee
              
              <lb/>
Any Kid'll Tel Ya...: Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
Anybody Here Seen...: New York Yankees, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Anyway You Look At It: Muhammad Ali, Floyd Mayweather
              
              <lb/>
Apartment Hunters: Detroit Tigers, Los Angeles Angels, Boston Red Sox, Chicago White Sox, Minnesota Twins
              
              <lb/>
Applause From This Corner: Boston Red Sox,  Ted Williams
              
              <lb/>
The Arbitrator: Joe Cronin
              
              <lb/>
Army Gets The Girl: Navy, Army, John Cartright
              
              <lb/>
Army Tosses a Late Party: Navy, Army, John Cartright, Carl Woessner, Steve Lindell
              
              <lb/>
The Art of Walking Backwards: baseball standings
              
              <lb/>
Assignment, Fight Camp: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Assignment, Madison Square: boxing, Golden Gloves, National Invitation Tournament, Madison Square Gardens
              
              <lb/>
Astrodome Sideshow: Ernie Terrell, Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
AT - ten - shun!: New York Rangers, Emile Francis
              
              <lb/>
Au Revoir: Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>

Back In the Club: Floyd Mayweather, boxing
              
              <lb/>
Back In the Old Stable: New York Giants, Darrell Dess
              
              <lb/>
The Back of Me Hand and the Side of Me Foot: Pete Gogolak, National Football League, American Football League
              
              <lb/>
Back to the Board: Barry Goldwater, Allie Sherman, Weeb Ewbank
              
              <lb/>
Bad Manners: Warren Spahn, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Bag and Baggage: New York Mets, Juan Marichal
              
              <lb/>
Bang, Boom, Bashes and Dashes: boxing, New York Rangers, New York Knicks, Olympics
              
              <lb/>
Barney: Barney Ross
              
              <lb/>
Basket Weaving: boxing, National Invitation Tournament, Temple University, Madison Square Gardens
              
              <lb/>
Batter Up!: Baltimore Orioles, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
The Battle of the Bulge: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Be My Guest: Kentucky Derby
              
              <lb/>Be My Guest: New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
Beantown or Bust: Muhammad Ali, Sonny Liston
              
              <lb/>
The Bear Who Came to Dinner: Leo Durocher, Chicago Cubs, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Beatin' the Blitz: Gary Wood, Fran Tarkenton, Y.A. Tittle
              
              <lb/>
The Beautiful Balloon: Lew Alcindor, Bill Bradley
              
              <lb/>
The Beautiful People: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Beautiful Shot: National Basketball Committee, dunking
              
              <lb/>
Because It's There: Joe Cronin, Charles O.  Finley 
              
              <lb/>Because It's There: boxing, Golden Gloves (1968)
              
              <lb/>
Beg Pardon: Joe Kapp, Aaron Brown
              
              <lb/>
A Beginning and an End: Joe Frazier, George Chuvalo
              
              <lb/>
Behind the Scenes: Vince Lombardi, Green Bay Packers
              
              <lb/> Bench Warmers: New York Yankees</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ber-By</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
              <lb/>
The Berth of the Blues?: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Best of Snow: sports news
              
              <lb/>
Best Sellers: New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Big Daddy: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Big Fish In A Big Pond: Hank Aaron, Mickey Mantle, Jimmy Foxx, Ted Williams, Met Ott, Lou Gehrig
              
              <lb/>
The Big Caper: American League, baseball
              
              <lb/>
The Big Caper (continued): Stan Musial, Dick Williams, Tom Yawkey
              
              <lb/>
A Big Hand For The Knicks: Walt Bellamy, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
The "Big" Hitters: New York Yankees, New York Mets, Bob Foster, Ralph Evans
              
              <lb/>
The Big Oh, Oh: New York Knicks, Oscar Robertson
              
              <lb/>
The Bigg Man: Verlon Biggs, Jackie Kemp, New York Jets, Buffalo Bills
              
              <lb/>
A Bird in the Hand Is Worth Two in the Busch: St. Louis Cardinals, Ken Boyer, New York Yankees, Bobby Richardson
              
              <lb/>
A Bird in the Hand ls Worth Two...: St. Louis Cardinals,  Jim Gentile
              
              <lb/>
A Bird on a Wing-Ding: Baltimore Orioles, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Birdland: World Series, Baltimore Orioles, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
Bird Watcher: Baltimore Orioles
              
              <lb/>Bird Watcher: St. Louis Cardinals, Bob Gibson 
              
              <lb/>
Birds, Bees and Baseball: Washington Senators, Detroit Tigers, St. Louis Cardinals, Eddie Stanky
              
              <lb/>
Blimp Overhead: boxing, Thad Spencer, Jimmy Ellis, Jerry Quarry
              
              <lb/>
Bonanza: horse racing, Eddie Neloy, Braulio Baeza
              
              <lb/>
Book of Knowledge: Johnny Sain, New York Yankees, Minnesota Twins, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>Boom or Bust: hockey, National Basketball Association, American Basketball Association, National Hockey League
              
              <lb/>
Boxing Notes from a Sketch Pad: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Boys Will Be Boys: National Football League, American Football League
              
              <lb/> 
The Brave Bulls: New York Giants, Allie Sherman, Tucker Fredrickson, Bob Timberlake, Ernie Koy Jr.
              
              <lb/>

Bright, My Foot!: Frank Howard, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
...and bringing up the rear, it's...: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Bubbling Over: New York Mets, Los Angeles Dodgers, Tommy Davis, Derrell Griffith, Jim Hickman
              
              <lb/>
Bugged: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Bum Dope: Los Angeles Dodgers, Claude Osteen
              
              <lb/>
Burp! (2 Cartoons): football, television
              
              <lb/>
By George, I think he's got it!: sportswriters
              
              <lb/></p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>C-E</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Calling A Turn: horse racing, Don Brumfield, Six Furlong Classic
              
              <lb/>
Calling An Audible Capitol Stuff: Denny McLain, New York Giants, San Francisco 49ers, Los Angeles Rams
              
              <lb/>Capitol Stuff: Washington Senators, Gil Hodges
              
              <lb/>
Case Closed: boxing
              
              <lb/>Case Closed?: Ford Frick 
              
              <lb/>
Cast of Characters: Boston Red Sox, St. Louis Cardinals, World Series (1967)
              
              <lb/>Cat-A-Pulter: Emile Francis, New York Rangers, Bob Seagren
              
              <lb/>
The Cat's Meow!: Emile Francis, National Hockey League
              
              <lb/>
The Cat's Paw: St. Louis Cardinals,  Detroit Tigers, Mickey Lolich
              
              <lb/>
Caught Off Guard: Allie Sherman, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
Chairmen of the Board: Mickey Lolich, Bob Gibson, Mayo Smith, St. Louis Cardinals, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
The Challenge: Bob Cleroux, Sonny Liston
              
              <lb/>
Chapter I: St. Louis Cardinals, Boston Red Sox, Stan Musial,  Dick Williams, World Series (1967)
              
              <lb/>
Chapter II: St. Louis Cardinals, Boston Red Sox, World Series (1967)
              
              <lb/>
Chapter III: St. Louis Cardinals, Boston Red Sox, World Series (1967)
              
              <lb/>
Chapter IV: St. Louis Cardinals, Boston Red Sox, World Series (1967)
              
              <lb/>
A Character Story: Nino Benvenuti, Emile Griffith
              
              <lb/>
Charge!: Kentucky Derby (1966)
              
              <lb/>Charge!: sports cartoons
              
              <lb/>
Charlie Dressen - A Baseball Man: Charlie Dressen, Detroit Tigers, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Chip Off the Ol' Block: Vince Lombardi
              
              <lb/>
Chitty Chitty Bang Bang?: Jerry Quarry, Jimmy Ellis
              
              <lb/>
Cinderfella?: New York Rangers, Stanley Cup
              
              <lb/>
Cliches (But, they ain't necessarily so): St. Louis Cardinals, New York Mets, Ken Harrelson, Joe Pepitone, New York Knicks, Lou Gehrig, baseball, football
              
              <lb/>
Close Quarters: National League, baseball, San Francisco Giants, Los Angeles Dodgers, Cincinnati Reds, Atlanta Braves, Pittsburgh Pirates
              
              <lb/> Collector's Item: New York Knicks, New York Rangers (November 1966)
              
              <lb/>
Color It Green: Weeb Ewbank
              
              <lb/>
Come an' Get Me!: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Come'n'Get It!: George Halas, Green Bay Packers, Chicago Bears
              
              <lb/>
Comin' and Goin': New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
C'mon Home, Knicks!: New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
C'mon Up!: Valery Brumel, high jumping
              
              <lb/>
Confrontation: Bob Foster, boxing
              
              <lb/>
Coolest Cat in Town: Emile Francis, Weeb Ewbank, Red Holzman, Allie Sherman, Gil Hodges, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Copy Cat: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Country of the Month: Muhammad Ali, Karl Mildenberger, Brian London
              
              <lb/>
Coupla Cutups: New Mets, George Weiss
              
              <lb/>
Court Room Drama: Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
Crossroads: Cus D'Amato, Jose Torres, Skeeter McClure
              
              <lb/>
C-R-A-Z-Y, Cat!: New York Rangers, Emile Francis
              
              <lb/>
A Crowded Room: Dan Topping, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
The Cubs Got It Made: Chicago Cubs
              
              <lb/>
A Cure for Achin' Backs: New York Rangers, Reggie Fleming, Bernie Geoffrion
              
              <lb/>
Darling of the day: Red Holzman, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
A Day with Grief: Emile Griffith, Joey Archer
              
              <lb/>
Decisions, Decisions, Decisions!: Emile Griffith, Dick Tiger
              
              <lb/>

Destroying the Evidence: Los Angeles Dodgers, New York 
              
              <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph>
              <lb/>
Did You Ever Notice?: National League, St. Louis Cardinals, New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Do You Know What WE Went and Did?:  New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Don't Fight It, Girls: football
              
              <lb/>
Don't Wait Up: Yonkers raceway, horse racing
              
              <lb/> Don Quixote: New York Mets, Yogi Berra, Wes Westrum
              
              <lb/> Dorian Clay: Muhammad Ali 
              
              <lb/>
Down the Line: American League, Joe Cronin
              
              <lb/>
Dream A Little Dream: Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
Dream World: Y.A. Tittle, Allie Sherman, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>

East Side, West Side: Frank McGuire, basketball
              
              <lb/>
Easy Now: Tom Matte
              
              <lb/>
Easy-When You Know How: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Eclipse: Mel Ott, Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
The Egg and I: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
The Envelope, Please...: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Even Steven: New York Mets, Charley Smith, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Everybody's Bag: Mickey Mantle, Ted Williams, Ron Swoboda, Eddie Stanky, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Everybody's Out of Step, but...: armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Excedrin Headache "No. 15": Richie Allen
              
              <lb/>
The Eye is on the Sparrow: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Eyes on the Ivy: Dartmouth College, Princeton University, Harvard University football</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>F-Hello</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Facts Fans and Fancy: New York Giants, football, baseball, Ron Swoboda, Ted Williams, Willie Pep, Ernie Lombardi, Sugar Ray Robinson
              
              <lb/>
False Alarm - We hope: gambling investigation, Pete Rozelle, football
              
              <lb/>
Famous LAST Words: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
The Fast Race: Maury Wills, Los Angeles Dodgers, San Francisco Giants, Jack Sanford
              
              <lb/>
Fatso: New York Mets 
              
              <lb/>
The Feature Race: New York Mets, New York Yankees 
              
              <lb/>
Festival Big Shots: Boston College, Joe Lapchick, Jim Walker, Providence, Bob Cousy
              
              <lb/>
A Few Words: New York Boxing Writers, Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
Fiddler on the Roof: Philadelphia, hockey,  basketball Madison Square Garden
              
              <lb/>
A Fight Columntoon: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Figure This: New York Giants, Minnesota Vikings, Cleveland Browns
              
              <lb/>
A Fine Kettle of Fish: New York Rangers, Chicago Blackhawks, New York Knicks, Boston Celtics, Long Island University, National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Fire at Will: Bowie Kuhn, Marvin Miller, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Fire Water: Rocky Colavito, Ralph Terry, Vic Davalillo, Cleveland Indians
              
              <lb/>
The First 50 are the Toughest: New York Mets (1966)
              
              <lb/>
The First, Last, and Always: New York Mets, New York Yankees, horse racing
              
              <lb/>
The First Rushes: Tucker Frederickson, Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>
First Time Out!: Little League
              
              <lb/>
Flag Wavers: Los Angeles Dodgers, San Francisco Giants, Pittsburgh Pirates, Chicago Cubs
              
              <lb/>
Flirting: Weeb Ewbank, New York Jets, Denver Broncos
              
              <lb/>
Folderama: San Francisco Giants, Los Angeles Dodgers, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Follow the Bouncing Ball: New York Rangers, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
Follow Up: Gil Hodges
              
              <lb/>
Football Is a Funny Game: Charlie Gogolak
              
              <lb/>
For Cabbies Only: John Huarte
              
              <lb/>
For Reel and For Real: New York Mets, Pittsburgh Pirates, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
...for the Trees: Yogi Berra, Ralph Houk, Minnesota Twins
              
              <lb/>
For Whom the Bell Tolls: boxing
              
              <lb/>
For Whom the Bells Toll: boxing, Sugar Ray Robinson
              
              <lb/>
Forget it, Kid!: football, television
              
              <lb/>
Forward, March!: New York Giants, Washington Redskins, New York Rangers, Chicago Blackhawks, New York Knicks, Los Angeles Lakers, Cazzie Russell
              
              <lb/>
Found - A Lost Art!: Ralph Houk, New York Yankees, Joe Verbanic
              
              <lb/>
The Foundling: Minnesota Vikings, Ron Yary, Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>
Fowl Ball: Atlanta Braves, Cleveland Indians
              
              <lb/>
From Here to Eternity: Yogi Berra
              
              <lb/>
From Little Acorns: Golden Gloves, boxing
              
              <lb/>
The Frustrated Puppet: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Full Up To Here: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Fun and Games: National League, baseball
              
              <lb/>

Garden Menagerie: New York Rangers, National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Gentlemen, an announcement!: San Francisco Giants, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
Gentlemen, be seated!: Sonny Liston
              
              <lb/>
Get in Line: George Chuvalo, Eduardo Corletti
              
              <lb/>
Getting the Message: Luis Tiant, Cleveland Indians, New York Yankees, Johnny Keane
              
              <lb/>
GIBSON, that's all pussycat!: Bob Gibson
              
              <lb/>
Girl Talk: Millrose Games
              
              <lb/>
Girl Watching: Peggy Fleming, Gabriele Seyfert, Joan Payson, New York Mets, Vera Shaw, Mildre Ignizio, bowling, figure skating, horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Glove's Labor Lost: New York Mets, Roy McMillan
              
              <lb/>
A Glutton: American League, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
Go!: sports cartoons
              
              <lb/>
Go Get 'Em, Clyde!: New York Yankees, Eddie Stanky
              
              <lb/>
Going, Going....:  Babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig
              
              <lb/>
Going to the Strong Box: Whitey Ford, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Goin' Outa' My Head: Joe Frazier, Jerry Quarry, New York Mets, Chicago Cubs, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Golden Gloves Reviewed - A HIT All the Way!: Golden Gloves, boxing
              
              <lb/>
The Golden Heritage: Sugar Ray Robinson (1969)
              
              <lb/>
Gonna Build A Mountain: Vince Lombardi
              
              <lb/> Good Catch, Roberto!: Roberto Clemente (1966)
              
              <lb/>
Good Field - No Hit: Joey Archer, Holly Mims, Hurricane Carter
              
              <lb/>
Good Field, Plenty Hit!: John Lobianco, Willie Pastrano, Emile Griffith, Jose Torres
              
              <lb/>
Good Grief!: Tucker Frederickson, Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>
Good Question: New York Yankees, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
Good Vintage Year?: Arnold Palmer, Jack Nicklaus, Tony Lema, U.S. Open
              
              <lb/>
The Good with the Bad: New York Rangers, Rod Gilbert
              
              <lb/>
Grape of Wrath: New  York Mets, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Gung-ho: Sandy Koufax, Cleveland Indians
              
              <lb/>
A Guy and a Doll: Eddie Stanky
              
              <lb/>
Haf - and - Haf: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Hair Raid: Ben Davidson
              
              <lb/>
Halvies: sports fans
              
              <lb/>
Hang In There!: New York Yankees, American League
              
              <lb/>
Hangin' In There: Yogi Berra
              
              <lb/>Hangin' In There: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Happiness is...: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Happiness is a Warm Blanket: Ralph Houk, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Happy Easter: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Happy Valentine: Allie Sherman, Ralph Houk, Leo Durocher
              
              <lb/>
The Happy Wanderer: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Happy Water: Mayo Smith, Red Schoendienst
              
              <lb/>
Hare! Hare!: Minnesota  Twins, Al Lopez, Chicago White Sox
              
              <lb/>Hare! Hare!: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Hatch as Hatch Can: Atlanta Falcons
              
              <lb/>
Hats Off!: Alan B. Shepard Jr.
              
              <lb/>
Hats Off, Commissioner!: Tom Seaver
              
              <lb/>
He May Be Wrong, But...: Floyd Patterson, Cus D'Amato
              
              <lb/>
He Must Be Doing Something Left: George Chuvalo, Ernie Terrell
              
              <lb/>
Headache No. 1: Richie Allen, Red Schoendienst
              
              <lb/>
Heads and Tails: horse racing, Belmont Stakes
              
              <lb/>
The Heavyweights: New York Mets, Don Drysdale, Manuel Ramos
              
              <lb/>
Hell Raiser?: Los Angeles Angels, Minnesota Twins, Detroit Tigers, Chicago White Sox
              
              <lb/>
Hello and Good-bye: boxing, Joe Falu, Stanley Ketchel
              
              <lb/>
Hello Yogi!: Yogi Berra</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Help-In</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
              <lb/>
Help!: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>Help!: boxing, Oscar Bonavena, Jimmy Ellis, hippies (August 1964- stamp on back reads, "Used in Time") 
              
              <lb/>
Here's the Picture: New York Yankees, Johnny Keane
              
              <lb/>
Here She Comes, Miss...: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Here was a Ballplayer: Mickey Cochrane
              
              <lb/>
Here's the Pitch: Rube Walker, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Hey, Look Me Over: Fred Hutchinson, Los Angeles Dodgers, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Hi Mom!: pitchers, Mother's Day
              
              <lb/>
High Card: Mike Burke:
              
              <lb/> 
Hip to Each Other: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
The Hitless Blunders: Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
Hold Everything!: San Francisco Giants, Bill Stafford, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Holy Cow!: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Horse Lovers: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Horsin' Around: New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Hot Dog!: New York Rangers, National Hockey League expansion (1967)
              
              <lb/>
Hot Stove League: sportswriters, athletes
              
              <lb/>
Hot Stuff: American League, baseball
              
              <lb/>
House Rules: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
How 'Bout That?: boxing, Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
How It Is: Baltimore Orioles, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
Huffin' and Puffin': Los Angeles Dodgers, Minnesota Twins 
              
              <lb/>
Hurray for Harry Howell: New York Rangers, Boston Bruins, Harry Howell
              
              <lb/>

I did it "My Way": 
              
              <lb/>
I May Be Wrong, But... (42 cartoons): Green Bay Packers, football, Ismael Laguna, Carlos Ortiz, New York Jets, Belmont, Oscar Bonavena, Joe Frazier, 
Floyd Patterson, Vince Lombardi, Manuel Ramos, New York Mets, New York Yankees, horse racing, Kentucky Derby, Y.A. Tittle, New York Giants, Joe Namath, Sugar Ray Robinson, Mickey Mantle, Minnesota Twins, Emile Griffith, Willie Pastrano, Joey Archer, Texas, Jose Torres, Dick Tiger, Nino Benvenuti 
              
              <lb/>
I'll Drink to That: New York Jets, New York Knicks, New York Rangers, sports fans
              
              <lb/>I'm yours!: Allie Sherman, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
If You Ask Me...: Oscar Bonavena
              
              <lb/>
Immovable: Bart Starr, Vince Lombardi, St. Louis Rams
              
              <lb/>
The Important Things...: Tommie Agee, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
The Important Things in Life: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Impressions of the Fight Camps: Joe Frazier, George Chuvalo
              
              <lb/>
Impressions of a Garden Fight: Oscar Bonavena, Joe Frazier
              
              <lb/>
Improbable Pictures: Chicago White Sox, Chicago police, New York Mets, Washington Senators, Floyd Patterson, Fran Tarkenton
              
              <lb/>Improbable Pictures: M. Donald Grant, Ralph Houk, Joe Pepitone, Hank Bauer, Vince Lombardi, Allie Sherman, Joe Namath, Joe Dimaggio, Red Schoendienst
              
              <lb/>Improbable Pictures: Joe Namath, New York Giants, New York Jets, Vince Lombardi, Spike Eckert, Bob Foster, Frank Depaula
              
              <lb/>Improbable Pictures: Kentucky Derby, Joe Garagiola, New York Giants, New York Jets, Oscar Bonavena, M. Donald Grant
              
              <lb/>Improbable Pictures: Joe Namath, Earl Morrall, Lew Alcindor, New York Jets, Weeb Ewbank, Ben Davidson
              
              <lb/>
In a Chicago Shanty: Chicago
              
              <lb/>
In a State of Shock: New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
In the Driver's Seat?: New York Rangers, New York Knicks, playoffs
              
              <lb/>
In Good Company: high school athletes
              
              <lb/>
In Victory We Cry - In Defeat We Cry: Manuel Ramos, Joe Frazier
              
              <lb/>
The Indomitable Snowman: skiing
              
              <lb/>
The Infernal Machine: Mickey Mantle, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Inherit the Wind: Leo Durocher, Eddie Stanky
              
              <lb/>
The Intangibles: New York Jets
              
              <lb/>
Interloper: Leo Durocher, Red Schoendienst
              
              <lb/>
Into the Lion's Mouth: Vince Lombardi, Green Bay Packers
              
              <lb/>
Into the Vault: Charles O. Finley </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Is-L</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
              <lb/>
Ismael Laguna Cha-Cha-Cha: Ismael Laguna, Carlos Ortiz
              
              <lb/>
It Figures:  basketball, hockey
              
              <lb/>
It Seems to Me... (10 cartoons): Yogi Berra, Gil Hodges, New York Knicks, Sonny Liston, football, Emile Francis, Tucker Frederickson, Floyd Patterson,  New York Giants, Vince Lombardi, Jimmy Ellis, Jerry Quarry, New York Mets, New York Yankees, Ralph Houk, Academy of Professional Sports, basketball, horse racing, Lew Alcindor, Thad Spencer, Joe Namath
              
              <lb/>
It's a Raid: football, basketball, hockey
              
              <lb/>
It's All in the Way We See It: Emile Griffith, Joey Archer
              
              <lb/>
It's Like This...: New York Yankees, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
lt's Like This, See...: New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
It's...It's Superbird!: Ralph Houk, New York Mets, New York Yankees, St. Louis Cardinals, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
It's the Berries: New York Mets, Willie Davis
              
              <lb/>
It's What's Happening, Baby: football, television
              
              <lb/>
It's Written All Over His Face!: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>

John Hancock, Et Al: Sandy Koufax, Don Drysdale, National Archives 
              
              <lb/>
The Joker is Wild: baseball, Satchel Paige, Charles O. Finley
              
              <lb/>
Jose by a Whisker: Jose Torres
              
              <lb/>
The Journey (Cont' d): Sugar Ray Robinson, Sonny Liston
              
              <lb/>
Just Thinkin': Johnny Keane, New York Yankees, bunting
              
              <lb/>

Keane Observations: Ralph Houk, Johnny Keane, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Keeping Posted:  Gary Wood, Pittsburgh Steelers, Elliot Ness
              
              <lb/>
Kelly Again!: horse racing, Kelso, Gun Bow
              
              <lb/>
Kicked Upstairs: Warren Spahn, New York Mets, San Francisco Giants
              
              <lb/>
Kid Ralphie: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Kid White Shoes makes an Impression: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Knight Ball, Anyone? Knock, Knock: baseball, pitching
              
              <lb/>Knock Knock: Long Island University, National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Knock, Knock (You know who's there, Joey!): Dick Tiger, Joey Giardelllo
              
              <lb/>

Ladies Day: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Landing a Mark: Muhammad Ali, Ernie Terrell
              
              <lb/>
Last Chance Saloon: Montreal Canadiens, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
The Last Drop...: Whitey Ford
              
              <lb/>
Lasting Impressions?: Oscar Bonavena, George Chuvalo
              
              <lb/>
The Laundryman Cometh: New York Rangers, Emile Francis
              
              <lb/>
Leading the Chorus: Allie Sherman, Gary Wood
              
              <lb/>
Legacy to Youth: John Leonard Martin
              
              <lb/>
Lesson in Philosophy: New York Mets, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Let's Build a Stairway to...: New York Mets, National Football League
              
              <lb/>
Let's Have a Hoss Quiz: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Let's Have a Sports Quiz (4 cartoons): horse racing, college basketball, baseball 
              
              <lb/>
Let's Not lose Our Heads: Ralph Houk, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
Let Us Pray: baseball, Robert F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Letters to Gilly...No. 3: New York Mets, Gil Hodges
              
              <lb/>
Letters to Ralphie...No. 1: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Letters to Ralphie...No. 2: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Letters to Ralphie...No. 3: National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Letters to Ralphie...No. 4: Stanley Cup  (1968)
              
              <lb/>
Life in a Goldfish Bowl: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Like Grant took LA: Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
Like Ham an' Eggs: New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
The Lil' Ol' Sign Maker: St. Louis Cardinals, Stan Musial, Red Schoendienst
              
              <lb/>
Lil' Two-Gun is Star Struck: New York Yankees, Baltimore Orioles, Hank Bauer
              
              <lb/>
Listen to the 'Mocking' Bird: Muhammad Ali, George Chuvalo
              
              <lb/>
A Little Give and Take: Baltimore Orioles, New York Mets, astrology
              
              <lb/>
Living Dolls (5 cartoons): Tucker Frederickson, Vince Lombardi, Washington Senators, Nat Fleischer, New York Knicks, Bob Nevin, Eddie Stanky, Joe Pepitone, Charlie Smith, William Eckert, Jimmy Ellis, Joe Frazier, Joe Namath, Red Holzman, Alex Webster, Clyde Frazier, Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>
The Long Season: Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>
Long Wind vs. Long Pants: Muhammad Ali, Archie Moore
              
              <lb/>
Look What They Did to the Blue Room!: Camille Henry, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Look Who'll Settle Things: St. Louis Cardinals, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Lord Knows: Walter O'Malley, expansion
              
              <lb/>
A Loser: Los Angeles Dodgers, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Loser's Weepers: Jerry Quarry, Jimmy Ellis, Buster Mathis, Joe Frazier
              
              <lb/>
Lovers: Vince Lombardi, championships</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>M-On</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Makin' the Scene: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Making Waves: Arthur Goldberg, Curt Flood, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Man of La Shea: Yogi Berra
              
              <lb/>
Man of Letters: Boston Red Sox, Dick Williams, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
The Man that Got Away: Carl Yastrzemski, New York Yankees, Boston Red Sox, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Mara Tech's School Song: football
              
              <lb/>
Match Race: Ralph Houk, Gil Hodges, New York Yankees, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Matter over Bind: New York Yankees, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
May the Best Man Win: New York Mets, Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
Meanwhile...: Boston Red Sox
              
              <lb/>
Meanwhile, Back at the ...: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Meanwhile, Over at the Boyers...: Clete Boyer, Ken Boyer
              
              <lb/>
Meet Nino - the New One: Nino Benvenuti
              
              <lb/>
Member of the Wedding: Muhammad Ali, Luci Johnson, Bill Gallo
              
              <lb/>
Membership Drive: Emile Griffith, Manny Gonzalez
              
              <lb/>
Men of Letters (5 cartoons): readers, baseball, , horse racing, boxing, college basketball, Madison Square Garden
              
              <lb/>
The Merry Monster: Minnesota Twins, American League
              
              <lb/>
Mirror, Mirror...: San Francisco Giants, Los Angeles Dodgers, Pittsburgh Pirates
              
              <lb/>
Mirror, Mirror on the Wall...: Wilt Chamberlain
              
              <lb/>
Missing - One Paddle: Ralph Houk, Yogi Berra, Johnny Keane
              
              <lb/>
Mission Impossible: Vince Lombardi, Darlye Lamonica
              
              <lb/>
Moment of Truth: Bill Rohr, Steve Barber
              
              <lb/>
Moon over Houston: basketball
              
              <lb/>
More Green Salad, Please: Weeb Ewbank, New York Jets, Superbowl
              
              <lb/>
The Morning Line: baseball
              
              <lb/>
The Moving Target Fights...: Joey Giardello, Dick Tiger
              
              <lb/>
Mule Train: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
My Secretary Speaks: boxing, New York Jets, Vince Lombardi
              
              <lb/>
Mystery Man: soccer referees
              
              <lb/>


Name Dropper: New York Yankees, Johnny Keane
              
              <lb/>
Name of the Game: Warren Giles, National League, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Nee-no, Nee-no - No! No!: Emile Griffith, Nino Benvenuti
              
              <lb/>
Needles in the Haystack: Joe Pepitone, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Never Say Die: Philadelphia Phillies, Houston Colts
              
              <lb/>Never Say Die: Muhammad Ali, Sugar Ray Robinson
              
              <lb/>
New Boss Hoss?: horse racing, Kelso
              
              <lb/>
New Faces Reviewed: boxing
              
              <lb/>
The New Garden is Ready to Sprout Cauliflower: Buster Mathis, Joe Frazier, Emile Griffith, Nino Benvenuti
              
              <lb/>
New Head Man: Steve Owens, Heisman trophy (1969)
              
              <lb/>
New Kid on the Block: National League, Montreal Expos
              
              <lb/>New Kid on the Block: National Basketball Association, American Basketball Association 
              
              <lb/>
New Toy in Town: Madison Square Garden
              
              <lb/>

New York is a ...: John Lindsay, New York Jets, New York Giants, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>Next Week, the Palace!: Leo Durocher, Eddie Stanky
              
              <lb/>
Next?: Muhammad Ali, draft
              
              <lb/>
A Night at the Gloves with Bill Gallo (part 1 and 2): Golden Gloves, boxing
              
              <lb/>
The Night Joey G. Lost It All: Joey Giardelo, Dick Tiger
              
              <lb/>
The Night of the Bumble Bee: Muhammad Ali, Sugar Ray Robinson
              
              <lb/>
A Night Out: hockey, basketball, Dave DeBusschere
              
              <lb/>
1925-1968: Madison Square Garden
              
              <lb/>
No Contest: Gene Mauch, Philadelphia Phillies, Montreal Expos (1969)
              
              <lb/>
No Guarantee: football, quarterbacks
              
              <lb/>
No Life with Father: sports, television, wives
              
              <lb/>
No Matter How Ya Slice It: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
No Mercy! (Chapter Six): Boston Red Sox
              
              <lb/>
No, No Ralphie -- It's a Flower Pot: Ted Williams, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
No Other Way: Minnesota Vikings, television, wives
              
              <lb/>
No Room at the Top:  New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Nobody's Perfect: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
...Nowhere in a Hurry: Joe Cronin, Charles O. Finley
              
              <lb/>
The Nominees: Ralph Houk, Gil Hodges (1968)
              
              <lb/>
Not Seeing's Believin': New York Knicks, Ned Irish, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>


O, Well, That's Show Biz: sportswriters
              
              <lb/>
October Morn: St. Louis Cardinals
              
              <lb/>
The Odd Couple: Ted Williams, Yogi Berra
              
              <lb/>
Of Things to Come: football
              
              <lb/>
Off the Wagon: Los Angeles Dodgers, San Francisco Giants, Pittsburgh Pirates
              
              <lb/>
Official Greeter: Ralph Houk, Washington Senators
              
              <lb/>
Oh, Johnny!: New York Jets, Joe Namath, Mike Taliaferro
              
              <lb/>
Oh, the Poor Fish: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Oh, Ralphie!: New  York Yankees, Bill Rohr
              
              <lb/>
OK, Floyd - You're a Stand-up Guy!: Eddie Floyd
              
              <lb/>
OK, Let's Face lt!: Green Bay Packers, Phil Bengston, Vince Lombardi
              
              <lb/>
The Ol' Clean-up Hitter is Up: Poncho Gonzales, tennis
              
              <lb/>
The Ol' Creek: World Series, Los Angeles Dodgers, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
On His Guard: Eddie Stanky, Dick Williams
              
              <lb/>
On the Brink: Baltimore Orioles
              
              <lb/>
Once There was a Scarecrow...: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Once Upon a Time...: St. Louis Cardinals, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
One Knock Deserves Another: Roger Maris
              
              <lb/>
One of Our Fastballs is Missing: Johnny Keane, Jim Bouton (April 6, 1965)
              
              <lb/>
One Scrambled Coming Up: New York Giants, Fran Tarkenton
              
              <lb/>
One Week Later...: New York Giants, New York Jets, New York Rangers, John Lindsay
              
              <lb/>
One Year Later...: Notre Dame, Michigan State University, football
              
              <lb/>
Only Turkey In Town: New York Giants, New York Jets, New York Rangers, New York Knicks, New York Mets</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Oo-R</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Ooh, Do We Worry!: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/> Oops!: Los Angeles Dodgers, Carl Furillo
              
              <lb/>
The Open Champ: Ben Hogan, Jack Nicklaus, Arnold Palmer, Julius Boros, Frank Beard, Gary Player
              
              <lb/>
Open Letter: New York Mets, Casey Stengel
              
              <lb/>Open Letter: Joe Namath
              
              <lb/>
An Open Letter: Bill Gallo, Colts
              
              <lb/> Opening Day - 1965: Mickey Mantle, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Orbiting...: Reggie Jackson
              
              <lb/>
The Other Side of the Tracks: Yankee Stadium
              
              <lb/>
Our Changing Times: Easter, hockey, basketball
              
              <lb/>
Our Deal: Red Holzman, Emile Francis, New York Knicks, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Our Era: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Our World: New York Giants, Cleveland Browns, Christopher Columbus
              
              <lb/>
Out of Sight, Out of Bind:  Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Over 'N"Out!: Navy, Army, Pat Donnelly
              
              <lb/>
Overnight Inflation: boxing, Nino Benvenuti
              
              <lb/>
Ownerships: Boston Celtics, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>


Panama Hotties: Panama, horse racing, baseball, boxing
              
              <lb/>
Pardon My Glove: Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
Partial Eclipse: Elvin Hayes, Lew Alcindor, college athletes
              
              <lb/>
Passing Fancy: Jack Kemp, New York Jets, Buffalo Bills, Pete Gogolak
              
              <lb/>
Paul Bunyan, Where are You?: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Peace is Hell: National Football League, American Football League
              
              <lb/>Peek-A-Boo: Floyd Patterson, Jose  Torres
              
              <lb/>
Perchance to Dream...: New York  Rangers, New York Knicks, Allie Sherman
              
              <lb/>
Perish the Thought: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Perusing the News: Joey Archer
              
              <lb/>
Philadelphia Story: Philadelphia Phillies, Frank Thomas, Gene Mauch
              
              <lb/>
Pia Mia: horse racing, Johnny Sellers, Pia Starr
              
              <lb/>
The Picture: American League
              
              <lb/>
Picture 145: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Pin (Stripe) Money: New York Yankees, Roger Maris, Roy Hamey
              
              <lb/>
Pitchers Don't Hit: Willie McCovey, Tom Seaver
              
              <lb/>
Play Ball!: Winter Olympics, Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Play Ball -. er, Hockey?: baseball, hockey
              
              <lb/>
Play, Gypsy: Joe Harris, Curtis Cokes
              
              <lb/>
The Play's the Thing: television, sports teams
              
              <lb/>
Playin' His Cards Right: St. Louis Cardinals, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>Please, No Jokes!: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Pop Art: Zora Folley
              
              <lb/>
Pop Goes the Weasel: Ralph Houk, Whitey Ford, injuries
              
              <lb/>
Position Wanted: Tony Kubek, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
The Possible Dream: New York Yankees, American League
              
              <lb/>
Press Conference: Ford Frick, William Eckert
              
              <lb/>
Press Releases: sports news items
              
              <lb/>
Prisoner of Love: football, television (1966-1967)
              
              <lb/>Prisoner of Love: New York Knicks, New York  Rangers
              
              <lb/>Prisoner of Love: Leo Durocher, Chicago Cubs, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
The Prizefighter and the Washerwoman: George Chuvalo, boxing
              
              <lb/>
Psst, Don't Tell Anybody, but...: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Pssst - Ralphie Comes Out Swingin'!: Ralph Houk, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Public Enemy: Madison Square Gardens
              
              <lb/>
Punch Bowl - 18,759 Served in The Garden: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Punch Lines (4 cartoons): boxing
              
              <lb/>
Put On: Washington Senators
              
              <lb/>


The Quest: Bud Harrelson, Tom Seaver
              
              <lb/>
Quick Change (Relief) Artist: New York Yankees, New York Mets, Hal Reniff
              
              <lb/>

The Rains Came: San Francisco Giants
              
              <lb/>
Ralphie at the Hat: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Ralphie - el: Ralph Houk, Al Downing, cartoons
              
              <lb/>
Ralphie Falls... : Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Ready, Aim...: Muhammad Ali, Brian London
              
              <lb/>Ready, Aim...: Major League Players' Association
              
              <lb/>
Ready When You Are, Y. B.: Yogi Berra, the Odd Couple
              
              <lb/>
A Real Drag: Warren Giles
              
              <lb/>
Recipe for Success: Dick Tiger
              
              <lb/>
Reduced to a Stepping Stone: Joe Frazier, Doug Jones
              
              <lb/>
Reflections: boxing
              
              <lb/>Reflections: Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
Rembrandt: Yankee Stadium
              
              <lb/>
Requiem for a Heavyweight: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Rise and Shine: Lee McPhail
              
              <lb/>Rise and Shine: cartoons, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
Roar, Mouse, Roar!: Bradley University, Long Island University, National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Roll Out the Barrel: New York Yankees, Andy Robustelli, spring training
              
              <lb/>
Room For One More: New York Jets, Weeb Ewbank
              
              <lb/>
Romeo and Juliet Cont'd.: Wes Westrum, Leo Durocher, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
The Rooters: Little League
              
              <lb/>
Rub a Dub - Dub: Chicago Blackhawks, Bobby Hull
              
              <lb/>
Runs, Hits and Errors: baseball</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Sa-Sh</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Sabbatical: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
A Sad Story: Wellington Mara, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
A SAINT, You Say?: Jim Taylor
              
              <lb/>
The Same to You, Fella: New York Giants, New York Jets
              
              <lb/>
Sandy-All Sandy!: Sandy Koufax
              
              <lb/>
The Scene Stealer: Warren Giles, Joe Namath
              
              <lb/>
School's in Session: Hank Bauer
              
              <lb/>
Score One: tennis
              
              <lb/>
The Search: Muhammad Ali, George Chuvalo, Ernie Terrell
              
              <lb/>
Second Thoughts: readers
              
              <lb/>
Secret Love: Leo Durocher, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Security is a Five-Letter Word: Green Bay Packers
              
              <lb/>
See How They Run: baseball, horse racing, soccer
              
              <lb/>
Set 'Em Up, Barkeep!: Allie Sherman, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
72 - Hour Leave: Lew Alcindor, Bob Seagren, Millrose Games, New York Rangers, Dave Patrick
              
              <lb/>
Shaking the Rafters: Leo Durocher, Chicago Cubs
              
              <lb/>
The Shape of Things... : Wilt Chamberlain, Oscar Bonavena
              
              <lb/>
Shave and a Haircut?: Sal Magile, baseball
              
              <lb/>
She May Be Wrong, But: football
              
              <lb/> She's No Lady: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Shocking: St. Louis Cardinals, Chicago Cubs, Leo Durocher
              
              <lb/>
Shootout: Earl Monroe, National Basketball Association
              
              <lb/>
A Shot an' A Chaser: Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
Show Credentials at All Times: Joe Medwick, Red Ruffing, Baseball Hall of Fame
              
              <lb/>
The Show Off: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Shuffle Off to Buffalo: O.J. Simpson
              
              <lb/>
Shuffle Off to Cooperstown: Boston Red Sox, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Shut-in's: Ralph Houk, World Series
              
              <lb/>
Sign of the Times : Muhammad Ali, draft
              
              <lb/>
Signs of the Times: Walt Frazier, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
Singles Game: tennis
              
              <lb/>
Sissy Stuff: New York Yankees, Hank Bauer
              
              <lb/>
Sittin' Pretty: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>Six Blocks of Granite: Casey Stengel, Vince Lombardi
              
              <lb/>
The Skaters Waltz: New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
Slants on Pants: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Smart Alec!: computer predictions
              
              <lb/>
Snow Use: snow, Minnesota Vikings, St. Louis Rams, Cleveland Browns
              
              <lb/></p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>So-To</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">10</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>So Goes: New York Jets, Joe Namath, Los Angeles Dodgers, Sandy Koufax
              
              <lb/>
So - Nothing's Perfect : Pete Rozelle, Superbowl
              
              <lb/>
So There!: Walter O'Malley, Maury Wills
              
              <lb/>So There!: New York Jets, American Football League, record attendance
              
              <lb/>
So, What Else is New?: Judge Kenesaw
              
              <lb/>
So, What's the Big Idea?: readers
              
              <lb/>
Some Got It - Some Ain't: Joe Frazier, Yank Durham, Jerry Quarry, Chick Wergeles
              
              <lb/>
Some Tom-A-Hawk: Al Dark
              
              <lb/>
Somebody Up There...: Mel Allen
              
              <lb/>
Sorry About That, Wes: athletes, Wes Westrum
              
              <lb/>
The Sound of Mu$ic: John Huarte
              
              <lb/>
Space Grabbers: New York Mets, Apollo 11
              
              <lb/>
Special Delivery: Valentine's Day
              
              <lb/>
Spectator Sports: Joe Kapp
              
              <lb/>
Spell It Out: Temple University, Virginia Tech, De Paul University, New York University, National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Spirit of 75: Casey Stengel
              
              <lb/>
The Spirit of 86: Wilt Chamberlain
              
              <lb/>
Split Decision: Cesar Toviar, Carl Yastrzemski (1967)
              
              <lb/>
The Spoiler?: Joe Namath, Boston Patriots, Weeb Ewbank, New York Jets
              
              <lb/>
Spots Before My Eyes: Joe Homer, New York Giants, Joe Frazier, Oscar Bonavena
              
              <lb/>Spots Before My Eyes: football ratings, hockey, boxing
              
              <lb/>
Spring Training: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Stand back, I'm still on: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Status Quo: Notre Dame, Michigan State University. football
              
              <lb/>
Sticks and Stones...: Jerry Quarry
              
              <lb/>
Still Out: Tucker Frederickson, Gale Sayers, New York Giants, Chicago Bears
              
              <lb/>
Still Puffin': Red Auerbach, Boston Celtics, Philadelphia 76ers
              
              <lb/>
Story of a Man: Primo Carnera
              
              <lb/>
Street Scene: Muhammad Ali, draft
              
              <lb/>
Strictly First Class: Bobby Hull, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
[Strictly From Hossville]: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Strictly Glovemen: Pete Richert, Joey Archer, pitching
              
              <lb/>
Strictly Instrumental: Yogi Berra, Harmonica Incident
              
              <lb/>
Strings That Bind Over: Bobby Hull
              
              <lb/>
Stripes Are Back: New York Yankees, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
The Strongman: sports stories, cartoons (1967)
              
              <lb/>
The Subject Is Mickey: Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
The Subject was Noses: New York Jets, New York Giants, attendance (November 2, 1968)
              
              <lb/>
Subway Alumni: Notre Dame, Purdue, football
              
              <lb/>
Success Story: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Sugar Coating: Emile Griffith, Manny Gonzalez, Sugar Ray Robinson 
              
              <lb/>
Sunday Dinner: Vince Lombardi, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
A Sunday Kind of Love: New York Jets, New York Giants, attendance
              
              <lb/>
Sunnyside Down: New York Mets, Los Angeles Dodgers 
              
              <lb/>
Super Sundae: Superbowl
              
              <lb/>
The Super Yankee: Joe Dimaggio, Mickey Mantle, Babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig
              
              <lb/>
The Supporting Cast: Lew Alcindor, UCLA, Houston
              
              <lb/>
Sure, and It's a Foin Blast: Notre Dame
              
              <lb/>
Sure Thing: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Sweet Charity: Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>


Tailor Made: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Tails, You Lose!: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Take the Bull By The...: George Weiss, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Take Two: Walter Babes, M. Donald Grant
              
              <lb/>
Tale's End?: American League
              
              <lb/>
A Tale of Two Cities: New York Rangers, Philadelphia Spectrum, Madison Square Garden
              
              <lb/>
Talk About 300 Hitters: bowling
              
              <lb/>
Talkin' to Himself: boxing, heavyweight champions
              
              <lb/>
Tall Timber: Brigham Young University, St. John's University, Providence College
              
              <lb/>
Tape Measure Job: Ross Moschitto, Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
Terrell's Recurrent Dream: Muhammad Ali, Ernie Terrell
              
              <lb/>
Testing: Vince Lombardi, Green Bay Packers
              
              <lb/>

That Race, That Fabulous Race:  Minnesota Twins, Boston Red Sox, Cal Ermer
              
              <lb/>
That's About the Size Of It: Army, Navy, football 
              
              <lb/>
That's the Ball Game!: baseball, Sandy Koufax
              
              <lb/>That's the Ball Game!: Gil Hodges, Ralph Houk, Washington Senators, Nelson Rockefeller
              
              <lb/>
That's Show Biz: Bill Bradley, Bing Devine, cartoons
              
              <lb/>
There's a Kind a Walk You Walk: New York Mets, standings 
              
              <lb/>
And Thereby Hangs a Tail: Preakness 
              
              <lb/>
And Thereby Hangs a Tale: Cleveland Browns, Baltimore Colts, Johnny Unitas
              
              <lb/>
They're a System: New York Mets 
              
              <lb/>
They're Off!: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
They Came to Fight: Emile Griffith, Joey Archer
              
              <lb/>
They may be Wrong, But... (5 cartoons): professional football, horse racing, college football
              
              <lb/>

This Could Be the Straw...: boxing
              
              <lb/>
This Ol' House: Yankee Stadium
              
              <lb/>
This Really Hurts!: Sandy Koufax, Los Angeles Dodgers, pennant
              
              <lb/>And This Too Shall Pass: Jack Johnson, race riots, Primo Carnera, boxing, Sonny Liston, Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
Those Were The Days My Friend: Willie Mays, Mickey Mantle, Ike Williams, golf, college basketball, Casey Stengel 
              
              <lb/>
The Thought is There: Mother's Day, baseball
              
              <lb/>
Thought You'd Like To Know: Southern Illinois Salukis, Rutgers University, National Invitation Tournament
              
              <lb/>
Three and a half Guys: New York Knicks, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
A Thriller, Starring "Big Ernie" and Whatzisname:  Ernie Terrell
              
              <lb/>
Tiger at the Gates: Emile Griffith, Dick Tiger, Candy McFarland
              
              <lb/>
To the Pound?: Muhammad Ali, U.S. Army
              
              <lb/>
To the Wire: Dallas Cowboys, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
To You and You and You and You...: Christmas, New York 
              
              <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph>
              <lb/>
Togetherness: Tom Tresh, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>Togetherness: Eddie Stanky, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Tonsorial Splendor: Boston Red Sox
              
              <lb/>
Too Much!: Tommie Agee, New York Mets, Tommy Davis, Jack Fisher
              
              <lb/>
Top Banana: Johnny Murphey
              
              <lb/>
Topic A: Madison Square Garden, Irving M. Felt
              
              </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Tr-We Visit</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">11</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Training Camp Look-In: Emile Griffith
              
              <lb/>
The Tree That Grows In Chicago: Leo Durocher
              
              <lb/>
Trick or Treat: New York Rangers, National Hockey League expansion
              
              <lb/>
The Trouble with Cassius: Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
True or False: basketball, football, Detroit Tigers, horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Tryouts: New York Yankees, Yogi Berra (stamp on back reads February 10, 1968)
              
              <lb/>
The Trick in Pickin' Horses: Triple Crown 
              
              <lb/>
Truth of the Matter: baseball
              
              <lb/>TV Sketchpad: Yogi Berra, New  York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
21 - Skidoo!: Sandy Koufax, Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>Two Birds Talkin' Sports: Curt Simmons, Yogi Berra, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Two Footballs Talkin' Sports: American Football League, National Football League
              
              <lb/>
Two Gals Talkin' Sports: baseball
              
              <lb/>Two Guys Talkin' Sports (19 Cartoons):  horse racing, Vince Lombardi, New York Yankees, Lenny Dawson, Bart Starr, New York Rangers, boxing Ismael Laguna, Frankie Narvaez, betting, trades, San Francisco Giants, National League, Terry McDermott, Walter O'Malley, American Football League, Preakness
              
              <lb/>
Two Horses Talkin' Sports: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Two Kids Talkin' Sports (10 Cartoons): Y.A. Tittle, Roger Craig, Allie Sherman, Weeb Ewbank, Mickey Mantle, Joe Namath, Willie Mays, athletes, Casey Stengel, Billy Martin, Hank Bauer, Old Timer's Day, baseball, New  York Giants, Yankee Stadium, food, Cincinnati, Bob Cousy
              
              <lb/>Two Kids Watchin' Sports: baseball
              
              <lb/>
Two Losers Talkin' Sports: Ralph Houk, Preakness, New York Yankees: 
              
              <lb/>
Two Teams Talkin' Sports: New York Mets, Philadelphia Phillies
              
              <lb/>
Two Guys Watchin' Sports: Joey Archer 
              
              <lb/>
Two Paper Bags Still Intact: Doug Jones, Ernie Terrell 
              
              <lb/>
Two Sheep Talkin' Sports: Roger Maris, Mickey Mantle, Charles O. Finley, Kansas City
              
              <lb/>
Two Stitches In Time...: Eddie Stanky, Chicago White Sox, Rocky Colavito, Ken Boyer
              
              <lb/>

Under the Table: Bob Gibson, Detroit Tigers
              
              <lb/>
Unhappiness is...: New York Mets
              
              <lb/>

The Unknown Quantity: Sonny Liston, Floyd Patterson
              
              <lb/>
The Unreachable Star: Willie Mays
              
              <lb/>
The Unsinkable Major Houk: Ralph Houk, New York Yankees 
              
              <lb/>
Up There and Out of Sight: Los Angeles Lakers, Jerry West
              
              <lb/>


Visit From Ali: Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>

Waddaya Hear?: Yogi Berra, Chicago White Sox, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Waddaya Mean Goodby?: Allie Sherman, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Waiting for Mickey: Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
And the Walls Came Tumbling Down : Wisconsin Supreme Court, Milwaukee Braves
              
              <lb/>
Wanna Climb a Mountain?: boxing
              
              <lb/>
Way Out: Soviet Union, Sonny Liston, Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
We Are Now at Ringside...: Detroit Tigers, Bob Gibson
              
              <lb/>
We Draw Our Own Conclusions: University of Pittsburgh, Syracuse University, Kenny Lucas, Eric Crabtree, Floyd Little, football
              
              <lb/>
We Got a Real Belt Out of 'Em: boxing
              
              <lb/>
We May Be Wrong But: New York Jets, Baltimore Colts
              
              <lb/>We May Be Wrong But: Dave Debusschere, New York Knicks, Cleveland Browns, Dallas Cowboys, Kansas City Chiefs, Baltimore Colts
              
              <lb/>We May Be Wrong But: Ernie Terrell, Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
We Serve Punch to a Full House: boxing
              
              <lb/>
We Talk to Jose Torres: Jose Torres, Dick Tiger, Emile Griffith
              
              <lb/>
And We Thought He Was Out!: Detroit Tigers, Mickey Lolich
              
              <lb/>
We Visit with Joey Archer: Emile Griffith, Joey Archer
              
              </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>We'll-Y</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">12</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
              <lb/>

We'll Drink to That!:  New Year's (1969-1970)
              
              <lb/>
Well, Hello, Fatso!: Los Angeles Dodgers, Sandy Koufax, Don Drysdale
              
              <lb/>
Well, I'll be a Rhodes Scholar, if it ain't...! : Bill Bradley, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
Well, shut my mouth!: Warren Giles, New York
              
              <lb/>
We're all right, Jack!: sports, television 
              
              <lb/>
West of the Great Divide: Milwaukee Braves
              
              <lb/>
Western Omelet: Roger Rouse, Dick Tiger <lb/>

A Whale of a Catch: New York Mets, Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
What a Relief: Ralph Houk, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
What Creek?: Ralph Houk, Yogi Berra, Pete Ramos
              
              <lb/>
What's Goin' an Here?: New York Giants, Green Bay Packers, Sonny Liston, Notre Dame, New York Knicks, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
What's the Big Idea?: Rolling Stones, hockey
              
              <lb/>What's the Gag?: Paul Brown, Cleveland Browns, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
What's Wrong with This Picture?: New York Knicks, New York Rangers
              
              <lb/>
When Irish Guys are Miling: Ron Delany, relay record
              
              <lb/>
When You Look Upon a Star: 1933 All-Star game
              
              <lb/>
Where There's a Will...: cartoons, Bill Gallo
              
              <lb/>
Where'd Everybody Go?: Mickey Mantle
              
              <lb/>
Wherefore are thou, Romeos?: Ralph Houk, Wes Westrum
              
              <lb/>
Wherever You Go... : New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Which Reminds Me...: boxing, Muhammad Ali, Ernie Terrell
              
              <lb/>
Who Said So?: Ken Harrelson, Red Schoendienst, Gil Hodges, Dave Zyglewicz
              
              <lb/>
Who's Buyin'?: competition
              
              <lb/>
Who's Hungrier?: Buster Mathis
              
              <lb/>
Who's On the Right Track?: Manuel Ramos, Joe Frazier
              
              <lb/>Who's Washed Up : unidentified athlete
              
              <lb/>
The Whole Card: Don Drysdale, Los Angeles Dodgers
              
              <lb/>
Why Not?: Casey Stengel
              
              <lb/>
The Wild Blue Yonder: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
Willie Peps - up the Hall: boxing, Willie Pep, Sandy Saddler
              
              <lb/>
Wilt the Winner: Wilt Chamberlain, Alex Hannum 
              
              <lb/>
Win, Place and Show: horse racing, Notre Dame
              
              <lb/>
Window Shopping: horse racing, George Sholty, Del Insko
              
              <lb/> Wired!: Johnny Unitas, Earl Morrall, Baltimore Colts
              
              <lb/>
Wives' Lament: sports attendance
              
              <lb/>
Without A Sound Frazier: New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
Woe, Woe, Woe: Joe Dimaggio, Oldtimer's Day 
              
              <lb/>
Word Game: Gabriel Elorde, Carlos Ortiz
              
              <lb/>
Work of Art: Ed Giacomin, Emile Francis
              
              <lb/>
The World in a Straitjacket: Robert F. Kennedy assassination, note on cartoon reads "Forgive me for veering away from my regular beat today". 
              
              <lb/>
Wotta World: Mayo Smith, Red Schoendienst, American League, National League
              
              <lb/>
Would You Believe...: John Lindsay, Sandy Koufax, Don Drysdale, New York Mets, George Chuvalo
              
              <lb/>
The Writing On the Wall: New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
Written In The Stars: Mel Stottlemyre, New York Yankees (1968)
              
              <lb/>


Yankee Stadium 1966: Mickey Mantle, Ralph Houk
              
              <lb/>
Yanks One Up (In This League): Yogi Berra, sailing
              
              <lb/>
A Year for Matadors: bullfighting, pitchers, hitters (stamp reads May 21 1968)
              
              <lb/>
Yearbook - 1968: boxing, heavyweight champions
              
              <lb/>
Yes I Can!: Muhammad Ali
              
              <lb/>
Yesterday's Mail: Willie Pep, Carlos Ortiz, basketball
              
              <lb/>
You are What You Eat: quarterbacks, Jimmy Ellis, baseball, umpires, sports cartoonists, television, football 
              
              <lb/>
You Can't Win Mother: television, football, New York Rangers, New York Knicks
              
              <lb/>
You Gotta Have Heart (And a Bench): Red Holzman, Dave Stallworth, Mike Riordau
              
              <lb/>
You Gotta Have A Strong Bench: baseball, popularity, National League
              
              <lb/>
You Said It!: Sandy Koufax, Juan Marichal 
              
              <lb/>You Said It!: readers
              
              <lb/>
Yours, Mine and Ours: National Football League, strike, pitchers, hitters, long hair 
              
              <lb/>

Yours, Mine and Ours: sporting events, vacation</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Untitled</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">12</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>


Casey Stengel and Yogi Berra Tapdancing
              
              <lb/>
Ted Williams - "Who Was 42 Years Young August 30th"
              
              <lb/>
"Under this pillow is Bill Dewitt - Owner of the Second Division Cincy Reds": Frank Robinson
              
              <lb/>
Muhammad Ali with his mouth zipped
              
              <lb/>
"Williams' Peak" and "Mount Lombardi"
              
              <lb/>
"The Giants, today in New Haven, planted their flag atop Mount Football and proclaimed themselves KING": same message for New York Jets
              
              <lb/>
Question Mark
              
              <lb/>
Gallo's Pick: Jerry Quarry
              
              <lb/>
Mickey Lolich
              
              <lb/>
Dick Tiger - A Civil War on His Mind
              
              <lb/>
The Fine Art of Winning - Mike Burke Could Always See the Stars
              
              <lb/>
player with a crown
              
              <lb/>
"It's Joe! But who dressed him so funny?</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Oversize cartoons</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">13</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>


Ah, But This One Is Only a Dream: Allie Sherman, Gil Hodges, Ralph Houk, Weeb Ewbank
              
              <lb/>
Around the Clock with Joe - The Star of the Show: Joe Namath, Weeb Ewbank
              
              <lb/>
Bar Exams: Olympics, Bob Seagren
              
              <lb/>Bravo, Bravo, Benvenutt: Nino Benvenuti, Emile Griffith, boxing
              
              <lb/>Defenseless: baseball
              
              <lb/>
"Enough, Enough," said the Ol' Bird: Mickey Lolich
              
              <lb/>
Fire!: New York Mets, Hal Reniff
              
              <lb/>
Follow the Bouncing Super Ball: Superbowl
              
              <lb/>
Hey Ralphie - I was supposed to do that trick!: Ralph Houk, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>
Honest, I only smoke cigars, but here's my super pipedream: Baltimore Colts, New York Jets
              
              <lb/>
Hot Off the Wire: Green Bay Packers, Oscar Vonavena, Joe Frazier, New York Rangers, New Knicks, baseball
              
              <lb/>
New York Skyline: New York Knicks, Willis Reed
              
              <lb/>
Talk About a Landing - WOW!: Joe Namath, New York Jets, New York Mets
              
              <lb/>Testing, Testing, 1...2...3...4: Joe Namath, Buffalo Bills, New York Giants, Chicago Bears, boxing
              
              <lb/>
That Day at Camp - It was a Sketch!: Muhammad Ali, Floyd Patterson
              
              <lb/>
That Ol' Black Magic Has Them In a Spell: Ralph Houk, New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>The Things That Happen on April 11th Openings: baseball, trivia
              
              <lb/>
They Twinked and They Shined: baseball players
              
              <lb/>The Unkindest Cut of All: Chicago Cubs, Leo Durocher, Red Schoendienst, St. Louis Cardinals
              
              <lb/>
We May Be Wrong, but...: Joe Frazier, Jerry Quarry, Beau Jack
              
              <lb/>
Whatever Bertha Wants, Bertha Gets: New York Yankees
              
              <lb/>
When You and I Were Young, Kiddo!: children, sports
              
              <lb/>
Yale Bowl: New York Jets, New York Giants
              
              <lb/>
[Hello, Bertha]: Allie Sherman, Weeb Ewbank, Emile Francis 
              
              <lb/>[UCLA]: UCLA, basketball</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Sketches</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Preliminary sketches</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <dimensions>8 ½" x 11"</dimensions>
              <extent>17 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1960/1970" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Incoming correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1960/1967" type="inclusive">1960-1967</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01><c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Newspapers</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York 
              
              <emph render="italic">Daily News</emph></unittitle>
            <abstract>final and night owl editions</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1970-01-17" type="inclusive">17 Jan 1970</unitdate>
            <container type="Oversize">13</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
