<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY searchcoll SYSTEM "searchcoll.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
<!ENTITY scrconline SYSTEM "scrconline.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 2.0, 20 Oct 2017 -->


<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
   <!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->
   <eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
      dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"
      relatedencoding="DC">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="george_fam">george_fam</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">George Family Photograph Collection</titleproper>
            <subtitle>An inventory of the collection at Syracuse University</subtitle>
            <author encodinganalog="Creator">MGC</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">
               &su_name;
               <lb/>
            </publisher>
            &su_address;
            <date normal="2020-03-06" encodinganalog="Date">6 Mar 2020</date>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Maria Cancro<date normal="2020-03-06">6 Mar 2020</date>
         </creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
         </langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"-->
      <revisiondesc>
         <list>
            <item/>
         </list>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
      <did>
         <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
         <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">
            &su_name;
            <lb/>
            &su_address;
         </repository>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">George Family Photograph
            Collection</unittitle>
         <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1941-1968" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1941-1968</unitdate>
         <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: "><extent>0.25 linear ft.</extent></physdesc>
         <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">A collection of candid family photographs, most from the Georges, reflecting African-American life in the 
		 mid-twentieth century.  The collection includes family members, friends, and colleagues spanning several states including 
		 Texas, Georgia, Illinois, California, New York, New Jersey, Delaware, Tennessee, and Kansas</abstract>
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="US"
            repositorycode="NSyU">5520045</unitid>
         <langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
         <head>Biographical History</head>
         <p>Very little information is present in the collection, but one of the postcards 
		 has a name and home address.  From that, and based on extensive research in 
            Ancestry.com, the US census, Findagrave.com, and information from curators of related collections
            (see Related Material below), the collection appears to be that of the George
            family.  Very few of the photographs are labeled, however; while a few more were 
			identifed through the abovementioned research, the 
            identities of most are unknown. Dates were also inferred through research as only a
            portion of the photographs are dated. Copies of the familial records as uncovered
            through research by SCRC staff have been placed in departmental files.</p>
			
         <p>The Georges were an African American family from Atlanta, Georgia. They had a
            tradition of scholarly achievements and community membership wherever they went. 
			Between 1920 and 1960 the family moved several times for education, employment, and 
			military deployment. They also had numerous friends and colleagues throughout the
            United States, including Texas, Delaware, New Jersey, New York, Illinois,
            Georgia, California, Tennessee, and Kansas. </p>
         <p>Claude Clarence George Sr. was a graduate of the Tuskegee Institute (1912) who went on
            to become an educator and later an insurance agent. He married Claudia Johnson George in
            1917. She was a graduate of Howard University and later became an educator for Howard
            herself. Together they had seven children: four sons (Bennie Johnson, Wilbur Green,
            Claude C. Jr., and John), and three daughters (Laurel, Evelyn, and Cora). </p>
         <p>Bennie Johnson George enlisted in the army and later attended Delaware State University.
            After a few years he returned to Delaware State where he was Physical Education
            Professor and head football coach.  He married Dorothy Luella Poole, with whom
			he had three daughters, Peggy Ann Nealy, Rosemarie Heflin, and Stacie Lynn Bratten; and 
			a son, Theo Braunskill.</p>
         <p>Wilbur Green George married Louise Victoria Yelverton and together they had a son, James
            Wendell George, and a daughter, Claudia George-Washington. </p>			
         <p>Claude C. George, Jr. became a doctor and married Gwendolyn Lampkin.  They had two
            daughters, Yvette G. George and Colette George Scott. </p>
         <p>John George went on to become an attorney in Oakland ,California and was the first
            African American elected to the Alameda County Board of Supervisors. </p>
         <p>Laurel George married Alfred Mouton and Cora George married Dr. James Greene Sr.  Cora
            and William had two sons Michael Greene and James C. Greene Jr.</p>
         <p>Evelyn George married William Castille. Evelyn and William had seven daughters:
            Valorie Jacquet, Tracey Castille, Kristy Castille, Eva Young, Dorothy Castille, Dorthea
            Castille, and Debra Castille-Hall.  </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
         <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
         <p>The <emph render="bold">George Family Photograph Collection</emph> is a collection of
            photographs and postcards featuring members of an African-American family, their friends
            and relatives, including several who served in the U.S military.</p>
         <p><emph render="bold">Photographs</emph> contains 186 photographs, five
            photographic post-cards, and one funeral procession program. There are a few formal 
			portrait photographs, but the majority are candid photos taken at
			home or at various events, such as graduation, school performances, teacher's dances, and 
			community and family gatherings.  There are several photographs of young children.</p>
            <p>There are photos of several unidentified African American men in
            military uniform, including the Marines, Air Force, and Army. There is also a series of
            photographs of a U.S. Army Recruiting Officer captioned "to Pop from son Joseph". 
			Though many of the individuals in the
            photographs have not been identified, a few individuals are prominently featured, one of
            whom is the Joseph mentioned above. He also appears in a few photographs with Japanese
            men and women; it is not known when or where these photos were taken. Several predominately or 
			exclusively African American schools appear in the collection, with one labeled
            as a teacher's dance and another showing several graduates standing in front of a "Carver High"
            sign.  Some of the photographs include references to, or identifable locations in, 
			Texas, California, Georgia, New York, New Jersey, Illinois, Delaware, Tennessee, and Kansas.  </p>
			<p>The photos range in size
            from 1" x 1" to 8" x 7.5". Many of the photographs are undated and one distinctly appears 
			to be a copy of a 19th century photograph based on the attire the individuals are wearing. 
			Those photographs that are dated range from 1941-1968.  Some of the photographs have creases and tears but most are in good condition.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <!--<originalsloc encodinganalog="535"><head>Location of Originals</head><p>Originals are here and here and here.</p></originalsloc>-->
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
         <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
         <p> Photographs are foldered, organized by like size, and when possible recognizable or identifiable 
		 individuals appearing in several photos have been grouped together. </p>
      </arrangement>
      <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>See also the <extref href="https://aafa.galileo.usg.edu/repositories/2/resources/42">Dr. Claude
               C. George, Jr. family papers</extref> at the Auburn Avenue Research Library on
            African American Culture and History in Atlanta, Georgia, and the
         <extref href="https://desu.libguides.com/ld.php?content_id=34895503">Delaware State
               College Sports Photograph collection, c. 1945-1965 </extref>at the Delaware State
            University Archives, William C. Jason Library, in Dover, Delaware.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0"><head>Separated Material</head><p/></separatedmaterial>-->
      <controlaccess>
         <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
		 <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">African Americans</subject>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">George, Bennie Johnson.</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">George, Claudia.</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Johnson, Nathaniel.</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Stephens, William.</persname>
         <famname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">George family.</famname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">City University of New York. -- City College.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Delaware State University.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Air Force -- African Americans.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Army -- African American troops.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Marine Corps.</corpname>
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Navy -- African Americans.</corpname>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcdgt">African Americans -- Photographs.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcdgt">Japanese Americans– Photographs.</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Graduation (School)</subject>
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975.</subject>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Atlanta (Ga.) -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Chattanooga (Tenn.) -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Chicago (Ill.) -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Fort Leavenworth (Kan.) -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">New Jersey -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">New York -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Los Angeles (Calif.) -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
         <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Texas -- History -- 20th century. </geogname>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="lcsh">Photographs.</genreform>
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="lcsh">Postcards.</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require
            advance notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance
            concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before
            publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
         <p> George Family Photograph Collection, <lb/> &su_name; </p>
      </prefercite>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
         <head>Acquisition Information</head>
         <p>Purchased, 2020.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583"><head>Appraisal Information</head><p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>-->
      <!--<accruals encodinganalog="584"><head>Accruals</head><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>-->
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>Inventory</head>
         <!--C01 @LEVEL must be set to 'series' to show up in TOC.-->
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
            </did>
            <!--Permissible values for @TYPE for first CONTAINER are: Box, Belfer, Package, SC, Oversize, Volume, Carton, Map-Case, Cabinet, or Tube.-->
            <!--Permissible values for @TYPE for second CONTAINER are: Folder, Frame, Tape, Page, Drawer, or Reel-->
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942">1942, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949/1950">1949-1950, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1954">1953-1954, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957/1961">1957-1961,</unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1968">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>This folder includes photographs of several Japanese persons with a U.S. Army
                     Recruiting Officer. There are two photos of African American men from Delaware
                     State University, one identified in writing as William Stephens and another
                     unidentified. There are four photographs with the photography studio addresses
                     listed (MD. State College Photo Dept, Fort Valley Georgia, Chicago Illinois,
                     and Atlanta Georgia_. There is a photograph of a young girl posing for a dance
                     recital, identified in a caption as Marlene Baker. The folder also has two birth
                     announcement photographs: 5-5-1957 11 days Michele Teree Poole and 10-8-1942 6
                     weeks (no name visible). There are also several school portraits with writing
                     on the back. This folder also has a photo which distinctly appears to be a copy
                     of a much older photograph, perhaps 19th century.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945">1945, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1955">1953-1955, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958/1961">1958-1961, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1968">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>This folder includes a photograph of David Jackson (identified by handwritten caption) in a
                     United States Navy uniform standing in front of a train "Los Angeles Special"
                     with a sign that says "Goodbye Calif. 1945". There is a photograph of an
                     unidentified African American man in U.S. Air Force uniform. There is also a series of
                     photos of a child's birthday party and a photo of two young women sitting
                     in front of a building with a small sign that says Suarez. There are
                     two postcards, one with a name on the back seemingly identifying the
                     woman as Marie E. Kelley and the other a letter addressed to a Miss Serlina
                     Williams from her brother [J.?] B. Williams.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1942">1941-1942, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948">1948, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1968">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>This folder includes the postcard from Bennie Johnson to his mother Claudia in
                     1942 during his military enlistment, which was the starting point for the 
					 research mentioned above that led to the identification of the collection.
					 There is also an advertisement for the play<emph render="italic"> Deep are the Roots</emph> which premiered on
                     Broadway in 1945. There are several portraits of African American
                     women and two Christmas cards, one from the Grants, the other from the Bryants.
                     There is a signed photograph of saxophone player Norman Satchell. There are
                     three more photos of William Stephens with friends, presumably at Delaware State
                     University. There is a photo of a young United States Marine in front of a sign
                     that says "Maintenance Company Provisional Service Battalion 9th MAB"
                     presumably taken in Okinawa, Japan.  There is a series of
                     photos of the United States Army Recruiting officer signed "to Pop from son
                     Joseph".</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Miscellaneous photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944">1944, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954/1955">1954-1955, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964, </unitdate>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1968">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>This folder includes a funeral program for La Nelle Cameron Salter in 1944
                     Chicago.  US Census data indicates that Ms Salter lived with Willie Mae Williams, Claudia George's sister, as a
                     lodger in 1940. There is a Christmas card with "Fort Leavenworth Kansas 1968"
                     written on the back. There is a portrait of a young African American man
                     named Ronnie with a note to his sister Peggy written on the back. There are a
                     few photographs of a teachers' dance captioned "Scene: Wilcox Co. Teachers dance
                     55". There is a series of photographs of several African American
                     students graduating. The building in front of which they are standing 
					 has a sign that reads "Carver High".</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
