<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 1.5, 5/26/2006 -->
<!--Added description of how to enter revisions-->

<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
	<!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->

<eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
		<eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="hendrickson_a">hendrickson_a</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Andrew Hendrickson Papers</titleproper>
				<subtitle>An inventory of his papers at Syracuse University</subtitle>
			<author encodinganalog="Creator">AMV</author><sponsor>The adult education holdings are collectively known as the <lb/><extptr title="Alexander N. Charters Library of Resources for Educators of Adults" href="https://library.syr.edu/scrc/collections/areas/adult-ed.php" show="new"/>.</sponsor></titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>
				&su_address;
				<date normal="1971-03" encodinganalog="Date">Mar 1971</date>
			</publicationstmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Michele Rothenberger
				<date normal="2006-07-25">25 Jul 2006</date>
			</creation>
			<langusage>
				<language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
			</langusage>
		</profiledesc>
		<!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"--><revisiondesc>
			<list>
				<item> Jan 1977 - revisions (-)</item><item>Jul 1991 - part 2 additions (KW)</item><item>25 Jul 2006 - 2 parts integrated, converted to EAD (MRR)</item>
			</list>
		</revisiondesc>
	</eadheader>
	<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
		<did>
			<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
			<repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">
			&su_name; <lb/> &su_address;
			</repository>
			<origination label="Creator: ">
				<persname encodinganalog="100">Hendrickson, Andrew,  1899-</persname>
			</origination>
			<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Andrew Hendrickson Papers</unittitle>
			<unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1925/1971" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1925-1971</unitdate>
			  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" normal="1948/1967" type="inclusive" label="Bulk Dates: ">1948-1967</unitdate><physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: "><extent>10.5 linear ft.</extent></physdesc>
			<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Consists of correspondence, reports, printed material, and memorabilia, including certificates, plaques, and photographs. The collection includes material generated by Herschel W. Nisonger (predecessor), William Dowling (successor), and Andrew Hendrickson during their tenures as professors of adult education at Ohio State University, however the bulk of the material belongs to Hendrickson (1947-1967). Correspondents whose letters are of significant depth and duration include: William D. Dowling, John B. Holden, Cyril O. Houle, Glenn S. Jensen, Homer Kempfer, Malcolm S. Knowles, Burton W. Kreitlow, Fern Long, Robert A. Luke, Herschel W. Nisonger, Newton C. Rochte, and Coolie Verner.  Part 2, added in 1991, contains miscellaneous pamphlets, additional memorabilia, and some material relating to the Adult Education Association (AEA), the National Association of Public School Adult Educators (NAPSAE), and the National Education Association (NEA).</abstract>
			<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="us" repositorycode="NSyU">149046</unitid>
			<langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
				
		<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
			<head>Biographical History</head>
			
		<p>Born November 17, 1899, in Pedrickstown, New Jersey, Andrew Hendrickson earned an A.B. in English from Bucknell University in 1925, an M.A. in English from Columbia University in 1935, and the Ph.D. in adult education from Columbia in 1943.

He  served as head of the English Department in the Cliffside Park, New Jersey, High School and taught social studies in the Westfield, New Jersey, High School and the New York City Regents Evening High School. </p><p>Hendrickson served as Assistant and Associate in adult education as well as instructor in sociology at the Teachers College of Columbia University and was an assistant professor of adult education as well as Director of Cooperative Education and Assistant Dean at Cleveland College of Western Reserve University. In 1947 Hendrickson went to Ohio State University as professor of Education, where in 1957 he was appointed director of the Center for Adult Education. Retiring from Ohio State in 1967, Dr. Hendrickson became director of the Institute of Senior Adults and professor of adult education in the Department of Adult Education at Florida State University.

</p><p>Andrew Hendrickson was a member and vice president of the National Education Association. He served on the executive committee and as a member of the Delegate Assembly of the Adult Education Association. A past secretary-treasurer of the Ohio Association for Adult Education, Dr. Hendrickson was editor of the journal of that organization, <emph render="italic">The Ohio Adult Observer</emph>, from 1948 to 1960. He was also one of the founders and the first president of the Adult Education Council of Greater Columbus, Ohio.</p></bioghist>
		
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
			<head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
			<p>The <emph render="bold">Andrew Hendrickson Papers</emph> arose primarily from Hendrickson's work at Ohio State University. All of the material came from the office of the professor of adult education at Ohio State. This material is almost exclusively Hendrickson's, but most of the material dated before 1947 resulted from the work of Hendrickson's predecessor, Herschel W. Nisonger. There is also correspondence from 1967 generated by William D. Dowling, Hendrickson's successor. The collection consists of correspondence, printed material including reproduced material and published material, and a few photographs. The inclusive dates of the collection are 1933-1971 but the bulk of the papers are dated between 1948 and 1967.</p><p>The collection arrived in two parts separated by nearly twenty years, and the two parts were treated separately.</p><p><emph render="underline">Part 1</emph> material is divided into three categories: correspondence, writings, and miscellaneous material. <emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph> covers the period 1937-1967, with emphasis on 1948-1967, and includes both incoming and outgoing letters, telegrams, and memoranda. The material is arranged chronologically with multiple items having the same date arranged alphabetically by the correspondents' names. Undated material is placed at the end of the section. Significant correspondents (those for whom there are at least twenty pieces in the collection) and the inclusive dates of their letters follow.  In no case are there more than fifty pieces for any individual.</p><list><item>Dowling, William D., 1967
</item><item>Bolden, John Bernard, 1943-1964
</item><item>Houle, Cyril Orvin, 1958-1966
</item><item>Jensen, Glenn S., 1959-1967
</item><item>Kempfer, Homer Hadley, 1947-1966
</item><item>Knowles, Malcolm S., 1951-1966
</item><item>Kreitlow, Burton, 1950-1967
</item><item>Long, Fern, 1948-1967
</item><item>Luke, Robert A., 1946-1966
</item><item>Nisonger, Herschel W., 1937-1962
</item><item>Rochte, Newton C., 1949-1963
</item><item>Verner, Coolie, 1953-1965</item></list><p>The inclusive dates of <emph render="bold">Writings</emph> are 1933-1969. Included in this category are articles and addresses, reports and proposals, copies of <emph render="italic">The Ohio Adult Observer</emph>, and student papers from Hendrickson's classes. There are eleven articles and
addresses, arranged alphabetically by title. Reports and proposals include documents prepared by Hendrickson or by committees of which Hendrickson was a member. These are arranged chronologically with undated pieces placed at the end of the section. Since Hendrickson was an editor of The Ohio Adult
Observer, there is a fairly complete run of this journal between the dates 1933 and 1966. Student papers are arranged chronologically.</p><p><emph render="bold">Miscellaneous material</emph>, 1945-1967, comprises biographical information on Hendrickson and Nisonger; meeting papers, including working papers, minutes and proceedings; memorabilia, including membership lists and rosters, photographs, programs, brochures, newspaper clippings, and a script; and unidentified pieces. Minutes include reports of only those meetings which Hendrickson attended and are arranged chronologically. Transcripts of meetings of the Commission of Professors of Adult Education for 1957 to 1959 are arranged chronologically in the section of proceedings. The CPAE, a branch of the Adult Education Association of the United States of America, was organized to develop a philosophy of adult education. Membership lists and rosters name members of organizations and rosters of conference and meeting participants. These lists are arranged chronologically, with undated material at the end of the section. The few photographs are mostly of meetings; they are undated and unidentified. The section of programs includes printed programs of meetings and conferences in which Hendrickson participated. The programs are arranged chronologically, and undated material is placed at the end of the section. The brochure relates to the program and services of the Bureau of Special and Adult Education at Ohio State University. The newspaper clippings describe the retirement of Herschel W. Nisonger. The script is of a skit performed at an appreciation banquet for Nisonger upon his retirement. Unidentified material is arranged chronologically.</p><p><emph render="underline">Part 2</emph> consists of miscellaneous pamphlets on various adult education topics, as well as a few documents reflecting Hendrickson's involvement with several adult education organizations. This group of materials date from the late 1920s to the early 1960s, with the 1950s and 1960s predominating.</p><p>Materials from Part 2 are organized by subject area into four groups:
<emph render="bold">Adult education - general</emph> contains a selection of adult-education related topics.  <emph render="bold">Adult education organizations</emph> comprises material such as reports, minutes, and programs related to the American Association for Adult Education (AAAE), the Adult Education Association (AEA), the National Education Association (NEA), and the Ohio Association of Public School Adult Educators (OAPSAE), a chapter of the national organization (NAPSAE).  <emph render="bold">Adult education (by state)</emph> has material specifically related to adult education in New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, West Virginia among others.  <emph render="bold">General topics</emph> contains  miscellaneous pamphlets on topics other than adult education.  The folders within each group are arranged alphabetically.</p><p>Topics of particular interest include the AEA; educational television and radio; leadership training; community development; and the United Nations &amp; UNESCO. Some materials, especially those dating from the 1920s and 30s, bear Dr. Herschel W. Nisonger's imprint. Dr. Nisonger was Hendrickson's predecessor at Ohio State.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		
		<!--<arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
			<head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 351$a)</p>
		</arrangement>-->
		
		<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
			<head>Related Material</head>
			<p>The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education.  Please refer to &subjindex; for a complete listing.  </p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		
		<!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
			<head>Separated Material</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
		</separatedmaterial>-->
		
		<!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
			<head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
		</otherfindaid>-->
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Adult education</subject>
			<!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc).  
Some have defaults set in the template.-->
            <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Dowling, William D.
</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Hendrickson, Andrew, 1899-</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Holden, John Bernard.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Houle, Cyril Orvin,  1913-
</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Jensen, Glenn S.
</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Kempfer, Homer.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Knowles, Malcolm Shepherd,  1913-
</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Kreitlow, Burton W.
</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Long, Fern.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Luke, Robert A.
</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Nisonger, Herschel Ward, 1890-</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Rochte, Newton C.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Verner, Coolie.</persname>
			
            
            <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf">The Ohio Adult Observer.</title>
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Adult education -- Ohio.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Adult education -- United States.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Older people -- Education.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Educators -- United States.</subject>
			
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Memorabilia.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
			<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Educators.</occupation>
			</controlaccess>
		
		<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
			<head>Access Restrictions</head>
			<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		
		<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
			<head>Use Restrictions</head>
			<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
		</userestrict>
		
		<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
			<head>Preferred Citation</head>
			<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
			<p>Andrew Hendrickson Papers, <lb/> &su_name; </p>
		</prefercite>
		
		<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
			<head>Acquisition Information</head>
			<p>Gift of <persname role="donor">Andrew Hendrickson</persname>, 1969 and 1971.</p>
		</acqinfo>
		
		<!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
			<head>Appraisal Information</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
		</appraisal>-->
		
		<!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
			<head>Accruals</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
		</accruals>-->
		
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>Inventory</head>
			<note><p>The following is a shelf list.  Minimal processing has been done on this collection.</p></note><c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle> Correspondence</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1947" type="inclusive">1937-1947</unitdate></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c02>
			<c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1948</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948-01/1948-07">Jan-Jul</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948-08/1948-12">Aug-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1949</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949-01/1949-03">Jan-Mar</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949-04/1949-12">Apr-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1950</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950-01/1950-06">Jan-Jun</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950-07/1950-12">Jul-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1951</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951-01/1951-05">Jan-May</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951-06/1951-12">Jun-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle><unitdate normal="1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">2</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1953</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953-01/1953-06">Jan-Jun</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953-07/1953-12">Jul-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1954</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954-01/1954-05">Jan-May</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954-06/1954-12">Jun-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1955</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955-01/1955-04">Jan-Apr</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955-05/1955-08">May-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955-09/1955-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1956</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956-01/1956-04">Jan-Apr</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956-05/1956-08">May-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956-09/1956-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">3</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1957</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-01/1957-03">Jan-Mar</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-04/1957-07">Apr-Jul</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-08/1957-10">Aug-Oct</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-1/1957-12">Nov-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1958</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958-01/1958-04">Jan-Apr</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958-05/1958-08">May-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956-09/1956-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1959</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959-01/1959-02">Jan-Feb</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959-03/1959-04">Mar-Apr</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959-05/1959-07">May-Jul</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959-08/1959-09">Aug-Sep</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959-10/1959-12">Oct-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1960</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960-01/1960-03">Jan-Mar</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960-04/1960-08">Apr-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960-09/1960-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1961</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961-01/1961-04">Jan-Apr</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961-05/1961-08">May-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961-09/1961-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1962</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962-01/1962-04">Jan-Apr</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962-05/1962-08">May-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962-09/1962-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1963</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963-01/1963-03">Jan-Mar</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963-04/1963-08">Apr-Aug</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963-09/1963-12">Sep-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1964</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964-01/1964-06">Jan-Jun</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964-07/1964-12">Jul-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1965</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965-01/1965-03">Jan-Mar</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965-04/1965-06">Apr-Jun</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965-07/1965-09">Jul-Sep</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965-10/1965-12">Oct-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1966</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966-01/1966-03">Jan-Mar</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966-04/1966-06">Apr-Jul</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966-08/1966-12">Aug-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle>1967</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967-01/1967-02">Jan-Feb</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967-03/1967-05">Mar-May</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967-06/1967-12">Jun-Dec</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03></c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1970" type="inclusive">1968-1970</unitdate></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">10</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c02><c02>
					<did>
						<unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1971" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">10</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Writings </unittitle></did><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Articles and addresses</unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1957">1947-1957</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959/1968">1959-1968</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Pamphlets</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c02><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Reports and proposals</unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936/1952">1936-1952</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1954">1953-1954</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955/1958">1955-1958</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959/1966">1959-1966</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1971" type="inclusive">Undated</unitdate></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">11</container>
						
						
						
					</did></c03></c02><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">The Ohio Adult Observer</emph></unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933/1949">1933-1949</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950/1954">1950-1954</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955/1956">1955-1956</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Student papers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950/1958">1950-1958</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle></did><c02><did><unittitle>Adult Basic Education, workshops</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1969">1968-1969</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="m-aea"><did><unittitle>Adult Education Association</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1971">1968-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did><note><p>See also Adult education organizations: <ref target="aeo-aea">Adult Education Association (AEA)</ref></p></note></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Biographical information</unittitle><container type="Box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="m-cpae"><did><unittitle>Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE)</unittitle></did><note><p>See also Adult education organizations: <ref target="aea-cpae">AEA-Commission for Professors in Adult Education</ref></p></note><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960/1967">1960-1967</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969/1970">1969-1970</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Conference on Aging</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Education for Older Persons</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969/1971">1969-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Handbooks and programs in adult education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944/1953">1944-1953</unitdate><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">12, 13</container></did></c02><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Meeting papers</unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle></did><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945/1952">1945-1952</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">13</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1957">1953-1957</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">13</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958/1959">1958-1959</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">13</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960/1967">1960-1967</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">13</container></did></c04></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Proceedings</unittitle></did><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">13</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c04></c03></c02><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle>Brochures</unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Certificate</unittitle><container type="Oversize">1</container></did></c03><c03><did>












<unittitle>Membership lists and rosters</unittitle></did><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1957">1947-1957</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958/1967">1958-1967</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1925/1971">Undated</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c04></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960, </unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Plaques and certificates</unittitle><container type="Box">19</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Programs</unittitle></did><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1946/1954">1946-1954</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">15</container></did></c04><c04><did><unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955/1967">1955-1967</unitdate></unittitle><container type="Box">15</container></did></c04></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Script</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Speeches</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965/1970">1965-1970</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Various papers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961/1968">1961-1968</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Unidentified fragments</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1967">1947-1967</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Adult education - general</unittitle></did><c02><did><unittitle>Continuing education
</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Educational media and methods

</unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle>Home study</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle> Radio and TV</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle> Other media</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Educational opportunities

</unittitle></did><c03><did><unittitle> Leadership training</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Publicity</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>
Research</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Adult education organizations</unittitle></did><c02><did><unittitle>American Association for Adult Education (AAAE) </unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aeo-aea"><did><unittitle>Adult Education Association (AEA)
</unittitle></did><note><p>See also Miscellaneous: <ref target="m-aea">Adult Education Association (AEA)</ref></p></note><c03 id="aea-cpae"><did><unittitle>AEA-Commission for Professors in Adult Education</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did><note><p>See also Miscellaneous: <ref target="m-cpae">Commission of Professors of Adult Education (CPAE)</ref></p></note></c03></c02><c02><did><unittitle>
National Education Association (NEA)
</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Ohio Association of Public School Adult Educators (OAPSAE/NAPSAE)

</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Adult education by state</unittitle></did><c02><did><unittitle>Ohio
</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>New York
(Chautauqua)</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Pennsylvania </unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>West Virginia </unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Other states</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>General topics</unittitle></did><c02><did><unittitle>Adult recreation</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>
Agriculture </unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Citizenship</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Community development </unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Family relations
</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Health education</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>
Labor</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>
Literacy
</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Race relations
</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>United Nations/UNESCO</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Veterans</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Vocational education</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>YMCA
</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02><c02><did><unittitle>Youth</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02></c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
