<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY scrconline SYSTEM "scrconline.txt">
<!ENTITY searchcoll SYSTEM "searchcoll.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 2.0, 20 Oct 2017 -->

<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
   <!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->

<eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="impact_visuals">impact_visuals</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Impact Visuals Photograph Collection</titleproper>
            <subtitle>An inventory of the collection at Syracuse University</subtitle>
         <author encodinganalog="Creator">MRC</author></titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>
            &su_address;
            <date normal="2020-09-03" encodinganalog="Date">3 Sep 2020</date>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Michele Combs<date normal="2020-09-03">3 Sep 2020</date>
         </creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
         </langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"--><revisiondesc>
         <list>
            <item></item>
         </list>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
      <did>
         <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
         <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">
         &su_name; <lb/> &su_address;
         </repository>
         <origination label="Creator: ">
            <corpname encodinganalog="110">Impact Visuals</corpname>
         </origination>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Impact Visuals Photograph Collection</unittitle>
         <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1984/2000" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1984-2000</unitdate>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: "><extent>0.25 linear ft.</extent></physdesc>
         <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Photographs documenting protests relating to labor, trade, health care, jobs, etc., mostly in the United States but a few in Canada, Guatemala, and India</abstract>
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="US" repositorycode="NSyU">5900296</unitid>
         <langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546">All captions and majority of content is in <language langcode="eng">English</language>; a few photos include signs in 
         <language langcode="spa">Spanish</language></langmaterial>
      </did>
            
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
         <head>Biographical History</head>
         
      <p>Impact Visuals (1986-2001) was a New York City-based photo agency, archive, and publication service, with a focus on social justice, equity, and multicultural issues.   Founded by Michael Kaufman, the co-op provided photographs and photojournalist services to a variety of clients, from mainstream newspapers and magazines  to  progressive, non-profit organizations and alternative media.  At some point, Impact Visuals acquired the  archive of South African cooperative Afrapix which was added to their archive.  Impact "[had] a core value of documenting people and their fight for self-determination. Also the goal is to support the photographers who do this kind of work and are members of the co-op." [<extref href="http://www.learningcentre.coop/resource/what-being-involved-means-us">"Nicholas Herman interviews Katie Brennan"</extref>, The Co-operative Learning Centre, undated]</p><p>Impact was cooperatively owned, with a high bar for membership; its 80 or so member photographers received 50% of the revenue generated from their archive sales and 60% of their assignment sales, but retained copyright to their images and were allowed to market their work independently.   Members were expected to be "photographically skilled with a consistently unique style of shooting, someone that is dedicated to political and social awareness, someone that is able to produce at a consistently high level, and someone who will add to the racial, ethnic, sexual and geographical diversity of the cooperative. Of utmost importance is the applicants independence, motivation and interest in working together towards a common goal." [Geraldine Baum, <extref href="https://medium.com/@geraldinebaum/impact-visuals-internship-journal-4171bc5a12de">"Impact Visuals Internship Journal"</extref>, Spring 1996]</p></bioghist>
      
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
         <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
         <p>The <emph render="bold">Impact Visuals Photograph Collection</emph> contains black-and-white photographs taken by members of the New York City photographers' co-operative.  Reflecting Impact Visuals' focus on documenting  social justice issues, most are of protests, rallies, marches, and other expressions of public pressure for change.  </p><p>Subjects include budget cuts, the Republican legislative agenda known as "Contract with America", health care, jobs/unemployment, "living wage," and the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).  Most of the photographs are of events in the United States, but there are a few from Canada, India, and Guatemala.  Specific issues, organizations, and identified individuals are given in the inventory below.  An <ref target="index">index to photographers</ref> whose work appears in the collection may be found at the end of this finding aid.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      
      <!--<altformavail encodinganalog="530">
         <head>Other Formats Available</head>
         <p>## Use MARC 530 or comment out if not applicable</p>
      </altformavail>-->
	  
      <!--<originalsloc encodinganalog="535">
	     <head>Location of Originals</head>
		 <p>Originals are here and here and here.</p>
      </originalsloc>--> 
	  
	  <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
         <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
         <p>Alphabetical by topic; the few international photos are filed at the end.</p>
      </arrangement>
      
      <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>Impact Visuals' archive is held by the <extref href="https://archivessearch.lib.uconn.edu/repositories/2/resources/453">Thomas J. Dodd Center</extref> at the University of Connecticut.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      
      <!--Use archref, not extref, to link to related collections.-->
	  <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
         <head>Separated Material</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
      </separatedmaterial>-->
      
      <!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
         <head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
      </otherfindaid>-->
      
      <controlaccess>
         <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
         <!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc). Some have 
defaults set in the template.-->
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Activism and social reform</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Photography</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Radicalism</subject><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Jackson, Jesse.</persname>
         <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Wallis, Jim.</persname><!--<famname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">##</famname>-->
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Impact Visuals.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Sojourners Fellowship.</corpname>
         <!--<title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf">##</title>-->
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Documentary photography -- United States.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United States -- Economic policy.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Environmentalism -- United States.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">North American Free Trade Agreement (1992 December 17)</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Protest movements -- United States.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Strikes and lockouts -- United States.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Trade regulation -- United States.</subject>
         
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
         <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Photographers.</occupation>
         <!--<function encodinganalog="657">##</function>--></controlaccess>
      
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advance notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
		 
</accessrestrict>
      
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
materials in this collection.</p>
      </userestrict>
      
      <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
         <p> Impact Visuals Photography Co-Op Collection, <lb/> &su_name; </p>
      </prefercite>
      
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
         <head>Acquisition Information</head>
         <p>Purchase, 2020.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      
      <!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
         <head>Appraisal Information</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
      </appraisal>-->
      
      <!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
      </accruals>-->
      
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>Inventory</head>
         <!--C01 @LEVEL must be set to 'series' to show up in TOC.-->
         <c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle></did>
            <c02 id="bank"><did><unittitle>Banking and finance</unittitle><abstract>interest rates, mortgage rates, etc.</abstract><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1991, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1993-1995</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>9 Jan 1991, Washington, DC - FDIC chairman William Seidman, Comptroller Robert Clarke at Senate Banking Committee hearing on bankruptcy of Bank of New England<lb/>
					11 Sep 1991, Washington, DC - Clark Clifford and Robert Altman at House hearings on BCCI and First American Bank<lb/>
					Apr 1993, Brooklyn - couple meeting with lawyer to refinance mortgage<lb/>
					15 Nov 1994, Washington, DC - rally in front of Federal Reserve during meeting of Federal Open Market Committee<lb/>9 Oct 1995, Washington, DC  - "BAP! the Bank" March and Rally, sponsored by Fifty Years is Enough</p></scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="budg"><did><unittitle>Budget cuts</unittitle><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1991-1992, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1995</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>4 Feb 1991, Brooklyn - demonstrators in front of Brooklyn Public Library<lb/>
					30 Apr 1991, New York City - union workers and others, on Wall Street and near World Trade Center<lb/>
					14 Mar 1992, Washington, DC - union workers (AFGE/AFSCME) protesting in Mayor Sharon Pratt Kelly's neighborhood<lb/>
					27 Mar 1995, Albany, NY - civil service workers protesting at state capitol; Mental Health Action Network<lb/>
					6 May 1995, New York City - protests in Times Square</p></scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="cowa"><did><unittitle>"Contract with America"</unittitle><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1995</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>29 Mar 1995, Ann Arbor, MI - students and welfare rights workers, University of Michigan<lb/>
					4 Apr 1995, Detroit, MI - NAACP, SEIU, other organizations<lb/>
					14 Aug 1995, Yorba Linda, CA - Teamsters and others protesting Gingrich's book signing ceremony at the Nixon Library<lb/>
					18 Aug 1995, Boston, MA - environmental, labor, pro-choice, and LGBT groups protesting Gingrich's book signing at Lauriat's Bookstore</p></scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="heca"><did><unittitle>Health care</unittitle><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1990 </unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>13 Jun 1990, Albany NY - union members and others at state capitol<lb/>
					3 Oct 1990, New York City - municipal workers at City Hall Park</p></scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="jobs"><did><unittitle>Jobs</unittitle><abstract>including layoffs, plant closings, unemployment</abstract><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1984, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1987, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1989, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1991-1993</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>1984, Paterson NJ - member of Typographical Union who lost job due to automation<lb/>
					Mar 1987, Detroit, MI - UAW workers protesting plant closings; lines of workers at unemployment office<lb/>
					Nov 1989, Detroit, MI - UAW workers protesting plant closings<lb/>
					Aug 1991, Rochester, NH - applicants waiting in line for hours to apply for jobs at Cabletron<lb/>
					Feb 1992, Manchester, NH - volunteers and unemployed at New Horizons Soup Kitchen<lb/>
					14 Jul 1992, New York City - "March of the Unemployed" outside Madison Square Garden during Democratic National Convention<lb/>
					29 Jul 1992, Detroit, MI - protests against privatization of emergency medical services (EMS)<lb/>
					18 Feb 1993, Washington, DC - unemployed workers from Pennsylvania protesting for extension of benefits<lb/>
					6 Apr 1993, Chicago, IL - applicants waiting in line for hours to apply for jobs at Michael Jordan's new restaurant<lb/>
					14 Apr 1993, Rochester, NY - Movement for a People's Assembly outside Kodak plant as part of "National Job is a Right Campaign"<lb/>
					21 Jun 1993, Fresno, CA - applicants waiting in line for hours to apply for jobs at Walmart<lb/>
					Oct 1993, New York City - anti-layoff demonstration of hospital workers<lb/>
					11 Nov 1993, Detroit, MI - applicants waiting in line for hours to apply for future jobs at potential new casino
					</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="liwa"><did><unittitle>Living wage</unittitle><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1996, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1998</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>24 Aug 1996, Chicago, IL - members of ACORN, SEIU, and others at Navy Pier during Democratic National Convention<lb/>
					7 Sep 1998, Alexandria, VA - Labor Day rally, mostly Latino workers, sponsored by Northern Virginia Livable Wage Campaign and Tenants and Workers Support Committee
					</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="naft"><did><unittitle>NAFTA</unittitle><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1992-1993</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>1992, New York City - General Motors layoffs<lb/>
					8 Jan 1993, Austin, TX - protesters outside during meeting between President Bill Clinton and Mexican President Salinas de Gortari<lb/>
					1 May 1993, Seattle, WA - "Not this NAFTA" rally organized by NAFTA/GATT Justice Committee and the Washington Coalition for Fair Trade and Social Justice<lb/>
					5 May 1993, Cleveland, OH - UAW members and others at rally organized by Jobs with Justice and a coalition of local activists<lb/>
					8 May 1993, Northfield, MN - protest at Armory, spurred by local firm Sheldahl Co. moving operations to Mexico<lb/>
					18 Sep 1993, Marcus Hook, PA - rally of unions, environmental activists, peace groups, and Mexican mushroom farm workers<lb/>
					2 Oct 1993, Buffalo, NY - Jesse Jackson with local labor and political leaders at Trico plant<lb/>
					23 Oct 1993, Atlanta, GA - union workers and environmental activists at state capitol<lb/>
					Nov 1993, Queens, NY - Queens Coalition to Stop NAFTA, Rego Park<lb/>
					10 Nov 1993, New York City - ILGWU members in garment district<lb/>
					12 Nov 1993, Tucson, AZ - homeless and others protesting outside Representative Jim Kolbe's office
					</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="misc-1"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous, identified</unittitle><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">1988-1995, </unitdate><unitdate normal="##" type="inclusive">2000</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>Sep 1988, New York City - Labor Day parade, signs expressing solidarity with Mexican workers<lb/>
					21 Oct 1989, St. Louis, MO - Victor Reuther at UAW New Directions Movement First National Congress<lb/>
					7 Oct 1990, New York City - tourists being turned away from the Statue of Liberty, closed due to government shutdown<lb/>
					[Jan?] 1991, Dover, DE - migrant farm worker<lb/>
					15 May 1992, Washington, DC - "Save Our Cities" march/rally; signs include mention of Rodney King and police brutality<lb/>
					3 Jun 1994, Cincinnati, OH - SEIU District 925 President Debbie Schneider and Mayor Diane Qualls at union's annual meeting<lb/>
					1 Dec 1994, Washington, DC - protesters against GATT outside White House<lb/>
					6 Dec 1995, Washington, DC - Sojourners members (including Jim Wallis, Tony Campolo, and Eugene Rivers) protesting GOP budget as anti-poor people, at US Capitol Building<lb/>
					18 Jun 2000, Eugene, OR - police in riot gear clearing protesters
					</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="misc-2"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous, unidentified</unittitle><abstract>includes CWA workers on strike against AT&amp;T</abstract><container type="Box">1</container></did></c02>
            <c02 id="cana"><did><unittitle>International</unittitle><abstract>Canada</abstract><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>26 Aug 1991, Toronto, ONT - Canadian Union of Postal Workers protesting privatization outside sorting plant of Canada Post<lb/>
					28 Apr 1993, Windsor, ONT - Workers Memorial Day march<lb/>
					24 Nov 1993, Toronto, ONT - Ontario Public Service Employees Union at Queen's Park (provincial legislature), protesting "social contract"<lb/>
					11 Dec 1995, London, ONT - postal workers outside sorting plant of Canada Post, protesting anti-labor policies and cutbacks of Ontario premier Mike Harris
					</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="guat"><did><unittitle>International</unittitle><abstract>Guatemala</abstract><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>3 Feb 1997, Mixco - protesters against unfair tax burden; foreground is close-up of young police officer's face</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
            <c02 id="indi"><did><unittitle>International</unittitle><abstract>India</abstract><container type="Box">1</container></did>
				<scopecontent>
				   <p>2 Feb 1987, New Delhi - sit-in by nurses outside residence of Human Resource Minister<lb/>
					1 Dec 1994, New Delhi - child labor at evening wedding</p>
				</scopecontent></c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   <index id="index"><head>Index to photographers</head><p>This index includes all photographers whose work is represented in the collection, with the topic folders where their work may be found.</p><indexentry><name>Anderson, Marilyn</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Beiler, Ryan</name><ptrgrp><ref target="guat">Guatemala</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Binder, Donna</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Burke, Bill</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Chase, Fred</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Cohen, George</name><ptrgrp><ref target="heca">Health care</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Condyles, J. Kirk</name><ptrgrp><ref target="budg">Budget cuts</ref><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Curtis, Rodney</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Dimitrov, Slobodan</name><ptrgrp><ref target="cowa">Contract with America</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Dotter, Earl</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Eliason, Orde</name><ptrgrp><ref target="indi">India</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Finkle, Harvey</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Fox, Robert</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Friar, Jerome</name><ptrgrp><ref target="bank">Banking</ref><ref target="budg">Budget cuts</ref><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Frumhoff, Marti</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Garg, Arvind</name><ptrgrp><ref target="indi">India</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Hartman, David</name><ptrgrp><ref target="cana">Canada</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Horn, Ansell</name><ptrgrp><ref target="bank">Banking/finance</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Humphries, Marilyn</name><ptrgrp><ref target="cowa">Contract with America</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Jensen, Kurt</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Kumar, Amitava</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Latimer, Steve</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Lichtenstein, Andrew</name><ptrgrp><ref target="budg">Budget cuts</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Ludak, Mark</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Marcus, Hilary</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Marshall, Russ</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>McKitterick, Tom</name><ptrgrp><ref target="budg">Budget cuts</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Neipris, Ellen</name><ptrgrp><ref target="budg">Budget cuts</ref><ref target="heca">Health care</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Palmer, Brian</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>PoKempner, Marc</name><ptrgrp><ref target="liwa">Living wage</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Reinhard, Rick</name><ptrgrp><ref target="bank">Banking/finance</ref><ref target="liwa">Living wage</ref><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Santow, Loren</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Savino, Tony</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Schuerholz, Dana</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Scott, Jeffry</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Smith, Catherine</name><ptrgrp><ref target="heca">Health care</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Smith, Christopher</name><ptrgrp><ref target="budg">Budget cuts</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Sorrentino, Joseph</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Stone, Les</name><ptrgrp><ref target="misc-1">Misc/identified</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Swift, Thor</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Tabor, Martha</name><ptrgrp><ref target="bank">Banking/finance</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Taylor, Adam</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>Tynan, Jim</name><ptrgrp><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>van Lier, Piet</name><ptrgrp><ref target="naft">NAFTA</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>
<indexentry><name>West, Jim</name><ptrgrp><ref target="cowa">Contract with America</ref><ref target="jobs">Jobs</ref><ref target="cana">Canada</ref></ptrgrp></indexentry>

</index></archdesc>
</ead>
