<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="morrisville_comm_ch" mainagencycode="NSyU">morrisville_comm_ch</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Morrisville Community Church (Morrisville NY) Records</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        its records 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">EFB</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
          <lb/></publisher>&su_address;
        <date encodinganalog="Date" normal="1970-07">Jul 1970</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           
        
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>20 Nov 2009 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
        <lb/>&su_address;</repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcnaf">Morrisville Community Church (Morrisville, N.Y.)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Morrisville Community Church (Morrisville NY) Records</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1805/1968" type="inclusive">1805-1968</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 microfilm reels;</extent>
        <dimensions encodinganalog="300$c">35 mm.</dimensions>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Minute books, financial records, legal documents, record books, minutes of church trials and other records of the churches which merged to form the Morrisville Community Church.  Churches involved include the Congregational Church (1805-1925), the Baptist Church (1809-1925), the United Church (1925-1968), and the First Methodist Church of Morrisville (1834-1968).</abstract>
      <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">149346</unitid>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>The Community Church of Morrisville, New York, was formed in 1968 by a merger of the 
United Church of Morrisville and the First Methodist Church. The United Church was itself 
the result of a merger in 1925 of the First Congregational and the First Baptist Churches 
of Morrisville. The history of the Community Church of Morrisville is thus a composite of 
the histories of these four different churches.</p>
      <p>The First Congregational Church of Morrisville was organized in June, 1805 by fifteen 
people, most of whom had come to the area from New England. They erected their first 
church building in 1817. In 1859, a vestibule was added, and in 1871 and 1902 extensive 
repairs were made.</p>
      <p>Organized as a Congregational Church, in 1805 it was admitted to membership in the 
Oneida Association of that denomination. However, under the influence of the second 
pastor, the church voted to become Presbyterian, severed its relationship with the Oneida 
Association, and united with the Oneida Presbytery in 1819. There was continuing 
opposition to this change, and its extent was great enough to cause a vote two years 
later to return the church to its original form of worship and organization. The 
relationship to the Oneida Presbytery continued for a time, but it was severed in 1842, 
and the church reunited with the Oneida Association of the Congregational denomination. 
In 1859 and 1897 the church experienced great revivals and large numbers of people were 
added to the membership.</p>
      <p>Part of the early records of this church are the minutes of church trials in which 
members of the congregation were "excommunicated" for failure to attend communion, 
intoxication, or working on Sunday, among other things. At one of the trials, Gerrit 
Smith was asked to serve as counsel. Noteworthy also is the fact that in 1842 the church 
voted resolutions against the institution of slavery and during the pre-Civil War period 
they continually gave financial aid to the cause of abolition.</p>
      <p>The Baptist Church of Morrisville had its origin in 1809.  It was received into the 
Madison Baptist Association in September 1809 and reported a membership of 27. In the 
early months of its history the church met in the schoolhouse for its services of 
worship, but later in 1809 the first meeting house was built.</p>
      <p>In 1826 the congregation built on a new site, and in 1849 another new site was chosen 
and a third church building was constructed. This building subsequently became the home 
of the United Church.</p>
      <p>The abolition movement also had its effect on the Baptist Church of Morrisville. The 
anti-slavery agitation caused a serious split in the church membership, and a large 
number left the church as a result.</p>
      <p>In June 1925 the First Congregational Church and the Baptist held the first meeting of 
a committee whose purpose was to study the union of the two churches. In August an 
agreement was drawn up which provided for a trial union of one year. The first meeting of 
the churches under this agreement was in October 1925, and in January 1926 they welcomed 
the first pastor. The denominational groups within the church continued to maintain some 
identity, particularly as it was legally necessary for them to administer property. It 
was not until 1934 that the church undertook its own separate incorporation.</p>
      <p>In 1938 the Congregational corporate body leased the former Congregational Church to 
the Roman Catholic diocese for use at St. Theresa's parish in Morrisville. The United 
Church now made the former Baptist Church its home. In 1939 the church building was 
improved by the addition of a new organ. Further improvements and expansion of the church 
facilities were undertaken in 1946.</p>
      <p>The Morrisville Methodist Episcopal Church began on February 24, 1834, with services 
held at the Old Court House. In 1835 the construction of a permanent place of worship was 
begun on land which was donated to the society, and the first permanent pastor began his 
ministry.</p>
      <p>In 1859 there is some record that Morrisville and Peterboro were linked as a single 
pastoral charge. Later, in 1876, records indicate that the churches in Morrisville and 
Eaton were also served by a single pastor. During this period the Methodists of the 
Morrisville area held yearly camp meetings at a farm near the town.</p>
      <p>In 1881 and 1882 the church building, which was originally constructed upon a high 
foundation, was lowered to make entry more accessible for the elderly of the 
congregation. In the process the kitchen and other auxiliary space under the building was 
lost. A new organ was installed in 1893 after one corner of the building was rebuilt, and 
in 1905 the church was reshingled, repainted, and recarpeted. New sheds were also built 
to house the horses of the congregation during the services.</p>
      <p>The promise of a subsidy from the Methodist annual conference induced the church to 
undertake the excavation of the church basement in order to provide more space. The 
subsidy was never forthcoming and the women's society paid the mortgage.</p>
      <p>The Community Church of Morrisville, New York had its origins in discussions between 
officials of the United Church of Morrisville and the First Methodist Church of 
Morrisville as to the possibility of a union of the two congregations. A committee was 
formed to study the matter, and, after studying the various possibilities, such a 
federation or union, with the help of churches which had chosen one of the alternatives, 
the decision was made to merge the two churches into a Community Church and to affiliate 
with the Presbyterian denomination. These plans were approved by both congregations and 
the merger was consummated in 1968.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The 
        
        <emph render="bold">Morrisville Community Church (Morrisville NY) Records</emph> are made up of the 
records of five different churches. The Congregational Church, 1805-1925, merged in 1925 
with the Baptist Church, 1809-1925, to form the United Church, 1925-1968, and this church 
in turn merged with the First Methodist Church of Morrisville, 1834-1968, to form the 
Community Church, 1968 to the present. The organization of the papers follows this 
sequence.</p>
      <p>The papers of the 
        
        <emph render="bold">Congregational Church of Morrisville</emph>, 1805-1939, consist of a church 
record book, minute books of church meetings, a church financial record book, minute 
books of the Woman's Missionary Society, church manuals, and legal papers and histories. 
Included in the record book is a history of the church from 1898 to 1939, part of which 
is made up of minutes of the annual meetings of the church. Of note also is the minute 
book, 1817-1938, of the Presbyterian Society, which was the legally constituted corporate 
body administering the property of the Congregational Church. The church manuals, 1849-
1903, contain statements of belief adhered to by the congregation and constitutions which 
detail its organization. The legal papers, 1939?, consist of a lease by the church of its 
property to St. Theresa's Roman Catholic Church.</p>
      <p>The papers of the 
        
        <emph render="bold">Baptist Church of Morrisville</emph>, 1809-1934, include church records, 
church minute books, minute books of the Ladies Aid Society, minute books of the Young 
People's Society of Christian Endeavor, legal papers, a church covenant and historical 
papers. The second volume of the church records, 1809-1934, and the first volume of the 
church minute books, 1835-1934, were both hand copied from original records and include a 
historical record of the church. The second volume of the church minutes, 1842-1892, 
contains the church covenant and articles of faith and practice, as well as a revised 
version of the same. The legal papers, 1849-1935, consist of a lease for a church pew and 
a lease of the Baptist Church property to the United Church. Among the historical papers, 
1814-1909, are a letter from a former member, an announcement of a church meeting, and a 
souvenir brochure of the church centennial.</p>
      <p>The papers of the 
        
        <emph render="bold">United Church of Morrisville</emph>, 1925-1967, consist of a minute book of 
the Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, a minute and financial record book of 
the United Missionary Society, minute books and a record book of the United Circle, the 
papers of the Ladies Auxiliary, financial papers, legal papers, historical material and 
histories, and correspondence. The record book of the United Circle contains information 
regarding the church suppers organized by the circle. The financial papers, 1929-1945, 
include church treasurers' reports and church budgets. The historical material, 1939-
1969, includes programs, photographs, specifications, and bank records relating to the 
purchase and dedication of an organ for the church. Also found here are a history of the 
United Church written for its 25th anniversary in 1950 and a souvenir history written for 
the sesquicentennial in 1959 of the churches which merged to form the United Church. The 
correspondence 1966, relates to the existence and location of early church records of the 
Congregational and Baptist churches.</p>
      <p>The papers of the 
        
        <emph render="bold">First Methodist Church of Morrisville</emph>, 1836-1923, consist of a 
church record book, minute books of the Quarterly Conference, a minute book of the 
trustees, and a record book of the church school. Included in the church record book are 
membership records for churches in Eaton, Fenner, and Peterboro.</p>
      <p>The papers of the 
        
        <emph render="bold">Community Church of Morrisville</emph>, 1958-1968, consist of materials 
gathered by the committee of the United Church and the First Methodist Church which was 
organized to study the possibility of a merger and the shape that merger should take. 
This includes a copy of the consolidation agreement of Danby, New York, Federated Church, 
1958; reports of the merger committee in Groton, New York, which created the Groton 
Community Church, and correspondence between the head of that committee and a committee 
member in Morrisville, 1964-1968; copies of the by-laws and the consolidation agreement 
of the West Winfield, New York, Federated Church, 1964; and memos to the members of the 
merger committee, letters to the church members and to denominational executives, a 
church newsletter, reports to the congregation, and an order of worship for the 
celebration of church union by the Morrisville Community Church, 1968.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>Other than the subdivision by church, the records appear to have been scanned in 
		no particular order.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>&scrc_name; has numerous collections relating to church and clergy in and around 
		Central New York.  Please refer to &subjindex; for a complete listing.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
    </separatedmaterial>--><!--
            <otherfindaid encodinganalog="555"><head>Other Related Finding Aids</head><p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p></otherfindaid>
            -->
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Church and clergy</subject>
	  <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">New York State</subject>
	  <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Baptist Church of Morrisville (Morrisville, N.Y.)</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Congregational Church of Morrisville (Morrisville, N.Y.)</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">First Methodist Church of Morrisville (Morrisville, N.Y.)</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Morrisville Community Church (Morrisville, N.Y.)</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United Church of Morrisville (Morrisville, N.Y.)</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Church records and registers -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Baptist church buildings -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Congregational churches -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Congregationalists -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Baptists -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Methodist Church -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Methodists -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">United churches -- New York (State) -- Morrisville.</subject>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Morrisville (NY)</geogname><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Church registers.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Ledgers (account books)</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Minutes (administrative records)</genreform>
    </controlaccess>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
                       all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
                       materials in this collection. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Morrisville Community Church (Morrisville NY) Records
        
        <lb/>&su_name;</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>The collection was microfilmed in August of 1970, from originals owned by the 
			Community Church of Morrisville and lent through the courtesy of Mr. William 
			Houghton.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <!--
            <appraisal encodinganalog="583"><head>Appraisal Information</head><p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       --><!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584"><head>Accruals</head><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Inventory</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>First Congregational Church of Morrisville, New York</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church record book</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1898/1939" type="inclusive">1898-1939</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">1</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Lists of pastors, deacons, baptisms, membership, marriages
              
              <lb/>
		Historical record</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church minutes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1805/1835" type="inclusive">1805-1835</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">2</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of church meetings
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of baptisms, admissions to membership, dismissions from membership, deaths and excommunications</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church minutes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1817/1938" type="inclusive">1817-1938</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">3</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings of the Presbyterian Society (corporate body)</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church financial records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1844/1922" type="inclusive">1844-1922</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">4</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Records of receipt and disbursement of funds</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minute book of Women's Missionary Society</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1909" type="inclusive">1897-1909</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">5</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church manuals</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1849/1903" type="inclusive">1849-1903</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">1</container></did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1938" type="inclusive">1938</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">2</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Lease of First Congregational Church building to St. Theresa's Roman Catholic parish</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Histories</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1909" type="inclusive">1909</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">2</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Centennial brochure
              
              <lb/>
		Morrisville Leader</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Morrisville Baptist Church</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church record book</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1882/1926" type="inclusive">1882?-1926?</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">6</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Membership list</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church record book</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1809/1934" type="inclusive">1809-1934</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">7</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Lists of membership, Sunday School statistics, pastors, clerks, treasurers, Sunday School superintendents, Deacons, Trustees, and general statistics
              
              <lb/>
		Historical record, 1809-1835</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church minutes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1835/1934" type="inclusive">1835-1934</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">8</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Historical record, 1835-1865
              
              <lb/>
		Minutes of church meetings, 1865-1934</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church minutes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1842/1892" type="inclusive">1842-1892</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">9</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Church Covenant and Articles of Faith and Practice, undated
              
              <lb/>
		Minutes, 1842-1892
              
              <lb/>
		List of membership, 1811-1880
              
              <lb/>
		Revised Church Covenant and Articles of Faith and Practice, 1858</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church minutes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1892/1923" type="inclusive">1892-1923</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">10</container></did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of Ladies Aid Society  (incomplete)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1897/1919" type="inclusive">1897-1919</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">11</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings, 1897-1919
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of contributions, 1897-1898
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1889/1891" type="inclusive">1889-1891</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">12</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Constitution, 1889
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership and officers, 1889-1891
              
              <lb/>
		Minutes of meetings, 1890-1891</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal papers and histories</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1849/1909" type="inclusive">1849-1909</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">3</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p> Lease of pew, 1849
              
              <lb/>Lease to United Church, 1935
              
              <lb/>
		Covenant of Morrisville Baptist Church, undated
              
              <lb/>
		Letter from A.P. Tillinghast, 1884
              
              <lb/>
		Announcement of Roll-Call meeting, 1891
              
              <lb/>
		Request for aid from Whitney Point Baptist Church, 1897
              
              <lb/>
		Souvenir History, One Hundredth Anniversary of the Morrisville Baptist Church, 1909</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>United Church of Morrisville, New York</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minute book of Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1935/1957" type="inclusive">1935-1957</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">13</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Lists of membership
              
              <lb/>
		Minutes of meetings, 1935-1937</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minute book of United Missionary Society</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1925/1963" type="inclusive">1925-1963</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">14</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings, 1925-1932
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Financial record of United Missionary Society</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1925/1963" type="inclusive">1925-1963</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">15</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Lists of contributors, 1925-1940
              
              <lb/>
		Financial reports, 1926-1963</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minute book of United Circle</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1956" type="inclusive">1945-1956</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">16</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings
              
              <lb/>
		Annual reports
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minute book of United Circle</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1961" type="inclusive">1956-1961</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">17</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minute book of United Circle</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1961/1967" type="inclusive">1961-1967</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">18</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Minutes of meetings
              
              <lb/>
		Annual reports
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of membership</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Record book of United Circle</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1949/1956" type="inclusive">1949-1956</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">19</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Records of Church suppers
              
              <lb/>
		Miscellaneous budgets, reports and correspondence</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Financial records, legal papers, histories and correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1922/1966" type="inclusive">1922-1966</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">4</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Constitution of Ladies Auxiliary of United Church (includes Constitution of Ladies Congregational Society and miscellaneous minutes), 1922?
              
              <lb/>
		Treasurer's reports and budgets, 1929-1945
              
              <lb/>
		Registration of rental dwelling, Office of Price Administration, 1942
              
              <lb/>
		Material related to dedication of organ, 1939 Brief history of United Church, 1940?
              
              <lb/>
		Souvenir history, Sesquicentennial of United Church, 1959
              
              <lb/>
		Correspondence regarding church records, 1966</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>First Methodist Church of Morrisville, New York</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church record book (includes records for Peterboro, Fenner, and Eaton)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1859/1881" type="inclusive">1859-1881</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">20</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Lists of membership, stewards, trustees, and other church officers.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of the Quarterly Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1869/1879" type="inclusive">1869-1879</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">21</container></did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of the Quarterly Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1878/1890" type="inclusive">1878-1890</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">22</container></did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of the Quarterly Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1890/1901" type="inclusive">1890-1901</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">23</container></did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of the Quarterly Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1902/1921" type="inclusive">1902-1921</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">24</container></did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Minutes of the Trustees</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1836/1923" type="inclusive">1836-1923</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">25</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Copy of Certificate of Incorporation of the First Society of the Methodist Episcopal Church in Morrisville, New York, 1834
              
              <lb/>
		Minutes of the meeting
              
              <lb/>
		Letters of resignation</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Church School Records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1869/1874" type="inclusive">1869-1874</unitdate>
          <container type="Volume">26</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Attendance records
              
              <lb/>
		Minutes of church school sessions
              
              <lb/>
		Lists of classes, teachers, and officers</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Community Church of Morrisville, New York</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Materials used in formation of Community Church of Morrisville</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1958/1968" type="inclusive">1958-1968</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">5</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Consolidation Agreement, First Congregational Society in Danby with First Danby Methodist Episcopal Church into Danby Federated Church, 1958
              
              <lb/>
		Report of Study Committee to members of Baptist Methodist, and United Churches of Groton Community Church to members of Baptist, Congregational and Methodist Churches, Mar 8, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Report of Special Committee on Denominational Affiliation of Groton Community Churches to church members, Apr 26, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Agenda, Joint meeting of members of Baptist Congregational and Methodist Churches of Groton, New York, May 1, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Report of Committee on Spiritual Life, Worship, and Doctrinal Procedure of Groton Community Church to church members, May 1, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Letter, Board of Trustees of Groton Community Church to church members, May 4, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Proposed Church Merger, First Methodist Church, First Baptist Church, First Congregational Church of Groton, New York, Jun 7, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Letter, Board of Trustees and Pastor of Groton Community Church to church members and Consolidated Constitution and By-laws of the Groton Community Church of the United Church of Christ, Sep 1, 1966
              
              <lb/>
		Letter, Board of Trustees of Groton Community Church to church members, Jan 3, 1967 
              
              <lb/>
		Suggested addition to Section 2, Article VII (page 5) of the Consolidated Constitution and By-laws
              
              <lb/>
		Report of Board of Trustees of Groton Community Church, 1967
              
              <lb/>
		Budget of Groton Community Church, 1967 
              
              <lb/>
		Proposed Church merger, First Methodist Church, First Baptist Church, First Congregational Church of Groton, New York, Jun 7, 1966 
              
              <lb/>
		History of Groton Community Church,1967 
              
              <lb/>
		Order of Worship, Service of Recognition and Installation, Groton Community Church, Apr 9, 1967
              
              <lb/>
		Letter, Stanley E. Skinner to Walter Ketcham, May 15, 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Correspondence, William Houghton to Howard Tyler, Jul 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Correspondence, Howard Tyler to William Houghton Jul 8, 1968</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Materials used in formation of Community Church of Morrisville</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1968" type="inclusive">1964-1968</unitdate>
          <container type="Folder">6</container></did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Revised copy, By-laws of the Federated Church of West Winfield, New York, Oct 1, 1964
              
              <lb/>
		Consolidation Agreement of First Baptist Church, Emmanuel Congregational Church and Harmony Society, and First Methodist Church of West Winfield, Winfield, New York, 1964
              
              <lb/>
		Revised copy of above
              
              <lb/>
		Memo to members of Denominational Affiliation Committee of Morrisville Community Church, 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Memo to Nominating Committee of Morrisville Community Church from Board of Trustees, 1968
              
              <lb/>
		List of actions to be taken, Merger Study Commission of Morrisville Community Church, 1968?
              
              <lb/>
		Letter to members of United Church of Morrisville and First Methodist Church of Morrisville from Merger Study Committee and Consolidation Agreement, Jun 12, 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Letter to William Houghton from Edwin G. Hambrick, May 8, 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Letter to Glenn Olmstead and William Houghton from Stanley Skinner, May 13, 1968
              
              <lb/>
		First issue of Morrisville Community Church newsletter, "Concern," Sep 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Report to members of Morrisville Community Church from Board of Trustees, Sep 1968
              
              <lb/>
		Order of Worship, Commemorative Celebration of Church Union, Morrisville Community Church, Nov 24, 1968</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
