<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="pease_b" mainagencycode="NSyU">pease_b</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Barzillai Pease Journals</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        his papers 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">AES</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
          <lb/></publisher>&su_address;
        <date encodinganalog="Date" normal="1969-06">June 1969</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           
        
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>3 Nov 2008 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item><item>2 Aug 2017 - rehoused (MRC)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
        <lb/>&su_address;</repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Pease, Barzillai, 1773-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Barzillai Pease Journals</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1789/1826" type="inclusive">1789-1826</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.5 linear ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">
                    American seaman, pilot, ship's captain.   Journals combining ship's logs and personal diaries concerning Pease's career as a merchant seaman and tenure as Commander of United States Transports on Lake Ontario during the War of 1812.</abstract>
      <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">149465</unitid>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Barzillai Pease was an American seaman, pilot, and ship's captain, and Commander of United States Transports on Lake Ontario during the War of 1812.</p>
      <p>Pease was born at Edgartown, Martha's Vineyard, Massachusetts, on July 27, 
		1773, the son of Barzillai Pease, a seaman who was prize master aboard a privateer during 
		the American Revolution, and Deborah Coffin Pease.

When Barzillai was fourteen years old, his family moved to Hudson, New York, in or near which 
he eventually established his own family of a wife, two sons and two daughters, both sons 
dying during the period covered by the journals.</p>
      <p>In 1789 he made his first voyage, aboard the whaling ship 
        
        <emph render="italic">Prudence</emph>, and continued his 
seafaring life at least through 1826 when the journals end. He shipped aboard whalers and 
sealers chiefly in his earlier years but occasionally on ships carrying cargo, sometimes as a 
crew member, at least once as mate, and several times as master of his own vessel.</p>
      <p>Infrequent visits home were joyful occasions but lasted only as long as it took Pease to find 
another berth. In 1814 he turned to fresh water navigation when he was appointed commander of 
United States Transports on Lake Ontario. For eighteen months of the War of 1812 he continued 
in this service, and after resigning in August, 1815, he continued to sail the lake as captain 
of a ship carrying passengers and cargo.</p>
      <p>Pease spent the winter of 1817-1818 in prison in Cambridge, Massachusetts, for an unidentified 
reason, perhaps a matter of debt. Whatever the cause, he protests his innocence in Journal 17, 
written during his incarceration.</p>
      <p>The final journal in the collection seems to indicate that Pease, sailing for Bermuda with 
Anguilla as his ultimate destination, was seeking treasure of which he had some knowledge. 
However, he found nothing and returned to New York on September 9, 1826, the date of the 
final entry in the journals.
</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The 
        
        <emph render="bold">Barzillai Pease Journals</emph> consists of fourteen journals in 
		nine volumes, which recount the adventures and misadventures of the American seaman, pilot, 
		and ship's captain.</p><p>The form of the journals varies. Some are composed of daily entries combining ship's log and notations of the nature of a general diary. Others are narrative accounts, apparently written after the voyages they describe were over. Sometimes these forms are combined in a single journal; and in one or two cases, narrative accounts seem to have been written from the daily journals which are included in the collection, thus accounting for some duplication of content.</p><p>The journals include accounts of a number of shipwrecks and hardships suffered; detailed descriptions of sealing and whaling procedures, some with ink drawings of whales; and descriptions with several profile drawings and a few maps of West Indian and Falkland Islands. Life aboard schooners, sloops and brigs of the late 18th and early 19th centuries is depicted and includes mutinous behavior and other personnel problems, sometimes involving violence.  Destinations include Martinique, the Falkland 
		Islands, the South Seas, Nantucket, New Bedford, Cape Horn, Barbados, Nova Scotia, 
		Newfoundland, and various cities on Lake Ontario.  </p><p>The two journals written while Pease was Commander of United States Transports on Lake Ontario during the War of 1812 describe transportation of soldiers on the lake, and New York towns bordering on the Lake, particularly Sackets Harbor, including their preparations for defense such as the building of forts and raising of militia. Also included are a list of names of all the men employed on the transports with the dates on which they worked and the wages paid, a list of the names and numbers of all United States Transports on Lake Ontario during the war, and a list of passengers and freight carried on the lake from May to December, 1816.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>The journals are in chronological order.  The first few volumes contain several journals 
		bound together.</p>
    </arrangement>
      <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>&scrc_name; has several other 18th and 19th century ship's logs.  Please search &summitref;, for "ship's logs" for a complete listing.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
    </separatedmaterial>--><!--
            <otherfindaid encodinganalog="555"><head>Other Related Finding Aids</head><p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p></otherfindaid>
            -->
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Military history</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">New York State</subject><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Pease, Barzillai, 1773-</persname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Merchant marine -- Officers.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Merchant mariners.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Navigation -- History.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Pilots and pilotage.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Sealing.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Sailors -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Ship captains -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Shipwrecks -- Archival resources.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Whaling -- Archival resources.</subject>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States -- History -- War of 1812.</geogname>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Naval, To 1900.</geogname>
      
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Diaries.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Ships' logs.</genreform>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Seamen.</occupation>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Ship captains.</occupation>
    </controlaccess>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
                       all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
                       materials in this collection. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Barzillai Pease Journals,
        
        <lb/>&su_name;</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Purchase, 1969.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <!--
            <appraisal encodinganalog="583">
				<head>Appraisal Information</head>
				<p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       --><!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584">
				<head>Accruals</head>
				<p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Inventory</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 1]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1789/1795" type="inclusive">1789-1795</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 1 (pp. 1-54): Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Prudence</emph>, Albertus Swain, Master, to Martinique and other islands;
	Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Prudence</emph>, Solomon Bunker, Master;
	Brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Nancy</emph>, John Barnard, Master, to the Falkland Islands;
	Brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Hero</emph>, to the "Western Islands"</unittitle>
            <abstract>narrative account</abstract><unitdate normal="1789/1790" type="inclusive">1789-1790</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>The first three pages give an account of Barzillai Pease' early life.  His first voyage is described beginning on page 4, aboard the whaling ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Prudence</emph> in 1789, Albertus Swain, Master. Twelve days out they ran into a violent storm which dismasted the ship. As they headed back, they spotted another wreck but because of the storm they were forced to proceed without offering help.  The 
              
              <emph render="italic">Prudence</emph> landed in Martinique, refitted, and the crew continued Whaling, catching only two whales.  Pease describes the poor physical treatment he received from the captain, being struck several times for minor offenses or none at all.  The ship returned to Hudson for repairs. Several pages describe his return home and life there before shipping on board the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Prudence</emph> again, Solomon Bunker, Master, for a whaling voyage of eight months, following which he returned again to Hudson.</p>
            <p>In 1790 Pease shipped aboard the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Nancy</emph>, John Barnard, Master, for a sealing voyage to the Falkland Islands. He describes the voyage and the loss of a man overboard. After carefully avoiding landing on the Barbary Coast because of fears of being taken as slaves if forced to land there, their first stop was the Cape Verde Islands.  Pease describes whales sighted along the voyage and landing in the Falklands. He describes the islands, sealing and the methods used, and other animals caught on the islands. On the return voyage he describes a narrow miss from crashing into an iceberg. The 
              
              <emph render="italic">Nancy</emph> landed in New York nineteen months after starting out on this voyage.</p>
            <p>Pease shipped next on the brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Hero</emph>, bound for the "Western Islands." He describes the voyage to South Georgia, the difficulty of avoiding icebergs and the landing. The ship was wrecked on the rocks and he describes in detail the efforts to save everything they possibly could. They waited for wreckage to float ashore and built a house from the salvaged wood. There were no provisions and the men were starving; half of them were suffering from dysentery. He describes the capturing and killing of animals for food and the gathering of eggs. Eventually they were able to board an English ship whose captain was both cruel and habitually drunk. After leaving South Georgia, they were attacked by a Spanish ship, the English ship boarded and plundered and its masts badly damaged by the Spanish guns. When stopped by English men-of-war, the English sailors were hidden. Fifteen Americans were taken prisoner and carried to England. Pease gives a brief account of their stay in England until their departure for America in an unidentified ship.</p>
            <p>The remaining journals follow the same general pattern of seamanship, description and events, and are described more briefly hereafter.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 2 (p. 55-78):
	Brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Nancy</emph> to the Falkland Islands</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1792-11-08/1794-05-12" type="inclusive">Nov 8, 1792-May 12, 1794</unitdate>
            <abstract>log; ontains two profile drawings of islands</abstract>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>There are no entries for Dec. 12-23, 1792, Jan. 8-27, 1793, and April 3-March 1, 1793.
Pease describes encounters with several whalers and notes a number of sightings of whales. The journal contains two ink drawings of profiles of islands at which they landed, with brief descriptions of the islands.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 3 (p. 79-116):
	Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Hero</emph> to South Georgia</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1794-09-19/1795-06-12" type="inclusive">Sep 19, 1794-June 12, 1795</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
The day-to-day record of the voyage to South Georgia on the ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Hero</emph>, 
which is described in a running narrative at the end of Journal 1. There are no entries for 
the first part of the voyage, nor for the period Nov. 17-29, 1794. The description of the 
voyage to South Georgia ends Jan. 1, 1795 and begins again on Jan. 26, after the shipwreck. 
Four and a half pages of entries in faded pencil apparently were written just after the wreck.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 2]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1795/1799" type="inclusive">1795-1799</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 4 (p. 1-29):
	Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">America</emph>, Strubel Coffin, Master, London to Boston</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1795-06-12/1795-10-27" type="inclusive">June 12, 1795-Oct 27, 1795</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Account of the voyage from London, where they were taken by an English ship 
	which picked them up after the shipwreck, to Boston in the ship America. After leaving 
	London, the 
              
              <emph render="italic">America</emph> was stopped by English men-of-war and 
	searched for Englishmen.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 5 (p. 30-115):
	Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Oswego</emph>, George Clark, Master, to Cape of Good Hope</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal; contains 42 drawings of whales</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1795-12-22/1797-07-01" type="inclusive">Dec 22, 1795-July 1, 1797</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Nearly the entire journal is concerned with whaling and includes sightings, 
	chases, the overturning of boats by whales and the sinking of several, harpooning, and 
	encounters and conversations with whalers from Nantucket and New Bedford, describing their 
	successes and the amount of oil secured. He describes the cutting up and boiling down of 
	the whales for oil. The journal has 42 whales drawn in.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 6 (p. 116-206):
	Brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Rebecca</emph>, Urial Coffin, Master, around Cape Horn, with some time spent on the Falkland Islands</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1797-12-18/1799-11-12" type="inclusive">Dec 18, 1797-Nov 12, 1799</unitdate>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal; contains profile drawings of several 
	islands and a map of Juan Fernandez drawn by Pease</abstract>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Shortly after leaving on this voyage, one of the crew died of smallpox. The 
	first stop was the Cape Verde Islands, for supplies; from there they continued toward the 
	Falkland Islands. During this part of the voyage a large comet was sighted and was visible 
	for ten or fifteen minutes.  In May, 1798, they landed in the Falklands. Pease describes the 
	islands and the sealing process on them. Rounding Cape Horn, they landed on the island of 
	Mocha, sighting many whales along the way. There they built a house for processing the seals 
	and further descriptions of sealing on Mocha follow. He gives a lengthy account of a boat in 
	which he and others were trying to land being wrecked on the rocks, and continues with 
	descriptions of skinning operations and a violent argument between the captain and a crew 
	member. The ship sailed from Mocha, met a Nantucket whaler who gave them wood with which to 
	rebuild their boat, and returned to Mocha to pick up their skins. The 
              
              <emph render="italic">Rebecca</emph> 
	then sailed to several other islands. Pease drew a map of Juan Fernandez and profiles of 
	several other islands in the journal. They met and boarded a number of other ships, mostly 
	whalers and sealers, and were told that three captains and twenty-seven crewmen had been 
	taken by the Spanish and it was thought they had been shot immediately. As they met various 
	whalers and their captains went aboard the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Rebecca</emph>, he describes 
	each ship and records the amount of oil she carried.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 3]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1802/1812" type="inclusive">1802-1812</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 7 (p. 1-39):
	Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">John</emph>, B. Pease, Master, to Cape Horn and Grand Turk Island;
	Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">John</emph> for Barbados;
	Sloop 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph>[?]  to Nova Scotia</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1802/1803" type="inclusive">1802-1803</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>The first journal containing accounts of voyages with Barzillai Pease 
	himself as Master. The journal includes three voyages, the first begun on Aug. 15, 1802, 
	the second on Dec. 24, 1802, and the third on Aug. 21, 1803. The first two were made in the 
	schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">John</emph>.  On Aug. 15, 1802, the 
	
              
              <emph render="italic">John</emph> started from New York for the Cape with a cargo of sheep, 
	but many of the animals perished on the voyage and it was terminated at Grand Turk Island, 
	the schooner returning to New York.  On Dec. 24 they left New York for Barbados. The ship 
	leaked and the crew were ill; one man died. Eighteen days out they landed at Guadalupe, 
	where they sold their cargo and bought cargo for the return trip. They then stopped at 
	several West Indian islands to purchase more cargo but found none to buy. Pease gives advice 
	on how to approach the islands.  Pease set out on a fishing voyage along the Northeast coast 
	to Nova Scotia on Aug. 31, 1803, but was badly damaged by a storm and arrived back at New York 
	Nov. 7.  This voyage may have been made in the sloop 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph>.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 8 (p. 39-53):
	Sloop 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph>, B. Pease, Master, to Newfoundland</unittitle>
            <abstract>running account</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1803/1806" type="inclusive">1803-1806</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>A running narrative from the spring of 1803 to May of 1806, beginning with 
	a description of the fitting out of the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph> for a fishing 
	voyage. After stopping at Edgartown, they proceeded to the coast of Newfoundland. Boarding 
	what they thought was an American ship, they discovered it was an English man-of-war 
	disguised as American to lure French ships into capture. The English had caught many French 
	ships in this way and had unloaded them before burning them. They advised Pease and the crew 
	to go into port and take all the fish they wanted from the supply taken from the French. 
	However, the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph> lost all her fish during a hurricane off the 
	coast.  After this voyage, Pease was charged with smuggling, but the charges were dropped. 
	He then bought his own ship, went on another fishing voyage along the coast and then to the 
	West Indies.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 9 (p. 59-81):
	Sloop 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph>, B. Pease, Master
	</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, log and journal; ship's log for voyages described in Journals 7 and 8</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1803-06-09/1803-11-09" type="inclusive">June 9, 1803-Nov. 9, 1803</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Aboard the sloop 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph> on a fishing voyage to the Straights, , B. Pease, Master.
This journal includes two voyages, the first already described in Journal 8 and the second in Journal 
7.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 10 (p. 85-143):
	Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">Olive Branch</emph>, B. Pease, Master, to West Indies;
	Robert Fulton's steamboat on the Hudson River, with B. Pease signed on as pilot;
	Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Delight</emph> (voyage not described);
	Voyage to West Indies</unittitle>
            <abstract>running account</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1806/1812" type="inclusive">1806-1812</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Pease describes the voyage to the Indies aboard the schooner 
	
              
              <emph render="italic">Olive Branch</emph> and trading there. There was trouble getting out 
	to sea at the start as the ship stuck on a sand bar. On the return voyage the 
	
              
              <emph render="italic">Olive Branch</emph> was struck by a hurricane and on pages 8-15 he 
	describes the wreck of his ship in detail. The 
              
              <emph render="italic">Olive Branch</emph> 
	turned over and Pease was trapped in the cabin but finally managed to get out of the ship 
	and swim to the surface. Climbing onto the ship's mast to stay afloat, he saw one member of 
	his crew, a Long Island Indian, swim to the surface. Pease threw him a rope and they lashed 
	themselves to the mast. Only he and the Indian survived the storm, four other crew members 
	drowning. They made nooses for catching sharks and retrieved floating oranges from the 
	wreckage. They climbed atop the ship's hull and Pease suffered a severe sunburn. Finally 
	making a sail to attract a ship, they were picked up and on the way to port saw the wreckage 
	of many ships. Pease was badly bruised and had a number of injuries.
</p>
            <p>After recovering, Pease took the ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">George</emph> to North 
Carolina and Jamaica. He describes in detail a dead mermaid which had floated ashore and 
claims he had seen many of them in the past, but continues to discuss the "mermaid mistake," 
indicating that he believes them to be a form of sea mammal similar to the seal. The boat 
being badly damaged, he sold it in sections when they reached St. Ann's and went on to 
Jamaica, returning to New York aboard the sloop 
              
              <emph render="italic">Polly</emph>.

</p>
            <p>For a while Pease worked as a pilot at Nantucket but the local pilots gave him some
 trouble. He then returned home and signed on as a pilot for Robert Fulton to pilot his 
 steamboat up the Hudson River early in 1808. On pages 39-46 he describes the journey up the 
 Hudson, including his disagreements with the captain, whose poor judgment ran the ship 
 aground and caused it to ram into a sloop, a dock and sandbars. He returned to Hudson and 
 left on Feb. 27, 1809 in the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Delight</emph> for a voyage which is not 
 described.

In 1811 Pease shipped on a voyage to the West Indies and was shipwrecked again, a hurricane 
wrecking his ship and many others. The final pages of the journal are concerned with this 
event, the last page containing his contract for a voyage to the Falkland Islands in 1812.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 11 (p. 145-163):
	Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">Delight</emph>, B. Pease, Master, to West Indies</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1810-02-27/1810-07-20" type="inclusive">Feb 27, 1810-July 20, 1810</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>From New York to St. Bartholomew's on the schooner 
	
              
              <emph render="italic">Delight</emph>.  Pease describes the various islands which they 
	touched and relates being stopped by English men-of-war but not harassed. There is a 
	full page account of a Fourth of July celebration aboard ship.
This is possibly the same voyage noted but not described in volume 10, although dates differ</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 12 (p. 164-191):
	Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">Governor Richardson</emph> to St. Martins</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal; contains six profile drawings of islands in the West
	Indies and drawing of a map of the harbor of St. Martins</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1810-08-27/1810-12-25" type="inclusive">Aug 27, 1810-Dec 25, 1810</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 4]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1812/1816" type="inclusive">1812-1816</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 13 (p. 1-46):
	Brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Nanina</emph>, Valentine Barnard, Master, to South Seas; return home on 
              
              <emph render="italic">Bingham</emph> of Philadelphia</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal; also a narrative account of parts of the voyage</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1812-03-12/1813-12-11" type="inclusive">March 12, 1812-Dec 11, 1813</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Four men, including Pease, undertook to make the voyage on the brig 
              
              <emph render="italic">Nanina</emph> as joint backers, Valentine Barnard being appointed Master by the others. They had a little trouble getting out of their American port because of the Embargo. Pease provides long descriptions of islands where they landed for supplies and includes a drawing of one.
After landing in the Falklands, Pease describes their sealing activities. There is serious 
trouble with a crew member who seemed to go berserk and had a violent quarrel with the captain, 
threatening them all with a pistol. The ship received news that America and England were at 
war, but picked up the crew of the wrecked English ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Isabelle</emph>. 
There are no entries for the month of May. </p><p>Captain Barnard was not in the main boat when the 
English crew was picked up. The others agreed to take the English to a South American port, 
but the English took Over the ship and refused to pick up Captain Barnard. Pease describes
their poor treatment at the hands of the English but they were set free finally and put on an 
English ship for Rio de Janeiro where his crew was ordered to work on the ship. Pease provides 
a lengthy account of prison life aboard the ship. Arriving in Rio, he protested to both the 
English and American ministers but received no aid. After several more unhappy encounters with 
the English, he managed to get home on the ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Bingham</emph> of 
Philadelphia.  Included with this journal are twenty copies of protests about their treatment 
at the hands of the English.  There is some duplication of entries for the same days and 
periods but they are not identical.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 14 (p. 46-69):
	Command of U. S. Transports on Lake Ontario; Packet 
              
              <emph render="italic">Oswego</emph>, B. Pease, Captain, on Lake Ontario</unittitle>
            <abstract>running narrative</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1814/1816" type="inclusive">1814-1816</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Pease was appointed Commander of United States Transports on Lake Ontario on 
	Sept. 6, 1814. On page 47 he describes fitting out an expedition for an unknown destination. 
	After the Battle of Lake Champlain, General Izard's 5000-man army arrived and Pease was told 
	to be ready to transport them in four days. He sailed with Commodore Chauncey's fleet, 
	unloaded the troops who marched to Black Rock, and returned.  Events related to the war and 
	his post as Commander of Transports continue on page 48, where he describes the New York 
	towns bordering on Lake Ontario, particularly Sackets Harbor, in their preparations for 
	defense, including the building of forts and raising of militia. He took charge of moving 
	all the wounded and sick to Brownville for safety, saw two deserters shot, and gives an 
	account of a spy who starved himself to death to forestall hanging. On Aug. 19, 1815, Pease 
	resigned his post.  He then worked for one summer on the packet 
	
              
              <emph render="italic">Oswego</emph>, sailing from Oswego to Niagara. The final part of the 
	journal describes small trips on the waterways and overland travel in upper New York State.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 5]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1814/1815" type="inclusive">1814-1815</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 15 (52 p.):
	Command of U. S. Transports on Lake Ontario</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1814-09-13/1815-10-25" type="inclusive">Sep 13, 1814-Oct 25, 1815</unitdate>
            <abstract>daily entries, combined log and journal</abstract>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>This journal covers a period also reported in Journal 14, but includes in 
	addition the names of the crew from Sackets Harbor under Pease as Commander of United States 
	Transports, a list of the names and numbers of all transports from Sackets Harbor on Lake 
	Ontario, and a list of names of men employed on the transports with the dates they worked 
	and wages paid. The list of transports appears on page 9, with lists of hands employed on 
	pages 1-2 and 16-17.
There are no entries from Jan. 1 to April 10, 1815.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 6]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1816" type="inclusive">1816</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 16 (62 p.):
	Ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Oswego</emph>, B. Pease, Master, on Lake Ontario</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1816-05-22/1816-12-23" type="inclusive">May 22, 1816-Dec 23, 1816</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Aboard the ship 
              
              <emph render="italic">Oswego</emph> of Oswego, New York, 
	B. Pease, Master, carrying passengers and cargo on Lake Ontario.  Description of trips on Lake 
	Ontario, many of them from Oswego to Fort Niagara and Sackets Harbor, and on rivers of upstate 
	New York. Pages 49-64 list passengers and freight carried, with dates and charges.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 7]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1817/1818" type="inclusive">1817-1818</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 17 (30 p.):
	Written in prison in Cambridge, Mass.</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1817-11-20/1818-01-30" type="inclusive">Nov 20, 1817-Jan 30, 1818</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>This journal was written while Pease was in prison in Cambridge, 
	Massachusetts, and describes his life as a prisoner. There is no indication of the reason for 
	his incarceration, but possibly it was a matter of debt. Whatever the cause, he protests his 
	innocence.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>]Volume 8]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1825/1826" type="inclusive">1825-1826</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 18 (46 p.): To Boston, B. Pease, Master;  Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">Margaret</emph> to St. Mary's, Georgia; Working at various shipping jobs in New York City and living aboard the ships;
	Fishing cruise</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1825-07-16/1926-04-29" type="inclusive">July 16, 1825 to April 29, 1826</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>This journal includes a number of brief voyages. The first was a voyage with 
	cargo from Hudson around Cape Cod to Boston and back, stopping at Edgartown on the return 
	trip, followed by various trips up and down the Hudson River. On Oct. 17, 1825, Pease shipped 
	aboard the schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">Margaret</emph> of Newport, Rhode Island, bound for 
	St. Mary's, Georgia, with cargo. He refers to "my low bred and mean captain," with whom the 
	entire crew was unhappy. After this voyage, Pease worked at various shipping jobs in New York 
	City, living aboard ship.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>[Volume 9]</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1826" type="inclusive">1826</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Journal 19 (26 p.):
	Schooner 
              
              <emph render="italic">Margaret</emph>, Darius D. Dennis, Mister, to Bermuda and Guadalupe</unittitle>
            <abstract>daily entries</abstract>
            <unitdate normal="1826-06-03/1826-09-09" type="inclusive">June 3, 1826-Sep 9, 1826</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>
Pease comments on the very poor crew of the 
              
              <emph render="italic">Margaret</emph>. After 
arriving at Bermuda on June 22, the ship caught fire in the harbor and sank. The captain was 
robbed so he could not pay Pease his wages. He describes the island of Bermuda before leaving 
it to sail 16 days to St. Martin's in Anguilla. In Bermuda Pease had been offered $5000 for a 
sworn statement of the location of treasure he apparently was seeking: he says he would accept 
$10,000. He offered the captain $5000 to $10,000 to take him to St. Martin's. When Pease 
found no treasure, the captain was very angry so that Pease records that he wishes he were 
off the ship. At Dominique he found a ship bound for Providence and took passage, arriving in 
New York Sept. 9, 1826.
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
