<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="porter_dd">porter_dd</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">David D. Porter Papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        his papers 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">EFB</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>&su_address;
                           <date normal="1971-04" encodinganalog="Date">April 1971</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>Dec 1975 - revised (EL)</item>
        <item>6 Jul 2009 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item><item>5 Jan 2017 - fixed index code (MRC)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name; <lb/>&su_address;
               </repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Porter, David D. (David Dixon), 1813-1891.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">David D. Porter Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1806/1890">1806-1890</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">69 items.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Papers of the American naval officer.  Correspondence (1806-1890), 35 
outgoing letters, and a number of third party letters which illuninate Porter's promotion of the use of the Fowler Wheel as a 
propulsion system on torpedo boats.  Also, an engraved portrait of Porter, and one of his father, David Porter (1780-1843).</abstract>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="US" repositorycode="NSyU">149527</unitid>
      <langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
<p>David Dixon Porter was a United States naval officer.  He assisted in blockade 
operations during the American Civil War, served as superintendent of the United 
States Naval Academy, and retired with the rank of Admiral.</p>

<p>David D. Porter was born on 8 June 1813 in Chester, 
Pennsylvania, a son of David and Evalina (Anderson) Porter. His father was an 
officer in the United State Navy who resigned in 1826 to take command of the 
Mexican Navy. His paternal grandfather was a Revolutionary naval officer.</p>

<p>Porter served under his father as a midshipman in the Mexican Navy and was 
captured by the Spanish in a naval engagement. He returned to the United 
States in 1829 and became a midshipman in the American navy. During his 
second cruise in the Mediterranean he met George Ann Patterson, the daughter 
of the commander of the ship on which he was serving and whom he would later 
marry.</p>

<p>From 1835, when he received his commission as a passed midshipman, to 1841, 
when he became a lieutenant, he served with the Coast Survey, making 
hydrographic studies along the Atlantic coast. After serving in the 
Mediterranean and off the coast of South America, he returned to Washington 
for additional surveying work. In 1846 he undertook a secret mission to 
evaluate conditions in the newly independent Republic of Santo Domingo prior 
to its recognition by the United States. The outbreak of the Mexican War 
prompted him to apply for an appointment in the action, but he was assigned 
instead to recruitment duty in New Orleans. He subsequently saw action at 
Tabasco, where he captured a fort with a small landing party, for which 
success he was rewarded with his first command.</p>

<p>At the war's end, after a few months at the Naval Observatory in Washington, 
he rejoined the Coast Survey. He resigned in 1849 and took command of the 
merchant steamer <emph render="italic">Panama</emph>  on a voyage to the Pacific, and, after his return, 
commanded the privately owned mail steamer <emph render="italic">Georgia</emph> on runs to Havana. He was 
later employed in Australia, commanding the <emph render="italic">Golden Age</emph>  between Sydney and 
Melbourne.</p>

<p>In 1855 he returned to the American navy and commanded the steamship <emph render="italic">Supply</emph> 
on two voyages to the Mediterranean. From 1857 to 1860 he was assigned to the 
Portsmouth (N.H.) navy yard. An offer from the Pacific Mail Steamship Company 
to serve as captain of the largest American passenger steamship, then about 
to be built, tempted Porter to leave his navy assignment, but in March 1861 
he was assigned to command the <emph render="italic">Powhatan</emph> on a special mission to the besieged 
Fort Pickens in Pensacola, Florida, and he decided to remain with the navy.</p>

<p>For the next few months he engaged in blockade duty at Pensacola, as well as 
off Mobile and at the mouth of the Mississippi River. During this time he was 
promoted to commander. He was active in planning the attack on New Orleans 
and recommended David G. Farragut, his adopted brother, for command of the 
operation. Porter commanded the mortar fleet that attacked Forts St. Philip 
and Jackson, forcing the surrender of these forts that guarded the river 
approaches to the city. The capture of New Orleans opened the Mississippi 
River to the United States Navy, and Porter's mortar fleet assisted 
Farragut's ships when they steamed upriver past the Vicksburg batteries. In 
October 1862 he was appointed commander of the Mississippi Squadron with the 
rank of acting rear admiral.</p>

<p>In January 1863 he assisted in the capture of Arkansas Post, an action 
which made possible General Ulysses Grant's campaign against 
Vicksburg. In the subsequent campaign, Porter's ships aided Grant in his 
futile attempts to approach Vicksburg from the North and allowed his 
circumvention of the city and the eventual landing of the army to the South. 
With the surrender of Vicksburg, Porter gained for the Union army control of 
the Mississippi River. In recognition of his successes on the Mississippi, 
Porter was made a rear admiral.</p>

<p>In 1864 he participated in the abortive Red River expedition into 
northwestern Louisiana. He was then put in command of the North Atlantic 
Blockading Squadron and was assigned to capture Fort Fisher, which guarded 
Wilmington, North Carolina, and protected the last open supply line by sea 
available to the Confederate armies. The surrender of the fort and the 
capture of Wilmington was accomplished in January 1865.</p>

<p>After the war, from 1865 to 1869, Porter served as superintendent of the 
United States Naval Academy at Annapolis, Maryland, and was instrumental in 
instituting changes in its curriculum and teaching methods. During 1866 and 
1867 he undertook a mission to Santo Domingo for the purpose of securing the 
cession or lease of Samana Bay to the United States, but he was unsuccessful. 
In 1866 he was promoted to vice-admiral.</p>

<p>President Grant appointed him as an advisor to the Secretary of the Navy in 
1869. By organizing boards of inspection for the fleet, beginning the repair 
of many vessels, and insisting that steam-powered ships also be equipped with 
sail, he demonstrated his effective control of the Navy Department. In 1870, 
after the death of Farragut, Porter was given the rank of admiral. From 1877 
until his death he was head of the naval Board of Inspection, but he steadily 
lost power in the Navy Department. During this period he made annual reports 
to the Secretary of the Navy criticizing the state of the fleet and insisting 
on the construction of a new navy, but his counsel was seldom heeded. He died 
in Washington, DC, on 13 February 1891.</p>

<p>For a more detailed biographical sketch, see the article "David Dixon Porter" 
in <emph render="italic">Dictionary of American Biography</emph>. A recent full-length biography is Noel 
Gerson's <emph render="italic">Yankee Admiral</emph> (1968).</p>
    </bioghist>

    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
<p>The <emph render="bold">David Dixon Porter Collection</emph> contains sixty-nine items of correspondence and 
memorabilia relating to the naval career and business affiliations of 
David Dixon Porter. The inclusive dates of the collection are 1806-1890, with 
the years 1870 to 1878 the most heavily represented.</p>

<p><emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph>, dated from 1806 to 1890, 
amounts to sixty-five letters. Thirty-eight of these (among them one 
typescript copy) are letters from David Dixon Porter. There is one incoming 
letter to David Dixon Porter, and there are two letters addressed to David 
Porter, father of David Dixon Porter. An <ref target="sic">index of the correspondence</ref> 
is appended to this inventory.</p>

<p>A group of some three dozen letters written between 1870 and 1879 
discusses the uses and capabilities of a new type of screw propeller for 
torpedo boats: Fowler's Patent Propeller, also known as the Fowler 
Wheel.  Porter actively promoted this new propulsion system, and these letters reflect his 
efforts to convince the Navy of its worth and his role in its subsequent 
tests by the Navy. Correspondents, besides 
Porter, include William H. Mallory, president of the American Propeller Company, 
and Joseph R. Hawley, a Hartford newspaper editor (later a senator from 
Connecticut) and a stockholder in the company. Other letters contain 
business correspondence of Mallory and Hawley, particularly during the years 
1878 to 1880, and reflect their attempts to sell the system to the British 
Navy and to establish a British company for its manufacture. Correspondence 
between Hawley and Sir William H. Stewart, a British admiral, 
and Sir Edward James Reed, a naval architect, concerns the testing of the 
system and the chairmanship of the proposed manufacturing company. There is 
also a letter to Mallory from Simon Stevens, president of the Tehuantepec 
Railway, who sought to purchase a steam launch for use at the Isthmus of 
Tehuantepec in Mexico and suggested one equipped with the Fowler Wheel 
recommended to him by Porter.</p>

<p>The earliest items in the collection are two letters dated 1806, from a United States 
counsel in Leghorn, Italy to David Porter (1780-1843), father of David Dixon Porter,  
while the senior Porter was commanding the 
schooner <emph render="italic">Enterprise</emph> in the Mediterranean. They concern another United States 
ship and the issuance of travel permits for Porter's officers by the town 
government of Leghorn.</p>

<p>Other items in the correspondence include a letter of 12 April 1863, in 
which Porter describes  to Gideon Welles, Secretary of the Navy, 
the shortage of manpower in the Mississippi Squadron, and two letters of 1866 
(during Porter's tenure as superintendent of the U.S. Naval Academy) to Rear 
Admiral Charles A. Davis. Three 1867 letters in photocopy form 
relate to an investigation by Gideon Welles into charges of misuse of funds 
against O.K. Bernbaum, an acting ship's master. In a letter of 1874 the 
sculptor Franklin Simmons describes the plans for a monument, possibly 
celebrating the Union capture of New Orleans. An 1882 David Dixon 
Porter letter to his cousin, Fitz John Porter, summarizes congressional 
developments in the long attempt to clear the cousin's name after a 
celebrated court-martial for failure to carry out orders of General John Pope 
at the Second Battle of Bull Run in 1862. Other Porter letters include one of 
1889 in response to an offer to sell an autograph letter of the naval 
engineer John Ericsson, and an 1890 letter in which he reminisces about his 
capture of the fort at Tabasco during the Mexican War.</p>

<p><emph render="bold">Memorabilia</emph> consists of two engraved portraits captioned "D. 
Porter" and "David D. Porter," a photocopy of a one-page biography of David 
Dixon Porter with corrections in an unknown hand, and holograph minutes, 
taken by William H. Mallory, of an 1874 meeting of the board of directors of 
the American Press and Clasp Company.</p>

    </scopecontent>

    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>Correspondence is arranged chronologically.  An <ref target="sic">Index to correspondence</ref> 
may be found at the end of this document.</p>
    </arrangement>

<!--   <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 1)</p>
    </relatedmaterial> -->

<!--   <separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
    </separatedmaterial> -->

<!--
            <otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
<head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
<p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p></otherfindaid>
            -->

<controlaccess>
<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Military history</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Civil War (U.S.)</subject>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Porter, David D. (David Dixon), 1813-1891.</persname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Navy.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Navy -- Officers.</corpname>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Admirals -- United States.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Propellers.</subject>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States -- History, Naval -- To 1900.</geogname>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Admirals.</occupation>
</controlaccess>

<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p></accessrestrict>

<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
                       all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
                       materials in this collection. </p></userestrict>

<prefercite encodinganalog="524"><head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
<p>David D. Porter Papers<lb/>&su_name;</p></prefercite>


      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
         <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Two letters to David Porter and a portrait labeled "D. Porter," purchase, 
1965.<lb/>
Twenty-one letters from David Dixon Porter or relating to him, and an 
engraved portrait, purchases, 1966, 1967, 1968, 1969.<lb/>
Correspondence between David Dixon Porter and William H. Mallory, and related 
items, including three contemporary copies of letters exchanged between 
Gideon Welles and O.K. Bernbaum, purchase, 1970.<lb/>
Typescript copy of a Porter letter to President Grant, transfer from the 
Carnegie Library, 1970.<lb/>
David D. Porter letters dated 23 June 1882 and 28 May 1885, transfers from 
the Theodorus Bailey Collection, 1971.</p>
      </acqinfo>

<!--
            

<appraisal encodinganalog="583"><head>Appraisal Information</head><p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       -->

<!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584"><head>Accruals</head><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->


      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>Inventory</head>
<c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle></did>
   <c02><did><unittitle>[General]</unittitle><unitdate normal="1806" type="inclusive">1806, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1844" type="inclusive">1844, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1863/1882" type="inclusive">1863-1882, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1885/1886" type="inclusive">1885-1886, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1889/1890" type="inclusive">1889-1890</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Undated</unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle></did>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Biographical material, photocopy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1844/1899" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Engraved portraits</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>David Porter</unittitle><unitdate normal="1862" type="inclusive">1862</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>David Dixon Porter</unittitle><unitdate normal="1863" type="inclusive">1863</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03>
   </c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Minutes of a meeting of the directors of the American Press and Clasp Company, Bridgeport</unittitle><abstract>holograph</abstract><unitdate normal="1874-09-16" type="inclusive">16 September 1874</unitdate><container type="Box">1</container></did></c02>
</c01>



      </dsc>

<index id="sic"><head>Index to correspondence</head>
<indexentry>
   <name>[unknown]</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>[no year], Jun 30, [London?], to Mallory, [W. H.]</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Appleton, Th.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1806 Nov 23, Leghorn, [Italy], to Porter, David</ref>
      <ref>1806 Dec 10, Leghorn, [Italy], to Porter, David</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>[Bernbaum, O.K.]</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1867 Jul 15, New York, to Welles, Gideon (copy)</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Boggs, Charles S.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1872 Jun 27, Washington, to Mallory, [W. H.]</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Calder, H. M.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1871 Jun 3, Winsted, Conn., to Mallory, Wm. H.</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Hawley, Joseph R.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1870 Jan 9, Hartford, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1870 Apr 15, Hartford, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1870 Jun 27, Hartford, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1872 Mar 12, Hartford, to Boutwell, George S.</ref>
      <ref>1872 Mar 12, Hartford, to [Mallory, W. H.] (copy)</ref>
      <ref>1876 Mar 2, Philadelphia, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1878 Aug 17, Bridgeport, Conn., to Corliss, George H.</ref>
      <ref>1885 Oct 27, Hartford, to Mallory, Mr. &amp; Mrs. George</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Hawley, Joseph R. and Mallory, William H.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1878 Aug 9, London, to Stewart, [Sir] William Houston</ref>
      <ref>1878 Aug 31, London, to Reed, [Sir] Edward James (copy)</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Mallory, W. H.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1879 Aug 10, London, to "My dear Parents"</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Mensing, A.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1882 Nov 11, South Orange, N.J., to Mallory, Mrs. W. H.</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Moore, John Whitley</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1872 Aug 22, New York, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Porter, David Dixon</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>[no year] Oct 13, Newport, [R.I.], to Mr. LaBell[?]</ref>
      <ref>1844 Aug 7, Providence, to Banks, [Nathaniel P.?]</ref>
      <ref>1863 Apr 12, Yazoo River, [Miss.], to Welles, Gideon</ref>
      <ref>1864 May 31, Cairo, [Ill.], to Harris, [  ]</ref>
      <ref>1864 Oct 20, Hampton Roads, [Va.], to Thatcher, H[enry] K.</ref>
      <ref>1865 Mar 4, Hampton Roads, [Va.], to Langthorne, A. R.</ref>
      <ref>1866 Apr 24, Annapolis, Md., to Davis, Charles H.</ref>
      <ref>1866 Nov 20, Annapolis, Md., to Davis, Charles H.</ref>
      <ref>1869 May 1, Washington, to Gilman, A. N.</ref>
      <ref>1869 Jul 31, Washington, to Cheney, T. Apoleon</ref>
      <ref>1870 May 27, Washington, to Grant, Ulysses S. (copy)</ref>
      <ref>1870 Nov 21, Washington, to Fowler, F. G.</ref>
      <ref>1870 Dec 1, Washington, to Fowler, F. G.</ref>
      <ref>1871 Sep 6, Washington, to Mallory, Wm. H.</ref>
      <ref>1871 Sep 13, Washington, to Mallory, Wm. H.</ref>
      <ref>1871 Sep 26, Washington, to Mallory, [W. H.]</ref>
      <ref>1871 Oct 23, Washington, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1872 May 1, Washington, to Boggs, [Charles S.]</ref>
      <ref>1873 Mar 27, Washington, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1873 Oct 18, Washington, to Fowler Steering Propellor Co.</ref>
      <ref>1874 May 4, Fortress Monroe, [Va.], to Mallory, Wm. H.</ref>
      <ref>1874 Aug 29, Catskill, [N.Y.], to Mallory [  ]</ref>
      <ref>1874 Sep 24, Lebanon Springs, [N.Y.], to [Mallory, W. H.]</ref>
      <ref>1874 Oct 1, Lebanon Springs, [N.Y.], to [Mallory, W. H.]</ref>
      <ref>1875 Dec 6, Washington, to Jameson, Mrs.</ref>
      <ref>1876 Feb 7, Washington, to Anthony, [Henry Bowen]</ref>
      <ref>1878 May 29, Washington, to Walke, Henry</ref>
      <ref>1878 Jun 28, Washington, to Hawley, J. R.</ref>
      <ref>1878 Nov 29, Washington, to Shellabarger, Samuel</ref>
      <ref>1879 May 13, Washington, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
      <ref>1882 Jun 23, Washington, to Porter, Fitz John</ref>
      <ref>1882 Jun 23, Washington, to Robinson, William E.</ref>
      <ref>1885 May 28, Washington</ref>
      <ref>1886 Dec 22, Washington, to Wright, Marcus J.</ref>
      <ref>1889 Mar 5, Washington, to Young[?], W. P.</ref>
      <ref>1889 Apr 16, Washington, to Pavey, Darwin C.</ref>
      <ref>1889 May 23, Washington, to Hall, Ernest</ref>
      <ref>1890 Sep 19, Jamestown, R.I., to Walke, [Henry]</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Reed, [Sir] Edward James</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1878 Aug 26, London, to Hawley, J. R. and Mallory, W. H.</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Richards, J.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1872 Nov 30, Providence, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Simmons, Franklin</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1874 Nov 7, Rome, [Italy], to Porter, David Dixon</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Stevens, Simon</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1871 Feb 15, New York, to Mallory, W. H.</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Stewart, [Sir] William H.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1880 Jul 23, [London?], to Brandreth[?], Thomas</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Welles, G[ideon]</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>1867 Jul 12, Washington, to Bernbaum, O.K. (copy)</ref>
      <ref>1867 Aug 31</ref>
      <ref>Washington, to Bernbaum, O.K. (copy)</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>
<indexentry>
   <name>Wheeler, C. N.</name>
   <ptrgrp>
      <ref>n.y. May 16, [  ], to [Mallory,] George</ref>
   </ptrgrp>
</indexentry>

</index></archdesc>
</ead>
