<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY scrconline SYSTEM "scrconline.txt">
<!ENTITY searchcoll SYSTEM "searchcoll.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="power_ts" mainagencycode="NSyU">power_ts</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Thomas S. Power Papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        his papers 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">--</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
          <lb/></publisher>&su_address;
        <date encodinganalog="Date" normal="2001-01-01">2001-01-01</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           
        
        
        
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>18 Jul 2008 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item>
        <item>5 Jan 2017 - condensed correspondence, fixed index (MRC)</item>
        <item>4 May 2017 - film processed, descriptions expanded (MRC)</item>
        <item>7 Sep 2017 - tapes processed, collection rehoused, inventory corrected/updated (MS)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository encodinganalog="852$a" id="scrc" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
        <lb/>&su_address;</repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Power, Thomas S. (Thomas Sarsfield), 1905-1970.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Thomas S. Power Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1928/1970" type="inclusive">1928-1970</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">22 linear ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">
                    Papers of the American military officer.  Powers was Assistant Chief of Operations, U.S. Strategic Air Forces, 1945; Assistant Task Force Commander for Air Operation Crossroads, Bikini Atoll, 1946; Vice-Commander of the Strategic Air Command, 1948-1954; Commander of the Air Research and Development Command, 1954-1957; and Commander-in-Chief of the Strategic Air Command, 1957-1964.  Collection includes communications and writings (1945-1970), correspondence (1945-1970), memorabilia (1934-1970), and organizational records (1928-1969), mostly pertaining to the American Security Council.  Notable correspondents include William F. Buckley, Lucius D. Clay, Carl T. Curtis, Donald W. Douglas, Ira Eaker, Joe Foss, Arthur Godfrey, Barry Goldwater, Roman L. Hruska, William R. Kintner, Curtis LeMay, Lyman L. Lemnitzer, Robert S. McNamara, Richard M. Nixon, Ronald Reagan, Francis Spellman, Lawrence Spivak, Stuart Symington, Lowell Thomas, Harry S. Truman, Nathan Twining, DeWitt Wallace, and Thomas D. White, among others.</abstract>
      <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">149530</unitid>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Thomas Sarsfield Power (1905-1970 was an American military officer who served as both Vice-Commander and Commander-in-Chief of the Strategic Air Command.  Born on June 18, 1905 in New York City, he graduated from Barnard School 
for Boys and entered the Air Corps flying school in 1928, receiving his commission as a second 
lieutenant in 1929. Early assignments took him to famed air corps fields of the day, including 
Chanute, Langley and Randolph Fields, where he served as an air mail pilot, a flying instructor and 
an engineering and armament officer.</p>
      <p>In World War II Power saw combat as a B-24 pilot in North Africa and Italy, and in 1944 he was 
named commander of the 304th Bomb Wing on Guam. He led the first large-scale fire bomb raid on 
Tokyo in March 1945, initiating new tactics that resulted in massive destruction in the Japanese 
cities. He served as Deputy Chief of Operations under General Carl Spaatz during the atomic attacks 
on Hiroshima and Nagasaki.</p>
      <p>After the war, Power was named as assistant deputy task force commander for air during the 
"Operation Crossroads" atomic bomb test at Bikini Atoll. He also served for a time in Washington 
and London. In 1948 he was named Vice Commander in Chief of the Strategic Air Command, serving 
under General Curtis E. LeMay, his former commander in the raids on Japan. In 1954 he was promoted 
to the rank of lieutenant general. He was in charge of the Air Research and Development Command 
from 1954-1957. In 1957 Power succeeded LeMay as Commander in Chief of Strategic Air Command, a 
post which he filled for seven years. As head of the U.S. nuclear strike force, including over 
1,000 nuclear-armed bombers and hundreds of Inter-Continental Ballistic Missiles, he was never far 
from the "red phone" connections that could bring him orders from the president to go to war.</p>
      <p>During his military career, Power was an outspoken proponent of nuclear deterrence, a policy of 
peace through the achievement of overwhelming nuclear superiority. He favored patriotism, preparedness, and a tough policy toward the Communist enemy. His views on the nuclear strategy were 
incorporated in a book in 1958, but Secretary of Defense Neil McElroy refused to clear the draft 
for publication. As a result, Power gained fame in conservative circles as the author of a "banned" 
book. He was the sole military man to testify against the nuclear test ban treaty before a Senate 
investigating committee in 1963.</p>
      <p>Upon his retirement in 1964, Power was named board chairman of Schick, Inc., with whom he was 
affiliated for six years. After extensive revision, his book was published in 1965 under the title 

        
        <emph render="italic">Design for Survival</emph>. It spent a few weeks on the bestseller lists and helped to make Power much in 
demand on the lecture circuit, where he called for nuclear superiority and victory in Vietnam. He 
served on a Veterans for Nixon group for the 1968 presidential campaign.
Thomas Power married Mae Ayre in 1936. They had no children. Power died on December 6, 1970.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The 
        
        
        
        <emph render="bold">Thomas S. Power Papers</emph> consists of communications and writings, 
memorabilia, organizational records, and photographs. Virtually all of Power's papers stem from his 
career in the U.S. Air Force and his activities in the years after his retirement in 1964.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Communications and writings</emph> form the bulk of the collection.  Dating from 1945 to 1970, this material includes articles and essays, books, book reviews, correspondence, interviews, 
memoranda, press releases, speeches, statements and miscellany.  The articles and essays, which were 
written by Power on topics of defense and nuclear deterrence, include one guest editorial for the 

        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph> entitled "In Defense of the Pentagon." The material on General Power's book, 
        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">Design 
for  Survival</emph>, comprises drafts, promotional material, reviews from the news media throughout the 
country, a signature proof and clippings of its serialization in two major newspapers. There is 
also a comic-book version, complete with color illustrations of the general. Of special interest is 
the 1958 draft of the book, unpublished at that time due to the objections of the Secretary of 
Defense. The single book review is of Curtis LeMay's 
        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">America Is In Danger</emph>.</p>
      <p>Correspondence (1945-1970) covers 25 years of Power's career.  Among those who wrote to Power are mportant figures 
in government, business, the news media and the military. Carbon copies of Power's replies may be found stapled to the top of the incoming 
correspondence.  Very little of the correspondence relates to specific military aspects of Power's career. 
There are letters dealing with social arrangements, notes of invitation and congratulations, and 
letters on current issues, many of which are from prominent individuals. There is also a 
substantial amount of correspondence from private citizens who wrote to commend Power's patriotism 
and dedication and to share their fears of the Communist encroachment with him. The correspondence 
also reflects Power's close association with top levels of defense-oriented corporations, 
particularly during the years of his service as head of the Air Research and Development Command. 
A series of letters from Richard Nixon in 1967 and 1968 stem from Power's support of Nixon's 1968 
presidential campaign.  A 
        
        
        
        <ref target="sic">Selected Index to Correspondence</ref> appears at the end of this finding aid. </p>
      <p>The interviews, which date from 1957 to 1970, include a substantial number of transcripts of 
interviews with Walter Judd of the American Security Council's 
        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">Washington Report of the Air</emph>, as 
well as a copy of Power's remarks during his appearance on 
        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">Meet the Press</emph>. Of particular interest 
is the 1966 
        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">Viet Nam Review</emph> interview in which Power urges escalation and use of air power in 
Indochina.</p>
      <p>The speeches originate from Power's occasional talks as an officer and from 
his engagements as a speaker after retirement. Power spoke chiefly to Republican clubs, business, 
civic and patriotic groups. The miscellany section consists of writings of others, most of which 
are articles on topics of special interest to Power. Specific information regarding Power's 
lectures can be found on the first page of each draft.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Memorabilia</emph>, which dates from 1934 to 1970, contains appointment books, biographical 
material, commendations and awards, a drawing of the general, a few items of ephemera, newspaper 
clippings, an obituary and several scrapbooks. The untitled scrapbooks contain a complete and 
mounted collection of clippings from Power's career.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Organizational records</emph>, 1928-1969, contain material from the American Security 
Council, the U.S. Air Force and the Air Force Academy. Power was a member of the National Strategy 
Committee of the American Security Council, a private organization dedicated to military 
preparedness against the Communist menace. The Air Force material consists of records from Power's early career, including 
commendations, discharge and commission papers, flight books and records, medical records, pilot 
orders, training papers and material on Operation Crossroads. The Air Force Academy papers date 
from Power's service on a General Officer Advisory Committee to that institution.</p>
      <p>Six boxes of 
        
        
        
        <emph render="bold">Photographs</emph>, 1928-1968, contain both albums and individual 
photos of a wide variety of subjects. There are a number of photographs from Power's visits to air 
bases and industrial plants, as well as visits to his command by foreign dignitaries and U.S. 
Presidents Kennedy and Johnson.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Audio-visual material</emph> includes five films, audiorecordings of interview and speeches, and 73 reels of audiotape containing episodes  of the American Security Council's 

        
        
        
        <emph render="italic">Washington Report of the Air</emph>, a three-minute daily briefing on current events. Six of these contain interviews with General Power on subjects of 
national defense.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <altformavail encodinganalog="530">
      <head>Other Formats Available</head>
      <p>Many of the audiovisual items from this collection <extref href="https://scrconline.syr.edu/xtf/search?brand=scrc;repository=scrc;f1-collection=Thomas%20S.%20Power%20Papers">have been digitized</extref>.  Please refer to &scrconline; to access these items.</p>
    </altformavail>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>Communications and writings are arranged alphabetically by type of 
material; within that material is arranged alphabetically by topic or title, with the exception of correspondence, memoranda, and press releases which are organized chronologically.  Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by type.  Organization records are arranged alphabetically by name of organization.  Photographs are arranged alphabetically by subject.  Audiovisual material is arranged by type and within that alphabetically by title.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <!--<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 1)</p>
    </relatedmaterial>-->

    <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
    </separatedmaterial>-->
<!--
            <otherfindaid encodinganalog="555"><head>Other Related Finding Aids</head><p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p></otherfindaid>
            -->
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon), 1897-1978.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Curtis, Carl T. (Carl Thomas), 1905-2000.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Douglas, Donald W. (Donald Willis), 1892-1981.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Eaker, Ira, 1896-1987.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Foss, Joe, 1915-2003.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Godfrey, Arthur, 1903-1983.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Goldwater, Barry, 1938-</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Hruska, Roman L. (Roman Lee), 1904-1999.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Kintner, William R. (William Roscoe), 1915-1997.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">LeMay, Curtis E.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Lemnitzer, Lyman L. (Lyman Louis), 1899-1988.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">McNamara, Robert S., 1916-2009.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Power, Thomas S. (Thomas Sarsfield), 1905-1970.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Reagan, Ronald.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Spellman, Francis, 1889-1967.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Spivak, Lawrence E. (Lawrence Edmund), 1900-1994.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Symington, Stuart, 1901-1988.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Twining, Nathan F. (Nathan Farragut), 1897-1982.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Wallace, DeWitt, 1889-1981.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">White, Thomas D. (Thomas Dresser), 1901-1965.</persname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">American Security Council.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Air Force.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Air Force -- Officers.</corpname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">United States. -- Air Force. -- Strategic Air Command.</corpname>
      <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf">Design for survival.</title>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Aeronautics, Military -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Arms race.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Deterrence (Strategy)</subject>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States -- History, Military -- 20th century.</geogname>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States -- Military policy.</geogname>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">16mm (photographic film size)</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Appointment books.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Clippings (information artifacts)</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Sound recordings.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Book reviews.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Interviews.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Memorandums.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Phonograph records.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Press releases.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Speeches (documents)</genreform>
      <function encodinganalog="657" source="lcsh">Aeronautics.</function>
    </controlaccess>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before 
publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Thomas S. Power Papers,
        
        
        
        <lb/>&su_name;</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Gift of 
        
        
        
        <persname role="donor">General Thomas S. Power</persname> and 
        
        
        
        <persname role="donor">and Mrs. Thomas S. Power</persname>, 1964-1971.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <!--
            <appraisal encodinganalog="583">
<head>Appraisal Information</head><p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       -->
<!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584">
<head>Accruals</head><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Inventory</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Communications and writings</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Articles and essays</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Notes</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>"Commander's Farewell," 
                
                
                
                <emph render="italic">Combat Crew</emph></unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964-12" type="inclusive">Dec 1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>"Deterrence or Defeat?" 
                
                
                
                <emph render="italic">Ordnance</emph> </unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968-11/1968-12" type="inclusive">Nov-Dec 1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>"In Defense of the Pentagon," 
                
                
                
                <emph render="italic">New York Times</emph></unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1970-05-23" type="inclusive">May 23, 1970</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>"The Nature of the Deterrent System," 
                
                
                
                <emph render="italic">Air Force</emph></unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1965-03" type="inclusive">Mar 1965</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>"A New Strategic Bomber?"</unittitle>
              <abstract>typescript reproduction</abstract>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Book, 
              
              <emph render="italic">Design for Survival</emph></unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Comic-book version</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Draft</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1958" type="inclusive">1958</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>2 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Excerpts</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Promotional Material</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Reviews</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1965" type="inclusive">1965</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>3 folders </extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Signature Proof</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Serialization, Los Angeles 
                    
                    
                
                <emph render="italic">Times</emph></unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1965" type="inclusive">1965</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Serialization, Philadelphia
                    
                    
                
                <emph render="italic"> Inquirer</emph> </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964/1965" type="inclusive">1964-1965</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Book review, 
                
              
              <emph render="italic">America is in Danger</emph>, Curtis E. LeMay, 
                
                
              
              <emph render="italic">National Review</emph></unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968-08" type="inclusive">Aug 1968</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Undated</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1945/1952" type="inclusive">1945-1952 May</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>75 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1952-06/1957-06" type="inclusive">1952 Jun-1957 Jun</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>61 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1957-07/1959-12" type="inclusive">1957 Jul-1959</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>30 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>38 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1963-01/1964-10" type="inclusive">1963-1964 Oct</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>24 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964-11/1968-07" type="inclusive">1964 Nov-1968 Jul</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>43 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[General]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968-08/1970-12" type="inclusive">1968 Aug-1970</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>18 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Interviews</unittitle>
          </did>
          <note>
            <p>See also 
              
              <ref target="power_ts_0006">Audiovisual material : Phonograph records: Thomas S. Power interviews</ref>.</p>
          </note>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>American Security Council 
                
                
                
                <emph render="italic">Washington Report of the Air </emph></unittitle>
            </did>
            <note>
              <p>Listed here are transcripts.  See 
                
                <ref target="tapes">Audiovisual material : Tapes</ref> for original recordings of these and other episodes featuring Power.</p>
            </note>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>On the changing strategic military balance</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">8</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>with Elias Demetracopoulos</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">8</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>with Elias Demetracopoulos</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">8</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>with Kenneth Leish</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">8</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Meet the Press</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1965-03-21" type="inclusive">21 Mar 1965</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">8</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <emph render="italic">U.S. News and World Report </emph>
              </unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1957-12-20" type="inclusive">20 Dec 1957; </unitdate>
              <unitdate normal="1965-01-25" type="inclusive">25 Jan 1965</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>2 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <emph render="italic">Viet Nam Review</emph>
              </unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1966-10-13" type="inclusive">Oct 13, 1966</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1961/1970" type="inclusive">1961-1970</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1964" type="inclusive">1945-1964</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press releases</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1962/1964" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
          </did>
          <note>
            <p>See also 
              
              <ref target="power_ts_0081">Audiovisual material : Tapes : Public Affairs Luncheon, Omaha Chamber of Commerce</ref>.</p>
          </note>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Contracts, Harry Walker Inc.</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1965" type="inclusive">1965</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Drafts</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1957/1959" type="inclusive">1957-1959</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>3 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Drafts</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1960/1968" type="inclusive">1960-1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>8 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Drafts</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1928/1970" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outline for informal remarks</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Statement, House Armed Services Committee Hearing on Reductions of Manned Bombers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellany</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>"A-2" / "Jap Flak vs the B-29"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1940/1950" type="inclusive">circa 1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kintner, William R. / "A Missile Moratorium?"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kintner, William R. / "Debacle Road"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kintner, William R. / "U.S. Overseas Defense Commitments Now and in the 1970's"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kintner, William R. / "The United States-Soviet Non-Proliferation Treaty"</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Libby, W. F. / "Man and the Physical World"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Libby, W. F. / "The Moon Base"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Schlafly, Phyllis / "The Twelve Big Gaps in Our Defense"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Strausz-Hupé, Robert / "On the Southeast Asian Confrontation"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Strausz-Hupé, Robert / "Analysis of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty"</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Appointment books</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1955/1964" type="inclusive">1955-1964</unitdate>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>4 folders </extent>
            </physdesc>
            <container type="Box">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Biographical</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1954/1965" type="inclusive">1954-1965</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commendations and awards</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1965" type="inclusive">1945-1965</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commendations and awards</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1965" type="inclusive">1945-1965</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commendations and awards (oversize)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1964" type="inclusive">1945-1964</unitdate>
            <container type="Oversize">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commendations and awards (oversize)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1964" type="inclusive">1945-1964</unitdate>
            <container type="Oversize">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commission certificates</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1929/1951" type="inclusive">1929-1951</unitdate>
            <container type="Oversize">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Drawing</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ephemera</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1965" type="inclusive">1945-1965</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1945/1965" type="inclusive">1945-1965</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Obituary, 
              
              <emph render="italic">Air Force and Space Digest</emph></unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1971-01" type="inclusive">Jan 1971</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>The Air Battle of Ploesti</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1944" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>My Eight Days in Moscow</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>USTAF</unittitle>
              <abstract>highlights the air campaign over Japan from bases in the Marianas</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1943/1945" type="inclusive">1943-1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Untitled</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1934/1959" type="inclusive">1934-1959</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Untitled</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Untitled</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Sketches</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1962" type="inclusive">circa 1957</unitdate>
            <container type="Oversize">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
            <abstract>academic robes, regalia, flags etc.</abstract>
            <container type="Box">25</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Organization records</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Security Council</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Newspaper clippings </unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>U.S. Air Force</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Commendations</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1937/1950" type="inclusive">1937-1950</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Discharge and commission papers</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1929/1948" type="inclusive">1929-1948</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Entertainment guest lists</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Flight books</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1928/1931" type="inclusive">1928-1931</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>4 volumes</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Flight records</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1929/1964" type="inclusive">1929-1964</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>5 folders </extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Medical records</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1944/1945" type="inclusive">1944-1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Operation Crossroads</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1946/1948" type="inclusive">1946-1948</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Pilot orders</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1929/1942" type="inclusive">1929-1942</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Training papers and certificates</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1928/1939" type="inclusive">1928-1939</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1929/1945" type="inclusive">1929-1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>U.S. Air Force Academy</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous
                
              </unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1957/1960" type="inclusive">1957-1960</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Albums</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Command Crew</unittitle>
              <container type="Oversize">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dedication Ceremony, Ellsworth Air Force Base</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>15th Air Force Bids Its Farewell to General and Mrs. Thomas S. Power</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Kodokan Judo Mission</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1953" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>MacDill Air Force Base</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>North Field, Guam, 314th Bombardment Wing</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>On Judo</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1951/1953" type="inclusive">1951-1953</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>On Judo</unittitle>
              <abstract>publications by Kudokan Institute, Tokyo</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>2 books</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>On Judo</unittitle>
              <abstract>Offutt Air Force Base</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Operation Crossroads</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1946/1948" type="inclusive">1946-1948</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Pictorial record of 314th Bombardment Wing accomplishments against the Japanese Empire from 25 February to 15 August 1945</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>President Kennedy's Visit to SAC Headquarters, Offutt Air Force Base</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Reception and Dinner in Honor of General and Mrs. Thomas S. Power, Westover AFB, Massachusetts</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[Untitled]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1915/1925" type="inclusive">circa 1920-1931</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[Untitled]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1938/1948" type="inclusive">circa 1943-1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[Untitled]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1940/1950" type="inclusive">circa 1945</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[Untitled]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1957/1962" type="inclusive">1957-1962</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[Untitled]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1962/1964" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>[Untitled]</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1962/1964" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Oversize">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Atomic Bomb Test, Bikini</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">14</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Awards</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Presidential</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Candids and views</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>3 folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Judo</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Kennedy, John F., Elgin AFB, Florida</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Portraits</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1928/1959" type="inclusive">1928-1959</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Portraits, oversize</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1940/1950" type="inclusive">circa 1945</unitdate>
            <container type="Oversize">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Portraits of others</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Portraits of others, oversize</unittitle>
            <container type="Oversize">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Social events</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Social events</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">17</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Visits</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Bases and industries</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Air Research and Development Command</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Anderson Air Force Base, Guam</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1961" type="inclusive">1961</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Barksdale Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Oversize">9</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Beale Air Force Base, California</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1960" type="inclusive">1960</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Boeing Airplane Co.</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1958" type="inclusive">1958</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Cambridge Research Center</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Edwards Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Eleuthera, Bahamas</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Fairchild Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>General Dynamics</unittitle>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>International Business Machines (IBM)</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1958" type="inclusive">1958</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Kirtland Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Lincoln Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Northrup Aircraft</unittitle>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Oerlikon Machine Tool Works</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1955" type="inclusive">1955</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Offutt Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1953/1960" type="inclusive">1953-1960</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Pease Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">17</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Raytheon</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Rome Air Development Center</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Schilling Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Thompson Product Museum</unittitle>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Western Development Division, Air Research and Development Command</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Wright Patterson Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1955" type="inclusive">1955</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Vandenberg Air Force Base</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1946/1957" type="inclusive">1946-1957</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Individuals</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Baudoin, King of Belgium</unittitle>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Bernhardt, Prince of the Netherlands</unittitle>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Johnson, Lyndon Baines</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Kennedy, John F.</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1960" type="inclusive">1960</unitdate>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <unittitle>Lodge, Henry Cabot</unittitle>
                <container type="Box">18</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>World War II</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Europe</unittitle>
              <abstract>mainly aerial bombing targets</abstract>
              <container type="Box">18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Japan, post-war</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Pacific Theatre</unittitle>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>3 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">19</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Pacific Theatre, oversize</unittitle>
              <container type="Oversize">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>2 folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <container type="Box">19</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Negatives</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">19</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Audiovisual material</unittitle>
        </did>
        <altformavail>
      
      <p>Many of the audiovisual items from this collection <extref href="https://scrconline.syr.edu/xtf/search?brand=scrc;repository=scrc;f1-collection=Thomas%20S.%20Power%20Papers">have been digitized</extref>.  Please refer to &scrconline; to access these items.</p>
    </altformavail>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Films</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Aerial Scenes (83249-2) (KC-Dupe 252)</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0002</unitid>
              <abstract>Film: 16mm; color; silent</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Japan (83249-3) (KC-Dupe 252)</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0003</unitid>
              <abstract>Film: 16mm; color; silent</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Tokyo (83249-1) (KC-Dupe 342)</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0001</unitid>
              <abstract>Film: 16mm; color; silent</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Part I: 1. Guam 2  .Nippon 3. Tokyo (burned out) 4. Cairo, Egypt 5. Greece (1945) </unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0004</unitid>
              <abstract>Film: 16mm; color; silent</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Part II: 1. Weisbaden, Germany 2 .Paris - Versailles 3. Paris - Pig Allee 4. W.Va. - Power’s and Large’s (1945) (26375403) </unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0005</unitid>
              <abstract>Film: 16mm; color; silent</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Phonograph records</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="power_ts_0006">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Thomas S. Power interviews</unittitle>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitid>power_ts_0006</unitid>
              <unitdate normal="1965-3-10" type="inclusive">3/10/1965; </unitdate>
              <unitdate normal="1965-3-21" type="inclusive">3/21/1965</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Side I: General Thomas S. Power (ret) March 10 1965 American Citizens Forum, Civic Auditorium, Omaha, Neb; Side II: General Power, Meet the Press March 21-65 followed by interview on KETV Channel 7 Omaha Neb 3-21-65.  Includes some items of ephemera in box with tape.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="tapes" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Tapes</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 id="power_ts_0081">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Public Affairs Luncheon, Omaha Chamber of Commerce</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0081</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1964-10-26" type="inclusive">10/26/1964</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for Sept. 11 - Sept. 15</unittitle>
              <abstract>VinylDisc; running time 3:15</abstract>
              <unitid>power_ts_0007</unitid>
              <unitdate normal="1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 item</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Side One, Cut 1, For Sept. 11 - Dr. Judd On "Pot And Kettle War: Soviet Reports On China" ; Side One, Cut 2, For Sept. 12 - Dr. Judd Interview With Gen. Thomas S. Power On "The History Of Soviet Treaty Keeping" ; Side One, Cut 3, For Sept. 13 - Dr. Judd Interview With Dr. Herminio Portell-Vila On "Carmichael In Cuba" ; Side Two, Cut 1, For Sept. 14 - Dr. Judd Interview WIth Gen. Thomas S. Power On "Communism And Coexistence" ; Side Two, Cut 2, For Sept. 15 - Dr. Judd On "Canada Gets Acquainted With Cuban Communists."</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 8 - April 12</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0008</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 8 - Dr. Judd - Crime And Punishment U.N. Double Standard ; Tape 2, For April 9 - Dr. Judd - Hanoi’s Organization Of Anti-U.S. Violence ; Tape 3, For April 10 - Dr. Judd Interview WIth Gen. Thomas S. Power - Military Uses Of Space ; Tape 4, For April 11 - Dr. Judd - Soviet Builds Indian Military Might ; Tape 5, For April 12 - Dr. Judd - Eden’s Views On Vietnam. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 15 - April 19</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0009</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 15 - Dr. Judd - The Indian Ocean: New sea of opportunity for Russia ; Tape 2, For April 16 - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - New Red penetration in Africa ; Tape 3, For April 17 - Dr. Judd interview with General Thomas S. Power - Relying too much on Russian "Rationality" ; Tape 4, For April 18 - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. H. Portell-Vila: Upheaval in Panama ; Tape 5, For April 19 - Dr. Judd - Free China’s offshore islands: Assets, not liabilities. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 22 - April 26</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0010</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 22 - Dr. Judd - Red Liberalization: Czechoslovak style ; Tape 2, For April 23 - Dr. Judd interview with General Thomas S. Power - The Atomic Test Ban Peril ; Tape 3, For April 24 - Dr. Judd - A British M.P. fears for America ; Tape 4, For April 25 - Dr. Judd interview with Edward S. Butler - Nature of the Underground Press ; Tape 5, For April 26 - Dr. Judd interview with Edward S. Butler - Composition of the Underground Press. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 29 - May 3</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0011</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 29 - Dr. Judd - Domestic Violence Promoted by Reds ; Tape 2, For April 30 - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar Ansel Mowrer - West Germany Looks Toward the East ; Tape 3, For May 1 - Dr. Judd - Is It Peace on Hanoi’s Terms? ; Tape 4, For May 2 - Dr. Judd interview with General Thomas S. Power - A Credible Nuclear Deterrent ; Tape 5, For May 3 - Dr. Judd - Red Unrest in Poland. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for May 13 - May 17</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0012</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For May 13 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Turmoil and trials inside Russia ; Tape 2, For May 14 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edward S. Butler - Communist Vietnam’s propaganda apparatus in the U.S. ; Tape 3, For May 15 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Cambodian sanctuary for the Reds ; Tape 4, For May 16 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - India’s political shift to the Left ; Tape 5, For May 17 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Olympic Games hypocrisy. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for May 20 - May 24</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0013</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For May 20 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - New realism in the United Nations ; Tape 2, For May 21 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Paul D. Bethel - Cuban subversion in Puerto Rico ; Tape 3, For May 22 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Paul D. Bethel - Cuban subversion of U.S. Black Power movement ; Tape 4, For May 23 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Paul D. Bethel - How to resolve the Cuban threat ; Tape 5, For May 24 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Anti-Communist nature of Red China turmoil. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 10 - June 14</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0014</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 10 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - West’s policy toward satellites - No time for freedom ; Tape 2, For June 11 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - French rapport with Communists and chaos, while Paris burns ; Tape 3, For June 12 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with W.K. Lambie - Sparks that ignite revolution ; Tape 4, For June 13 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Unrest in Brazil - From Communists to Clergy ; Tape 5, For June 14 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - The extent of Mao’s desperation. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 17 - June 21</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0015</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 17 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Policy threatens our base in Pakistan ; Tape 2, For June 18 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s new rail penetration in Africa ; Tape 3, For June 19 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Future of our Spanish bases in jeopardy ; Tape 4, For June 20 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with General Thomas S. Power - The correct role of the U.S. serviceman ; Tape 5, For June 21 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with General Thomas S. Power - Effort to destroy the serviceman’s morale. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 1 - July 5</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0017</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 1 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - American diplomacy operates on double standards ; Tape 2, For July 2 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Passport hypocrisy as practised by the British ; Tape 3, For July 3 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interviews Mr. Charles Wiley - Truth about the ARVN ; Tape 4, For July 4 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Communist China: In spite of the masses ; Tape 5, For July 5 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interviews General T.S. Power - The true meaning of peace (as both sides see it). The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 8 - July 12</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0018</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 8 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Violence in America: An assessment ; Tape 2, For July 9 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interviews Dr. Herminio Portell-Vila: New Red labor movement in Latin America ; Tape 3, For July 10 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet power invades Czechoslovakia ; Tape 4, For July 11 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interviews General T.S. Power - Defense research on campus ; Tape 5, For July 12 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interviews with General T.S. Power: Young Americans - Our real source of strength. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 15 - July 19</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0019</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 15 (Monday) - Dr. Judd talks about Al-Fattah: The Arab underground in Israel ; Tape 2, For July 16 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Cuban power: Threat to the United States in 1968 ; Tape 3, For July 17 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - The Consular Treaty: Merely a Communist shell game ; Tape 4, For July 18 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - President Balaguer’s position in Dominican Republic ; Tape 5, For July 19 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interviews Dr. Herminio Portell-Vila: How Panama is assisting the Communists. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 22 - July 26</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0020</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 22 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The Czech crisis: A repeat of Hungarian uprising? ; Tape 2, For July 23 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Forces in Far East unable to react in time to save "Pueblo" from capture ; Tape 3, For July 24 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - South Korea’s needs for defense against aggression ; Tape 4, For July 25 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interviews J.F. Lewis - Dominican Republic: Ready for another Communist take-over ; Tape 5, For July 26 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interviews J.F. Lewis - Where anti-communist strength lies in Dominican Republic. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 29 - August 2</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0021</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 29 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar Ansel Mowrer - West Germany and Nuclear non-proliferation ; Tape 2, For July 30 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Two Roman Catholic priests support Red terrorism ; Tape 3, For July 31 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Laos and Cambodia concerned about their survival ; Tape 4, For August 1 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - The Diary of Che Guevara: How authentic is it? ; Tape 5, For August 2 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar Ansel Mowrer - Possible West German agreement with Moscow. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 24 - June 28</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0016</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 24 - Dr. Judd - Exposure of new Red threats to our security ; Tape 2, For June 25 - Dr. Judd interview with Gen. Thomas S. Power - Potential contribution of Vietnam Vets ; Tape 3, For June 26 - Dr. Judd - France’s Labor - Student coalition planned in Moscow ; Tape 4, For June 27 - Dr. Judd - Red-led Trade Unions take more militant stance ; Tape 5, For June 28 - Dr. Judd interview with Charles Wiley - Harmful reporting of Vietnam war. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 5 - August 9</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0022</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1 For August 5 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - NORAD: The United States obsolete warning system ; Tape 2 For August 6 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. decision to cut back on defenses weakens our bargaining position with Russia ; Tape 3 For August 7 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. Lev Dobriansky - Czechoslovakia’s spirit of freedom: Will it die? ; Tape 4 For August 8 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. Lev Dobriansky - Unrest in Russia: Something we hear little about ; Tape 5 For August 9 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - The Yoshida letter: Free China’s warning to Japan. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 12 - August 16</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0023</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 12 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. Lev Dobriansky - Human Rights Or Wrongs? ; Tape 2, For August 13 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Threat As Seen From Taiwan ; Tape 3, For August 14 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interviews J.F. Lewis - Russian Ploy In Berlin ; Tape 4, For August 15 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Russia’s Penetration Of Japan ; Tape 5, For August 16 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interviews J.F. Lewis - Disarmament, Soviet Style. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 19 - August 23</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0024</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 19 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - General Earle Wheeler And The Soviet Military Threat ; Tape 2, For August 20 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interviews John F. Lewis - Renewed Tensions In The Middle East ; Tape 3, For August 21 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interviews John F. Lewis - Soviet Spy Ships In The Americas ; Tape 4, For August 22 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interviews John F. Lewis - New Kremlin Assault On Creative Artists ; Tape 5, For August 23 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Campaign In Burma. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 26 - August 30</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0025</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 26 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Commander’s Appraisal Of Latin Arms Needs ; Tape 2, For August 27 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Africa’s Chad: Strategic Ground For Russia ; Tape 3, For August 28 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - ALSAM: New Missile Proposed For America’s Defense ; Tape 4, For August 29 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Illegality Of The Rhodesian Sanctions Raised ; Tape 5, For August 30 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - General Shtemenko: The New Warsaw Pact Chief. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 2 - September 6</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0026</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 2 (Monday) - Dr. Walter H. Judd interviews J.F. Lewis - Czechoslovakia’s Candle Of Freedom Snuffed Out ; Tape 2, For September 3 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - A New British Attitude Toward Britain’s Asian Role ; Tape 3, For September 4 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Once Again The Red Menace Emerges In Indonesia ; Tape 4, For September 5 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Operation "Combat Fox" For South Korean Defenses ; Tape 5, For September 6 - Dr. Judd - Red War In Portuguese Guinea: An Eyewitness Report. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 9 - September 13</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0027</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 9 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - For The West, It Is Business As Usual Despite The Invasion Of Czechoslovakia ; Tape 2, For September 10 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - The Message Of Communism Remains Unchanged ; Tape 3, For September 11 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Syria: Has Russia Gained Yet Another Satellite ; Tape 4, For September 12 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - The U.S. Policy Of Abusing Our Friends, Whilst Making Friends With The Enemy ; Tape 5, For September 13 (Friday) - Dr. Walter H. Judd interview with Mr. John F. Lewis - Ukrainian Unrest Behind The Czech Crisis. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 16 - September 20</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0028</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 16 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The Soviet Attitude Toward Rumania ; Tape 2, For September 17 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Lenin’s Message to Czechoslovakia ; Tape 3, For September 18 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Assassination of Ambassador Mein ; Tape 4, For September 19 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Latin American Bishops Dispute over Red Subversion ; Tape 5, For September 20 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Those Who Flee from Communism. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 23 - September 27</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0029</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 23 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Vasily Kuznetsov, Moscow’s Hatchet-Man in Prague ; Tape 2, For September 24 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - North Vietnam’s Support of Russian Oppression ; Tape 3, For September 25 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Television and the War in Vietnam ; Tape 4, For September 26 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Pyrrhic Victory May Be Mao’s Reward ; Tape 5, For September 27 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Russia Launches New Purge of Jews. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 30 - October 4</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0030</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 20 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Threat to West Germany ; Tape 2, For October 1 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Mass Power Threat to West ; Tape 3, For October 2 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Extent of Mao’s "Cultural Revolution" Purges ; Tape 4, For October 3 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Sanctions on Rhodesia Punish African Neighbors ; Tape 5, For October 4 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Yugoslavia Menaced by Warsaw Pact. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for October 7 - October 11</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0031</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For October 7 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Peking Still Generates Agitation Abroad ; Tape 2, For October 8 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Frank Johnson - Soviet Legalistic Threat to West Germany ; Tape 3, For October 9 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Forced Labor for Red China’s Students ; Tape 4, For October 10 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Free China’s Independence Day ; Tape 5, For October 11 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Domino Theory Already in Practice. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for October 14 - October 18</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0032</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For October 14 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Mexico’s Lesson in Communism ; Tape 2, For October 15 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Frank Johnson - Soviet Targets: Rumania and Yugoslavia ; Tape 3, For October 16 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Aeroflot: Soviet Trojan Horse ; Tape 4, For October 17 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Eritrean Guerillas Suffer Setback ; Tape 5, For October 18 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Hopeful Trends in Vietnam. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for October 21 - October 25</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0033</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For October 21 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s New Aggression in India ; Tape 2, For October 22 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - The Build-Up to Russia’s Newest Moves ; Tape 2, For October 23 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Indian Opposition to Red China Grows ; Tape 2, For October 24 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Jordan: Spark-Filled Powder Keg ; Tape 5, For October 25 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Consumer Goods Crisis. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for October 28 - November 1</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0034</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For October 28 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with William K. Lambie - Plan to Bolster Internal Security ; Tape 2, For October 29 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - The Dilemma of U.S. Isolationism ; Tape 3, For October 30 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. John H. Davis - Distribution of Palestine Arab Refugees ; Tape 4, For October 31 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - More Military Coups in Latin America? ; Tape 5, For November 1 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. John H. Davis - Plight of the Arab Refugees. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for November 4 - November 8</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0035</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For November 4 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Latest Soviet Naval Developments ; Tape 2, For November 5 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Red China’s New Accomplishments ; Tape 3, For November 6 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Zambia: Newest Violator or African Freedom ; Tape 4, For November 7 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. John H. Davis - How Reds Take Advantage of Arab Frustrations ; Tape 5, For November 8 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Secret Police in Czechoslovakia. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for November 11 - November 15</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0036</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For November 11 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Red Spy Penetration of NATO ; Tape 2, For November 12 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Algeria: Communism’s African Cuba ; Tape 3, For November 13 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Philby and NATO Spy Scandals ; Tape 4, For November 14 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Yugoslavia: Raw Nerves Exposed ; Tape 5, For November 15 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Ancient China’s Techniques Used to Fight Mao. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for November 18 - November 22</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0037</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For November 18 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - A U.S. Affront to Freedom ; Tape 2, For November 19 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Harry E. Martens - Profiles of Arab Refugees ; Tape 3, For November 20 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Re-Alignment in the Kremlin ; Tape 4, For November 21 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Red Reverses in Burma ; Tape 5, For November 22 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Czechoslovakia: Nation in Name Only. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for November 25 - November 29</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0038</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For November 25 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Critical Image in Vietnam ; Tape 2, For November 26 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Cambodia urges U.S. stay in Asia ; Tape 2, For November 27 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Red Espionage Center in Mexico ; Tape 4, For November 28 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Red Tactical Dispute in Indonesia ; Tape 5, For November 29 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Madame Mao’s Thoughts Muddy China Thinking. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for December 2 - December 6</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0039</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">21</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For December 2 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Bid for Castro’s Friendship ; Tape 2, For December 3 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Base in Zanzibar ; Tape 3, For December 4 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - NATO and the "Prague Coup" ; Tape 4, For December 5 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Biafra Backing from Red China ; Tape 5, For December 6 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - France Wakes up to Algerian Menace. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for December 9 - December 13</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0040</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For December 9 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Loss of Vietnam Subject of U.S. Debate ; Tape 2, For December 10 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Spain, U.S. Near Bases Accord ; Tape 3, For December 11 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Sabotage in Red Cuba ; Tape 4, For December 12 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Building Polaris Defense ; Tape 5, For December 13 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - China Extends Isolation from West to Press. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for December 16 - December 20</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0041</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For December 16 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Intellectual Ferment in Russia ; Tape 2, For December 17 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Power of Poets in Russia Today ; Tape 3, For December 18 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - A Yugoslav Poet’s Protest ; Tape 4, For December 19 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Rationale Puts NATO on Alert ; Tape 5, For December 20 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - The Domino Fact: Shaky Southeast Asia. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for December 23 - December 27</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0042</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For December 23 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Threat to Mid East Peace ; Tape 2, For December 24 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar A. Mowrer - Fallacy of Building Bridges to Reds ; Tape 3, For December 25 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Philippines: A Potential Asian Cuba ; Tape 4, For December 26 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar A. Mowrer - How to Undermine Red Tyranny ; Tape 5, For December 27 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - What Peking Seeks in Warsaw Talks. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for December 30 - January 3</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0043</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For December 30 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Budgeting for Military Superiority ; Tape 2, For December 31 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - New Year’s Eve - Time of Hopes and Fears ; Tape 3, For January 1 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Frank Johnson - Soviet Interest in the Suez Canal ; Tape 4, For January 2 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - U.N. Irresponsibility ; Tape 5, For January 3 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Washington’s Statements Hurt Saigon’s Prospects. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for January 6 - January 10</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0044</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For January 6 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Presses Claim to Control Mediterranean ; Tape 2, For January 7 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Guyana Versus Communism: The People Win ; Tape 3, For January 8 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Unstable Latin America ; Tape 4, For January 9 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - East-West German Bridge-Building ; Tape 5, For January 10 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Reorganization of Soviet Secret Police. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for January 13 - January 17</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0045</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For January 13 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with Amb. Ong - Fears for Peace in Vietnam ; Tape 2, For January 14 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Henry Kissinger on Vietnam ; Tape 3, For January 15 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Tibet Deserves "Conscience of Mankind" ; Tape 4, For January 16 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Red Chinese Build-Up in Central Asia ; Tape 5, For January 17 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with Amb. Ong - Malaysia’s New Red Uprising. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for January 20 - January 24</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0046</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For January 20 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The "Finlandization" of West Germany ; Tape 2, For January 21 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar A. Mowrer - Italy in Trouble ; Tape 3, For January 22 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Guerrilla War Growing in Thailand ; Tape 4, For January 23 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Amb. Tan Sri Ong - Malaysia’s Attraction for Reds ; Tape 5, For January 24 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Carlos Romulo Speaks for the Philippines. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for January 27 - January 31</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0047</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For January 27 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Cyprus: New Issue for Soviet Propaganda ; Tape 2, For January 28 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Robert F. Turner - Vietnam Misgivings ; Tape 3, For January 29 (Wednesday) Dr. Judd - Red China’s New Campaign Against Us ; Tape 4, For January 30 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Robert F. Turner - What a Viet Cong Victory Might Mean ; Tape 5, For January 31 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Dictatorship in Brazil. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for February 3 - February 7</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0048</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For February 3 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with Robert F. Turner - Threat of Red Victory and Purges in Vietnam ; Tape 2, For February 4 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Diplomatic Moves in the Middle East ; Tape 3, For February 5 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar A. Mowrer - Czechoslovakia Today ; Tape 4, For February 6 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Chinese Red Pot Calls U.S. Kettle Black ; Tape 5, For February 7 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with Robert F. Turner - How Reds View Peace Talks in Vietnam. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for February 10 - February 14</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0049</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For February 10 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Establishing Nuclear Center in Cuba ; Tape 2, For February 11 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Odell Lee - What Vietnamese People Want ; Tape 3, For February 12 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - New Soviet Propaganda Attack on Yugoslavia ; Tape 4, For February 13 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Odell Lee - Strength of Vietnamese People ; Tape 5, For February 14 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Moscow Explains Role of Satellites. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for February 17 - February 21</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0050</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For February 17 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Renewed Assault on Thailand ; Tape 2, For February 18 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Odell Lee - Vietnamese Villagers’ View of Americans ; Tape 3, For February 19 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Laotian Highway Penetration ; Tape 4, For February 20 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Odell Lee - Black American’s View of War in Vietnam ; Tape 5, For February 21 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Uruguay: Victim of Red Aggression. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for February 24 - February 28</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0051</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For February 24 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The Next Moves in Vietnam ; Tape 2, For February 25 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Seek Spanish Port Facilities ; Tape 3, For February 26 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Edgar A. Mowrer - Italy’s Recognition of Red China ; Tape 4, For February 27 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Rebirth of Stalin as Soviet Hero ; Tape 5, For February 28 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Death of an African Terrorist Leader. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for March 3 - March 7</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0052</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For March 3 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - New Communist Guerilla Move in Bolivia ; Tape 2, For March 4 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Fails to Understand North Korea ; Tape 3, For March 5 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Aim for Middle East Oil ; Tape 4, For March 6 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with john F. Lewis - Iraq: Middle East Time Bomb ; Tape 5, For March 7 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Laos Bombing Now Critical in Southeast Asia Situation. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for March 10 - March 14</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0053</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">22</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For March 10 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Communist Pressure on Berlin ; Tape 2, For March 11 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Undesirable Alternatives in the Middle East ; Tape 3, For March 12 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Ceausecu and Longo Criticize the Kremlin ; Tape 4, For March 13 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Reds Win Crucial Election in West Bengal ; Tape 5, For March 14 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Political Play in Middle East. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for March 17 - March 21</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0054</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For March 17 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - New Soviet Military Developments ; Tape 2, For March 18 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Frank Johnson - What Motivates the Russians ; Tape 3, For March 19 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Protest the Policage of "Linkage" ; Tape 4, For March 20 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Odell Lee - North Vietnamese Blunder in South Vietnam ; Tape 5, For March 21 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Behind Sweden’s Swing to the Left. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for March 24 - March 28</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0055</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For March 24 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with Amb. Sudjatmoko - Indonesian Comeback ; Tape 2, For March 25 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Israel’s Communists Help Arab Claims ; Tape 3, March 26 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Amb. Sudjatmoko - Southeast Asian Cooperation ; Tape 4, For March 27 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Peking’s Trade Penetration of Asia ; Tape 5, For March 26 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with Amb. Sudjatmoko - Foreign Investment for Indonesia. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for March 31 - April 4</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0056</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For March 31 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The Soviet Purpose in Talks with the United States ; Tape 2, For April 1 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Increase Influence in Arabian Peninsula ; Tape 3, For April 2 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Slander U.S. in India ; Tape 4, For April 3 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Berlin Cruch to Continue ; Tape 5, For April 4 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Soviets Reiterate Right of Intervention. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 7 - April 11</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0057</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 7 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet First-Strike Threat ; Tape 2, For April 8 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - South Africa Fears Red Chinese ; Tape 3, For April 9 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - South Africa Prepares Indian Ocean Defenses ; Tape 4, For April 10 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Zambia’s Internal Breakdown ; Tape 5, For April 11 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Toothless British Lion. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 14 - April 18</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0058</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 14 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Russia’s "Pro" ABM System ; Tape 2, For April 15 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Cuba’s Red Embassy in South Vietnam ; Tape 3, For April 16 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - African Terrorism ; Tape 4, For April 17 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - New Red Empire in Asia ; Tape 5, For April 18 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - New Hope for Free Asians. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 21 - April 25</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0059</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 21 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - General Giap Unmasked ; Tape 2, For April 22 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - What is Provacative in ABM ; Tape 3, For April 23 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Terrorism Today in Portuguese Africa ; Tape 4, For April 24 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Red China Rewrote the Rules ; Tape 5, For April 25 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Giap’s Claim of America’s Defeat. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for April 28 - May 2</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0060</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For April 28 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Russian Anti-Space Defense ; Tape 2, For April 29 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. Edward Teller - Costs: Defense Versus Offense ; Tape 3, For April 30 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. Edward Teller - Will an ABM System Work? ; Tape 4, For May 1 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. Edward Teller - The Fate of an Assured Deterrence ; Tape 5, For May 2 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Giap Demands Total Victory. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for May 5 - May 9</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0061</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For May 5 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Leadership Lack Threatens Free World ; Tape 2, For May 6 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. John Wheeler - ABM Needed to Protect Morale ; Tape 3, For May 7 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Warsaw Pact Reorganization ; Tape 4, For May 6 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Dr. John Wheeler - How Offensive is an ABM Defense? ; Tape 5, For May 9 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Military Games, 1969. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for May 12 - May 16</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0062</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For May 12 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - ABM: Weapon Against War ; Tape 2, For May 13 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Military Capability ; Tape 3, For May 14 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Nuclear War "Inevitability" in Kremlin Mind ; Tape 4, For May 15 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Opposition Arguments to ABM ; Tape 5, For May 16 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Loses Superiority at Sea. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for May 19 - May 23</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0063</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For May 19 (Monday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Special ABM Study ; Tape 2, For May 20 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Systemic Conflict ; Tape 3, For May 21 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Objectives in the Cold War ; Tape 4, For May 22 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Wartime Economy of U.S.S.R. ; Tape 5, For May 23 (Friday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Soviet Education Lead. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for May 26 - May 30</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0064</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For May 26 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Lin Piao’s Moment of Victory ; Tape 2, For May 27 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - The Error of Mao According to Lin Piao ; Tape 3, For May 28 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - South Africa: America’s Friend ; Tape 4, For May 29 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - South Atlantic Invitation to Soviets ; Tape 5, For May 30 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - The Mystery of the Soviet Generals. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 2 - June 6</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0065</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 2 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet ICBM Construction Rate Increasing ; Tape 2, For June 3 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - New Terror in Africa ; Tape 3, For June 4 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Africa’s Red Training Camps ; Tape 4, For June 5 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - African Insurgency Knows Little Success ; Tape 5, For June 6 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Offensive Against NATO. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 9 - June 13</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0066</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 9 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The Soviet Game In The Middle East ; Tape 2, For June 10 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Peking Inspires Malaysian Unrest ; Tape 3, For June 11 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Leftist Threat to U.S. Business ; Tape 4, For June 12 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - The Soviet Gambit In The Mediterranean ; Tape 5, For June 13 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Czechoslavakia, The Complete Slave. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 16 - June 20</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0067</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 16 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Behind World Revolution: Politics, Not Economics ; Tape 2, For June 17 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Hits Cambodian Bases ; Tape 3, For June 18 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Objectives in Red China ; Tape 4, For June 19 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Operation Vesna, Soviet Spring Maneuvering ; Tape 5, For June 20 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Military Industrial Complex. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 23 - June 27</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0068</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 23 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Singapore’s Financial Showdown with Peking ; Tape 2, For June 24 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Podgorny’s Visit to North Korea ; Tape 3, For June 25 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Red China’s Education System in Ruins ; Tape 4, For June 26 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - New Soviet MIRV Testing ; Tape 5, For June 27 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Thailand Holds Its Breath. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for June 30 - July 4</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0069</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For June 30 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Aircraft Industry Complex ; Tape 2, For July 1 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Raymond Joseph - Haitian Powder Keg ; Tape 3, For July 2 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - U.S. Industry: Victim of U.S. African Policy ; Tape 4, For July 3 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Raymond Joseph - Haitian Coalition of Hope ; Tape 5, For July 4 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Secretary Laird Provides New Information on the Soviet Strategic Threat. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 7 - July 11</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0070</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 7 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Secretary Laird Provides New Information on the Chinese Communist Strategic Threat ; Tape 2, For July 8 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with Raymond Joseph - Communists Inside Haiti ; Tape 3, For July 9 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet Connivance in Pueblo Seizure ; Tape 4, For July 10 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with Raymond Joseph - Castro’s Threat to Haiti ; Tape 5, For July 11 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - "Viva" Means Life for U.S. Colleges. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 14 - July 18</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0071</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 14 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Much Ado About Nothing ; Tape 2, For July 15 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - SDS Convention Splits Markist Group ; Tape 3, For July 16 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Did Castro Jump The Gun in Vietnam? ; Tape 4, For July 17 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Russia’s Involvement in Nigeria ; Tape 5, For July 18 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - The ABM and Arms Control. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 21 - July 25</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0072</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 21 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Southeast Asians Face Red Realities ; Tape 2, For July 22 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Mboya’s Assassination in Kenya ; Tape 3, For July 23 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - World Communists Rubber-stamp Kremlin Authority ; Tape 4, For July 24 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Nixon and Rumania ; Tape 5, For July 25 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Asian Mutual Security Pact Urged. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for July 28 - August 1</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0073</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For July 28 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Letter from a Soviet Concentration Camp ; Tape 2, For July 29 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Latin America in Revolt ; Tape 3, For July 30 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - New Iraq Assault on Kurds ; Tape 4, For July 31 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Reds and West German Elections ; Tape 5, For August 1 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Westerner Sees China’s Nuclear Arsenal. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 4 - August 8</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0074</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 4 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - A New Era, New Realities for Soviets ; Tape 2, For August 5 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Russian Fleet in the Atlantic ; Tape 3, For August 6 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - United States and Israel Scored by Reds in the Mideast ; Tape 4, For August 7 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - "Soccer War," A Red Gain ; Tape 5, For August 8 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Artillery and the Soviet Military Industrial Complex. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 11 - August 15</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0075</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 11 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - No Coalition For Giang Dang Survivors ; Tape 2, For August 12 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Soviet Maneuvers To Suppress Czechoslovakians ; Tape 3, For August 13 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Hoover’s Report: The Enemy Within ; Tape 4, For August 14 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Latin American Subversion Renewed ; Tape 5, For August 15 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - South Africa’s Appeal to the West. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 18 - August 22</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0076</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 18 (Monday) - Blueprint for Hemisphere Revolution Released - Dr. Walter H. Judd ; Tape 2, For August 19 (Tuesday) - Russian Writer Kuznetsov Defects - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis ; Tape 3, For August 20 (Wednesday) - Kuznetsov: From Shadows of Fear - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis ; Tape 4, For August 21 (Thursday) - British Problems with a Defector - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis ; Tape 5, For August 22 (Friday) - Story of an African Revolutionary - Dr. Walter H. Judd. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for August 25 - August 29</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0077</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For August 25 (Monday) - Micronesia: America’s "Bali Hai" - Dr. Walter H. Judd ; Tape 2, For August 26 (Tuesday) - The New Soviet Strategy In Asia - Dr. Walter H. Judd ; Tape 3, For August 27 (Wednesday) - Russian Control Of Intellectual Minds - John F. Lewis ; Tape 4, For August 28 (Thursday) - Dean Acheson’s Assessment of The Red Threat - Dr. Walter H. Judd ; Tape 5, For August 29 (Friday) - The Soviet Union As It Really Is - Dr. Walter H. Judd. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for Sept. 1 - Sept. 5</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0078</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For Sept. 1 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - How Peking Builds Support for Subversion ; Tape 2, For Sept. 2 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Peking Support for Latin American Terrorists ; Tape 3, For Sept. 3 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd interview with John F. Lewis - Communist Gain, Central America’s Loss ; Tape 4, For Sept. 4 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Red Complaints, Whose Ox Is Gored? ; Tape 5, For Sept. 5 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Clarification of Soviet Missile Developments. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 8 - September 12</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0079</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 8 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - Communism’s Latest Assault on Czechoslovakia ; Tape 2, For September 9 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - South Africa’s Naval Importance ; Tape 3, For September 10 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - French Aid to South Africa’s Defenses ; Tape 4, For September 11 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Red China Bolsters Its Soviet Frontier ; Tape 5, For September 12 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - A Tourist’s Nightmare in Russia. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Washington Report of the Air, for September 15 - September 19</unittitle>
              <unitid>power_ts_0080</unitid>
              <abstract>1/4 inch audio tape</abstract>
              <unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>1 reel; running time 3:15</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">24</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
              <p>Tape 1, For September 15 (Monday) - Dr. Judd - The Demise of a Pro-Western Libya ; Tape 2, For September 16 (Tuesday) - Dr. Judd - Soviet-Spanish Port Agreement ; Tape 3, For September 17 (Wednesday) - Dr. Judd - Zambia: Example of Bad Red Advice ; Tape 4, For September 18 (Thursday) - Dr. Judd - Reds Cooperate to Destroy ; Tape 5, For September 19 (Friday) - Dr. Judd - Kremlin Complaint About West’s Propaganda. The credit line at the end of each program fulfills the requirements of the broadcasting industry to identify the underwriter of public service programming on the air. </p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
    <index id="sic">
      <head>Selected index to correspondence</head>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Adams, Paul D.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Dec 6</ref>
          <ref>1963 Jun 11</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Aiken, George D.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 May 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Allen, William M.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 Jul 10</ref>
          <ref>1961 Jan 17</ref>
          <ref>1961 Feb 2</ref>
          <ref>1961 Mar 31</ref>
          <ref>1961 Sep 29</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Alsop, Joseph</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Mar 5</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Beall, J. Glenn</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 Feb 27</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Beerman, Ralph F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Dec 4</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Bergan, G.T.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Feb 24</ref>
          <ref>1964 Apr 14</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jan 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Boggs, J. Caleb</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1965 Jul 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Bolton, Frances P.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Aug 13</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Bradley, Mark E. Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1950 Feb 23</ref>
          <ref>1963 May 28</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Brewster, Daniel B.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Mar 18</ref>
          <ref>1964 Mar 26</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Bridges, Styles</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Mar 2</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Brundage, Percival</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Dec 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Bryant, Farris</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Dec 31</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Buckley, William F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1969 Apr 30</ref>
          <ref>1969 Jun 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Burke, Arleigh</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Apr 19</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Callaway, Lew L.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Feb 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Cannon, Howard W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Jun 11</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Case, Francis</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Nov 20</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Childlaw, B. W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1954 Mar 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Clark, Mark W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Sep 25</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Clay, Lucius D.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Feb 5</ref>
          <ref>1963 Dec 4</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 23</ref>
          <ref>1967 Jan</ref>
          <ref>1967 Oct 6</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Collbohm, Frariol</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Jan 5</ref>
          <ref>1962 Mar 14</ref>
          <ref>1963 Apr 30</ref>
          <ref>1964 Jul 20</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Considine, Bob</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Dec 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Cousins, Norman</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Sep 18</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Craigie, L. C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1952 Jul 28</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 20</ref>
          <ref>1963 Oct 25</ref>
          <ref>1964 Gen </ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Curtis, Carl T.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Sep 12</ref>
          <ref>1963 Oct 8</ref>
          <ref>1963 Nov 5</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Daniel, Price</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Nov 10</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Davis, Frank W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Jan 13</ref>
          <ref>1961 May 26</ref>
          <ref>1961 Jul 13</ref>
          <ref>1961 Aug 28</ref>
          <ref>1961 Sep 14</ref>
          <ref>1964 Jan 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Dole, Robert</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Jan 4</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Dominick, Peter H.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1970 Sep 16</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Donovan, Hedley</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Apr 27</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Douglas, Donald W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Aug 22</ref>
          <ref>1958 Sep 12</ref>
          <ref>1960 Aug 8</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Dulles, Allen</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1954 Jan 11</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Faker, Ira C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 May 6</ref>
          <ref>1961 Oct 30</ref>
          <ref>1962 Mar 14</ref>
          <ref>1964 Dec 2</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 24</ref>
          <ref>1968 Mar 20</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Ellsworth, Robert</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1967 May 1</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Foss, Joe</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 Aug 28</ref>
          <ref>1957 Sep 10</ref>
          <ref>1957 Oct 3</ref>
          <ref>1958 Nov 12</ref>
          <ref>1962 Apr 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Fulbright, J. William</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Jan 26</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Godfrey, Arthur</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Jan 9</ref>
          <ref>1959 May 25</ref>
          <ref>1959 Sep 1</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Goldwater, Barry</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Jun 14</ref>
          <ref>1964 Jan 21</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 15</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hagerty, James C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 May 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Halleck, Charles A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Oct 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hardin, Clifford M.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Sep 30</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hart, Philip A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1966 Jan 18</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hickenlooper, Bourke B.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1950 May 22</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hollings, Ernest F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Sep 15</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hope, Bob</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Mar 27</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hopper, Hedda</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Sep 10</ref>
          <ref>1960 Aug 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hosmer, Craig</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Aug 30</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Hruska, Roman L.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1953 Nov 20</ref>
          <ref>1957 Dec 11</ref>
          <ref>1957 Dec 13</ref>
          <ref>1958 Jan 14</ref>
          <ref>1961 Mar 16</ref>
          <ref>1962 May 21</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Johnson, G.K.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Mar 19</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Johnson, U. Alexis</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Jul 17</ref>
          <ref>1961 Jul 18</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Kalber, Floyd</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Apr 29</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Kennedy, John F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Apr 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Kennedy, Robert F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Apr 25</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Kinter, William R.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1968 Jan 19</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 7</ref>
          <ref>1969 Dec 3</ref>
          <ref>1970 Sep 4</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Kissinger, Henry A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Mar 9</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Duter, Laurence S.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1955 May 11</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 14</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 21</ref>
          <ref>1959 May 28</ref>
          <ref>1961 May 5</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>LeMay, Curtis E.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1954 Oct 14</ref>
          <ref>1957 Apr 13</ref>
          <ref>1957 Nov 23</ref>
          <ref>1961 May 29</ref>
          <ref>1966 Oct 6</ref>
          <ref>1966 Oct 11</ref>
          <ref>1967 Mar 13</ref>
          <ref>1967 May 10</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Lemnitzer, L.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Aug 31</ref>
          <ref>1962 Jun 18</ref>
          <ref>1962 Sep 20</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Lewis, Roger</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1965 Feb 2</ref>
          <ref>1965 Apr 6</ref>
          <ref>1965 May 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Lincoln, Frank B.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1967 Jul 14</ref>
          <ref>1967 Jul 24</ref>
          <ref>1967 Oct 4</ref>
          <ref>1967 Nov 22</ref>
          <ref>1968 Feb 8</ref>
          <ref>1968 Feb 19</ref>
          <ref>1968 Mar 26</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jul 16</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jul 30</ref>
          <ref>1968 Sep 11</ref>
          <ref>1968 Nov 9</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Ling, James L.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Jun 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Lindsay, Richard C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1948 Dec 29</ref>
          <ref>1951 Oct 24</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Lodge, Henry Cabot</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Apr 28</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Long, Russell B.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1952 Aug 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>McCone, John A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1950 Dec 27</ref>
          <ref>1967 Sep 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>McConnell, J. P.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Dec 24</ref>
          <ref>1961 Jun </ref>
          <ref>1965 Feb 2</ref>
          <ref>1967 Mar </ref>
          <ref>1967 Oct 18</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>McElroy, Neil</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Apr 26</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>MacGregor, Clark</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1970 Aug 14</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>McNamara, Robert S.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Sep 1</ref>
          <ref>1962 Feb 27</ref>
          <ref>1963 Jan 31</ref>
          <ref>1963 Jan 19</ref>
          <ref>1963 Jul 1</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Miller, Troup Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Oct 3</ref>
          <ref>1962 May 8</ref>
          <ref>1962 Jan 2</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Montgomery, Field Marshal the Viscount of Alamein</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1965 Jun 5</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Morrison, Frank B.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 May 22</ref>
          <ref>1964 Apr 30</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Murphy, George</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1968 Jun 11</ref>
          <ref>1969 Dec 13</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Nimitz, Chester</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1965 Mar 27</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Nixon, Richard M.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1967 Feb 9</ref>
          <ref>1967 Oct 26</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jan 5</ref>
          <ref>1968 Apr 8</ref>
          <ref>1968 Apr 16</ref>
          <ref>1968 May 25</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jun 28</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jul 29</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 1</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 26</ref>
          <ref>1969 Jan 14</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Nixon, Richard M. [C. Calvert Knudsen, Office of the President-Elect]</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1968 Dec 2</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Norstad, Lauris</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1952 Aug 13</ref>
          <ref>1957 Oct 15</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Old, Archie J. Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 Jun 19</ref>
          <ref>1958 Dec 12</ref>
          <ref>1960 Jun 18</ref>
          <ref>1961 Mar 15</ref>
          <ref>1962 Sep 7</ref>
          <ref>1963 Feb 25</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Pace, Frank Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 May 21</ref>
          <ref>1958 Nov 12</ref>
          <ref>1959 Jan 22</ref>
          <ref>1959 Oct 26</ref>
          <ref>1960 Dec 6</ref>
          <ref>1963 Oct 15</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 24</ref>
          <ref>1965 Feb 15</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Quarles, Donald A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1955 Jan 4</ref>
          <ref>1957 Apr 8</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Ransom, Harry Howe</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Mar 14</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Rawlings, E. W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1956 Jul 30</ref>
          <ref>1959 Feb 10</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Reagan, Ronald</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1967 May 23</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 19</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Reynolds, Sam W.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1954 Jul 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Rivers, L. Mendel</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1967 Aug 16</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Rumsfeld, Donald</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Aug 12</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Rusk, Dean</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Apr 6</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Russell, Richard B.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Mar 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Ryan, John D.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1952 Oct 10</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 22</ref>
          <ref>1962 Nov 14</ref>
          <ref>1964 Dec 23</ref>
          <ref>1965 Feb 18</ref>
          <ref>1969 Dec 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Schlafly, J. Fred</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1967 Oct 18</ref>
          <ref>1968 Mar 11</ref>
          <ref>1968 Apr 10</ref>
          <ref>1968 Apr 4</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 19</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 21</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Schlafly, Phyliss</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1966 Feb 7</ref>
          <ref>1966 May 16</ref>
          <ref>1966 Jun 23</ref>
          <ref>1966 Aug 8</ref>
          <ref>1968 Mar 28</ref>
          <ref>1968 Aug 21</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Schlatter, D. M.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1948 Nov 17</ref>
          <ref>1948 Dec 23</ref>
          <ref>1950 Jan 20</ref>
          <ref>1953 Mar 5</ref>
          <ref>1953 Sep 28</ref>
          <ref>1955 Aug 2</ref>
          <ref>1956 Mar 15</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 21</ref>
          <ref>1965 Feb </ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Schriever, B. A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1955 Feb 3</ref>
          <ref>1957 Nov 6</ref>
          <ref>1962 Aug 27</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Smart, Jacob E.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Feb 13</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Spaatz, Carl A.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 Mar 30</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Spellman, Francis Cardinal</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Jul 6</ref>
          <ref>1965 Feb 25</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Spivak, Lawrence E.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 May 21</ref>
          <ref>1964 Apr 17</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 30</ref>
          <ref>1965 Jan 8</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Stennis, John</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Jun 19</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Stewart, James</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Dec 2</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Stikker, D. U.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Jun 4</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Stratemeyer, George E.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Aug 21</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Stratton, Samuel F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Feb 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Sweeney, W. C. Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Dec 30</ref>
          <ref>1959 Sep 29</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Swofford, R. P. Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1955 Sep 6</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 13</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Sylvester, Arthur</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1961 May 23</ref>
          <ref>1961 Jun 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Symington, Stuart</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1951 Dec 29</ref>
          <ref>1954 Jan 5</ref>
          <ref>1954 Jan 18</ref>
          <ref>1954 Aug 9</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 24</ref>
          <ref>1961 Jan 7</ref>
          <ref>1964 Oct 19</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Taylor, Maxwell</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1962 Dec 7</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Thomas, Lowell</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Sep 10</ref>
          <ref>1959 Oct 1</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Todt, George</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Nov 29</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 1</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 7</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 8</ref>
          <ref>1966 Jan 14</ref>
          <ref>1970 Aug 8</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Truman, Harry S.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1959 Aug 3</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Tunney, Gene</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Jan 22</ref>
          <ref>1960 Feb 12</ref>
          <ref>1960 Mar 18</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Twining, Nathan F.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1954 Jun 16</ref>
          <ref>1956 Jul 18</ref>
          <ref>1958 Apr 10</ref>
          <ref>1968 Jun 4</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Vandenberg, Hoyt S.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1949 Jun 14</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Vinson, Carl</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Jul 24</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wallace, Dewitt</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1957 Oct 18</ref>
          <ref>1959 Dec 30</ref>
          <ref>1964 Mar 30</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Watson, Thomas J. Jr.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1956 Feb 9</ref>
          <ref>1956 Jun 8</ref>
          <ref>1957 May 22</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wedemeyer, A.C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Aug 22</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Westmoreland, W.C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1960 Aug 25</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Weyland, O.P.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1955 Jun 15</ref>
          <ref>1957 Jun 4</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wheeler, Earle G.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Sep 23</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wheless, Hewitt T.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1965 Feb 4</ref>
          <ref>1967 Sep 11</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wilson, C.E.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1954 May 17</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>White, Thomas D.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1951 Aug 27</ref>
          <ref>1953 May 27</ref>
          <ref>1957 Apr 11</ref>
          <ref>1957 Sep 17</ref>
          <ref>1958 Jul 7</ref>
          <ref>1959 Dec 7</ref>
          <ref>1960 Aug 25</ref>
          <ref>1961 Aug 17</ref>
          <ref>1962 May 31</ref>
          <ref>1963 May 17</ref>
          <ref>1963 May 19</ref>
          <ref>1963 Aug 15</ref>
          <ref>1965 Feb 18</ref>
          <ref>1965 Mar 8</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Williams, Robert H.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Sep 16</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wright, Jerauld</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1958 Sep 6</ref>
          <ref>1963 Jan 14</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Wyman, Louis C.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1963 Aug 21</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Yorty, Sam</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1964 Nov 9</ref>
          <ref>1969 Dec 1</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
      <indexentry>
        <name>Zuckert, Eugene M.</name>
        <ptrgrp>
          <ref>1952 Nov 6</ref>
          <ref>1964 Nov 24</ref>
        </ptrgrp>
      </indexentry>
    </index>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
