<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
<eadid countrycode="us" identifier="schweitzer_a" mainagencycode="NSyU">schweitzer_a</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Albert Schweitzer Papers</titleproper>
<subtitle>An inventory of his papers at Syracuse University</subtitle>
<author encodinganalog="Creator">-</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
<lb/>
</publisher>&su_address;
<date encodinganalog="Date" normal="0000">unknown</date>
</publicationstmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>AMCon <date normal="2006-10-14">14 Oct 2006</date>
</creation>
<langusage>
<language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
</langusage>
</profiledesc>
<revisiondesc>
<list>
<item>14 Oct 2006 - converted to EAD (AMCon)</item><item>8 Jan 2010 - additions (MRC)</item>
</list>
</revisiondesc>
</eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
<did>
<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
<repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
<lb/>&su_address;</repository>
<origination label="Creator: ">
<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965.</persname>
</origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Albert Schweitzer Papers</unittitle>
<unitdate calendar="gregorian" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1896/1965" type="inclusive">1896-1965</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
<extent encodinganalog="300$a">18 linear ft.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">
                    Papers of the theologian, philosopher, physician, organist, and music scholar; born in Alsace, France.  Founded a missionary hospital in Lambaréné, French Equatorial Africa (now Gabon).  Received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1952 for his advocacy of the brotherhood of nations.   Collection includes correspondence (1901-1965); 123 notebooks (1918-1965); manuscript essays and lectures on religion, philosophy, and medicine; and sermons. Correspondence includes nearly 1400 letters between Schweitzer and wife Hélène Bresslau (1901-1939); 396 letters (1950-1965) written in German to Erica Anderson; 180 letters to daughter Rhena Schweitzer Miller; and 70 letters to various recipients, including 3 to Rudolf Bultmann. Notebooks document Schweitzer's daily life in Lambaréné, the diseases and stories of his patients, and the arrival of visitors to the mission.  They also contain poems, quotations, excerpts from books on philosophy, religion, and history; clippings from French, German, English, and African newspapers; reports on world politics; and commentaries on himself and his work.</abstract>
<unitid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">149738</unitid>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
Majority in <language langcode="eng">English</language>, some in <language langcode="fre">French</language> and <language langcode="ger">German</language>
</langmaterial>
</did><bioghist encodinganalog="545">
<head>Biographical History</head>
<p>Albert Schweitzer (January 14, 1875-September 4, 1965), German theologian, philosopher, musician, musicologist, doctor, surgeon, and medical missionary, was born in Kaysersberg, Alsace (French territory then occupied by Germany), the son of a liberal Lutheran minister, Louis Schweitzer, and Adele (Schillinger) Schweitzer.  He began music lessons at age five, went on to study theology and philosophy at Strasbourg University and, briefly, philosophy at the Sorbonne in Paris.  In 1902 he became a lecturer in the faculty of theology at Strasbourg University, and in the following year principal of the Theological College of St. Thomas.</p><p>Even at this young age, Schweitzer was well-known throughout Europe for his achievements in music and theology.  He was an exceptional performer and critic of Bach as well as an influential organ-builder whose published works were to change the pattern of organ restoration and installation. In theology and philosophy, his unorthodox ideas about the need for reason and truth within Christian dogma were earning him controversy and praise.  The publication in 1906 (1910 in English) of his <emph render="italic">The Quest of the Historical Jesus</emph>, in which Schweitzer took a new look at the Synoptic gospels and tried to understand exactly what Jesus really believed, was  a landmark in Christian theology. </p><p>In 1896, despite a sucessful scholastic career, Schweitzer decided that he could not live a life purely devoted to academia. "I decided that I would make my life my argument," he said, intending to act out his beliefs rather than just preach them.  At the age of thirty he returned to Strasbourg University to study medicine and in 1913 he became a fully qualified doctor, with a specialization in tropical diseases.  He began actively to raise funds for the establishment of a hospital in equatorial Africa.  Although his unorthodox theology was received by most mission societies with suspicion and disapproval, the Paris Missionary Society at last agreed to sponsor his venture and gave him land on which to build his hospital. This he did, with the help of his wife, Hélène Bresslau, who had qualified as a nurse to help with his mission.</p><p>The Schweitzers set up their hospital in Lambaréné, a fiercely tropical area of French equatorial Africa.  Schweitzer's unorthodox medical methods (he ran Lambaréné like a typical African village) were frequently criticized but Schweitzer believed that blending African culture with his own techniques would address the needs of the population better than the imposition of a purely Western style upon them.  The affection and trust he inspired in those who came to him for treatment and the success of his hospital over the years would seem to confirm this view. The villagers christened him "Oganga," meaning "the fetishman," a term of respect. By the time of his death, Lambaréné had about seventy buildings and attracted dedicated and talented medical staff from around the world.</p><p>At the outbreak of World War I he and his wife, both German citizens, were palced under house arrest and eventually taken to an internment camp in France, where they stayed until the end of the war.  In 1924 he returned to Lambaréné,  rebuilt the hospital on a new site, and spent the rest of his life devoted to its development, traveling regularly to Europe to give concerts to raise funds.  Hélène's health suffered after her experience in the internment camp and she remained in Europe, apart from the occasional visit, but their daughter Rhena trained as a laboratory technican so she could work alongside her father.</p><p>Prior to the outbreak of World War II, Schweitzer continued to visit and lecture in Germany until the increased power of the Nazis made it no longer safe.  The war itself drove Lambaréné to the brink of closure, but assistance from the Unitarian Service Committee in America enabled it to recover.</p><p> Schweitzer's ethical system, which he termed Reverence for Life, centered on a belief that  everything on earth is equally sacred.  "Man's






 ethics," he said, "must not end with man, but should extend to the universe." In his view, it is up to mankind to invest living with moral value, since nature and the universe are neutral.  Schweitzer elaborated this theory in his writings and exemplified it in his own life, refusing to kill anything, even insects, unless it was absolutely essential. (Part of the responsibility of this approach, he knew, was the need to accept that in some situations killing is necessary.)  </p><p>In 1952 Schweitzer was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize, the money from which he put towards building a leper colony near the hospital. In 1957 Hélène died, and thereafter he remained at Lambaréné. He became increasingly outspoken on the issue of nuclear weapons, joining with some of the greatest intellects in the world to discuss and denounce their proliferation. In 1958 he made three radio appeals from Oslo entitled "Peace or Atomic War?," and until the end of his life he welcomed visiting journalists or politicians who wished to discuss this issue with him.</p><p>He died, peacefully, in 1965, and was buried alongside his wife at Lambaréné. </p><p>(Biographical statement adapted from <emph render="italic">World Authors 1900-1950</emph> (1996)
Copyright (c) by The H. W. Wilson Company)</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
<head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
<p>Assembled from a variety of sources, the <emph render="bold">Albert Schweitzer Papers</emph> spans the years 1896 to 1965 and comprises <emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph>, <emph render="bold">Writings</emph> and <emph render="bold">Memorabilia</emph> of the Nobel Peace Prize-winning humanitarian doctor (1875-1965). Of Alsatian background, Schweitzer spoke both French and German, and his notebooks and family correspondence move freely, at times randomly, between the two. In 1913 Albert Schweitzer relinquished a promising career as a theologian and musician to travel to French Equatorial Africa where he established a hospital at Lambaréné on the Ogowe River. Documenting Schweitzer's realization of his own philosophy of "reverence for life," the collection offers an intimate look at the thoughts and daily life of one of the most revered men of the twentieth century.</p>
<p>Arranged alphabetically, the <emph render="bold">Correspondence/subject files</emph> (boxes 1-5) consists primarily of original letters which Schweitzer wrote to his wife Hélène (née Bresslau), his daughter Rhena, and his biographer and friend Erica Anderson. Other correspondents include Emory Ross, Director of the Albert Schweitzer Fellowship, biographer Hermann Hagedorn, and John F. Kennedy, to whom there is a draft of a Schweitzer letter.</p>
<p><emph render="bold">Writings</emph> (boxes 6-21) includes a working copy with notes for revisions of the book <emph render="italic">More from the Primeval Forest</emph>; essays, including drafts for his three radio messages on the dangers of nuclear proliferation; 127 notebooks covering the years 1918 to 1965; program notes for an organ concert; thoughts on nuclear weapons testing; the script for the documentary film "Albert Schweitzer;" as well as a short story, speeches and sermons.</p>
<p>Constituting the bulk of the <emph render="bold">Writings</emph> and arranged chronologically, the notebooks (boxes 7-19) "make up the core of what might be generally considered Albert Schweitzer's personal journal." (Ursula Berkling "The Albert Schweitzer Papers at Syracuse University", <emph render="italic">Syracuse University Library Associates Courier</emph>, vol.XXI, no.2, Fall 1986, p.27) They embrace a wide variety of topics, including official hospital records and accounts of daily life at Lambaréné, as well as travel diaries of Schweitzer's many concert and/or lecture tours to Europe and the United States. The notebooks also contain observations about people and world events; explorations of ideas in philosophy, theology, linguistics and music; records of and excerpts from Schweitzer's correspondence; financial and personnel records; construction hints; poems; recipes; and many other items indicating a mind that seems to have been interested in everything. Together with the dates and Schweitzer-provided titles for most notebooks, a partial description of their contents is listed.</p>
<p>A watercolor painting by Lambaréné nurse Gloria Coolidge; clippings; photographs, some signed by either Schweitzer or photographer Erica Anderson; a book on harmony and a pamphlet about French missionary work in Africa, both inscribed by Albert Schweitzer to his daughter; two copies of an autograph typescript essay, "Les Deux Frères," by Nikos Kazantzakis; and some early documents from Schweitzer's days as a student at the University of Strassburg constitute <emph render="bold">Memorabilia</emph> (box 22 and oversize package 1). Also included is a mahogany box, possibly made at Lambaréné, which is inscribed "avec mes bonnes pensées Albert Schweitzer."</p>

<p>Original Schweitzer letters to Raymond P. Currier, Hermann Hagedorn, and Emory Ross were relocated to this collection from the <emph render="bold">Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records</emph>, as were original Schweitzer letters to Clarence F. Avery from the <emph render="bold">Albert Schweitzer Center Records</emph>.</p></scopecontent>

<!--
<arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
<head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
<p>## OPT (MARC 351$a)</p>
</arrangement>--><relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
<head>Related Material</head>

<p>The library also holds the <extref href="../a/asfr.htm">Albert Schweitzer Fellowship Records</extref> (one series of which is the <emph render="bold">Albert Schweitzer Center Records</emph>).   Other Albert Schweitzer-related material at &scrc_name; may be found among the papers of <extref href="../b/bultmann_rk.htm">Rudolf Bultmann</extref>, <extref href="../d/dahlberg_et.htm">Edwin T. Dahlberg</extref>, <extref href="../h/hagedorn_h.htm">Hermann Hagedorn</extref>, and <extref href="../j/joy_cr.htm">Charles R. Joy</extref>.  See also the <archref href="../r/reitzer_j.htm">Johanna Reitzer Collection on Albert Schweitzer</archref>.</p></relatedmaterial><!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
<head>Separated Material</head>
<p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
</separatedmaterial>--><!--
<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
<head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
<p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
</otherfindaid>-->
<controlaccess>
<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Music</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Religion and Philosophy</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Science and medicine</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Activism and social reform</subject><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Anderson, Erica.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Bresslau, Helene, 1879-1957.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Bultmann, Rudolf Karl, 1884-1976.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965.</persname>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Schweitzer Miller, Rhena.</persname>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Humanists.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Missionaries, Medical.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Missions -- Gabon.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Missions, Medical -- Gabon.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Organists.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Philosophers.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Theologians.</subject>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Gabon -- Description and travel.</geogname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Lambaréné (Moyen-Ogooué, Gabon)</geogname>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Essays.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Lectures.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Notebooks.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Sermons.</genreform>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Missionaries.</occupation>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Musicians.</occupation>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Physicians.</occupation>
<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Theologians.</occupation>
</controlaccess>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use Restrictions</head>
<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
<p>Albert Schweitzer Papers, <lb/> &su_name;</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchased, in part, by Library Associates from Rhena Schweitzer Miller.</p>
<p>The bulk of the notebooks and the correspondence with both Hélène Schweitzer and Rhena Schweitzer were purchased from Rhena Schweitzer Miller with funds provided by Syracuse University Library Associates. Additional letters and notebooks, Albert Schweitzer's early papers, and the Nikos Kazantzakis manuscripts are the gift of Rhena Schweitzer Miller.</p>
<p>Copies of Schweitzer's letters to Rudolf Bultmann, an original letter to Hauptverband Baumwollindustrie Frankfurt, a map of Lambaréné, and an Erica Anderson portrait of Albert Schweitzer are the gift of Antje Bultmann Lemke.</p>
<p>A letter to Mrs. Otto A. Pokorny and an autograph portrait of Albert Schwietzer are the gift of Mrs. Carl H. Grathwol.</p><p>Letters to Irving Townsend, Columbia Records gift of Elizabeth Nestor, 2009.</p>
<p>The William P. Tolley Endowed Library Fund supported the purchase of concert program notes and a printed autograph portrait of Albert Schweitzer.</p>

<p>The mahogany box bearing Schweitzer's inscription is the gift of Kimberlee T. Knauf.</p>

</acqinfo>

<!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
      <head>Appraisal Information</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
    </appraisal>-->
<!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
      <head>Accruals</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
    </accruals>-->
<dsc type="combined">
<head>Inventory</head>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Correspondence/subject files</unittitle>
</did>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>American Leprosy Mission</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="currierrp">Currier, Raymond P.</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
 <did>
<unittitle>Anderson, Erica</unittitle>
</did>

<c03><did><unittitle>Inventory of Erica Anderson correspondence</unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950/965">1950-1965</unitdate><physdesc><extent>18 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">1</container></did><note>
<p>See also Writings: <ref target="scripts">Scripts</ref>
</p>
</note></c03></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Avey, Clarence F.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1946/1965">1946-1965</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Boegner, Alfred</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1905-07-09">July 9, 1905</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Bresslau, Harry</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1911-12-22">Dec. 22, 1911</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Bresslau, Hélène</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="schweitzerh">Schweitzer, Hélène</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Bultmann, Antje</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1931-10-11">Oct. 11, 1931</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Bultmann, Rudolf</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1929">1929, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Christian Medical Council for Overseas Work</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="humee">Hume, Edward</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Columbia Records (Irving Townsend)</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Courboin, Charles N.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1946-12-28">Dec. 28, 1946</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 id="currierrp">
<did>
<unittitle>Currier, Raymond P.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956-05-12">May 12, 1956</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Dahlberg, Edwin T.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945-04-23">Apr. 23, 1945</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Eckert, Rhena</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="schweitzerr">Schweitzer, Rhena</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Ehretsmann, Louisa</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See Memorabilia: <ref target="cbo">Correspondence by others</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Louisa</unittitle>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Evangelical Women's Union</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="pokornymoa">Pokorny, Mrs. Otto A.</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hagedorn, Hermann</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944">1944, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">n.d.</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hauptverband der Baumwollindustrie Frankfurt</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Heuss-Knapp, Elly</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Hill, Jerome</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See Writings: <ref target="scripts">Scripts</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 id="humee">
<did>
<unittitle>Hume, Edward</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942/1944">1942-1944</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Kennedy, John F.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>New South Wales Peace Committee</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962-07-15">July 15, 1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 id="pokornymoa">
<did>
<unittitle>Pokorny, Mrs. Otto A.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933-06-11">June 11, 1933</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Riedert, J.</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1906-03-14">Mar. 14, 1906</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Ross, Emory</unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>17 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1965">1941-1965</unitdate>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 id="schweitzerh">
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Hélène</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Selected list of correspondence</unittitle>
<container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>

<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1906">1901-1906</unitdate>
<physdesc><extent>9 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">2</container>
</did>
</c03><c03><did>
<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>

<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1907/1913">1907-1913</unitdate>
<physdesc><extent>9 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">3</container>
</did></c03><c03><did>
<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>

<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1919/1939">1919-1939</unitdate>
<physdesc><extent>20 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">4</container>
</did></c03>
</c02>


<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Louis</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See Memorabilia: <ref target="cbo">Correspondence by others</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Louisa</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See Memorabilia: <ref target="cbo">Correspondence by others</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 id="schweitzerr">
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Rhena</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Selected list of correspondence</unittitle>
<container type="Box">5</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle></unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>31 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1925/1965">1925-1965</unitdate>
<container type="Box">5</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Steinwascher, Rolf</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Urquhart, Clara</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962-05-12">May 12, 1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">5</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Von Halen, Luise</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See Memorabilia: <ref target="cbo">Correspondence by others</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Von Schubert, Margaret - recipient</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See Memorabilia: <ref target="cbo">Correspondence by others</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Dear Friend"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1908-06-10">June 10, 1908</unitdate>
<container type="Box">5</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Re: request for medical supplies</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate>
<container type="Box">5</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Books</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle><emph render="italic">More from the Primeval Forest</emph></unittitle>
<abstract>working copy with notes for revision and photographs</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Essays</unittitle>
</did>
<c03 id="friedeoa">
<did>
<unittitle>"Friede oder Atomkrieg"</unittitle>
</did>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Erster Appell: Verzicht auf Versuchsexplosionen"</unittitle>
</did>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript</unittitle>
<abstract>autograph</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Holograph notes</unittitle>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript</unittitle>
<abstract>English translation</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript with notes</unittitle>
<abstract>French translation</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Zweiter Appell: Die Gefahr eines Atomkrieges"</unittitle>
</did>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript with notes</unittitle>
<abstract>4 copies, one bearing a signature</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript with notes</unittitle>
<abstract>French translation</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Dritter Appell: Verhandlungen auf höchster Ebene"</unittitle>
</did>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript with notes</unittitle>
<abstract>4 copies, one bearing a signature</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
<c05>
<did>
<unittitle>Typescript with notes</unittitle>
<abstract>French translation</abstract>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c05>
</c04>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Für Japan"</unittitle>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Für Reform des Orgelbaus"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Die Geziehungen zwischen und farbigen Rassen"</unittitle>
<container type="Box">6</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Jesus und wir"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1906-01-23">Jan. 23, 1906</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Los von Unmenschlichkeit, los von Atomwaffen"</unittitle>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Nachtrag zu 'Orgelbaukunst'"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1927-02">Feb. 1927</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Paix ou Guerre Atomique"</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="friedeoa">"Friede oder Atomkrieg"</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Peace or Atomic War"</unittitle>
<note>
<p>See <ref target="friedeoa">"Friede oder Atomkrieg"</ref>
</p>
</note>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Von Neuen Testament"</unittitle>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Notebooks</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>names, addresses, schedules, notes for lectures</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1918/1919">1918-1919</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise Herbst 1921 Reise Schweiz"</unittitle>
<abstract>diary of the Switzerland trip</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise nach Schweden Herbst 1921"</unittitle>
<abstract>diary of a concert and lecture tour through Sweden</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>names, addresses, memory aids, timetables, income tax calculations</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Concert-r[?] Vortragsreise Schweden. Januar - April 1922 Reise Schweden-Berlin-Paris-England - Schweden"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the concert and lecture tour</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise England Früjahr 1922"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on programs, organs and people during a concert tour of England</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Tournée in Dänemark Herbst 1922"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes about lectures, sermons, concerts and organs; remarks about people and accommodations; plans for a trip to Germany</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; comments about people, organizations, and contributors</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; comments about people in England, Ireland, Canada and the United States</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise nach Prag und München Januar 1923"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from a concert tour to Prague</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; notes on construction, medical problems, supplies needed for Africa; comments on book reviews</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Afrikareise Februar 1924"</unittitle>
<abstract>detailed description of the trip from Bordeaux to Africa; addresses; notes on medical issues</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1924">1924</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise Schweden Herbst 27, Reise Dänemark Herbst 27 Rückkehr durch Deutschland Herbst 27"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on a concert tour through Sweden and Denmark</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise Holland September 1927 Reise nach England September 1927"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on a concert tour through the Netherlands and England</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
<container type="Box">7</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Concerte Schweiz Herbst 1928"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; descriptions of programs and organs on a concert tour through Switzerland</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Concertreise Deutschland Herbst 1928"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; descriptions of programs and organs on a concert and lecture tour through Germany</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise Holland Früjahr 28, Reise England Früjahr 28, Rückkehr durch Holland Früjahr 28"</unittitle>
<abstract>descriptions of programs and organs; notes about people; addresses</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1928"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes about lectures and concerts in the Netherlands and England; poems; hymns; addresses; royalty statements; notes on tropical diseases; a list of lectures given at the University of Strassburg from 1902 to 1912</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Concert und Vortrage Reisen in Elsass und Deutschland 1929_Januar bis Juni"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on programs, organs, people and accommodations; timetables; information about distribution of donations</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Strassbourg - Lambaréné Nov.-Dec. 1929"</unittitle>
<abstract>baggage list; addresses; expenses; notes during the voyage to Africa</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1929"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on daily events, incoming letters, and organs; poems; lists of books, clothing, medical supplies and potential personnel for Lambaréné; recipes; thoughts on the Apostle Paul</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Comm[andes] médicam[ents] Hôpital Schweitzer 1930-1951"</unittitle>
<abstract>orders for medicine, medical instruments, and books</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930/1951">1930-1951</unitdate>
<container type="Box">8</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1930"</unittitle>
<abstract>hospital accounts; supplies; names; addresses; comments about people who have applied to work at the hospital; clippings; quotes; jokes</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Therapeudische Notizen"</unittitle>
<abstract>medical notes</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1931"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on hospital business matters; clippings; quotes; abstracts of letters; notes on the history of the church in Günsbach; plans for future lecture tours</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"1932 April Reise Holland Früjahr"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on a concert and lecture tour through the Netherlands</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"England Früjahr 1932"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; comments on people, concerts and lectures; notes on the conferring of an honorary doctorate at Oxford</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Paris - Berlin 1932 12 Nov."</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; appointments; notes about a meeting with Gerhard Hauptmann and Albert Einstein</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Vorträge und Konzerte 1932 Deutschland"</unittitle>
<abstract>lists of individuals and associations to be invited to concerts</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1932"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on salaries for doctors; travel notes from Germany, France, Switzerland, the Netherlands and Scotland; remarks on concerts and interviews; some family research; a list of expenditures; thoughts on the Goethe centennial; ideas on philosophy; plans for meetings with Ina Seidel, Widor, Einstein, Gerhard Hauptmann and Cosima Wagner</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage à Paris 25_II_1933, 17 Avril 1934, 6_VII_1934"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes, names and addresses from the concert tour to Paris. (The page following the entries for April 18 and 19, 1933 has a note written by Marcel Dupréon which Schweitzer has written "for Rhena Schweitzer - autograph of Marcel Dupré.")</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933/1934">1933-1934</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"IVe Voyage à Lambaréné avec Brazza-Afrique 18 Marz - 22 April 1933"</unittitle>
<abstract>diary of the 4th Africa voyage, including expenses, events, and addresses for letters of thanks</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Listes des malades pour lesquelles il y a à établir une facture 1931"</unittitle>
<abstract>a list of patients who had been billed in 1931; notes on Chinese and Indian languages</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1933"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes for the upcoming trip to Africa; remarks on books and lectures; quotes; poems; accounts; addresses with personal comments; list of birthdays of the Schweitzer family; a speech in Latin for Oxford University; technical notes on organs and medicine</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage en Angleterre octobre 1934"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, schedule and notes from the concert tour to England and France</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Anfragen für Concerte Vorlesungen und Vorträge in England, zussamengestellt Reiseheften und Briefen - dazu Adressen"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses from England, with inquiries about and invitations for concerts and lectures</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; book and medical supply orders; notes on philosophy and language; memoranda about lectures, medical treatments, and a planned trip to England; newspaper clippings; poems; an abstract of a letter from Mendelssohn</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
<container type="Box">9</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Vorträge in Schweiz Januar 1935"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from a lecture tour through Switzerland, with themes, appointments, addresses, and a list of donations</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Départ pour Lambaréné. Docteur 5 février 1935"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the 5th voyage to Africa, with a baggage list</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage en Angleterre - Herbst 1935 - Gifford - lectures II"</unittitle>
<abstract>plans for the trip to England; notes; addresses; technical information about organs; notes on concerts and lectures; clippings; quotes; poems; lists of purchases and orders; names of candidates for Lambaréné; a list of recordings; a review of the year 1936</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voage[sic] Lambaréné - Lausanne aôut-septembre 1935"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the 5th voyage to Africa, with a baggage list</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Diary from the 5th voyage to Africa, and from the voyage to Europe;</unittitle>
<abstract>Addresses; comments about books; clippings; poems; notes on personnel matters; technical details about organs; thoughts on the philosophy of civilization; plans for future lecture tours</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Vorträge + Konzerte Schweiz April - Mai 1936"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on programs, itinerary, and participating conductors and organizers; addresses; expenses of the concert and lecture tour through Switzerland</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on concerts and lectures; clippings; quotes; poems; lists of purchases and orders; names of candidates for Lambaréné; technical details about organs; a list of recordings; a review of the year 1936</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Sur succession des ----- -----"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on preparations for the 6th voyage to Africa; addresses; comments on correspondence; quotes; poems; thoughts about philosophy; a diary of the voyage</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage sur --- Foucauld, Bordeaux-Port Gentil. Départ Afrique avec Foucauld (ancièn) 29_I_1937"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes made on the 6th voyage to Africa, including names of the crew and a detailed baggage list</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Uber werk bei --------"</unittitle>
<abstract>diary from Lambaréné, including medical issues, personnel matters, addresses; information about donations; plans for the upcoming trip to Europe; a review of the year 1938</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"2 voyages. Voyage de retour Lambaréné - Günsbach janvier 1939 sur Asie (11_1 - 2_2_39) et retour Lambaréné 14_2_39"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on the two voyages; baggage list</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from two voyages (to and from Europe) and from a sojourn in Alsace, including information about supplies ordered; poems; notes on correspondence; clippings; lists of contributors; comments about the imminent outbreak of war in Europe</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Calculs de la déclarations de l'impôt sur la revenu"</unittitle>
<abstract>customs forms; lists of supplies</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1955">1940-1955</unitdate>
<container type="Box">10</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; notes on correspondence, medical and personnel matters; expenditures; remarks about the war, including an extensive description of the 20 day seige of Lambaréné</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Cahier des Editeurs 1941_1942_1943_1944_1953"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses of editors, with notes about financial agreements</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1944">1941-1944, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; a description of life at Lambaréné, including Hélène Schweitzer's arrival; quotes; recipes; notes on personnel matters; remarks about astronomy and gardening</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Medizinische Notizen Heft III"</unittitle>
<abstract>medical notes 1942 list of hospital personnel; poems; quotes; recipes; notes on medical issues; addresses, with comments about people; a review of the year 1942</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>list of hospital personnel; poems; quotes; recipes; reminiscences; addresses, with comments about people; thoughts about religion; clippings; a review of the year 1943</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on daily events; addresses; recipes; personnel matters; quotes; remarks about the American capture of Strassburg; comments about a will; a review of the year 1944</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on daily events at Lambaréné; comments about the end of the war; notes on correspondence</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Déclaration de Revenues 1946_1947_1948_1949_1950_1951_1952_1953_1954"</unittitle>
<abstract>income tax returns</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1946/1954">1946-1954</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Medizinische Notizen Heft IV"</unittitle>
<abstract>medical notes 1946 addresses; excerpts from correspondence; poems; recipes; notes about Jean Paul Sartre and about the Strassbourg-Basel railroad line; lecture notes; clippings; a review of the year 1946</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1946/1950">1946-1950</unitdate>
<container type="Box">11</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"11 Adresses importants 21 lettres à ecrire"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses and notes about correspondence to be answered</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1948">1947-1948, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1954">1953-1954</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; notes on books; quotes; poems; clippings; comments about construction projects at Lambaréné</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Reise Schweiz 2_11_48"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, with comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes about daily events and politics; addresses; comments about people and correspondence; historical dates in African history; history of the Schweitzer family; poems; lecture invitations; concert programs</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage en Amérique 22_6_49"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; comments about people; and other notes from the U.S. trip</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage en Amérique 22_6_1949 Günsbach Alsace"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes about the U.S. trip; lists of addresses</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Scandinavie-Hollande 8_9_1949"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes about the trip through Scandinavia and the Netherlands; addresses; timetables; comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Paris octobre 1949"</unittitle>
<abstract>short notes; addresses from the trip to Paris</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Départ 28 octobre 1949 Brazza pour Lambaréné"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; short notes</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Suisse 1949"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, with comments about people; other notes from the trip to Switzerland</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Daily events in Alsace</unittitle>
<abstract>notes about Bach and Goethe in preparation for the U.S. trip; addresses; poems; quotes; excerpts from letters; comments on books</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>A diary from Lambaréné</unittitle>
<abstract>including comments on greetings for Schweitzer's 75th birthday; names of candidates for Lambaréné; quotes; clippings; historical notes; recipes; a list of authors and actors banned from East Germany</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Lambaréné-Günsbach par Foucauld quittant Bordeaux le 19 juin 51"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the trip to Europe, including addresses; a list of baggage; a detailed description of the voyage</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Frankfurt 16_9_51"</unittitle>
<abstract>mostly a list of addresses</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Paris 22_9_51"</unittitle>
<abstract>short notes on schedules and people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>A diary from Lambaréné,</unittitle>
<abstract>including notes about medical issues, politics, and religion; excerpts from letters about book and recording contracts; comments about the Albert Schweitzer Fellowship; clippings; various notes from the trip to Europe</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
<container type="Box">12</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Bordeaux - Lambaréné sur Foucauld. Départ 28_11_52"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes form the voyage, including information about people, addresses, and a list of baggage</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Lambaréné - Alsace par Foucauld 5-23 juillet 1952"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the voyage, including a list of baggage, the names of the crew</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Liste der im Jahre 1952 beantworteten Briefe"</unittitle>
<abstract>a list of letters answered in 1952</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Paris 1952"</unittitle>
<abstract>names; addresses; comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on daily events; orders; excerpts from books; poems; timetables; comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Medizinische Notizen"</unittitle>
<abstract>medical notes</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; notes about daily events at Lambaréné and in the world; quotes; notes on medical issues and personnel matters; orders; comments about correspondence. Also included are Schweitzer's comments about the message from the Nobel committee notifying him of his selection as recipient of the Peace Prize</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"cahiers spéciaux des calculs des Revenus en: 1954_1955_1956_1957_1958_1959_1960_1961_1962_1963_1964_1965."</unittitle>
<abstract>a list of income by year</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954/1965">1954-1965</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Affaire Réduction Impôts des Français en USA à 15% calculs à présenter lettre Paris 18 sept."</unittitle>
<abstract>records of income in the United States</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954/1958">1954-1958</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Oslo 1954"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Général LeClerc - Voyage Günsbach - Lambaréné. Embarquement 10 déc. 1954. Port-Gentil 27 déc. 54"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the voyage, including a list of baggage 1955 "Voyage Angleterre automne 1955" addresses, with comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Paris automne 1955"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the trip to Paris and Switzerland</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Cahier 1955" an extensive diary, including poems, reminiscences, notes about medical issues and incoming letters</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
<container type="Box">13</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notes médicales 1956_1957_1958. Et Esquires de Commandes"</unittitle>
<abstract>orders for medical supplies</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1958">1956-1958</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Commandes et envois de sont genre attendées et arrivés"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, with comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>extensive diary with personal thoughts and poems</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Lambaréné - Bordeaux sur Brazza 2-20 aôut 1957"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes from the voyage to Europe, including addresses; a list of baggage</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Bordeaux - Lambaréné déc. 1957 Brazza"</unittitle>
<abstract>travel documents; a baggage list</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Lambaréné 1957"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, with comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyages en 1957"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, with comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses, with comments about people; notes on daily events and personnel matters; clippings with notes about atomic testing issues; financial records; excerpts from correspondence</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
<container type="Box">14</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Devant liste des lettres pressées"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; excerpts from correspondence; a list of exchange rates for various currencies</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958/1959">1958-1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; excerpts from correspondence; notes on daily events</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>extensive notebook from Lambaréné, with clippings; comments on current events and history; notes on personnel and patients; poems; excerpts from correspondence</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage en Europe de aôut à fin novembre"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; schedule; a list of baggage; comments about people and accommodations</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Voyage Bordeaux - Port Gentil sur Général Leclerc 9 dec.-27 dec. 1959"</unittitle>
<abstract>a list of baggage; some comments on people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Cahier 1959"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; clippings with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notices 1959"</unittitle>
<abstract>clippings, with comments on a wide variety of subjects</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">15</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Zeitungsnachrichten und gedanken über Atom problem"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on world events; clippings, with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">16</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on daily events; addresses, with comments about people</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">16</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>(cover missing) clippings, with a few comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
<container type="Box">16</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses; comments about people and contributions</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
<container type="Box">17</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>mostly clippings, with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
<container type="Box">17</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Atom. nouvelles sur la question"</unittitle>
<abstract>clippings, with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate>
<container type="Box">17</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Cahier 1961"</unittitle>
<abstract>clippings, with comments; quotes; poems</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate>
<container type="Box">17</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Lettres et affaires 1961"</unittitle>
<abstract>some clippings; notes on correspondence</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate>
<container type="Box">17</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Ausschnitte in Atomsachen 1962"</unittitle>
<abstract>clippings, with comments, mostly concerning nuclear testing and the Cuban Missile Crisis</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">17</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Cahier 1962"</unittitle>
<abstract>mostly clippings, with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"1) Courrier 1962 2) Notices sur affaires 1962"</unittitle>
<abstract>notes on correspondence; a list of expenses</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch für Hosentasche"</unittitle>
<abstract>addresses with comments about people; contributions</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Lettres envoyés 1963"</unittitle>
<abstract>a list of letters answered</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Nouvelles et notices Notizbuch"</unittitle>
<abstract>clippings, with comments covering a variety of subjects</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Atom Waffen Sachen und Politik"</unittitle>
<abstract>clippings, with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Taschen Notizbuch"</unittitle>
<abstract>daily events; notes on correspondence and donations</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Notizbuch 1965"</unittitle>
<abstract>a few clippings, with comments</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>[untitled]</unittitle>
<abstract>mostly clippings, with comments; a few addresses</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate>
<container type="Box">18</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Medizinische Notizen Heft II"</unittitle>
<abstract>medical notes</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">19</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Medicaments Suisse"</unittitle>
<abstract>list of medication available from Swiss medical supply firms</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">19</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Medicaments USA"</unittitle>
<abstract>list of medication available from U.S. medical supply firms</abstract>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">19</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Program notes</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Draft of program notes for November 28, 1920 organ concert at Fraümunster, Zürich</unittitle>
<abstract>holograph manuscript, printed program, and English translation</abstract>
<container type="Box">20</container></did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="scripts">
<did>
<unittitle>Scripts</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Albert Schweitzer"</unittitle>
<abstract>a film biography</abstract>
</did>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Notes for director Jerome Hill</unittitle>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Shooting scripts with notes</unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>3 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Skizzen des Film, notizen für Erica"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953-10-26">Oct. 26, 1953</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Text zu den Bildern"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">Dec. 1954</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Text zu den Günsbachszenen"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Text zu den szenen in Günsbach"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Miscellaneous notes</unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>3 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c04>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Sermons</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Lambaréné</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930-06-22/1930-09-28">Jun. 22-Sept. 28, 1930</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Short Story</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Moderne Berufe - der Wanzenzüchter"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Goethe als Denker und Mensch"</unittitle>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Message pour la centenaire/ de deBrazza/ de la naissance fêté à Alger le 15 fevrier "</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Der Stromschnellen-Fetisch von Theodor Steimen"</unittitle>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Meddelanden från Professor Albert Schweitzer"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1928">1928, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Notes on atomic weapons testing and disarmament</unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>9 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">20</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle>
</did>

<c02><did><unittitle>Selected list of memorabilia</unittitle><container type="Box">21</container></did></c02><c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Artwork</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Watercolor painting "Le Docteur Schweitzer et Monsieur Eckert devant la maison à Gunsbach" by Gloria Coolidge</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>2 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903">1903, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1910">1910, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02>
<did>
<unittitle>Concert programs and schedules</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1912">1912, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1928">1928, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1929">1929, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries" id="cbo">
<did>
<unittitle>Correspondence by others</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Louis to Hélène Bresslau</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1912-03-13">Mar. 13, 1912</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Schweitzer, Louisa to Hélène Schweitzer</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1926-12-28">Dec. 28, 1926</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Von Halen, Luise to Margaret Von Schubert</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Manuscripts by others</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Les Deux Frères" by Nikos Kazantzakis</unittitle>
<abstract>autograph typescript (2 copies)</abstract>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Portraits of Albert Schweitzer</unittitle>
</did>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>"Night Rounds" by Erica Anderson, and bearing her signature</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Lambaréné, with Albert Schweitzer signature</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Printed portraits (2), each with Albert Schweitzer signature</unittitle>
<physdesc>
<extent>2 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Portraits (4), no signatures</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Portrait of Schweitzer mounted with scene of Lambaréné, by Erica Anderson, and bearing her signature</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c04>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
</did>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Scenes of Lambaréné</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c04>
<c04>
<did>
<unittitle>Printed portrait of Carl Ludwig Schleich with holograph note by Albert Schweitzer</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c04>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Printed material</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Contrepoint et Harmonie" A. Dommel-Diény</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>"Mission du Congo Français sur les Rives de l'Ogooué" inscribed "À ma fille Rhéna. Albert Schweitzer Lambarènè"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961-06-28">28_6_1961</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
<c02 level="subseries">
<did>
<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
</did>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Class schedules from Strassburg</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1906/1908">1906-1908, </unitdate>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1965">undated</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>List of students and their fees</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Map of Lambaréné with Albert Schweitzer signature</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Pi Kappa Lambda membership certificate and pin</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Themes for the theological "Staatsexamen"</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1896">1896</unitdate>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Miscellany</unittitle>
<container type="Box">21</container>
</did>
</c03>
<c03>
<did>
<unittitle>Mahogany box inscribed "avec mes bonnes pensées Albert Schweitzer"</unittitle>
<container type="Oversize">1</container>
</did>
</c03>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
