<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 1.11, 17 Oct 2008--><!--Revised standard blurb for related material -->
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="shevchik_j" mainagencycode="NSyU">shevchik_j</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">John Shevchik Cartoons</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of his cartoons at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">–</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
          <lb/></publisher>&su_address;
        <date encodinganalog="Date" normal="1971">1971</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>MD
            
        
        <date normal="2008-11-5">5 Nov 2008</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"-->
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>5 Nov 2008 - converted to EAD (MD)</item>
        <item>11 Nov 2009 - added detailed bio, scope and added subjects to inventory (SK)</item>
        
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
        <lb/> &su_address;</repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Shevchik, John</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">John Shevchik Cartoons</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1959/1971" type="inclusive">1959-1971</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent>4.1 linear ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Over 1200 original editorial cartoons.</abstract>
      <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">2644641</unitid>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>John Shevchik (1915-1994) was an American editorial cartoonist for the Beaver Falls (Pa.) 
        
        <emph render="italic">News-Tribune</emph>. </p>
      <p>John Shevchik was born on August 23, 1915 in Beaver Falls, Pennsylvania. His father was a carpenter and Shevchik had no formal art training. However, he was friends with and influenced by cartoonist Cy Hungerford of the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Pittsburgh Post Gazette</emph> .  In the 1930s, Shevchik worked at the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Pittsburgh Post Gazette</emph> and left for World War II service with the 816th Engineering Unit of the United States Army where he gained drawing experience. Following the war, Shevchik worked in the capacities of artist and cartoonist for several greater Pittsburgh area newspapers including the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Daily Citizen</emph> in Ambridge, Pennsylvania. </p>
      <p>In 1954, Shevchik became editorial cartoonist for the Beaver Falls 
        
        <emph render="italic">News Tribune</emph> where he worked until 1979 when the paper was purchased by the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Beaver  County Times</emph>. Then Shevchik began drawing weekly cartoons for the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Valley Tribune</emph>, serving portions of Beaver County, Pennsylvania. </p>
      <p>Shevchik was a member of the American Association of Editorial Cartoonists and was also known as “Shevy”. He received over a dozen Freedoms Foundation awards and his work in promoting highway safety was recognized by the National Safety Council who presented him with their first place award in 1954 and also an honorable mention in 1961. His work appeared in the 
        
        <emph render="italic">Best Editorial Cartoons of the Year</emph> series and he also edited an anthology of Cy Hungerford's World War II cartoons (1985).</p>
      <p>John Shevchik died in 1994. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The 
        
        <emph render="bold">John Shevchik Cartoons</emph> contains  1,203 original editorial cartoons published in the Beaver Falls (Pa.) 
        
        <emph render="italic">News-Tribune</emph> from approximately 1959-1971.</p>
      <p>Most of Shevchik’s cartoons address national and international events. Several involving coal mining and the steel industry would have had possible implications for his local audience. </p>
      <p>Like other cartoonists during this period, Shevchik’s subject matter was frequently dominated by the Vietnam War as President Lyndon Johnson escalated the war. However, Shevchik regularly commented on the increasing number of war casualties and framed the casualties in comparison to the number of highway traffic fatalities and also noted how many of the soldiers lacked voting rights because they were under the age of 21 (for example, see “He’s Not Old Enough to Vote”).  </p>
      <p>Regular themes and imagery include skeletons representing casualties (from the war, automobile accidents and nuclear fallout), leaders focusing on solving jigsaw puzzles comprised of world problems, leaders as fishermen, Lyndon Johnson as a struggling soldier in Vietnam, giant metaphorical smoldering bombs and U. Thant looking out of the United Nations building at various world problems. </p>
      <p>Several of the cartoons in the collection bear the same caption.  Shevchik also produced cartoons about different subjects but with very similar visual imagery and variations of the same theme. Some of these appear to be close versions of the same cartoon while others feature the same composition but with different figures or labels. An example of the latter are cartoons about John F. Kennedy and Lyndon B. Lyndon Johnson’s presidential inaugurations. The cartoon entitled, “JFK's Top Hat” depicts John F. Kennedy’s inauguration top hat as a replacement for the dome of the U.S Capitol. After Johnson's inauguration, a similar cartoon appeared with his cowboy hat atop the Capitol.</p>
      <p>Heavily covered subject matter includes the escalation and cost of the Vietnam War and Richard Nixon’s effort to scale down the war, problems between the U.N. and Nikita Khrushchev who failed to pay U.N. dues, the rejection of China in the U.N. and the Berlin Wall. Shevchik also often evoked the statements of George Washington and Abraham Lincoln to comment on civil rights and the United States' intervention and alliances in foreign affairs. </p>
      <p>Shevchik made extensive use of labels to annotate his cartoons which rarely contained dialogue. These labels often identified people and visual representations of issues. At times he also mentioned specific news items or statistics, such as those involving Vietnam war casualties.</p>
      <p>None of the cartoons are dated. Shevchik drew the cartoons on paper primarily with ink with some crayon shading. Traces of pencil are visible. Captions appear in pencil at the top. Dimensions listed in the inventory are approximate.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>Cartoons are arranged alphabetically by caption.  Please note that the cartoons are not dated, so the time period covered by the cartoons was estimated from subject material.
</p>
    </arrangement>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>&scrc_name; has collections of over one hundred cartoonists.  Please refer to &subjindex; for a complete listing.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
         <head>Separated Material</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
      </separatedmaterial>-->
      
      <!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
         <head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
      </otherfindaid>-->
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
      <!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc). Some have 
defaults set in the template.-->
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Art -- Cartoonists</subject>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Ho Chi Minh, 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Shevchik, John</persname>
      <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">United States. Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.</corpname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">American wit and humor, Pictorial.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cartoonists -- Pennsylvania.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cartoonists -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Civil rights movements -- United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Editorial cartoons -- United States.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Editorial cartoons -- Pennsylvania.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Inflation -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Space exploration -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Strikes and lockouts -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Traffic fatalities -- Caricatures and cartoons. </subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">War casualties -- Caricatures and cartoons.</subject>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">China -- Politics and government, 1949-1976 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</geogname>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Soviet Union -- Politics and government, 1945-1991 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</geogname>
      <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government, 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.</geogname>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Cartoons (humorous images)</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Editorial cartoons.</genreform>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Cartoonists.</occupation>
    </controlaccess>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
materials in this collection.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>John Shevchik Cartoons, 
        
        <lb/> &su_name; </p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Gift of 
        
        <persname role="donor">John Shevchik</persname>, 1970.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
         <head>Appraisal Information</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
      </appraisal>-->
      
      <!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
      </accruals>-->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Inventory</head>
      <!--C01 @LEVEL must be set to 'series' to show up in TOC.-->
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Cartoons</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1959/1971" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent>1203 items</extent>
            <dimensions>11 1/4" x 13 1/4"</dimensions>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>A</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Academic Freedom Spanking: college students, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>Accenting the Positive: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
African Ghost: Patrice Lumumba, Nikita Khrushchev, United Nations, Congo
              
              <lb/>
African Storm Clouds: Congo, Algeria, United Nations, U. Thant
              
              <lb/>
After Such an Anxious Time: space exploration 
              
              <lb/>
After Year of $000,000,000: United Nations, Indonesia, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Ageless Figure of Freedom: Abraham Lincoln, Gettysburg Address (1966)
              
              <lb/>
Air Pirates Storm: hijacking 
              
              <lb/>
Alabama Classroom: integration, Alabama, George Wallace
              
              <lb/>
Alabama Freedom March: voting, Alabama, Abraham Lincoln
              
              <lb/>
Alabama's Tidal Wave: integration, George Wallace, Alabama
              
              <lb/>
All Set to Go: Great Society, Congress, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Alliance for Progress Sharp Blow: Argentina, oil 
              
              <lb/>
America's Second Moon Landing: space exploration, Russia, Alexey Kosygin
              
              <lb/>
American Combat Deaths Down: Vietnam War, Richard Nixon, peace
              
              <lb/>
American Dream Again: Richard Nixon, elections
              
              <lb/>
American Way ("Dick" and "Jack"): Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
American Way (Freedom Foundation Cartoon): religion
              
              <lb/>
Ancient Old Flame: Christmas
              
              <lb/>
And an Angel Appeared Out of a Cloud: Lyndon Johnson, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
And I Mean It: Fidel Castro, Cuba, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
And Now What?: nuclear weapons, China, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Annual Duel: hunting
              
              <lb/>
Another Awardee: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Another Big Flame: Congo, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Another Bomb Crisis: peace, Vietnam War, China
              
              <lb/>
Another Card Burner: China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Another Championship Fight: Lyndon Johnson, China, Vietnam War, Dominican Republic
              
              <lb/>
Another City Smear: civil rights, riots
              
              <lb/>
Another Ear Pulling Act: Hubert Humphrey, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Another Flare-Up in Saigon: police, Nguyen Khahn, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Another Headache: Cuba, Fidel Castro, Mig attacks
              
              <lb/>
Another Heart Transplant: Lyndon Johnson, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War, peace
              
              <lb/>
Another Hospital Case: Medicare, Congress, American Medical Association, Social Security
              
              <lb/>
Another Korea: Vietnam War, Korean War
              
              <lb/>
Another Length Burned Up: Dean Rusk, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War 
              
              <lb/>
Another Length Burned Up: Cuba, Soviet Union, Fidel Castro 
              
              <lb/>
Another Moon's Visitor: space exploration, Vietnam War, riots, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
Another Newspaper Burial: journalism, unions, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Another Shot at the United Nations: Congo, United Nations, Belgium
              
              <lb/>
Another Splitting Headache: Republican Party 
              
              <lb/>
Another Tragic Disaster: coal mining accident, West Virginia
              
              <lb/>
Another Wedding: steel industry, inflation, Lyndon Johnson, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Another World (world with a face drawn on it): World Series, national and international worries 
              
              <lb/>
Another World: World Series, national and international worries 
              
              <lb/>
Anxious Watchers: John F. Kennedy, Roosevelt, Lyndon Johnson, peace
              
              <lb/>
Any Bets: traffic fatalities, Christmas
              
              <lb/>
Any Future for You?: United Nations, nuclear weapons, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Any Real Answer in this Duel?: strikes, labor, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Any Site in Sight?: Lyndon Johnson, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War, peace
              
              <lb/> Anything in the Basket?: United Nations, U. Thant, Nikita Khrushchev, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Anything May Explode: ace relations, Haiti, John F. Kennedy, South America 
              
              <lb/>
Appeals to Reds to Cancel the Big Blast: nuclear weapons, Communism 
              
              <lb/>April Fool's Day Kick: United Nations, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Arab's Black Eye: Israel, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Middle East
              
              <lb/>
Armed Forces Day: armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Army Surplus Shoes: taxes, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
As He Sowed, so Shall He Reap: Israel, Adolf Eichmann, Holocaust
              
              <lb/>
As the Nation/ World Mourns: Dwight D. Eisenhower
              
              <lb/>
As the War Slogs On: Vietnam War, peace, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Asian Treadmill: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Auto-Safety Furor: auto industry, Congress
              
              <lb/>Avalanche Country: Jawaharlal Nehru, China
              
              <lb/>
Aviation's Worst Air Crash: Venezuela, aircraft accidents
              
              <lb/>
Axe Seat: taxes, John F. Kennedy  </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>B</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">	1	</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Baby Business is Still Good: birth rate, population
              
              <lb/>
Baby Needs a Woman's Touch: India, peace, Indira Ghandi
              
              <lb/>
Baby Play with Nice Bombs: nuclear weapons, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Back from his Fishing Trip: Communism, China, Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Back Home After His Global Tour: Richard Nixon, Asia
              
              <lb/>
Back of the new U.S. Ambassador: United Nations, Adlai  Stevenson, Arthur Goldberg
              
              <lb/>
Back to Geneva: disarmament, peace
              
              <lb/>
Back to Work: railroad industry, Lyndon Johnson, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Bad Day for Mama Eagle: armed forces,  college students
              
              <lb/>
Bad Easter Egg: Thomas Dodd, ethics, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Bag is Getting Bigger: crime
              
              <lb/>
Bait Stealing Champion: inflation, cost of living
              
              <lb/>
Barry's Whistlestop Train Like in '48: Barry Goldwater 
              
              <lb/>
Be Sure to Remember Santa: Congress, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Be Sure to Register: Medicare, Social Security
              
              <lb/>
Be Sure to Vote: voting
              
              <lb/>
Bear Went over the Mountain: Nikita Khrushchev, Cold War
              
              <lb/>
Bells Across the Nation Day: freedom, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Beatles of England are Here: The Beatles
              
              <lb/>
Beginning of a Great New Society: Great Society, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Begins his 8-Year Prison Term: Jimmy Hoffa 
              
              <lb/>
Behind and in Front: Boy Scouts
              
              <lb/>
Berlin Nightmare Showdown: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Berlin's Barrier and a Challenge: Nikita Khrushchev, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Better Talk Fast: Berlin, Andrei Gromyko, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Between Two Mountains: Congress, elections
              
              <lb/>
Beyond the Big Mountains (variation of Between Two Mountains): Congress
              
              <lb/>
Big Atomic Poker Game: John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Big Bag in Washington: budget, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Big Campaign Headache: foreign policy, voting
              
              <lb/>
Big Catch: Walter Reuther, United Auto Workers, auto industry
              
              <lb/>
Big Changes in Draft: Lyndon Johnson, draft
              
              <lb/>
Big Circus Act: Nikita Khrushchev, Cuba, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Big Cloud over the Week: Congo
              
              <lb/>
Big Communist Snub: China, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Big Confusion: Vietnam War, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Big Drop from the Moon: Nikita Khrushchev, Soviet Union, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Big Election Mystery: elections 
              
              <lb/>
Big Fire Against De Gaulle: Charles De Gaulle, Algeria
              
              <lb/>
Big French Race: Russia, China, Charles De Gaulle, NATO, Germany
              
              <lb/>
Big Handout: foreign aid
              
              <lb/>
Big Handouts and Insults: Gamal Abdel Nasser, Egypt, Congo
              
              <lb/>
Big Head Hunter: graduates (1962)
              
              <lb/>
Big Propaganda Echo: nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Big Race: Republican Party, Richard Nixon, Nelson Rockefeller, Hubert Humphrey, Eugene McCarthy, George Wallace, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Big Rainfall: civil rights, Lyndon Johnson, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Big Safety Problem: traffic fatalities, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Big Shadow on the Wall: United Nations, Soviet Union, U. Thant, peace
              
              <lb/>
Big Stake at Hand: economy, Congress, railroad industry, unions
              
              <lb/>
Big Stamp of Approval: auto industry, Congress, traffic fatalities
              
              <lb/>
Big Wild Waves: Indonesia, communism, Sukarno
              
              <lb/>
Big Wild Waves: Latin America, Cuba, trade, Panama, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Big Wind from the Kremlin: Andrei Gromyko, Adlai Stevenson, United Nations, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Biggest Rooter for the Protestors: demonstrations, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Bird in a Gilded Page: nuclear weapons, peace, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
Bird Nest: Lyndon Johnson, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Birth Control: population, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Birthstone for July: freedom, justice
              
              <lb/>
Bit by Bit: Vietnam War, China, Nguyen Khahn
              
              <lb/>
Black Eye: Medicare, Congress, Ted Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Black Eye: Lyndon Johnson, Republican Party, foreign policy, J. William Fulbright
              
              <lb/>
Black Eyes: race relations, Britain
              
              <lb/>
Blastoff: Lyndon Johnson, War on Poverty, Congress, Appalachia
              
              <lb/>
Blocking it Anywhere: communism, Fidel Castro, Dominican Republic
              
              <lb/>
Blossom Time: Charles De Gaulle, Europe
              
              <lb/>
Blowing his Steam: NATO, Charles De Gaulle, Germany, NATO
              
              <lb/>
Blowing the Bugle: World War II, Pearl Harbor (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Bluffing: China, India
              
              <lb/>
Bombers Must Go: Cuba, Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro, Cuban Missile Crisis
              
              <lb/>
$B,000,0000 — We Need It: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Book Worth Keeping: Abraham Lincoln, John F. Kennedy (1963)
              
              <lb/>
Bookworms About their Late Boss: John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Boomerang: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev, Dag Hammarskjold 
              
              <lb/>
Boots Lined Up for the Saddle: Republican Party, George W. Romney, Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller
              
              <lb/>
Bottom Fell Out!: George W. Romney, Republican Party, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Boys! It's Only Nikita Smoking a Cigar: John F. Kennedy, Cuba, Cuban missile crisis, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Boy, This is Keen Fun: Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater
              
              <lb/>
Breaking All Sales Record: auto industry (1962-1963)
              
              <lb/>
Breaking Through!: freedom, democracy, Russia, Czech
              
              <lb/>
Briefing in Washington: Vietnam War, Congress, Lyndon Johnson 
              
              <lb/>
Brinkmanship: NATO, nuclear weapons, Charles De Gaulle, France
              
              <lb/>
Broken Promises Needle: Nikita Khrushchev, Laos, Cuba, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Buck Teeth Threat: inflation, cost of living
              
              <lb/>
Bucking Bronco: budget, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Buddhists War Against Anti-Nguyen Cao Ky Drive: peace, Buddhists, Vietnam War, Nguyen Cao Ky
              
              <lb/>
Bulwark of Freedom: communism, religion, U.S. Constitution (Freedoms Foundation cartoon- published before Oct. 28th)
              
              <lb/>
Burglary Loot in the Nation: crime
              
              <lb/>
Burning Fuse and the Tick Tock: disarmament, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Burning Fuses: Laos, Cuba, communism
              
              <lb/>
Burning Fuses: Cuba, NATO, Algeria,  Berlin, Laos, Congo, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Burning Fuses: United Nations, Berlin, New Guinea, Cuba, Congo, Algeria, Africa 
              
              <lb/>
Bursting Bubble: Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller, George W. Romney, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Bursting Problems: United Nations, peace, Arthur Goldberg
              
              <lb/>
Bursting World: Lyndon Johnson 
              
              <lb/>
Business as Usual "Holiday Traffic Toll": traffic fatalities, holidays
              
              <lb/>
Business as Usual "New Year's Holiday Toll": traffic fatalities, holidays
              
              <lb/>
Business is Good: Fidel Castro, Cuba, trade
              
              <lb/>
Busy Bird with Nest Egg: United Nations, India, Pakistan, peace
              
              <lb/>
Busy Presidential Bees: Hubert Humphrey, Nixon, Nelson Rockefeller, Eugene McCarthy, elections
              
              <lb/>
Busy Undertaker: newspapers, journalism, New York, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Butcher Boys: Republican Party, Nixon, Nelson Rockefeller
              
              <lb/>
Buzzing Around: Lyndon Johnson, Wayne Morse, Vietnam War
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>C</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">	1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Calling for Peace: Pope Paul VI, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Calling for Your Support: charity
              
              <lb/>
Camel Cowboy's Rough Ride: Egypt, Lyndon Johnson, Gamal Abdel Nasser
              
              <lb/>
Can 200,000 Doctors be Wrong: Medicare
              
              <lb/>
Can Hit Fly in the Sky: Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Can I get into the Surplus Handout: farming, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Can I Use This:  government spending, taxes, budget
              
              <lb/>
Can't You Take My Word?: nuclear weapons, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev, John F. Kennedy, Harold Macmillan, Britain
              
              <lb/>
Car in Front: trucking industry, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Careful Navigation to Avoid Trouble: peace, armed forces, Britain
              
              <lb/>
Carrying the Bags: John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Carrying the Olive Branch: Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, Lyndon Johnson, peace, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Casting the Big Shadow: communism, armed forces, Vietnam. Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
Fidel Castro's Official Red Sign: Fidel Castro, peace, Cuba, communism
              
              <lb/>
Cat Came Back: Congress, election, Adam Clayton Powell
              
              <lb/>
Catch He Was Waiting For: Republican Party, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Caught in the Fire: Vietnam War, Great Society, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Caught in the Political Rivalry: Nguyen Cao Ky, Vietnam War, elections
              
              <lb/>
Ceiling Zero: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Challenge on Leadership: Charles De Gaulle, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Challenge on this Major Problem: Laos
              
              <lb/>
Challenged on Vietnam Peace Plans: Andrei Gromyko, Goldberg, United Nations, Vietnam War, Britain
              
              <lb/>
Changing World of Today: taxes, China, Soviet Union, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Chilly Diplomatic Weather: Andrei Gromyko, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Chef Wants a Cake Knife: taxes, Richard Nixon, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Chinese Attacks: China, Jawaharlal Nehru, Mao Zedong, India
              
              <lb/>
Chinese — French Honeymoon: Charles De Gaulle, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Chinese — Soviet Big Split: Communism, Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong, China,  Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Chopstick Trouble: Lyndon Johnson, peace, Vietnam War, China, Asia
              
              <lb/>
Christmas Package: Republican Party, elections
              
              <lb/>
Christmas Prayer: peace, Christmas
              
              <lb/>
Christmas in the Soviet: Nikita Khrushchev, farming, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Christopher Columbus: nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Chronic Pain in the Stomach: South America, Argentina, Juan Domingo Peron
              
              <lb/>
Churchill Farewell: Winston Churchill
              
              <lb/>
Clipping the Big Beard: Latin America, Fidel Castro, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Cocky Alabama Rooster: George Wallace, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Cloud and the Pick: mining, coal industry, strike
              
              <lb/>
Cloud over Santa: Congo, peace
              
              <lb/>
Cold Bird out on the Limb: Hubert Humphrey, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
Cold Wave in the Split Communist World: Mao Zedong, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, Russia, China
              
              <lb/>
Collective Leadership in Moscow: Chou, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Columbus Day ("Has America Changed?"): Columbus Day
              
              <lb/>
Columbus Day ("How the Place is  Bursting"):  United Nations, peace, Vietnam War, nuclear weapons, Middle East
              
              <lb/>
Columbus Day ("How the Place has Changed"): United Nations, inflation, cost of living
              
              <lb/>
Columbus Day ("It's an Entirely Different Sight"): United Nations, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Columbus Day ("Man in Space Progress"): space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Come and Have Fun with Me: graduates
              
              <lb/>
Comforting Hand: voting rights, Lyndon Johnson, Abraham Lincoln
              
              <lb/>
Communism Yule Spirit: Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Communism's Fire Eater: North Korea, Vietnam War, Laos, Cambodia, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Communist Birthday Party: Soviet Union, China, Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Communist Chef: Nikita Khrushchev, Ethiopia, Algeria, Congo, Laos
              
              <lb/>
Communist Clash: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, communism
              
              <lb/>
Communist Friendly Bedfellows: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, communism
              
              <lb/>
Communist Gains in Cuba?: Russia, Cuba, Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev, trade
              
              <lb/>
Communist Giants Battle: nuclear weapons, China, Russia, Mao Zedong, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
Communist Hijackers of the High Seas: Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Communist Propaganda Gimmick: peace, Vietnam War, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Communist Revolution Smoker: Fidel Castro, Dominican Republic
              
              <lb/>
Conflicts between the Communist Powers: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Confronting the Ball: John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Coronation in Rome: Pope Paul VI, peace
              
              <lb/>
Could I get a Nice Bomb: Ludwig Erhard, Lyndon Johnson, nuclear weapons, Britain, France, China, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Could it Really be True: Stalin, Nikita Khrushchev, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Counting Sheep: George Wallace, elections
              
              <lb/>
Counting the Sheep: Congress
              
              <lb/>
Covering up the Dirty Spots: peace, Christmas, Cuba, China, Congo, South America, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Crackdown on Health Sweetner: food and drugs
              
              <lb/>
Crackdown on the Motorcycle Gangs: law and order
              
              <lb/>
Crime Shadow: crime 
              
              <lb/>
Crisis in South Vietnam: Vietnam War. communism, Buddhists
              
              <lb/>
Crisis of Democracy: Greece, Constantine
              
              <lb/>
Critical Session: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev, Laos, Congo
              
              <lb/>
Crosses on a Hill: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Cuban Crisis: Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Cuban Revolution began its Tenth Year: Fidel Castro, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Cuban Santa: Fidel Castro, communism, South America
              
              <lb/>
Cutting the Split in Communism World: Soviet Union, Mao Zedong, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, China
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>D</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">	1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Danger Ahead: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, Congress, Medicare, education, poverty
              
              <lb/>
D-Day for Auto Safety: auto industry
              
              <lb/>
D-Day for College Men: draft, college students
              
              <lb/>
D-Day Twenty Years Ago: Europe, World War II
              
              <lb/>
Daily Air Raids: peace, Vietnam War, Ho Chi Minh
              
              <lb/>
Dan Cupid's Broken Arrow: Nelson Rockefeller, Republican Party, elections
              
              <lb/>
Dark Christmas: mining
              
              <lb/>
Dark Trail in Vietnam: McNamara, Vietnam War, communism
              
              <lb/>
Dead End: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Dear Santa: Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Death of a Salesman: peace, Vietnam War, communism
              
              <lb/>
Deaths in the Air: aircraft accidents
              
              <lb/>
Declaration of War: War on Poverty, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Democrat Nomination Fight: Robert F. Kennedy, Lyndon Johnson, Richard Nixon, Eugene McCarthy
              
              <lb/>
Deep in the Deep South: racial violence, segregation, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Deeper Population Problem: population
              
              <lb/>
Defense Secretary Roadwork: Ho Chi Minh, Robert McNamara, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
De Gaulle's Trip to Moscow: Charles De Gaulle, NATO, Alexey Kosygin, Europe
              
              <lb/>
Delicately Balanced Again: Dwight Eisenhower, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Depends How You Look at It: nuclear weapons, Russia, Cuba, Barry Goldwater, Congress
              
              <lb/>
De Gaulle's Napoleonic Illusions of Grandeur: Charles De Gaulle, Europe, Harold Macmillan, Britain, France
              
              <lb/>
Democrat Poll Vaulter Champ: Robert F. Kennedy, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Did it Hurt Again?: United Nations, China, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Dilemma for Soviet Foreign Policy: Middle East, United Nations, Alexey Kosygin, U. Thant, Arthur Goldberg, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Diplomatic Courtesy in Germany: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Do I Deserve Another Raise?: Congress
              
              <lb/>
Do I Hear a Noise?: Congress, civil rights
              
              <lb/>Doctor, Stay Away: foreign aid, Cambodia
              
              <lb/>
Dogs Are More Dangerous Politically than the World: Lyndon Johnson, animal rights
              
              <lb/>
Doing Holiday Business with the U.S.A.: Fidel Castro, John F. Kennedy, Cuba, Bay of Pigs
              
              <lb/>
Do Not Despair! Help is on the Way!: taxes, John F. Kennedy, economy
              
              <lb/>
Don't Ever Tell a U.S. Senator: Hubert Humphrey, Congress, Stuart Symington
              
              <lb/>
Don't Forget this Hot Dish: Bobby Baker, Republican Party, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Don't Get into this — It looks Dark: Charles De Gaulle, Harold Macmillan, common market
              
              <lb/>
Don't Get Space — Struck: science, space exploration, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Don't You Hear It — War Mongers: Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons 
              
              <lb/>
Dove of Peace "Eggs": Lyndon Johnson, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Dove or Hawk?: China, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Draftees Birthday Cake Numbers: draft
              
              <lb/>
Drama that Came to a Climax: Vietnam War, Ngo Dinh Nhu 
              
              <lb/>
Dropout Season: school dropouts
              
              <lb/>
Dropping the Cuban Pilot: Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro, Cuban Missile Crisis
              
              <lb/>
Dropping the Egg: U. Thant, Vietnam War, peace
              
              <lb/>
Dry your Tears Mourners: civil rights, school prayer, Everett Dirksen
              
              <lb/>
Duel of the Guns: Israel, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Middle East, peace</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>E</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">	2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Early Christmas Shopping: Republican Party, Richard Nixon, Charles H. Percy, Hatfield, George W. Romney
              
              <lb/>
Early Variety Catalogue: Republican Party, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Early Bird and the Worm: John F. Kennedy, unemployment, recession
              
              <lb/>
East Berlin Reds Party Congress Meeting: China, Nikita Khrushchev, Walter Ulbricht, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Easter Bunny: Walter Reuther, United Auto Workers
              
              <lb/>
Easter Offering: Easter, peace
              
              <lb/>
Economic Picture: economy, John F. Kennedy, unemployment
              
              <lb/>
Egyptian Home Run King: Soviet Union, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Israel, Middle East
              
              <lb/>
Eleanor Goes Home: Eleanor Roosevelt (1962)
              
              <lb/>
Election is Coming: voting rights, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Election is getting more Interesting: Nguyen Van Thieu, Nguyen Cao Ky, Vietnam War, elections, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Election Year Spaceman: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Electors Carrier: peace, Algeria
              
              <lb/>
Emergency Calls: natural disasters
              
              <lb/>
End of the Game: traffic fatalities
              
              <lb/>
End of the Long Weekend: Labor Day, traffic fatalities
              
              <lb/>
England's Pound Squeeze: Britain, Harold Wilson
              
              <lb/>
European Diplomatic Trip: Europe, NATO, Hubert Humphrey
              
              <lb/>
Everlasting Applause: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Everything Free in 1980: Nikita Khrushchev, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Everything's Under Control Now: Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons, Dean Rusk
              
              <lb/>
Executive Flu: Medicare, Dean Rusk, Lyndon Johnson, Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
Explosion He Likes to Hear: civil rights, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Explosion of the China's Bomb: China, nuclear weapons, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Eyes of the Nation: Jack Ruby, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Eyes on Moscow: 

Averall Harriman, peace, nuclear weapons, Soviet Union, China</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>F</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Face in the Window: space exploration, China, education, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Facing the Population Problem: population, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Fact Finding Mission Completed: Nelson Rockefeller, Latin America, South America, Richard Nixon, Romania
              
              <lb/>
Faith in Prayers: religion, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Far from the U.S. Political Battle: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Fateful Duel in Moscow: communism, Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong, Russia, China
              
              <lb/> Fearless Stork: France, Algeria, Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Female of the Species: Florida, natural disasters
              
              <lb/>
Fidel's Burning Issue: Fidel Castro, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Fidel's Favorite False Face: Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Fidel's Peaceful Overtures: Organization of American States, Cuba, economy, Fidel Castro, socialism 
              
              <lb/>
Figure on the Race Track: horse racing
              
              <lb/>
Finally Caught the Big One: United Auto Workers, strikes, Walter Reuther
              
              <lb/>
Find the Answers by March First: Lyndon Johnson, riots
              
              <lb/>
Finding it Hard to Fill: Charles De Gaulle, Georges Pompidou
              
              <lb/>
Finest Leadership in the Nation: Dwight Eisenhower, Richard Nixon, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.
              
              <lb/>
Fire Eater: China, Thailand, India, Vietnam War, Laos
              
              <lb/>
Fire will get bigger without that Bag: communism, Vietnam War, Ngo Dinh Nhu
              
              <lb/>
First Day of Spring ("The Early Birds and the Presidential Worm"): elections, Lyndon Johnson, Eugene McCarthy, Richard Nixon, Robert F. Kennedy, Nelson Rockefeller
              
              <lb/>
First Day of Spring ("Vietnam"): Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, peace, Ho Chi Minh
              
              <lb/>
First Step Toward Peace: U. Thant, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
First Touch of Spring: Congress, Lyndon Johnson, foreign aid
              
              <lb/>
First Woman in Outer Space: space exploration, women, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
First American into Space and Back: space exploration, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Fishinable Material and the Smoker: Fidel Castro, Cuba, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Fishing for the Big Catch: Cuba, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Fishing in the Far East: Vietnam War, Laos
              
              <lb/>
Fishing Season Big Catch: inflation
              
              <lb/>
Five Billion Nike-X Anti-Missile Project: McNamara, China, nuclear weapons, anti-missile systems
              
              <lb/>
Flag Day: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Flame Thrower: China, Asia, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Flight From Soviet Communism Rule: Svetlana Stalin
              
              <lb/>
Flux Look: elections, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Flying Around the British Royalty: England
              
              <lb/>
The "Flying A$tronaut" over Washington: Congress, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Flying Saucers — Are they Real?:  inflation, taxes, cost of living, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Flying Stork Around the Vatican: population, birth control, Pope Paul VI
              
              <lb/>
Following Along the Trail: Pope Paul VI, Pope John XXIII, Christianity
              
              <lb/>
Footprints in Texas: Congress, Billie Sol Estes, Texas
              
              <lb/>
Footsteps to Peace: United Nations, peace, Pope Paul VI
              
              <lb/>
Fog in New York and Cleveland: newspapers, strike
              
              <lb/>
Foundation and Freedom of Individual Liberty: prayer
              
              <lb/>
Foundation of Freedoms: religion
              
              <lb/>
France's "Geographical Position": NATO, France, Charles De Gaulle, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
France's "Globe Trotter": France, Charles De Gaulle, Europe, Wilson, Britain, common market
              
              <lb/>
Friend in Need: charity
              
              <lb/>
Friendly Persuasion: Lyndon Johnson, China, Mao Zedong, Ho Chi Minh, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
From the White House Kitchen: John F. Kennedy, Congress, schools, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Full Speed Ahead: railroad industry, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Full Support for Change of Formula: Congo, United Nations, U. Thant
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>G</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Gangway: sports
              
              <lb/>
General Passes On: Douglas MacArthur (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Getting Bigger: crime
              
              <lb/>
Get the Point, Khrush and Fidel Castro?: Monroe Doctrine
              
              <lb/>
Getting Hit by His Own Truck: Jimmy Hoffa, Teamsters
              
              <lb/>
Getting Hotter?: Cuba, Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Getting into the Race: Robert F. Kennedy, Eugene McCarthy, Lyndon Johnson, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Getting Nowhere: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Ghost at the Window: Russia, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Girl He's Leaving Behind: United Nations, U. Thant, Vietnam War, peace
              
              <lb/>
Giving it a Pep Shot: Republican Party, William Scranton, Eisenhower
              
              <lb/>
Glad to Help: Eisenhower, John F. Kennedy, communism
              
              <lb/>
Globe Trotter Peace Salesman: Organization of American States, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Go Find Your Own Tree: China, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, Congo
              
              <lb/>
Go Home, Madame Nhu: Ngo Dinh Nhu
              
              <lb/>
God's Guidance System: space exploration, prayer
              
              <lb/>
Goes Home: Great Society, taxes, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Going After Another One: United Auto Workers, Walter Reuther
              
              <lb/>
Going Home to His Real Friends: Abraham Lincoln, Robert F. Kennedy, John F. Kennedy, Martin Luther King Jr.
              
              <lb/>
Going Up?: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Going Up: cost of living, auto industry
              
              <lb/>
Goldberg Ready for Action: United Nations, Andrei Gromyko, Adlai Stevenson, Arthur Goldberg
              
              <lb/>
Good Friday — Nineteen Sixty-Four: Christianity, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Good, But Not Spectacular Performance: business
              
              <lb/>
Good News for Richard: Richard Nixon, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Good News from Moscow: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Good News to Khrush: Nikita Khrushchev, communism, John F. Kennedy, Adlai Stevenson
              
              <lb/>
Good Will Visit and the Speech: France, Charles De Gaulle, Latin America, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Goose-Step Kick: Nazism, Ludwig Erhard, elections, Germany
              
              <lb/>
G.O.P. Drafty Room: William Scranton, Richard Nixon, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
G.O.P Leaders look at the Washington Skater: Everett Dirksen, inflation, Great Society, Vietnam War, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
G.O.P Presidential Team: Richard Nixon, Spiro T. Agnew, elections, Republican Party 
              
              <lb/>
G.O.P's Turkey Trot: Dirksen, Lyndon Johnson, government spending, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Governor's Re-Marriage: Nelson Rockefeller, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Grab it, Boy: John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Graduation Gift: graduates, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Grave Diggers: Vietnam War, traffic fatalities
              
              <lb/>
Grace of the III-Fated Submarine: USS 
              
              <emph render="italic">Thresher</emph> (1963)
              
              <lb/>
Great Debate — Round Two: John F. Kennedy, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Great Society Juggler: poverty, Lyndon Johnson, Congress, budget, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
Great Society Tightrope Walker: Lyndon Johnson, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Great Warrior and Leader: Dwight Eisenhower (1969)
              
              <lb/>
Greatest Conquest of Space: space exploration, prayer
              
              <lb/>
Greek and Turkey Thin Ice: Middle East, Cyprus, United Nations, Makarios III
              
              <lb/>
Grim Reaper: natural disasters, Yugoslavia
              
              <lb/>
Groundhog Day in France: Charles De Gaulle, China 
              
              <lb/>Groundhog Day in Southeast Asia: Vietnam War, North Korea, USS 
              
              <emph render="italic">Pueblo</emph>
              <lb/> Growing Figure: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Guideline: steel industry, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Guilty Verdict: Jimmy Hoffa
              
              <lb/>
Gunsmoke Fight: steel industry, economy, Lyndon Johnson</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>H</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Had Enough of Debates: unions, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Hailed on His Birthday: Winston Churchill
              
              <lb/>
Halloween Season: Mao Zedong, China, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Hand of the Law: Jimmy Hoffa
              
              <lb/>
Hanoi's Bluff Act: Vietnam War, peace, Ho Chi Minh, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Happy Birthday: United Nations
              
              <lb/>
Happy Birthday, Ike: Eisenhower (1962)
              
              <lb/>
Happy Birthday, Mr. Hoover: Herbert Hoover (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Happy Lincoln: Abraham Lincoln, civil rights (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Hard Blow in Algeria: Organization of American States, Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Hard Boiled Egg: Congress, taxes, economy
              
              <lb/>
Hard Climb: Congress, civil rights, fair employment practices
              
              <lb/>
Hard Up: Congress, Poor People's Campaign
              
              <lb/>
Harvest Moon in Britain: Harold Macmillan, elections
              
              <lb/>Headin' for the Moon: cost of living
              
              <lb/>
Heading for the Moon: national debt, budget, Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
He Doesn't Choose to Run: Republican Party, Nelson Rockefeller, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Healthier and a Greater Potential: railroad industry,  Pennsylvania
              
              <lb/>
Heat March: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Hello? Is that the Washington Zoo?: Nikita Khrushchev, China
              
              <lb/>
He's Off in a Cloud of Dust: Hubert Humphrey, peace, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Headaches for the Aggression: China, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
 
Heading to North Vietnam?: Vietnam War, foreign policy
              
              <lb/>
Heat Spell: inflation, taxes, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Heat Wave in Vietnam: communism, armed forces, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Heat Wave: Laos 
              
              <lb/>
Heat Wave ("Vietnam"): civil rights, elections, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Heavy Issue: Richard Nixon, anti-missile systems
              
              <lb/>
He'll be too Host for Us: Barry Goldwater, communism, Mao Zedong, Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
He's Not Leaving: Mao Zedong, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
He's Not Old Enough to Vote: voting rights, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
He Shot an Arrow into the Air: nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Here We Come Again: Lyndon Johnson, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Hey Fellows ! Help Me with this Warmonger: China, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Harold Macmillan
              
              <lb/>
Hi Joe I'm getting ready to Retire: Stalin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
High Cost of Ending Pollution: pollution
              
              <lb/>
High Cost of Polluted Air: pollution, population
              
              <lb/>
High Noon on Germany: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
High Court Decision: Supreme Court, schools, prayer
              
              <lb/>
High Explosive: Gamal Abdel Nasser, Israel, Middle East
              
              <lb/>
Highway Robbery: traffic fatalities, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
His Appetite is "Conquest": peace, Asia, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
His Arms Full: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
His Big Worry: China, Mao Zedong, Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
His First Big Act — S-T-E-A-D-Y: John F. Kennedy, budget, Congress
              
              <lb/>
His First Big Problem: Congress, education, John F. Kennedy, U.S. Constitution
              
              <lb/>
His Latest Move in African Struggle: Congo, war, violence
              
              <lb/>
His Master's Voice: John F. Kennedy, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
His Move for the Reserve Call: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, armed forces
              
              <lb/>
His Prayer Lives Through the Years: prayer, George Washington
              
              <lb/>
His Presidential Trial Balloons: George Wallace, Charles H. Percy, Richard Nixon, George W. Romney, Ronald Reagan, Nelson Rockefeller
              
              <lb/>
His Toast to the Graduates: graduates, taxes, Vietnam War, inflation
              
              <lb/>
His Top Challenger: Richard Nixon, inflation, economy
              
              <lb/>
His Weekend Prayers: riots, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Hit Again: Congress, Lyndon Johnson, Abe Fortas
              
              <lb/>
Hit It Harder: China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Hitting Hard Back in the Jungle: Vietnam War, Nguyen Van Thieu
              
              <lb/>
Hitting the Doorstep: Mao Zedong, China, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Hitting the Moon's Bullseye — But no Pictures: space exploration, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Hitting the Truckers: John F. Kennedy, trucking industry
              
              <lb/>
Ho Chi Minh's Shot: Richard Nixon, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Hold It "Nobody Here but us Chickens": Cuba, Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Holding Firm: Panama
              
              <lb/>
Holding the Communist Puppet: Fidel Castro, Cuba, Dominican Republic
              
              <lb/>
Holiday Pick-Up: traffic fatalities, Independence Day
              
              <lb/>
Home After a Long Session: Congress, civil rights, taxes, poverty
              
              <lb/>
Hot Baseball Game: Robert McNamara, Laos, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Hot Crater Lake: nuclear weapons, disarmament, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Hot Line: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Hot Potato: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Hot Potatoes: John F. Kennedy, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Hot Summer: race relations
              
              <lb/>
Hot World for Jack: Dwight Eisenhower, John F. Kennedy, Cuba, Africa, Laos (1960)
              
              <lb/>
How About Kickin' a Field Goal?: China, Ho Chi Minh, communism, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
How About the Big Fellow: Lyndon Johnson, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
How About the Tail?: John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
How Does the Garden Grow?: industry (general), labor, economy, John F. Kennedy, inflation
              
              <lb/>
Ho Chi MinhDo We End the War in Vietnam: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
How Everything has Changed: civil rights, demonstrations, Abraham Lincoln
              
              <lb/>
How Far Will He Chew It: China, Mao Zedong, Jawaharlal Nehru, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
How Long Can He Carry the Ball: Vietnam War, peace, demonstrations, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
How Times Have Changed: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
How to Keep from Growing Old: China, Mao Zedong, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Humpty Dumpty Makes a Come Back: stock market, economy
              
              <lb/>
Humpty Dumpty Sat on a Wall: Vietnam War, George McGovern, Eugene McCarthy, Hubert Humphrey, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Hunters to Start Blasting Away: Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Hydrogen Halloween  Sower: Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>I</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>I Better Not Run Out of Gas: John F. Kennedy, taxes, economy
              
              <lb/>
I Didn't Know I Was Running: Barry Goldwater, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
I Didn't See Any Crowds or Parades for Me: Konrad Adenauer, Charles De Gaulle, common market
              
              <lb/>
I Like 'em Both: elections, Barry Goldwater, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
I Really Need a $10,000 Pay Raise: Congress
              
              <lb/>
I Resign My Job: Supreme Court, Abe Fortas
              
              <lb/>
I Said; "Please Speak More Distinctly": nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
I Think I Hear a Heartbeat: John F. Kennedy, Medicare, Congress
              
              <lb/>
I Thought Nothing Was Wrong: Thomas Dodd, Congress
              
              <lb/>
I Want Something That's Purely European: Charles De Gaulle, Konrad Adenauer, John F. Kennedy, Harold Macmillan
              
              <lb/>
I Waited a Long Time for This: Lyndon Johnson (1964)
              
              <lb/>
I Want to Negotiate a Settlement: Lyndon Johnson, Ho Chi Minh, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
I was Misquoted by the Press: Soviet Union, nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
I won't Recognize Their Monster Bomb: nuclear weapons, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
I'll Carry the Words to Vietnam: Alexey Kosygin, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
I'll be Delighted: Charles De Gaulle, NATO
              
              <lb/>
I'll Make My Own U.N. Plans Now: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev, Dag Hammarskjold
              
              <lb/>
I'll Quit the United Nations Membership: Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, United Nations, U. Thant, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
I'll Save You: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
I'm Glad it's Ours: space exploration, Russia
              
              <lb/>
I'm Just Thinking about "My Congress": Congress, Social Security, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
I'm Still Boss: Fidel Castro, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
If You Were President, What Would You Do?: taxes, inflation, economy, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Ike and Jack Discussion: John F. Kennedy, Dwight Eisenhower (1960)
              
              <lb/>
Ike at the United Nations: Dwight Eisenhower, United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Ike's Report to Congress: Dwight Eisenhower, Congress, economy
              
              <lb/>
Ike's Return: John F. Kennedy, Dwight Eisenhower, politics
              
              <lb/>
Imperialist Warmongers want to Destroy Us!: Russia, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Imprisoned Professor Flies Home: Nikita Khrushchev, espionage, Frederick Barghoorn
              
              <lb/>
In a World of Confusion: religion
              
              <lb/>
In God's Hand: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
In the Back: Laos
              
              <lb/>
In the Middle of a Big Stretch: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, Alabama
              
              <lb/>
In the Same Old Bed: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
In Time the Wall Will Collapse: John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
Indian Peace Call Falls — Britain Will Try: Indira Ghandi, Harold Wilson, Alexey Kosygin, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Inflation Balloon: cost of living, Lyndon Johnson, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Inflation Watch: economy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
International Problem Child: Cyprus, peace
              
              <lb/>
Interruption: stock market
              
              <lb/>
Interruption for a New Talk Site: strikes, telephone industry
              
              <lb/>
Into the Homestretch ("Jack" and "Dick"): Lyndon Johnson, Barry Goldwater
              
              <lb/>
Into the Homestretch ("LBJ" and "Barry"): Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Intrusion into the Communist World: Richard Nixon, peace, Asia
              
              <lb/>
Is Fidel Castro Next: Brazil, Fidel Castro, communism
              
              <lb/>
Is He Dangerous: China, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Is It a First Step?: peace, nuclear weapons, disarmament, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Is It Going to be a Long Hot Summer: civil rights, riots
              
              <lb/>
Is It Safer Out There: Vietnam War, Dominican Republic, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Is Soviet Union Ahead in This Field: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Is That Ball Moving?: Lyndon Johnson, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
Is the Baby European?: Harold Macmillan, common market
              
              <lb/>
Is the Pressure on the Lid Eased?: inflation, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Is There More Cooking?: Bobby Baker, Lyndon Johnson, Democratic Party, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Is This Trip Necessary: John F. Kennedy, Europe
              
              <lb/>
It Could Happen Anywhere: John F. Kennedy, Warren Commission
              
              <lb/>
It Couldn't Be the Congo Heat: Nikita Khrushchev, disarmament, United Nations, Congo
              
              <lb/>
It May Be a Real Storm: Congress, Bobby Baker
              
              <lb/>
It Pays to Drive with Safety Rules: Congress, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
It Really Takes a Bite: taxes
              
              <lb/>
It Scares Them: Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
It Seems Like Every Day is April First ("Cuban Crisis"): Cuba
              
              <lb/>
It Seems Like Everyday is April First ("War"): Vietnam War, Alabama
              
              <lb/>
It Seems to be April Fool Everyday: Lyndon Johnson (1964)
              
              <lb/>
It's All Your Fault: Fidel Castro, Soviet Union, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
It's Getting Hotter for Khrush: Berlin, Russia, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
It's Going to Be Interesting: Republican Party, elections
              
              <lb/>
It's Good and Loud: United Nations, U. Thant, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
It's Good to Light My Cigars: Fidel Castro, Cuba, Dean Rusk, John F. Kennedy 
              
              <lb/>
It's Just One Thing: Labor Day, traffic fatalities
              
              <lb/>
It's Not that We Don't Like You: inflation, steel industry, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
It's Not that We Don't Trust You: Lyndon Johnson, Nikita Khrushchev, Soviet Union, nuclear weapons
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>J</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Jack and the Big Axe: taxes, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
JFK Report to the Nation: Warren Commission, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
JFK's Easter Egg: John F. Kennedy, steel industry
              
              <lb/>
J.F.K's Top Hat: John F. Kennedy, Democratic Party (1961)
              
              <lb/>
Jinny and the Bottle: Democratic Party, Republican Party, Eugene McCarthy, Lyndon Johnson, Robert F. Kennedy, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Job for Jack, the Giant Killer: John F. Kennedy, unemployment
              
              <lb/>
Job Well Done: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Judgement of the General: Charles De Gaulle, Nikita Khrushchev, NATO, Britain
              
              <lb/>
Just a Little Package for Fidel: farming, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, hunger
              
              <lb/>
Just Flying Around?: Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro, Cuba, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Just Like the Last One: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Just Listening: Andrei Gromyko, Lyndon Johnson, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
Just Missed: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Just Waiting: United Nations, China
              
              <lb/>
Just Waiting to Pick Up the Press: Berlin, Charles De Gaulle, Khrushchev, NATO, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Just Warming Up: Richard Nixon, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Just Watching ("Hubert" and "LBJ"): Hubert Humphrey, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Just Watching ("National Guard" and "Moratorium Parade"): demonstrations, Vietnam War</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>K</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Keep it Free, America! (Freedoms Foundation Cartoon): freedom
              
              <lb/>
Keeping a Close Watch: Cuba, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Keeping His Fingers Crossed: steel industry, economy, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Keeping the Fuse Lighted: Nikita Khrushchev, Berlin, peace
              
              <lb/>
The "John F. Kennedy" Prospector: Robert F. Kennedy, Democratic Party, Hubert Humphrey, Eugene McCarthy
              
              <lb/>
John F. Kennedy vs. Eisenhower — Campaigners: John F. Kennedy, Dwight Eisenhower, elections
              
              <lb/>
John F. Kennedy's Big Tasks: John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
John F. Kennedy's "Heat Wave": John F. Kennedy, nuclear weapons, civil rights, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
John F. Kennedy's Quintuplets: John F. Kennedy, nuclear weapons, civil rights, education, taxes, healthcare
              
              <lb/>
Khrush and His Little Pigs: United Nations, Fidel Castro, Janos Kadar, Wladyslaw Gomulka, Zhikov
              
              <lb/>
Khrush Now on the Other End: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Khrush Taking Another Nosedive: Lyndon Johnson, Nikita Khrushchev, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Khrush's Appleseed: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Khrush's Can't Boast About This: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Khrush's Communist Tie-Up: Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev, Makarios III
              
              <lb/>
Khrush's Pain in the Neck: Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Khrush's Pre-Halloween Hobgoblin: Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Khrush's Dummy and Pot Act: Fidel Castro, Khrushchev, Laos, Cuba
              
              <lb/> Kicked for the Twentieth Time: China, United Nations, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Kicking the Communist Out: Fidel Castro, Chile, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Kicks Off State GOP Drive: Republican Party, Nelson Rockefeller, Richard Nixon, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.
              
              <lb/>
Kindly Snake: China, Jawaharlal Nehru
              
              <lb/>
Kite Flying Time (JFK): John F. Kennedy, youth, unemployment 
              
              <lb/>
Kite Flying Time (LBJ): Lyndon Johnson, Appalachia, healthcare, schools</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>L</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Labor Day Links: Pennsylvania, labor
              
              <lb/>
Labor's Big Reach: labor
              
              <lb/>
Laborer Worthy of His Higher: labor
              
              <lb/>
Lack of Confidence in Civil Defense: civil defense, nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, fallout shelters
              
              <lb/>
Lady Economy: taxes, business, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Large Bomb Juggler: India, Pakistan, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, peace
              
              <lb/>
Last Stand: Robert McNamara, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev, anti-missile systems, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Last Year's Bird Nest: peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Last Walk on India's Sands of Time: India, Pakistan, Lal Bahadur Shastri
              
              <lb/>
Latest Casualty Report: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Latest Egyptian Situation: Dwight Eisenhower, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
LBJ's Big Catch: Lyndon Johnson, elections
              
              <lb/>
LBJ's "Great Society" Fat Man: budget, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
LBJ's Hard-Boiled Viet Eggs: peace, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
LBJ's Peace Traveling Salesman: Vietnam War, Hubert Humphrey, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
LBJ's Price Battle Punch: Lyndon Johnson, aluminum industry, inflation
              
              <lb/>
LBJ's Proposed School Plan: Lyndon Johnson, schools, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Let Me Reduce Your Storage Problems: Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Let Me Take You for a Walk: China, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Let the Whole World Hear Us: U.S. Constitution, religion
              
              <lb/>
Let Them Vote: voting, 26th Amendment
              
              <lb/>
Let There Be Peace: Middle East, United Nations, U. Thant
              
              <lb/>
Let This Be a Warning Commie: Cuba, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Let Us All Pray for Our Nation: prayer
              
              <lb/>
Let Us Pray: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Let Us Pray for Peace: nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Let's Fill the Basket: Britain, Europe, Harold Macmillan, common market
              
              <lb/>
Let's Put the Puzzle Together: Democratic Party, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Let's Smoke the Peace Pipe Together: business, economy, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Let's Stop Him: crime, Lyndon Johnson, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Let's Take a Fifty Miles Hike: John F. Kennedy, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Little Axe in the Petrified Forest: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Little Man, What Now? (1962): war, peace
              
              <lb/>
Little Man, What Now? (1963): war, peace
              
              <lb/>
Little Man, What Now? (1966): peace, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Little Pig Went to Market: Russia, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
Long, Hot Summer: riots
              
              <lb/>
Look Fellow — You Don't See Me Worrying: nuclear weapons, fallout shelters
              
              <lb/>
Look How Big He Is, Now!: common market, tariffs, John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Look Out Mountain: peace, disarmament, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Looking At the Crystal: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Looking at the Messy World: foreign policy, Great Society, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Looking At the World Economic View: economy, Russia, Britain, Europe, common market
              
              <lb/>
Looking Down on a Troubled World ( Lincoln looking at Soviet emblem): communism, peace 
              
              <lb/>
Looking Down on a Troubled World (Lincoln looking at Soviet  rockets and satellites):  
communism, peace
              
              <lb/>
Looking Down on the Birmingham Precedent: Abraham Lincoln, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Looking for a Bombproof Shelter: civil defense, nuclear weapons, cities, population
              
              <lb/>
Looking for a Place to Drop It: United Nations, Charles De Gaulle, Lyndon Johnson, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Looking for a Solution to Stop Strikes: strikes, Congress, labor
              
              <lb/>
Looking for a Warless Solution, Fellows?: Dean Rusk, Andrei Gromyko
              
              <lb/>
Looking into the Future: Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Looking It Over Carefully: gun control, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Looking to Washington: John F. Kennedy, peace, Cold War, economy
              
              <lb/>
Looks Like He Will Reach It: taxes, John F. Kennedy, government spending, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Looks Like I Need Your Help: John F. Kennedy, taxes, government  spending, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Losing His Popularity Grip?: Middle East, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson, Alexey Kosygin, peace
              
              <lb/>
Losing His Strength: Teamsters, Jimmy Hoffa
              
              <lb/>
Lost Boy Found: nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Loud and Clear: France, Charles De  Gaulle, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Love Birds: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, Laos,  Thailand
              
              <lb/>
Lyndon had a Little Lamb: Lyndon Johnson, inflation, cost of living
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>M</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>M-Day Blastoff: Lyndon Johnson, Medicare
              
              <lb/>
Make Him Pay Up or Else: United Nations, U. Thant, Russia, Nikita Khrushchev, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Make It Wide Enough to Bury Yourself, Too!: Nikita Khrushchev, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
The Man on the Capitol Steps: Congress, unemployment, John F. Kennedy, economy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Man Who Came to Dinner: China, India, China
              
              <lb/>
March Lion and Lamb: peace, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Marooned on the Island: peace, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Mao Zedong Celebrates the Chinese Fourth: peace, China, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Mao Zedong's Unhappy Anniversary of Red Rule: farming, China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Mao Zedong's Unhappy 14th Birthday: China, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
May I Have a Shelter Guidebook: civil defense, nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
May I Help You, Sonny?: peace (1961)
              
              <lb/>
Maybe I'll Move It a Little Closer: Europe, common market, Harold Macmillan, England
              
              <lb/>
Maybe This One Will Work: NATO, Europe, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Maybe We Can Get Together Sometime: Berlin, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
McNamara's Problem of Security: Robert McNamara, Congress, Vietnam War, draft
              
              <lb/>
Memorial Day Big Wreath: traffic fatalities (1965)
              
              <lb/>
Memorial Day Races: traffic fatalities (1967)
              
              <lb/>
Merry Christmas Wringing: steel industry, taxes, cost of living
              
              <lb/>
Mess of Dough in Washington: Bobby Baker, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Mind If I Cook While We're Talking: John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, Laos
              
              <lb/>
Mighty Strong Smoke: smoking, cancer
              
              <lb/>
Miracle If It Happens: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Month of Prayer for Peace: prayer, Pope Paul VI, Vietnam War, peace
              
              <lb/>
Moon Over Washington: Bobby Baker, Congress
              
              <lb/>
More Important than `Readin' — `Riting and 'Rithmetic: communism, patriotism

              
              <lb/>
More Tombstones?: violence, John F. Kennedy, Robert F. Kennedy, Martin Luther King, Jr.
              
              <lb/>
More Trouble Ahead: Vietnam War, elections, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Moscow — Peking Ideological Split: Soviet Union, China
              
              <lb/>
Moscow's Merry Go Around: space exploration, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Mount De Gaulle Mountain Climbers: Charles De Gaulle, nuclear weapons, Harold Macmillan, Dean Rusk, John F. Kennedy, NATO, common market
              
              <lb/>
Mounting Against Him: Vietnam War, peace, Richard Nixon, communism
              
              <lb/>
Mounting Figure: aircraft accidents, Japan
              
              <lb/>
Mourning: Winston Churchill (1965)
              
              <lb/>
Mourning a Great American: Adlai Stevenson, United Nations (1965)
              
              <lb/> The Mourning United Nations: Dag Hammarskjold, United Nations (1961)
              
              <lb/> Moving Slowly: civil rights, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Mud Slinging Targets: Lyndon Johnson, Robert F. Kennedy, Vietnam War
 
              
              <lb/>
My OLE Buddy: Tito, Yugoslavia, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
My Wonder World of Policy: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
My Wonderful Fat Baby: John F. Kennedy, budget, taxes
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>N</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Nation Mourns the Astronauts: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Nation's Visitor: Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Nation's Worst Air Tragedy: aircraft accidents
              
              <lb/>
National Bible Week Oct. 17-23: religion
              
              <lb/>
National Civil Defense Day: nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
National Crisis for All Americans: civil rights
              
              <lb/>
National Disgrace: Vietnam War, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
Nature of the Troops Mission: SEATO, Mao Zedong, China, Thailand
              
              <lb/>
Negotiations for a New Contract: steel industry
              
              <lb/>
Nest Egg: United Nations, Cyprus, U. Thant, Arthur Goldberg, Turkey, Greece, peace
              
              <lb/>
New Addition to the John F. Kennedy Administration: John F. Kennedy, Jr. (1960)
              
              <lb/>
New Baby: Republican Party, New York City
              
              <lb/>
New Chief Justice: Richard Nixon, Warren Burger
              
              <lb/>
New Frontier Colic: Congress, civil rights, education
              
              <lb/>
New Frontier's Prodigal Father: taxes, budget, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
New Look in Washington: Congress
              
              <lb/>
New Prime Minister: Canada, Lester Pearson, Diefenbaker
              
              <lb/>
New Round: nuclear weapons, Berlin, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
New Start in Vietnam: Buddhists, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
New Top Men Abroad: Ludwig Erhard, Alec Douglas-Home
              
              <lb/>
Next?: polio, cancer
              
              <lb/>
Nikita Proposes a Toast: Fidel Castro, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Nikita's New "Peace Offensive": John F. Kennedy, China, Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Nikita's Reactions: Central Intelligence Agency, Khrushchev, Russia, China, Cuba, Latin America, economy, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Nineteen Sixty-two Economy Run: taxes, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Nineteen Sixty-Four Spring Bonnet: Cold War, Leap Year, peace, Republican Party, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Ninety Miles Focus on Cuba: Cold War, Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Nixon — The Political Figure: Richard Nixon, Republican Party, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Nixon's Punching Bag: Richard Nixon, Fidel Castro, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Nixon's Physical Checkup: Richard Nixon, Republican Party, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
No Communist Victory: Ho Chi Minh, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
No Deal With Communists, Now!: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
No Easy Route: Charles De Gaulle, Algeria, peace
              
              <lb/>
No Gun Test Ban Treaty in Sight: Korea, China
              
              <lb/>
No Time for Nesting: peace
              
              <lb/>
No Writer's Cramp: labor, auto industry
              
              <lb/>
Nobody Loves This Fat Man (LBJ): Lyndon Johnson, budget, foreign aid
              
              <lb/>
Nobody Loves This Fat Man (Congress): Congress, budget, taxes, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Nobody Pays Any  Attention to Me: Guantanamo, Fidel Castro, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Nominee Ride the Democrat's Saddle: Richard Nixon, Hubert Humphrey, elections
              
              <lb/>
Noise May Spell Trouble: China, peace, Lyndon Johnson, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Not Out Yet: Berlin
              
              <lb/>
November Fight is On: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon Johnson, elections (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Now! The Homestretch: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon Johnson, Republican Party, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Now, What?: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Nuclear Derby Jockeys: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>O</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Off on a Crisis-Hopping Trip: Dean Rusk, foreign policy, Europe, New Frontier
              
              <lb/>
Oh! My Aching Back: Soviet Union, Cuba, Congress, John F. Kennedy, New Frontier
              
              <lb/>
Oh, Say, Can You See: demonstrations, draft
              
              <lb/>
Oh, We Recognize You All Right: United Nations, China, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Old Birds Carries On: population, China
              
              <lb/>
Old Religious Feud: religion, violence, Northern Ireland
              
              <lb/>
Old Soldier Vacation: Dwight Eisenhower
              
              <lb/>
Olive Branch, Anybody?: peace, Lyndon Johnson, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
On the Cold War Front: China, Nikita Khrushchev, communism
              
              <lb/>
On With the British Politics Show: common market, Harold Macmillan, elections
              
              <lb/>
One Big Word: Algeria, France, peace
              
              <lb/>
One Nation Under God: school prayer, Supreme Court
              
              <lb/>
Open Season for Peace Doves: Mao Zedong, Ho Chi Minh, Lyndon Johnson, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Open This Sometime This Year, Maybe: taxes, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Operation K.O. Polio Plans: polio, Pennsylvania
              
              <lb/>
Orbit: space exploration, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Orbit Around the World Three Times: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Orbit the Earth — The American Way: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Orbiting the Moon: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Orderly Transfer of Executive Responsibility: Dwight Eisenhower, John F. Kennedy (1961)
              
              <lb/>
Our Involvement Could Become Deeper: China, Vietnam, communism
              
              <lb/>
Our Ace Photographer Takes Moon Photos: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Our Freedoms in Its Hand: religion, freedom, U.S. Constitution
              
              <lb/>
Out — And In Again: Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Maxwell Taylor, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Outlook in Southeast Asia: Vietnam War, Asia, peace, Lyndon Johnson</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>P</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Pain in the Neck: Lyndon Johnson, J. William Fulbright
              
              <lb/>
Parisian Style of Endorsement: Charles De Gaulle, France, elections
              
              <lb/>
Passing Up the Cashier: United Nations, Russia, Congo, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Paul's Historic Journey to Holy Land: prayer, Pope Paul VI
              
              <lb/>
Peace — A Look Ahead: peace, nuclear weapons, Cold War
              
              <lb/>
Peace Doves Talks: peace, South Korea, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, USS 
              
              <emph render="italic">Pueblo</emph>
              <lb/>
Peace Proposal?: India, Pakistan, United Nations
              
              <lb/>
Peace in Steel Union — But?: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, steel industry
              
              <lb/>
Peace Prospects in Vietnam: peace, Pope Paul VI, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Peace Slugger at Bat: United Nations, Arthur Goldberg, India, Pakistan
              
              <lb/>
Peaceful Movement: Cyprus, Turkey, United Nations, Makarios III
              
              <lb/>
Peaceful Revolution Shots: Latin America, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Peiping Tom's Shadow: China, Formosa, Chiang Kai Shek
              
              <lb/>
Pentagon Bugler: Robert McNamara, draft, armed forces, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Pentagon Bugler and the Question: Robert McNamara, armed forces, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Pentagon Turkey: Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
Peru's Fatal Soccer Kick: sports, Peru, Argentina
              
              <lb/>
Philadelphia Story: liberty, justice, democracy, freedom
              
              <lb/>
Phone Call to Ho Chi MinhChi Minh: peace, Richard Nixon, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Pig Trying to Wreck the Building: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Pilgrim's Progress: nuclear weapons (1961)
              
              <lb/>
Piling On: government spending, taxes, unemployment
              
              <lb/>
Playing It Cool: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson, draft, Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
Please Remit: United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Pledge of Yule Troop Withdrawal: Richard Nixon, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Political Trouble Ahead: John F. Kennedy 
              
              <lb/>
Political Trouble in Greece: democracy, Greece, Constantine II
              
              <lb/>
Poor Old French General: Charles De Gaulle, Algeria
              
              <lb/>
Poor Old French Santa: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Pope Paul's Message: peace, Pope Paul VI, Pope John XXIII
              
              <lb/>
Popular Heart Shots: Valentine's Day
              
              <lb/>
Porcupine: Barry Goldwater, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Postman's Ring: U.S. Postal Service
              
              <lb/>
Pot's Boiling: United Nations, U. Thant, Congo, Patrice Lumumba
              
              <lb/>
Pouring into the Vatican City: Pope Paul XXIII (1963)
              
              <lb/>
Power Without Responsible: black power, riots, violence
              
              <lb/>
Prayer for Peace: peace, Thanksgiving, Cuba, Berlin, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Prayers in the Sky: peace, prayer, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
President Lyndon Johnson's Tasks: Lyndon Johnson, Russia, civil rights, John F. Kennedy (1963)
              
              <lb/>
President Nguyen Van Thieu Plea to U.S. — "Can't Fight Alone": Richard Nixon, Vietnam War, Nguyen Van Thieu, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
Presidential Brinkmanship: John F. Kennedy, Congress, railroad industry, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Presidential Leap Year: Republican Party, Harold Stassen, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., George W. Romney, William Scranton, Richard Nixon, Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater
              
              <lb/>
Presidential Stumping Season: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
President's Appeal: Lyndon Johnson, prayer, Congress
              
              <lb/>
President's Decision: nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
President's View to Congress: John F. Kennedy, Congress, economy (1962)
              
              <lb/>
Pressure on the Hammer: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Price of War: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Problem of Dealing With the Communists: Fidel Castro, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Profumo Aftermath: Harold Macmillan, England
              
              <lb/>
Public in Suspense: railroad industry, strikes 
              
              <lb/>
Public's Opinion: Warren Commission, Pennsylvania
              
              <lb/>
Put It Together or Leave It: Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Put That Gun Away or Else!: Fidel Castro, Cuba</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Q</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Question Mark: nuclear weapons, fallout shelters, civil defense
              
              <lb/>
Question Mark of the Party: Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Question Mark to Adlai: United Nations, Adlai Stevenson
              
              <lb/>
Question of the Rock: crime, law and order
              
              <lb/>
Questions for the World: China, India, Russia
              
              <lb/>
Quick Shave With This: Lyndon Johnson, taxes, Congress</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>R</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Race Isn't Over by a Long Shot: Soviet Union, space exploration, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Rail Merger Boon to Country: railroad industry, Pennsylvania
              
              <lb/>
Railroad Lantern — Then What?: railroad industry, strikes, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Rainstorm: United Nations, U. Thant, disarmament, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Rattling Another Bomb: Alexey Kosygin, nuclear weapons, United Nations, China
              
              <lb/>
Read'em and Sweat: Congress, organized crime
              
              <lb/>
Reading the Sad News: Vietnam War, Ho
              
              <lb/>
Ready for Action on the Bill: Abraham Lincoln, Congress, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Ready to Eat the Cake: economy, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Ready to Tee Off: John F. Kennedy, unemployment
              
              <lb/>
Ready to Use the Bugle Call: Robert McNamara, draft, armed forces, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Rebel — To — Back —To — Work Call: mining
              
              <lb/>
Record Walking in Orbit: Republican Party, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Red China's Smoke: China, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Red Schoolhouse: education, communism
              
              <lb/>
Red Snapper: foreign aid, Latin America, Charles De Gaulle, China
              
              <lb/>
Re-Election and the Gathering Storms: Congo, Cuba, Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev, United Nations, U. Thant
              
              <lb/>
Rejected Under Fire: Richard Nixon, Supreme Court
              
              <lb/>
Remember Fellows, My Promise — "No Cheating": nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Remember Our Old Friend Stalin: Molotov, Nikita Khrushchev, Joseph Stalin
              
              <lb/>
Republican Fire Fighter Hot Job: Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Vietnam War, communism, religion
              
              <lb/>
Republican Leader Going Home: Everett Dirksen(1969)
              
              <lb/>
Reservists Tightrope: armed forces, China, Cuba, Berlin, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Resigning as Defense Secretary: Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
Rest in Peace: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Restless Red Dragon: China, Laos
              
              <lb/>
Resumption of Negotiations: economy, steel industry, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Retreat: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Riding High Again: space exploration, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Right On Our Doorstep: John F. Kennedy, Cuba, Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Righteousness Exalteth a Nation: religion, Bill of Rights
              
              <lb/>
Ring Out the Old — Ring in the New: peace (1962)
              
              <lb/>
Ringside Seat: Nelson Rockefeller, Richard Nixon, Eugene McCarthy, Hubert Humphrey, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Rising Sun: Vietnam War, draft, Ho Chi Minh, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
Rising Tide: Vietnam War, taxes, Congress, national debt
              
              <lb/>Rising Tide (Medicare): Medicare
              
              <lb/>
Rival Presidents: Charles De Gaulle, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Rocking Chair Lullaby: John F. Kennedy, budget
              
              <lb/>
Rocky Finally Hit the Champ: Nelson Rockefeller, Richard Nixon, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Rocky, No Hard Feelings in New Hampshire: Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater
              
              <lb/>
Rocky Road to New Frontier: John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Rocky Rockin' Chair: John F. Kennedy, Congress, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Roller Run-In With the Traffic Safety: traffic fatalities, auto industry
              
              <lb/>
Rolling Truck: taxes, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Roosting High and Above: China, United Nations, Cold War
              
              <lb/>
Rough Road Ahead: George W. Romney, elections, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
`Round the World: Nikita Khrushchev, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
`Round the World and Safely Back: space exploration, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Running With His Trophy and Bad Shoes: Lyndon Johnson, foreign policy, taxes, economy, elections
              
              <lb/>
Running With the Shadow: Britain, trade, Rhodesia
              
              <lb/>
Rush for the Hustings — But Not Goodbye: Congress, civil rights, Cuba, economy (1962)
              
              <lb/>
Rushing the Halloween Season: Cuba, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Russia — China Wrestling Bout: China, Mao Zedong, Russia, Nikita Khrushchev, communism
              
              <lb/>
Russia's Agricultural and Economy Setback: farming, Canada, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Russia's Another Great Boast: space exploration, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
Russians Are Shelling Again: Lyndon Johnson, demonstrations, Vietnam War, Republican Party, Soviet Union</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>S</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Sad Santa: aircraft accidents, New York, Germany
              
              <lb/>
Safely Home: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Saint Nick in East Berlin: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Same Old Thing: peace
              
              <lb/>
Santa Fidel Castro: Fidel Castro, communism, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Santa in France: Charles De Gaulle, Lyndon Johnson, NATO, France
              
              <lb/>
Santa in Washington: Congress, Lyndon Johnson, economy, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Santa Khrush — Another Art Thief: peace, Congo, Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Santa 'thrush's Big Package: Soviet Union, peace, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Santa Pulling in His Belt: Lyndon Johnson, budget, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Santa's Old Medicine Bottle: Medicare, Lyndon Johnson, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Scarlet Letter: U.S. Postal Service
              
              <lb/>
Scat: journalism, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Scram! You're Stealing My Job: railroad industry, automation, labor
              
              <lb/>
Scrap This Law for a Friend of Mine: labor, Congress, right to work law, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Scrooge for the Pentagon: Robert McNamara, armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Seeing is Believing ("Space Specs"): space exploration, Russia 
              
              <lb/>
Seeing is Believing ("Gordon Cooper's Orbits"): space exploration, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Setback in His Driving: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Seventy-fifth Anniversary: prayer (World Day of Prayers)
              
              <lb/>
Shadow of Inquiry: Ku Klux Klan, HUAAC, 5th Amendment
              
              <lb/>
Shadow on the Gallows: Adolf Eichmann, Holocaust
              
              <lb/>
Shadow Over the Capital: Congress, gun control
              
              <lb/>
Shall I Be Easy or Get Tougher: foreign policy, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Shameful Texas Campus Tragedy: gun control, University of Texas (1966)
              
              <lb/>
She Wasn't a Lady: natural disasters
              
              <lb/>
She's Wearing a New Hat: inflation
              
              <lb/>
Shipwrecked!: Britain, Harold Macmillan, common market, economy
              
              <lb/>
Shocked!: riots, civil rights, democracy, George Washington
              
              <lb/>
Shocking American Tragedy: Martin Luther King, Jr., civil rights, Abraham Lincoln (1968)
              
              <lb/>
Shocking News: New York City,  children, thalidomide
              
              <lb/>
Shooting for the Moon: taxes, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Shouting About Me: Cuba, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Showdown Hand Over a Site for Peace Talks: Ho Chi Minh, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Showdown of the Railroad Crisis: railroad industry, strikes, unions
              
              <lb/>
Signing the New Draft Law: draft, Richard Nixon, armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Sinking: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Sinking United Nations: United Nations, U. Thant, peace
              
              <lb/>
Sitting on Top of the Axe: Lyndon Johnson, Congress, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Sizzling Sun: Robert McNamara, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Sleeping Americans: elections, China, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Slipping on the Greased Poll: Lyndon Johnson, elections, Vietnam War, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
Slugging It Out: Russia, Vietnam War, armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Smog Death Toll Abroad: China, United Nations, Arthur Goldberg
              
              <lb/>
Smog over the United Nations: England
              
              <lb/>
Smoke in the Hood: Ku Klux Klan, HUAAC
              
              <lb/>
Smoker's Puff: smoking
              
              <lb/>
Snarling the Air Travel: strikes, airline industry
              
              <lb/>
Somebody Help Me Stop Him: inflation, taxes, Richard Nixon, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Something I'd Like to Get, Santa: Congress, taxes, civil rights, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Something We Hope to See in Orbit: Nikita Khrushchev, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Something Went Wrong: Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong, India
              
              <lb/>
South Pacific Dawn: United Nations, New Guinea, Indonesia
              
              <lb/>
South Pacific's Blastoff: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Soviet — Chinese Dispute: Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong
              
              <lb/>
Soviet "Red" Riding Hood: China, Alexey Kosygin, Asia
              
              <lb/>
Soviet's Wall Sentry: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Spaceman Goes to Washington: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Space Platform? — We Already Have One: inflation, space exploration, cost of living
              
              <lb/>
Space Race: Russia, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Space Race in Orbit: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Speak for Yourself Grom: Andrei Gromyko, China, United Nations
              
              <lb/>Speaking of the Election: Republican Party, California, Democratic Party, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Speaking of Nuclear Bombs: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon Johnson, elections
              
              <lb/>
Speaking of Target Areas: Nikita Khrushchev, Laos, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>

Special Delivery: John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Special Delivery, Too!: John F. Kennedy, Congress, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Speeding Train: railroad industry
              
              <lb/>
Spider and the Fly: Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Spirit of Lincoln: Abraham Lincoln, United Nations, Charles De Gaulle, Cyprus, peace
              
              <lb/>
Spirit We Need Today: George Washington
              
              <lb/>
Spring Bonnet: taxes, inflation, Vietnam War, economy, cost of living, Lyndon Johnson, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Spring Cleaning Time: foreign policy, Fidel Castro, Nikita Khrushchev, Brazil
              
              <lb/>
Steel Talks: steel industry, unions
              
              <lb/>
Steering Clear of Everything: Lyndon Johnson, Congress, taxes, Vietnam War, inflation, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
Stepchild of the Penna Family: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Still Knocking: China, United Nations
              
              <lb/>
Still on LBJ's "First Term": Hubert Humphrey, Lyndon Johnson, Robert F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Still No Answer at the Door: China, United Nations, India, Pakistan, Indonesia
              
              <lb/>
Still Puffing Away: steel industry, economy, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Still Waiting: Congress, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Sting Blow to Fidel: Fidel Castro, Venezuela, Cuba, Raul Leoni
              
              <lb/>
Stockings Were Hung by the Chimney With Care: nuclear weapons, peace (1960)
              
              <lb/>
Stop Fighting! Let's Talk: United Nations, U. Thant, peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Storm and Shadow: Congo, U. Thant, United Nations
              
              <lb/>
Stormy Sea in State: John F. Kennedy, Democratic Party, Republican Party, New Frontier
              
              <lb/>
Strain on the Poll Vaulter (LBJ): violence, civil rights, taxes, Great Society, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Strain on the Poll Vaulter (Nixon): Richard Nixon, Vietnam War, elections, peace
              
              <lb/>
Strategic Arms Limiting Talks: peace, nuclear weapons, Richard Nixon, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
Strength of Test: Cuba, United Nations, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, peace
              
              <lb/>
Striking Back With Fury: Muslims, Algeria, violence, terrorism
              
              <lb/>
Striking for His Country and Life: Vietnam War, Russia, armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Strong Man and His Problems: trucking industry, Teamsters, Jimmy Hoffa
              
              <lb/>
Sudden Loud Exclamation May Start an Avalanche: peace, disarmament, nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Suddenly It Came Alive: taxes, Congress, Lyndon Johnson, Britain
              
              <lb/>
Summer Heat Wave: communism, Robert McNamara, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Summertime in Washington: gun control, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Summit Rehearsal: Khrushchev, John F. Kennedy, Harold Macmillan, Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Sun is Shining Brighter: Canada, Pearson, nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Sunday — Day of Mourning: Robert F. Kennedy (1968)
              
              <lb/>
Support from Hubert Humphrey on the Vietnam War: Hubert Humphrey, Vietnam War, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Surely You Don't Mean Our Billy?: Congress, Democratic Party, Billie Sol Estes
              
              <lb/>
Surgery Wave: Winston Churchill
              
              <lb/>
Sweet Land of Liberty: Congress, unions, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Swallowing Up the Ocean to Save Himself from Drowning: Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Swinging the Lantern: strikes, unions, Congress, Lyndon Johnson</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>T</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Tackling the Tough Old Turkey: Lyndon Johnson, civil rights, defense, taxes, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Take a Good Look: China, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Take a Good Look, Fidel: Fidel Castro, armed forces, Guatemala, Nicaragua
              
              <lb/>
Take That Paper off the Table: United Nations, Andrei Gromyko, Congo, Adlai Stevenson, Dag Hammarskjold 
              
              <lb/>
Taking a Closer Look and: civil rights, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Taking Off Again: airline industry, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Taking the Family Out for a Stroll: John F. Kennedy, inflation, steel industry, railroad industry, unemployment, business
              
              <lb/>
Talking About Me!: Cold War, John F. Kennedy, Harold Macmillan, disarmament, Berlin, Russia, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Tax Cut: taxes, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Tell Khrush How to Understand Peace: peace, Andrei Gromyko, Berlin, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Terrifying Demonstration: Nikita Khrushchev, Berlin, Germany
              
              <lb/>
Terror Campaign Against Voters: Vietnam War, elections
              
              <lb/>
Test for U Thant: United Nations, U. Thant, Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Testing the Public: Congress, thalidomide
              
              <lb/>
Texan Look in Washington: Lyndon Johnson 
              
              <lb/>
Texas Cowboy: taxes, Congress, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
That Burning Fuse Again: Dominican Republic, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
That Guy Needs a Strait Jacket: Mikoyan, Cuba, China, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
That Limb Must be Cut: John F. Kennedy, Congress, Republican Party, budget
              
              <lb/>
That One I'll Have to Lasso: economy, Congress, Lyndon Johnson, budet, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
That's No Peace Dove: Asia, Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
That's Sweet Music to Me: communism, students, Cuba, Fidel Castro, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
Three Years After Test Ban: nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
They're Off: Republican Party, Barry Goldwater, Democratic Party, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
There's a Big Gap in This Table: defense, Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
There's a Santa Claus!: Cuba, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
This I Gotta See: taxes, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
This is Your Freedom: U.S. Flag, Bill of Rights
              
              <lb/>
This Would be Uncle Sam's Biggest Bang: Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Three-Headed Peace Maker (Moscow Style): Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Throw Out the Old, Bring in the New: welfare, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Throwing in His Own Card: Nikita Khrushchev, Congo, United Nations, disarmemenet
              
              <lb/>
The Tiger on the Loose: crime
              
              <lb/>
Tightrope Walker: Richard Nixon, anti-missile systems, Russia, China, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
To the Rescue: Lyndon Johnson, steel industry, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Toast to Tragedy: traffic fatalities
              
              <lb/>
Tobacco Road: smoking, cancer
              
              <lb/>
Too Many Fuses Burning: war, Iraq, Cuba, Latin America, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Tornado Aftermath: Illinois, natural disasters
              
              <lb/>
Tough Nest Eggs: peace, Lyndon Johnson, Ho Chi Minh, Mao Zedong, United Nations
              
              <lb/>
Tough World Series: Richard Nixon, Vietnam War, demonstrations
              
              <lb/>
Train to San Francisco: Barry Goldwater, William Scranton, Republican Party
              
              <lb/>
Travelling Salesman and the Hawks: China, Vietnam, Lyndon Johnson, peace, freedom, prosperity
              
              <lb/>
Tribute to Sir Winston Churchill: Winston Churchill (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Trick or Treat!: voting, Barry Goldwater, Lyndon Johnson, Republic Party, Democratic Party
              
              <lb/>
Trimming His Communist Beard: Fidel Castro, Brazil, economy
              
              <lb/>
Trouble Shooter: United Nations, U. Thant, Congo, Moise Tshombe
              
              <lb/>
Truce Talks Collapsed: peace, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Trying for a Homerun Record: Walter Reuther, United Auto Workers, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Trying Hard to Lose His Shadow: John F. Kennedy, taxes, unemploymenet, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Trying to Get It Together: United Nations, U.  Thant, Moise Tshombe, Congo
              
              <lb/>
Trying to Hatch It (U. Thant): U. Thant, United Nations, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Trying to Hatch It ("JFK" and "Congress Egg"): United Nations, Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Trying to Put Them to Sleep!: taxes, government spending, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Trying Hard to Rope' em: Lyndon Johnson, Congress, civil rights, taxes, budget, government spending
              
              <lb/>
Trying to Sidetrack It: railroad industry, strikes, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Trying to Wash His Hands of It: Lyndon Johnson, Walter Jenkins
              
              <lb/>
The TV Weather Eye Satellite Reporter: television, weather, space exporation
              
              <lb/>
`Twas the Night Before Christmas ("The World"): peace
              
              <lb/>
`Twas the Night Before Christmas" ("Ike"): Dwight Eisenhower, peace
              
              <lb/>
T'was the Week After Christmas: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Twentieth Century Foot Race: automation, progress, jobs
              
              <lb/>
Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the Japanese Attack: World War II, Pearl Harbor (1966)
              
              <lb/>
Twin Ships in Space Orbit: Nikita Khrushchev, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Two Views of LBJ: Lyndon Johnson, Great Society, Vietnam War
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>U</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>U Thant in Cuba: Cuba, U. Thant, Fidel Castro, Soviet Union, nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Un-American Committee Should Investigate These Words!: school prayer
              
              <lb/>
Uncle Sam Gets a Tighter Grip: Social Security, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Uncle Sam's Sore Neck: Honduras, Latin America
              
              <lb/>
Uncle Sam's Sore Pains: peace, Dominican Republic, South America
              
              <lb/>
Uncle Sam's Theme Song: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Under the Mistletoe: United Nations, Adlai Stevenson, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Undue Hardship Case in Washington: taxes, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Unexpected Space Flight: steel industry, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Unions Mud Throw: Lyndon Johnson, unions, railroad industry, Congress
              
              <lb/>
United Nation's Day: United Nations, peace
              
              <lb/>
United Nations Dove Flies to Cairo: U. Thant, United Nations, Middle East
              
              <lb/>
United Nation's Dove of Peace: nuclear weapons, United Nations, Arthur Goldberg, China, Rhodesia, Indonesia
              
              <lb/>
United Nations Dove Stays On: United Nations, U. Thant
              
              <lb/>
United Nations Missionary: Dag Hammarskjold, United Nations, Congo, Krhuschev
              
              <lb/>
United Nation's Mother Hubbard: Congo, Dag Hammarskjold, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
United Nations Peace Dove and the Hawk: Arthur Goldberg, peace, Andrei Gromyko, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
United Nations Peace Dove Flies Home: U. Thant, peace, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War, China
              
              <lb/>
United Nations Peace Efforts: Middle East, United Nations, peace, Lyndon Johnson, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
              
              <lb/>
United Nations' Santa's Black Eyes: United Nations, Adlai Stevenson, Congo
              
              <lb/>
United Nations' Smoke Clouds: U. Thant, United Nations, Congo
              
              <lb/>
United States and Soviet Space Flights: space exploration, Soviet Union
              
              <lb/>
United States Big Load Fighting Communists: Vietnam War, Robert McNamara
              
              <lb/>
United States Big Step to the Moon: space exploration
              
              <lb/>
United States the Breadwinner: hunger
              
              <lb/>
United States Greatest Production in Orbit: television, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
United States New Course: Soviet Union, Berlin, espionage
              
              <lb/>
United States Position in Vietnam: Vietnam War, China, Dean Rusk, Congress, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
United States Stars of Space Progress: space exploration, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
United States "Weather Eye" Photographer: weather, space exploration
              
              <lb/>
Unity Shattered: Black Power
              
              <lb/>
Up and Around: inflation, cost of living, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Unrest Troubles and Problems: Cuba, Latin America, poverty, Argentina, Guatemala
              
              <lb/>
Unsmiling Faces: freedom, nuclear weapons, peace, Cuba
</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>V</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>V — Day for Ludwig Erhard's Party: Ludwig Erhard, Christianity
              
              <lb/>
Vengeance or Justice?: Holocaust, Adolf Eichmann
              
              <lb/>
Verdict — "Guilty": Jack Ruby, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Veteran's Counteroffensive: armed forces, demonstrations, Vietnam War, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Veteran's Day: armed forces
              
              <lb/>
Vice President's Protest: Spiro T. Agnew, Richard Nixon, Vietnam War, television, journalism
              
              <lb/>
Viet and Western Fronts: Vietnam War, riots, Watts
              
              <lb/>
Vietcong Nine Lives: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson, peace, Ho
              
              <lb/>
Viet Cong's Violations Could be Used: Vietnam War, Richard Nixon
              
              <lb/>
Vietnam Duel: Dean Rusk, Wayne Morse, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Vietnam Election Observer: democracy, elections, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Vietnam Heat Wave: Vietnam War, Ho Chi Minh, communism
              
              <lb/>
Vietnam Jigsaw Puzzle: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Vietnam's Hunting Season: communism, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
View from Capitol Hill: Congress, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
View of World Armament Race: nuclear weapons, peace
              
              <lb/>
Volcano Eruption of Destruction: natural diasters, Philipines</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>W</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Waiting for a Southern Break: Barry Goldwater, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Wake Up — Here It Comes: John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Wales Slide Tragedy: Wales (1966)
              
              <lb/>
Walking the Police Dog: Walter Ulbricht, Nikita Khrushchev, Lyndon Johnson, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
Walking the Tightrope: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, Dominican Republic
              
              <lb/>
Wall of Shame: Berlin, riots, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Wall Should Come Down, Too: Berlin, Harold Macmillan, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Wanted: A Big Push: Kenndy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
War in Washington: Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, Jacob Javits, J. William Fulbright
              
              <lb/>
Warmonger: John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Warm — Up for Returning to Private Life: Dwight Eisenhower
              
              <lb/>
Warm Up on Cold War: Andrei Gromyko, Dean Rusk, Congress, Laos, Congo, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
War's End in Sight?" riots, civil rights, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Washington Balancer: Great Society, Lyndon Johnson, Congress, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Washington Balancing Act: taxes, Great Society, Vietnam War, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Washington Ball Game: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Washington Bumblebee: Congress, Lyndon Johnson, government spending, inflation
              
              <lb/>
Washington Dome: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Washington Round — Up Time: Lyndon Johnson, budget, defense
              
              <lb/>
Washington Rump Session: Congress, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Washington Showdown: taxes, Congress, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Washington Superman: Great Society, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War, J. William Fulbright, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Washington Woodchopper: taxes, government spending, John F. Kennedy, Congress, economy
              
              <lb/>
Washington's Broken Record: Dirksen, unions, right to work law
              
              <lb/>
Washington's Heat: John F. Kennedy, Congress, civil rights
              
              <lb/>
Washington's Magic Carpet: Social Security, Lyndon Johnson, Congress, taxes
              
              <lb/>
Washington's Strain on the Back: USS 
              
              <emph render="italic">Pueblo</emph>, Lyndon Johnson, North Korea, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Washington's Tree Pot: taxes, government spending, Congress, Great Society, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Washington's Whirlwind Pace: Nikita Khrushchev, New Frontier, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Watch on Miami and Caribbean: Fidel Castro, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
Watch Out for the Pitfall: China, Vietnam War, communism
              
              <lb/>
Watch What You Say: China, Soviet Union, Alexey Kosygin
              
              <lb/>
Watchful Vulture: Vietnam War, Philippines, peace, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
Watching the Candid Camera: space exploration, George Washington
              
              <lb/>
Watching the Clock: Congress, elections, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Watching the Dark Clouds: Cold War, Nikita Khrushchev, Mao Zedong, China, Soviet Union, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Watching the Explosive Unrest: Vietnam War, violence, terrorism
              
              <lb/>
Watching the Thermometer: civil rights
              
              <lb/>
We Are Winning the War Slowly: Robert McNamara, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
We Can Build Walls, Too: Russia, espionage
              
              <lb/>
We'll Get Him Under Control: nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev, Lyndon Johnson, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
We'll Have to Dive in Soon: taxes, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Well! Well! Did You Fall Off: disarmament, Nikita Khrushchev, Dean Rusk
              
              <lb/>
We Must Retain Control of Our Policy: Cuba, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
We Pray You Save Us from Ourselves: religion
              
              <lb/>
We Seek No Wider War: Vietnam War, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
We're Going to Bury Him Yet: Chou, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev, Tito, communism
              
              <lb/>
We're Happy that Ike is a Pennsylvanian: Dwight Eisenhower, Pennsylvania
              
              <lb/>
We're Ready for the Invasion: Fidel Castro, Cuba, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
Western Troops Get Out of Divided City: Russia, Khrushcev, space exploration, Berlin
              
              <lb/>
What a Beautiful Sunset: economy, poverty, propsperity, Lyndon Johnson, Appalachia
              
              <lb/>
What a Strange Two-Headed Monster: Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons, Russia
              
              <lb/>
What are the Answers? (Dean Rusk): Dean Rusk, Andrei Gromyko, disarmament, nuclear weapons, peace
              
              <lb/>
What are the Answers ("Massive Power Blackout, Plane Crashes"): aircraft accidents, power blackout, shipwrecks
              
              <lb/>
What Am I Fighting For and Against?: communism, Vietnam War, Great Society
              
              <lb/>
What Direction to Steer Clear: China, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
What Happens When This Cork is Pulled?: Congress, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
What, No Sugar?: Cuba, Fidel Castro, Russia, trade
              
              <lb/>
What's Ahead: economy
              
              <lb/>
What's Ahead in Vietnam by November: armed forces, defense, Robert McNamara, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
What's Ahead Now, Little Man?: New Year's (1965)
              
              <lb/>
What's It Doing to Our Children?: television
              
              <lb/>
What's Next? ("Cuban Crisis"): Nikita Khrushchev, Cuba, Berlin, Laos, Vietnam War, Iran
              
              <lb/>
What's Next ("JFK" and "Vienna Agreement on Laos"): Laos, Berlin, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, Thailand
              
              <lb/>
What's Next ("Kremlin Insincerity"): Berlin
              
              <lb/>
What's That — A Real Bomb?: Mao Zedong, China, John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
What's the Answer?: riots, New Jersey, Ohio, Pennsylvania
              
              <lb/>
What's the Rush?: Congress
              
              <lb/>
What's Yours?: taxes
              
              <lb/>
When a Fellow Needs a Lift: graduates, education, jobs
              
              <lb/>
When a Fellow Needs a Friend: school dropouts, jobs, education
              
              <lb/> When Pigs Fly: Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro, Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy
              
              <lb/>
Where Do We Go from Here?: peace, Soviet Union, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Where's My Communist Friend?: Fidel Castro, Cuba, hungar, economy
              
              <lb/>
Whew — That Was Just a Little Too Close: Charles De Gaulle
              
              <lb/>
Which Bucket is Victory?: Republican Party, M.C. Smith, Richard Nixon, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Harold Stassen, Nelson Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater
              
              <lb/>
Which is Your Choice?: Democratic Party, Republican Party, voting
              
              <lb/>
Which Road to Starting Point: John F. Kennedy, NATO, Soviet Union, China, Africa, Cuba
              
              <lb/>
While Our Boys Die in Vietnam: Vietnam War, demonstrations, China, Ho
              
              <lb/>
While We Enjoy Our Holidays: Labor Day, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
Whirling Dervish: Egypt, Israle, Middle East, Suez Canal
              
              <lb/>
White House Astronaut: space exploration, forieng aid, economy, John F. Kennedy, Congress
              
              <lb/>
White House Baker: Congress, Lyndon Johnson
              
              <lb/>
White House Chef: Lyndon Johnson, foreign policy
              
              <lb/>
White House "Club": Lyndon Johnson, business, aluminum industry
              
              <lb/>
White House Portrait: Lyndon Johnson, economy, defense, employment
              
              <lb/>
White House Santa: John F. Kennedy, South America, foreign policy
              
              <lb/>
White House Skier: Great Society, Lyndon Johnson, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Who's Going to Control the Button: nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Who's Going to Put Out the Fire: United Nations, Cyprus, U. Thant, Makarios III
              
              <lb/>
Who's Going to Save Me?: taxes
              
              <lb/>
Who's Next?: Dominicna Republic, Vietnam War, Colombia, Venezuela
              
              <lb/>
Who's Winning?: civil rights, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Why?: aircraft accidents
              
              <lb/>
Why Can't We Be Friends?: Jawaharlal Nehru, Mao Zedong, China
              
              <lb/>
Why Can't We Talk of Our Moon Trips?: Berlin, nuclear weapons, John F. Kennedy, Khrushcev
              
              <lb/>
Why Fight Over Berlin?: Berlin, Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
Why We're Misunderstood: television
              
              <lb/>
Widening the Viet War: Vietnam War, Ho Chi Minh, Lyndon Johnson, peace
              
              <lb/>
Will it be Sidetracked: Congress, railroad industry, strikes
              
              <lb/>
Will it Bite the Hand that Feeds Him: foreign aid
              
              <lb/>Will the Train Stop: Congress, railroad industry, strikes
              
              <lb/>
The Winner: Georges Pompidou, France, Charles De Gaulle, elections
              
              <lb/>
Winning the Politicians Award: taxes, Congress
              
              <lb/>
Winston's Birthday Smoke: Winston Churchill
              
              <lb/>
Woman Scorned: natural diasaster, Texas, Louisana
              
              <lb/>
World Angers (dangers of war): Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons 
              
              <lb/>
World Angers ("Super Bomb Blast"): Nikita Khrushchev, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
World Mourns: Pope John XXIII
              
              <lb/>
World Series: Ho Chi Minh, Soviet Union, Lyndon Johnson, Vietnam War
              
              <lb/>
World of Today: China, Vietnam War, George Washington
              
              <lb/>
World's "Atomic Club" Member: Charles De Gaulle, nuclear weapons, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>
World's Population Growing: United Nations, population
              
              <lb/>
World's Public Servant Goes Home: Hebert Hoover (1964)
              
              <lb/>
Worthwhile Contribution: Pennslyvania, charity
              
              <lb/>
Writing on the Wall:
United Nations, Greece, Turkey, Cyprus</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Y</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent>
            <p>Yaaa — The Last Nuclear Test. So There!: nuclear weapons, Nikita Khrushchev, disarmament
              
              <lb/>
You Better Let Me Fix It: poverty, politicians
              
              <lb/>
You Came Here as a "Courageous Warrior": Nikita Khrushchev, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Egypt, peace
              
              <lb/>
You Must Get Back into the Bottle: John F. Kennedy, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
 
You Got Our Message, Nikita: Germany, Nikita Khrushchev
              
              <lb/>You'll Have to Bury Him: Alexey Kosygin, Nikita Khrushchev, China
              
              <lb/>
Young Man's Competitor: automation, graduates
              
              <lb/>
You're in a Tough Spot: steel industry, economy, strikes 
              
              <lb/>
You're Pretty With That Lovely Ribbon: Congress, nuclear weapons
              
              <lb/>
You're Quarantined!: John F. Kennedy, Cuba, Nikita Khrushchev, Fidel Castro
              
              <lb/>
Your Country Needs You: John F. Kennedy, Republican Party</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
