<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 1.5, 5/26/2006 -->
<!--Added description of how to enter revisions-->

<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
	<!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->

<eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
		<eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="stewart_dw">stewart_dw</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper encodinganalog="Title">David W. Stewart Papers</titleproper>
				<subtitle>An  inventory of his papers at Syracuse University</subtitle>
			<author encodinganalog="Creator">MRR</author><sponsor>The adult education holdings are collectively known as the <lb/><extptr title="Alexander N. Charters Library of Resources for Educators of Adults" href="https://library.syr.edu/scrc/collections/areas/adult-ed.php" show="new"/>.</sponsor></titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>
				&su_address;
				<date normal="2006-08-04" encodinganalog="Date">4 Aug 2006</date>
			</publicationstmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Michele Rothenberger
				<date normal="2006-08-04">4 Aug 2006</date>
			</creation>
			<langusage>
				<language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
			</langusage>
		</profiledesc>
		<!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"--><revisiondesc>
			<list>
				<item></item>
			</list>
		</revisiondesc>
	</eadheader>
	<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
		<did>
			<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
			<repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">
			&su_name; <lb/> &su_address;
			</repository>
			<origination label="Creator: ">
				<persname encodinganalog="100">Stewart, David Wood, 1929-</persname>
			</origination>
			<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">David W. Stewart Papers</unittitle>
			<unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1980/1987" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1980-1987</unitdate>
			  <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: "><extent>6.5 linear ft.</extent></physdesc>
			<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Papers relating to Stewart's book on Eduard Lindeman, educator and social philosopher.   Includes interviews, correspondence, notes, drafts, photocopies of many of Lindeman's papers from Columbia University</abstract>
			<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="us" repositorycode="NSyU">2463718</unitid>
			<langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
				
		<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
			<head>Biographical History</head>
			
		<p><emph render="bold">David W. Stewart</emph></p><p>David W. Stewart is a consultant,  columnist and author, university instructor, policy analyst, workshop leader, and public speaker in adult education.  He was Director of Program Development at the Center for Adult Learning and Educational Credentials at the American Council on Education and President of the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) in 1988-1989.  He served as a member of the Planning Committee for the First World Conference on Lifelong Learning held in Rome in 1994. </p><p>As President of CAEO, he helped organize the New Sweden '88 Adult Education Conference in celebration of 350 years of Swedish settlement in America, and organized an exchange visit of Soviet adult educators to the United States under an agreement concluded with Znanie, the official Soviet adult education agency.

</p><p>He is widely published and the recipient of the Imogene Okes Award for Outstanding Research in Adult Education in 1987 and the Philip Frandson Award for Literature in 1988. He is the principal author of the "Bill of Rights for the Adult Learner" and "Guidelines for Developing and Implementing a Code of Ethics for Adult Educators," and the author of <emph render="italic">Adult Learning in America: Eduard Lindeman and His Agenda for Lifelong Education</emph>.</p><p><emph render="bold">Eduard Lindeman</emph></p><p>Eduard Christian Lindemann (he later dropped the final "n")  was born May 9th 1885, in St Clair, Michigan, the tenth child of German-Danish immigrant parents Frederick and Frederecka Johanna Von Piper Lindemann.  He attended Michigan Agricultural College (later Michigan State University) where he became involved in the YMCA, developed a writing society and helped to found the Ethnic-Sociological Society. After graduation, he  worked with the Boys and Girls Clubs and 4-H as a youth worker and community organizer.  He taught at the YMCA College of Chicago for a year and briefly at the North Carolina College for Women in Greensboro, then joined the New York School of Social Work (later the Columbia University School of Social Work) in 1924, where he remained until his retirement in 1950. He became closely associated with the leftist <emph render="italic">New Republic</emph> (whose writers included  H. L. Mencken, John Dos Passos, Willa Cather and Michael Gold), served on various commissions, was advisory editor to Mentor Books and was Chair of the American Civil Liberties Union Commission on Academic Freedom (1949).</p><p>Over the course of his career, Lindeman published some 200 articles, 107 book reviews, five books, 16 monographs, and 17 chapters in other works. He edited four books, shared joint authorship of another, and gave at least 44 lectures of which some written record remains.</p><p>Lindeman's life and work (for he did not separate the two) were not confined within traditional borders; his writing displays a broad viewpoint that encompassed adult education, community organization, politics, sociology and philosophy.  Much of his philosophical outlook was shaped by his friend and colleague John Dewey, by Danish philosopher/educator/theologian Nikolai Grundtvig, and by Ralph Waldo Emerson.  In her book on him, his daughter Betty writes:</p><blockquote><p>Not only could he relate education, social sciences and social problems to the problems of the day; he could combine concepts from social sciences with both natural sciences and philosophy. He was a pioneer on many interlocking fronts – a pioneer social scientist with an allegiance to both science and to society and its processes, and also a pioneer in adult education and social philosophy. (Leonard 1991: xxiii)</p></blockquote><p>Lindeman was a Progressive; his theories and allegiances did not sit well with some in 1940s America.  When he was invited to speak before the Texas State Teachers' Association, a faction attempted to have him removed from the program on the grounds that he was a member of the ACLU and the Committee to Free Earl Browder, and therefore must be a Communist.</p><p>Lindeman was not one to separate education from the rest of life.  "Education is life," he wrote in <emph render="italic">The Meaning of Adult Education</emph>.  He saw adult education not as an end in itself but as a continuous process, arising not from formalized, structured classrooms but from every situation encountered, which had as its purpose to relate the individual to his community and to put meaning into the whole of life.  Above all, adult education was a social effort, central to the health and maintenance of democracy.  His life and work demonstrate his abiding concern for social justice, a belief in the possibilities of education and human action, and a deep commitment to democracy.  </p></bioghist>
		
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
			<head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
			<p>Apart from a single folder of columns that Stewart wrote for <emph render="italic">Adult and Continuing Education Today</emph>, the <emph render="bold">David W. Stewart Papers</emph> consists of  Stewart's voluminous notes and research materials for his book on Eduard Lindeman.   Much of it is photocopies (of Lindeman's correspondence, articles, book excerpts, etc); the remainder is Stewart's own notes and drafts, some handwritten and some typed.</p><p><emph render="bold">Lindeman biography</emph> contains material related to the research, writing and publication of Stewart's biography of Eduard Lindeman.  </p><p>Material  related to specific chapters of Stewart's book comprises <emph render="underline">Chapter files</emph>.  Folder titles are those supplied by Stewart; corresponding chapter numbers have been added in brackets.</p><p><emph render="underline">Subject files</emph> cover Lindeman's family (including Denmark and Danish ancestry, Lindeman's wife Hazel and daughter Betty), friends, and colleagues; aspects of education (discussion method, importance of life experiences, workers education; other adult educators (Basil Yeaxlee, Malcolm Knowles, Mary Parker Follet); and various general topics (capitalism, Germany, Russia, politics, propaganda, religion, racial discrimination).</p><p>Lindeman was close friends for many years with social activist and philanthropist Dorothy Straight Elmhirst.  Dorothy and her first husband, Willard Straight, founded <emph render="italic">New Republic</emph>; with her second husband, Leonard, she founded Dartington Hall, an experiment in progressive education and rural reconstruction in Totnes, Devon.  Material on Dorothy can be found in the <ref target="dose">Dorothy</ref> and <ref target="daha">Dartington Hall</ref> folders.  Other individuals of interest in the collection include Mary Parker Follett (social worker, consultant, and author of books on democracy, human relations, and management); Herbert Croly (journalist and another friend of Dorothy Straight); Betty Leonard (daughter of Lindeman and author of a biography of him -- a manuscript of her book is included); and Max Otto (atheist, pacifist and professor of philosophy at the University of Wisconsin).</p><p><emph render="underline">Photographs</emph> includes photographs of Lindeman, his family, and a few other individuals, including several of Dorothy Straight Elmhirst.</p><p><emph render="underline">Miscellaneous</emph> contains two doctoral dissertations, several audiocassettes of interviews, an audiocassette of Hazel Taft Lindeman's memorial service, and approximately two thousand index cards of Stewart's research notes, divided by subject.</p><p> Awards, critiques, prospectus sent to publishers, publisher correspondence, and reviews are found in <emph render="underline">Reactions to the book</emph>.</p><p><emph render="bold">Other writings</emph> consists of a single folder containing clippings of "Trendlines," a regular column Stewart wrote for  <emph render="italic">Adult and Continuing Education Today</emph>.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		
		<arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
			<head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
			<p>Subject file folders are arranged in alphabetical order, their titles and contents exactly as supplied by Stewart.   Folder titles for the most part are self-explanatory; where necessary additional information is provided in brackets [ ].  "See also" references have been added where appropriate.  The contents of the folders are as Stewart had them, apart from the few correspondence files whose contents have been arranged by date.</p><p>Some of the subject files contain note cards.  These have been left as Stewart had them.  In some cases the cards are clipped together into sections, in others they are loose.  Some were rubber-banded but the rubber bands had decayed or disintegrated so have been removed.</p><p>The bulk of the note cards were in a single carton.  These have been kept in the divisions given them by Stewart as much as possible, though divisions may not always be accurate as the cards shifted about during shipment.</p>
		</arrangement>
		
		<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
			<head>Related Material</head>
			<p></p><p>The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education.  Please refer to &subjindex; for a complete listing.  Collections particularly related to this one include:</p>
		<list><item><extref href="../c/caeo.htm">Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) Records</extref></item><item><extref href="../k/knowles_ms.htm">Malcolm S. Knowles Papers</extref></item></list></relatedmaterial>
		
		<!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
			<head>Separated Material</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
		</separatedmaterial>-->
		
		<!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
			<head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
		</otherfindaid>-->
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Adult education</subject>
			<!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc).  
Some have defaults set in the template.-->
            <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">	Elmhirst, Dorothy Payne Whitney Straight</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Grundtvig, N. F. S. (Nicolai Frederik Severin), 1783-1872</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Lindeman, Eduard</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Stewart, David Wood, 1929-</persname>
			
            
            <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf">Adult Learning in America: Eduard Lindeman and His Agenda for Lifelong Education</title>
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Adult education</subject>
			
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Drafts (documents)</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Research notes.</genreform>
			<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Educator</occupation>
			</controlaccess>
		
		<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
			<head>Access Restrictions</head>
			<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		
		<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
			<head>Use Restrictions</head>
			<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
		</userestrict>
		
		<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
			<head>Preferred Citation</head>
			<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
			<p> David W. Stewart Papers, <lb/> &su_name; </p>
		</prefercite>
		
		<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
			<head>Acquisition Information</head>
			<p>Gift of David W. Stewart</p>
		</acqinfo>
		
		<!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
			<head>Appraisal Information</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
		</appraisal>-->
		
		<!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
			<head>Accruals</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
		</accruals>-->
		
		<dsc type="combined"><head>Inventory</head><note><p>All folder titles are as supplied by Stewart.  Additional clarification added as applicable during processing  appears in brackets [ ].</p></note><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Lindeman biography</unittitle></did><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Chapter files</unittitle></did><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Preface"</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Fresh Hope" [ch. 1]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="chap-root">
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Understanding Adult Learning at its Roots" [ch. 2]</unittitle>
						
						<physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Subject files: <ref target="sub-root">Roots</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Young Man in a Hurry" [ch. 3]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="chap-soac">
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Social Action and Adult Ed" [ch. 5]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Subject files: <ref target="sub-soac">Social action</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"1925" [ch. 6]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"<emph render="italic">The Meaning of Adult Education</emph> in its Time" [ch. 7]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">1</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="rean">
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Rediscovering Andragogy" [ch. 8]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">2</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Subject files: <ref target="tlak">Teaching/learning: Andragogy/Knowles</ref></p></note></c03><c03 id="dain">
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Danish influence" [ch. 9]</unittitle>
						
						<physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">2</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Subject files: <ref target="degr">Denmark/Grundtvig</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"The Importance of Life Experience" [ch. 10]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">2</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Adult educators as facilitators" [ch. 11]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">2</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="lide">
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Lifeblood of Democracy" [ch. 12]</unittitle>
						
						<physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Subject files: <ref target="demo">Democracy</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Crisis" [ch. 14]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"Post-War World" [ch. 15]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03></c02><c02 level="subseries">
				<did>
					<unittitle>Subject files</unittitle>
				<!--c02 @LEVEL must be set to 'series' to show up in TOC.--></did>
				<c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>AAAE beginnings</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Adult ed - general</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Beers, Marion</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Books and articles</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Capitalism</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Caribbean/Porto Rico [sic]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Characteristics</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">3</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Childhood and early life</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle><emph render="italic">College Characters</emph></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Columbia University</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Communism</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Conference</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Cornell archives</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence - general</unittitle>
						
						<unitdate normal="1980/1987" type="inclusive">1980-1987</unitdate><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="cobl">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence - Betty Leonard</unittitle>
						
						<unitdate normal="1975" type="inclusive">1975, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1980/1987" type="inclusive">1980-1987</unitdate><container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also <ref target="bele">Leonard [Betty, ECL's daughter]</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Croly, Herbert</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dallas and Texas</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Danish ancestry</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="daha">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dartington Hall</unittitle>
						
						<abstract>This folder contains photocopies of ECL's correspondence with Dorothy Straight Elmhirst, Leonard Elmhirst, and Wyatt Rawson</abstract><container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also <ref target="dose">Dorothy [Straight Leonard]</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Death/tributes</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">4</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="demo">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Democracy</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">5</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Chapter files:  <ref target="lide">Lifeblood of Democracy</ref></p></note></c03><c03 id="degr">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Denmark/Grundtvig</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">5</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also <ref target="dain">Danish influence</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dewey, John</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">5</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Discussion method</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">5</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="dose">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dorothy [Straight Elmhirst]</unittitle>
						
						<abstract>correspondence between Dorothy and ECL (photocopies from various libraries and archives), most from 1920 - 1940</abstract><container type="Box">5</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also <ref target="daha">Dartington Hall</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Emerson [, Ralph Waldo]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Extension</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Family life</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Friendships</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>General info</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Germany 1945</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Gessner, Robert (his book)</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle><emph render="italic">The Gleaner</emph></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Greystone [ECL's home]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Hallowell [, Bob]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Hazel [Taft Lindeman, ECL's wife]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>India</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>"The Inquiry"</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Institutions</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Interviews</unittitle>
						
						<abstract>photocopied transcripts of interviews with Martha Anderson, Roger Baldwin, Flora Thurston Allen, Byron Mock, Sally Ringe Goldmark, Valerie Keating.  Except for Martha Anderson, who was interviewed by Stewart's daughter Miriam, the interviews were conducted by Betty Leonard in the 1970s for her book on Lindeman.</abstract><container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Italy</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Konopka, Gisela (her book)</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Learner (ECL as)</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="bele">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Leonard [Betty, ECL's daughter]</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also <ref target="cobl">Correspondence - Betty Leonard</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Letters to me (re ECL)</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Lying</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">6</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Manuscript (Betty Leonard's)</unittitle>
						
						<physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Mary Parker Follett <emph render="italic">Creative Experience</emph></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>McGraw, Harriet</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Michigan State University</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Narrative (mostly unused)</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle><emph render="italic">New Republic</emph></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>New York (Columbia) Soc. Wk. School</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>North Carolina</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Otto, Max</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Paperback books</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">7</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Parent education</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Peace (Ad. Ed. for)</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Politics</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Promotion</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Propaganda</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Prophetic</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Racial discrim.</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Rauschenbusch lectures</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Recreation/leisure</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Religion</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="sub-root">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Roots</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Chapter files: <ref target="chap-root"> 	"Understanding Adult Learning at its Roots" [ch. 2]</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Russia</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Shaw, Charles</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="sub-soac">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Social action</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Chapter files: <ref target="chap-soac"> 	"Social Action and Adult Ed" [ch. 5]</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Social discovery</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches/themes</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Survey/survey graph</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">8</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03 id="tlak">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Teaching/learning: Andragogy/Knowles</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				<note><p>See also Chapter files: <ref target="rean">"Rediscovering Andragogy" [ch. 8]</ref></p></note></c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Trivia</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>University of Minnesota</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Volunteerism</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Washington/WPA</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle><emph render="italic">Wealth &amp; Culture</emph></unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>What adult educators should do for America</unittitle>
						
						<physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Workers' education</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Yeaxlee, Basil</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>YMCA Chicago</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03></c02><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle></did><c03><did>
						<unittitle>Miscellaneous photos</unittitle>
						
						<abstract>ECL, family and friends, including several of Dorothy Straight Elmhirst</abstract><container type="Box">9</container>
						
						
						
					</did></c03></c02><c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Reaction to the book</unittitle></did><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Awards</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">10</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did>
						<unittitle>Critiques by readers</unittitle>
						
						<container type="Box">10</container>
						
						
						
					</did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did><unittitle>Prospectus (prop. to publisher)</unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did><unittitle>Publishers (corres./info.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1981/1986">1981-1986</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did>
				</c03><c03>
					<did><unittitle>Reviews</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">10</container></did>
				</c03></c02><c02 level="subseries">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
						
						
						
						
						
					</did>
				<c03><did><unittitle>Contee, Jerome A.  "The Politics of Education Decision making for K-12 Public Education in Washington, D.C.  (doctoral dissertation)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1974-08">Aug 1974</unitdate><physdesc><extent>1 reel microfilm</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Finlay, Kenneth Wayne.  "Policy Development in an American University: A Description of a Political Process (doctoral dissertation)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><physdesc><extent>1 reel microfilm</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Hazel Taft Lindeman Memorial Service</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980-08-20">20 Aug 1980</unitdate><physdesc><extent>1 audiocassette</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Interviews</unittitle><physdesc><extent>11 audiocassettes</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Research notes (4" x 6" index cards)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>4 boxes</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Other writings</unittitle></did><c02><did><unittitle>"Trendlines"</unittitle><abstract>regular column written for <emph render="italic">Adult and Continuing Education Today</emph></abstract><container type="Box">10</container></did></c02></c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
