<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY scrconline SYSTEM "scrconline.txt">
<!ENTITY searchcoll SYSTEM "searchcoll.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 1.5, 5/26/2006 -->
<!--Added description of how to enter revisions-->

<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
	<!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->

<eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
		<eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="supce">supce</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education (SUPCE) Records</titleproper>
				<subtitle>An inventory of its records at Syracuse University</subtitle>
			<author encodinganalog="Creator">MRR</author><sponsor>The adult education holdings are collectively known as the <lb/><extptr title="Alexander N. Charters Library of Resources for Educators of Adults" href="https://library.syr.edu/scrc/collections/areas/adult-ed.php" show="new"/>.</sponsor></titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>
				&su_address;
				<date normal="1991-07-22" encodinganalog="Date">22 Jul 1991</date>
			</publicationstmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Michele Rothenberger
				<date normal="2006-08-02">2 Aug 2006</date>
			</creation>
			<langusage>
				<language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
			</langusage>
		</profiledesc>
		<!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"--><revisiondesc>
			<list>
<item>2 Aug 2006 - additions, reorg, converted to EAD (MRR)</item>
<item>24 Aug 2007 - additions, description updated (MRC)</item>
<item>26 May 2008 - additions (MRC)</item>
<item>8 Jul 2009 - OCP 59 added (MRC)</item><item>20 Jun 2011 - MSS 15 and 33 added (MRC)</item><item>8 Mar 2016 - REP139 located and returned (MRC)</item><item>23 Jun 2016 - MSS21 correction (MRC)</item><item>5 Jun 2018 - REP144 found (MRC)</item>
			</list>
		</revisiondesc>
	</eadheader>
	<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
		<did>
			<head>Overview of the Collection</head>
			<repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">
			&su_name; <lb/> &su_address;
			</repository>
			<origination label="Creator: ">
				<corpname encodinganalog="110">Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education.</corpname>
			</origination>
			<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education (SUPCE) Records</unittitle>
			<unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1951/2008" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1951-2008</unitdate>
			  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" normal="1955/1975" type="inclusive" label="Bulk Dates: ">1955-1975</unitdate><physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: "><extent>19 linear ft.</extent></physdesc>
			<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Material collected or published by Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education (SUPCE). Publications include original monographs as well as works  from the Clearinghouse of Resources for Educators of Adults, Fund for Adult Education, the International Seminar on Adult Education, the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, ERIC, American Foundation for Continuing Education, the Library of Continuing Education at Syracuse University, and miscellaneous publications by notable adult educators including Alexander N. Charters, Cyril O. Houle, J. Roby Kidd, A.A. Liveright, John Ohliger, James B. Whipple, et al.  There are also three boxes of administrative files.</abstract>
			<unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="us" repositorycode="NSyU">148693</unitid>
			<langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
				
		<processinfo><p>During processing (Aug 2006), Box 9 could not be found.  All box 9 items have been marked [MISSING] until it can be located.</p></processinfo><bioghist encodinganalog="545">
			<head>Biographical History</head>
			
		<p>In 1969 the Ford Foundation approved a five-year grant to Syracuse University for the continued availability, distribution, and servicing of materials developed by the American Foundation for Continuing Education and the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, both former grantees of the Ford Foundation's Fund for Adult Education.  Prior to that, in 1950, University College (UC) of Syracuse University (SU) had published a series of "blue books" in the field; the University's Library of Continuing Education (LCE) developed and published a number of works in the 1960s; and ERIC initiated documents, which the University had published alone or in cooperation with other institutions.  All began to be collected under the general rubric of SUPCE, along with significant works by prominent adult educators and material published by other adult education organizations such as the Fund for Adult Education.  Doris Chertow served as the editor for the publications under SU's Vice President for Continuing Education, Alexander N. Charters.</p><p>Although SUPCE's federal funding ended in 1975, it continued to release updates to  original SUPCE publications as well as publishing the occasional new monograph under its own name and, later, under the auspices of the Academic Institute for Educators of Adults (AIEA) within the School of Education at Syracuse University, until 2008.</p></bioghist>
		
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
			<head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
			<p>The <emph render="bold">Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education (SUPCE) Records</emph> consists of a near-complete set of all material collected or published by SUPCE, along with drafts of some items and some administrative files for both SUPCE and Syracuse Resources for Educators of Adults (SUREA).  Individuals well-known in the field of adult education represented in the collection include Robert J. Blakely, Alexander N. Charters, Roger DeCrow, Cyril O. Houle, J. Roby Kidd, A. A. (Alexander Albert) Liveright, Paul H. Sheats, John Ohliger, and James B. Whipple.</p><p><emph render="bold">Drafts, notes and galleys</emph> contains pre-publication versions of a few SUPCE publications.  </p><p><emph render="bold">Publications</emph> contains a nearly-complete set of all items published, reprinted, or collected by SUPCE over the course of its existence.  Although SUPCE's federal funding ended in 1975, updates to many of its publications as well as the occasional new SUPCE monograph have been released on an irregular basis over the years, under the auspices of the Academic Institute for Educators of Adults (AIEA) within the school of education at Syracuse University.  The publications are divided into several subseries which are arranged alphabetically; individual items are in numerical order  by their three-letter code.  </p><p>Note that several of the MSS subseries documents contain lists of SUPCE publications or resources.  These were accurate at the time of compilation but naturally may have since been superseded; this finding aid comprises the most complete and current listing.  Because a complete list of SUPCE materials does not exist elsewhere, we have taken the unusual step of making the list given here in the finding aid complete, despite the fact that the collection itself is not.  Items missing from the collection are indicated by the notation "[MISSING]" immediately following the three-letter code and preceding the title of the item.   As of August 2006, Box 9 was missing.  All items in that box are therefore marked as [MISSING].</p><p><emph render="bold">Administrative files</emph> and <emph render="bold">SUREA</emph> comprise office files pertaining to the operation of these two organizations, including correspondence, financial records, order logs, and more.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		
		<arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
			<head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
			
		<p>Material is sorted alphabetically by SUPCE's three-letter codes, and within that titles are listed numerically.</p></arrangement>
		
		<altformavail encodinganalog="530">
         <head>Other Formats Available</head>
         <p>Many of the MSS series documents have been digitized and are available online.  To view these document, please click <extref href="http://library.syr.edu/digital/guides/a/AlexanderNCharters/ms_docs.htm">here</extref>.</p>
      </altformavail><relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
			<head>Related Material</head>
			<p>The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education.  Please refer to &subjindex; for a complete listing.</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		
		<!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
			<head>Separated Material</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
		</separatedmaterial>-->
		
		<!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
			<head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
		</otherfindaid>-->
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Subject and Genre Headings</head><subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Adult education</subject>
			<!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc).  
Some have defaults set in the template.-->
            <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Blakely, Robert J. </persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Charters, Alexander N.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Chertow, Doris.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">DeCrow, Roger.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Houle, Cyril Orvin,  1913-</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Kidd, J. R. (James Robbins), 1915-1982.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Liveright, A. A. (Alexander Albert),  1907-</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Sheats, Paul H., 1907-</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Ohliger, John.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Whipple, James B.</persname>
			
            <corpname encodinganalog="611" source="local">International Seminar on Adult Education.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">American Foundation for Continuing Education.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults.</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Fund for Adult Education (U.S.)</corpname>
            
            <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Adult education.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Educational publishing.</subject>
			
            <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Bibliographies.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Drafts (documents)</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Essays.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Monographs.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Pamphlets.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Reports.</genreform>
			<occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Educators.</occupation>
			</controlaccess>
		
		<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
			<head>Access Restrictions</head>
			<p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		
		<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
			<head>Use Restrictions</head>
			<p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
		</userestrict>
		
		<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
			<head>Preferred Citation</head>
			<p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
			<p>Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education (SUPCE) Records, <lb/> &su_name; </p>
		</prefercite>
		
		<!--<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
			<head>Acquisition Information</head>
			<p>### (MARC 541 and/or  561)</p>
		</acqinfo>-->
		
		<!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
			<head>Appraisal Information</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
		</appraisal>-->
		
		<!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
			<head>Accruals</head>
			<p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
		</accruals>-->
		
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>Inventory</head>
			<c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Drafts, notes and galleys</unittitle></did>
   <c02 id="dng-afc48"><did><unittitle>AFC48 Science and Public Policy (AFCE/Oceana)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>7 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">1</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: American Foundation for Continuing Education (AFCE) series (AFC): <ref target="afc48">AFC48 Science and Public Policy (AFCE/Oceana)</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-lnh2"><did><unittitle>LNH2 The Cooperative Extension Service: Paradoxical Servant (Miller, Paul A.)</unittitle><container type="Box">1</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Landmark and New Horizons series (LNH): <ref target="lnh2">LNH2 The Cooperative Extension Service: Paradoxical Servant</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes59"><did><unittitle>NES59 The System of Adult Education in Yugoslavia (Savicevic, Dusan M.)</unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes59">NES59 The System of Adult Education in Yugoslavia</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes60"><did><unittitle>NES60 Liberal Education Reconsidered: Reflections on Continuing Education for Contemporary Man (Whipple, James B. Goldman, Freda H. Haygood, Kenneth Siegle, Peter)</unittitle><container type="Box">2</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes60">NES60 Liberal Education Reconsidered: Reflections on Continuing Education for Contemporary Man</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes61"><did><unittitle>NES61 Aim: From Concept to Reality (Wedemeyer, Charles A. Najem, Robert E.)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">2</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes61">NES61 Aim: From Concept to Reality</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes62"><did><unittitle>NES62 Dilemmas of American Policy: Crucial Issues in Contemporary Society (Cook, Samuel Dubois Stern, George G. Green, Thomas F. Weiner, Anthony J.)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">2, 3</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes62">NES62 Dilemmas of American Policy: Crucial Issues in Contemporary Society</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes63"><did><unittitle>NES63 Knowledge is Power to Control Power (Blakely, Robert Lappin, I.)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">3</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes63">NES63 Knowledge is Power to Control Power</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes64"><did><unittitle>NES64 The University and Community Service (Whipple, James B. Chertow, Doris)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">3</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes64">NES64 The University and Community Service</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes65"><did><unittitle>NES65 Essays on New Careers: Social Implications for Adult Educators (Riessman, Frank Rosen, Sumner M. Featherstone, Joseph Gartner, Alan)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>8 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">4</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes65">NES65 Essays on New Careers: Social Implications for Adult Educators</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes66"><did><unittitle>NES66 Essays on the Future of Continuing Education Worldwide (Ziegler, Warren)</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">4</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes66">NES66 Essays on the Future of Continuing Education Worldwide</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes69"><did><unittitle>NES69 Ends and Means: The National Conference on Continuing Education in Nursing (McHenry, Ruth W.)</unittitle><container type="Box">4</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes69">NES69 Ends and Means: The National Conference on Continuing Education in Nursing</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes70"><did><unittitle>NES70 Residential Continuing Education (Houle, Cyril O.)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes70">NES70 Residential Continuing Education </ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-nes71"><did><unittitle>NES71 Selected Concepts from Educational Psychology and Adult Education for Extension and Continuing Educators (Leagans, J. Paul Copeland, Harlan G. Kaiser, Gertrude E.)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Notes and Essays and Reports in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES): <ref target="nes71">NES71 Selected Concepts from Educational Psychology and Adult Education for Extension and Continuing Educators</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-ocp19"><did><unittitle>OCP19 Accent on Adults: The Small College Program at Brooklyn (Jacobson, Myrtle S. Offenbacher, Deborah I.)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP): <ref target="ocp19">OCP19 Accent on Adults: The Small College Program at Brooklyn</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-ocp20"><did><unittitle>OCP20 Faculty Perceptions of Continuing Education at Syracuse University (Porter, Lee)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP): <ref target="ocp20">OCP20 Faculty Perceptions of Continuing Education at Syracuse University</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-ocp21"><did><unittitle>OCP21 Community Service and Continuing Education (Whipple, James B.)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP): <ref target="ocp21">OCP21 Community Service and Continuing Education</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-ocp22"><did><unittitle>OCP22 Adult Education and the Disadvantaged Adult (Anderson, Darrel Niemi, John)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP): <ref target="ocp22">OCP22 Adult Education and the Disadvantaged Adult</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-ocp24"><did><unittitle>OCP24 Lifelong Learning or Lifelong Schooling: A Tentative View of the Ideas of Ivan Illich (Ohliger, John McCarthy, C.)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP): <ref target="ocp24">OCP24 Lifelong Learning or Lifelong Schooling: A Tentative View of the Ideas of Ivan Illich</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02 id="dng-ocp25"><did><unittitle>OCP25 The Learning Force: A More Comprehensive Framework for Educational Policy (Moses, Stanley)</unittitle><container type="Box">5</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP): <ref target="ocp25">OCP25 The Learning Force: A More Comprehensive Framework for Educational Policy</ref></p></note></c02>
</c01>
<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle>Publications</unittitle>
				<!--C01 @LEVEL must be set to 'series' to show up in TOC.--></did>
				   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>American Foundation for Continuing Education (AFCE) series (AFC)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC1 Economics and Politics (Harlan, H. C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC2 Readings in World Politics v. 1-4, plus Discussion Leader's Manual</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951">1951</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC3 Readings in World Politics v. 1-3, 2nd edition </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC4 Readings in World Politics, Vol. 1, 2 (Goldwin, Robert A. and Lerner, Ralph; Stourzh, Gerald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC5 Readings in World Politics, Session Guides (Staff, American Foundation for Political Education) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC6 Readings in World Politics, Sessions 1 and 2 (Staff, American Foundation for Political Education) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC7 Readings in World Politics, Discussion Leader's Manual (Staff, American Foundation for Political Education),</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC8 Readings in Russian Foreign Policy, Vol. 1 and Vol. 2, 2d Edition (Goldwin, Robert A. and Zetterbaum, Marvin) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC9 Readings in Russian Foreign Policy, Vol. 1 and Vol. 2, 3rd Edition (Goldwin, Robert A. and Zetterbaum, Marvin)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC10 Readings in Russian Foreign Policy, Sessions 8 &amp; 9 (Staff, American Foundation for Political Education) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC11 The Russian Foreign Policy Program, Discussion Leader's Manual (Zetterbaum, Marvin)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC12 Readings in Russian Foreign Policy, Supplement; Tables and Maps (Goldwin, Robert A. and Zetterbaum, Marvin)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC13 Readings in American Democracy, Vol. 1 and 2 (Stourzh, Gerald and Lerner, Ralph)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC14 [MISSING] Readings in American Democracy, Sessions 1 &amp; 2 (Staff, American Foundation for Political Education)</unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC15 A Statement Concerning the American Foundation for Political Education (Staff)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC16 Annual Report of Ex. Director Year ending March 31, American Foundation for Political Education (Nelson, Charles E.)</unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC17 Annual Report of Ex. Director Year ending June 30, American Foundation for Political Education (Nelson, Charles E.)</unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC18 American Foundation for Political Education, A Statement - Including Annual Report of Exec. Director - Year ending June 30, 1955 (Nelson, Charles E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC19 American Foundation for Political Education, A Statement - Including Annual Report of Exec. Director - Year Ending June 30, 1956 (Ziegler, Jerome M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC20 American Foundation for Political Education, Annual Report - Year ending June 30, 1957 (Ziegler, Jerome M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC21 American Foundation for Continuing Education, 2 Year Report - Period ending June 30, 1959 (Ziegler, Jerome)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC22 [MISSING] American Foundation for Continuing Education, Programs and Publications (Williams, Harold S.)</unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC23 American Foundations for Continuing Education, Programs and Publications (Williams, Harold S.)</unittitle><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC24 [MISSING] The American Foreign Policy Program, Discussion Leader's Manual (Goldwin, Robert A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>

      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC25 [MISSING] Readings in American Foreign Policy (Goldwin, Robert A. and Stourzh, Gerald) 6th edition</unittitle><abstract>Vol. I - Sessions 1-5<lb/>Vol. II - Sessions 6-8 </abstract><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC26 [MISSING] Readings in American Foreign Policy  (Goldwin, Robert A.) 4th edition</unittitle><abstract>Vol. 1 - Sessions 1-4<lb/>Vol. 2 - Sessions 5-7<lb/>Vol. 3 - Sessions 8-10</abstract><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC27 [MISSING] Readings for Men &amp; Labor (Fertig, Ralph D.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC28 Readings for Peace Corps Trainees, nos. 1-5, 8-10 (Christensen, David; University of Chicago) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><physdesc><extent>8 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">6</container></did><scopecontent><p>Vol. I - The Peace Corps: Missionary Society's Peace Army or What?<lb/>Vol. II - Cultural Confrontation:Terrifying and Illuminating<lb/>Vol. III - Freedom Round or Freedom Square<lb/>Vol. IV - On the Making of Volunteers<lb/>Vol. V - Of Gifts and Bribes and Stones that Cry<lb/>Vol VIII - Varieties of Cannibalism<lb/>Vol. IX - Bringing It All Back Home<lb/>Vol. X - Where Has It Been and Where Is It Going?</p></scopecontent></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC29 [MISSING] Ways to Justice (Sinclair, Lister)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC30[MISSING] Jefferson and Our Times (Malone, Dumas)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC31 [MISSING] Jeffersonian Heritage (Malone, Dumas)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC32 [MISSING] Introduction to the Humanities (record album) </unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="afc33"><did><unittitle>AFC33 [MISSING] Great Issues in American Politics Part I (Hofstadter, Richard)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did><note><p>See also Administrative files: <ref target="ad-giap">"Great Issues in American Politics"</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC34 [MISSING] The Power to Govern: An Examination of the Separation of Powers in the American System of Government (Odegard, Peter H. and Rosenblum, Victor G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC35 [MISSING] Economics and Politics: A Book of Readings (Harlan, H. C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC36 [MISSING] Arms and Foreign Policy in the Nuclear Age (Rakove, Milton)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC37 [MISSING] Developing Responsible Public Leaders (Nelson, Charles A.) </unittitle><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC38 [MISSING] The Case of the Lively Ghost (Goldwin, Robert A. and Shoemaker, Don)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC39 [MISSING] The Case of the Toppling Idol (Stourzh, Gerald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC40 [MISSING] The Case of the Lengthening Chain (Steward, Jr., Charles K. and Goldwin, Robert A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC41 [MISSING] The Case of the Blighted City (Banfield, Edward C.) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC42 [MISSING] The Case of the Censored Librarian (Berns, Walter F.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC43 [MISSING] The Case of the Golden Door (Davidson, James F.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC44, 45, 46 [MISSING] Readings for Capitol Hill, Vols. 1, 2, 3 (Ziegler, Warren L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC47 [MISSING] Exploring the Universe (McGraw-Hill)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="afc48"><did><unittitle>AFC48 [MISSING] Science and Public Policy (AFCE/Oceana)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-afc48">AFC48 Science and Public Policy (AFCE/Oceana)</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC49 [MISSING] The Exploration of the Universe (AFCE)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC50 [MISSING] Democracy in America: Scripts of the Fourteen Dramatizations (with National Educational Television Radio Center) (Sinclair, Lister and Probst, George E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC51 [MISSING] The Happy Republic (Probst, George E., ed.; Harper Torchbooks)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC52 [MISSING] Democracy in America: Vols. 1 &amp; 2 (de Tocqueville, Alexis; Vintage Books and Schocken Books)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC53 [MISSING] Democracy in America: Laden's Discussion and Reading Guide (Probst, George E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC54 [MISSING] Democracy in America: Discussion and Reading Guide (for students and discussion participants) (Probst, George E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC55 [MISSING] Readings in American Foreign Policy (Stourzh, Gerald and Goldwin, Robert A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC55A [MISSING] Readings in American Foreign Policy, second edition (Goldwin, Robert A. and Clar, Harry M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC56 [MISSING] Readings in Russian Foreign Policy (Stourzh, Gerald and Zetterbaum, Marvin, eds).</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">9</container></did></c03>      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC57 Exploring the Ways of Mankind (book) (Goldschmidt, Walter, editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC58 Aging in Today's Society (Tibbits, Clark and Donahue, Wilma)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC59 Discovering Modern Poetry (Drew, Elizabeth and Conner, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC60 The Mystery of Matter, Vol. 1 (Young, Louise B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">6</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC61 [MISSING] The Mystery of Matter, Vol. 2 (Young, Louise B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC62 [MISSING] The Mystery of Matter, Vol. 3 (Young, Louise B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC62A The Mystery of Matter (Young, Louise B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC63 Discussion Leader's Guide for Use with Discovering Modern Poetry (Drew, Elizabeth and Conner, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC64 [MISSING] Reading in Economics and Politics (Harlan, H. C.; Galbraith, Kenneth; Lerner, Max; Nixon, Richard; Kennan, George, editors)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC65 Readings in American Democracy (Stourzh, Gerald and Lerner, Ralph, eds)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC66 Ten Major Issues in American Politics (Hofstadter, Richard)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC67 Readings in World Politics (Pearce, Anthony; Oxford Press)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="afc68"><did><unittitle>AFC68 Evolution of Man (Young, Louise B., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did><note><p>See also Administrative: <ref target="eom-corr">"Evolution of Man" - correspondence</ref>; Administrative: <ref target="eom-cont">"Evolution of Man" - contract agreement</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC69 Readings on Drug Education (Reagen, Michael V., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC70 [MISSING] The Citizen and the New Age of Science, Vol. 1</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>AFC71 Advanced Management Training Workbook</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Syracuse University Centennial series (CEN)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN1 [MISSING] Continuing Education Programs #1 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN2 Bureau of School Service #2 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN3 Division of International Programs Abroad #3 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN4 Division of Summer Sessions #4 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN5 ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education #5 (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="cen6"><did><unittitle>CEN6 International Management Development Department (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN7 Library of Continuing Education #7 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN8 Archives of Continuing Education #717A (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN9 Professional Development in Adult and Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN10 Publications in Continuing Education #9 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="cen11"><did><unittitle>CEN11 Research, Evaluation, and Planning in Adult and Continuing Education #10 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CEN12 This is U.C. #11 (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Clearinghouse of Resources for Educators of Adults (CREA) series (CRE)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CRE1 Acquisition List, Clearinghouse of Resources for Educators of Adults: by Descriptive Subject Headings (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald P.)</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="cre2"><did><unittitle>CRE2 Newsletters, Clearinghouse of Resources for Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald P.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1978">1978</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="cre3"><did><unittitle>CRE3 Professional Development for Educators of Adults: A Bibliography (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald P. Compilers)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="cre4"><did><unittitle>CRE4 Annotated Bibliography for the Education of Public Offenders: By Descriptive Subject Headings (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald P. Willis, Michael J.)</unittitle><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="cre5"><did><unittitle>CRE5 Community Education: An Annotated Bibliography (Charters, Alexander N. and Gschwender, Edward J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">7</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>CRE6 Literacy in the '70s: An Annotated Bibliography (Rivera, W. and Laubach, Robert S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Distributing Agent series (DAG)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>DAG1 Strategies for Lifelong learning (Himmelstrup, Per, et al., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1981">1981</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03></c02>

			   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Eric Clearinghouse on Adult Education series (ECA)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA1 Evening College Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA2 Higher Adult Education #1</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA3 [MISSING] Community Education for Adults</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA4 Adult Basic Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA5 Continuing Education in the Professions</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA6 Management Development</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA7 Television and Radio in Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA8 Methods and Techniques in Adult Training</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA9 Training of Adult Education Personnel</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA10 Public School Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA11 Human Relations-Training and Research</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECAl2 Higher Adult Education #2</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA13 Adult Education in Africa</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA14 Adult Education in Asia, Australia and New Zealand</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA15 Education for Aging</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA16 Programmed Instruction in Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA17 Community Education for Adults</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA18 Management Development</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA19 Adult Basic Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA20 Public School Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA21 Adult Learning Characteristics</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>

      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA22 Continuing Education of Women</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA23 Counseling and Personnel Services in Adult Education: Counseling, Testing, Selection, Retention (Glick, Barry, ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA24 [MISSING] Unknown</unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA25 Residential Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container><note><p>300+ pages, available on microfilm only. MICROFILM #2973.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA26 Management and Supervisory Development</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA27 Adult Basic Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA28 Programmed Instruction in Business and Industry</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>

      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA29 Occupational Training for Disadvantaged Adults</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA30 Parent, Home and Family Life Education,</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA31 Personnel Development in Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA32 Continuing Education of Women</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA33 [MISSING] Training of Law Enforcement Personnel</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA34 [MISSING] Methods and Techniques of Adult Training</unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA35 Cooperative Extension</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA36 [MISSING] Adult Education Research Current Information Series</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA37 [MISSING] ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA38 [MISSING] ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA39 [MISSING] Scope and Service of ERIC-AE</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA40 ERIC-AE Publications 1967-69</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA41 [MISSING] Joint Newsletter with University College, Syracuse University Eric Clearinghouse on Adult Education </unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA42 Continuing Education for Adults (Nos. 129-154, 155, 157, 163, 166, 167, 171, 177, 179)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1973">1968-1973</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>

      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA43 Research and Investigation in Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA44 Evening College Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA45 Adult Education Periodical Holdings Literature</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA46 Abstracts of Papers Presented to the National Seminar on Adult Education Research</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA47 A Model Information System for the Adult Education Profession (DeCrow, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA48 [MISSING] Cross-Cultural Training (DeCrow, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA49 Mass Media in Adult Education: A Review of Recent Literature (Ohliger, John)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA50 A Register of Research and Investigation in Adult Education Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA51 Cross-Cultural Interaction Skills: A Digest of Recent Training (DeCrow, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA52 Adult Education and the Disadvantaged Adult (Anderson, Darrell and Niemi, John A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA53 Adult Education in Germany: Bibliography (Schadt, Armin L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA54 [MISSING] A Handbook for Teachers of English to Non-English Speaking Adults (Hefferman-Cabrera, Patricia)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA55 [MISSING] Adult Learning and Instruction (Grabowski, Stanley M., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA56 Education for Aging: A Review of Recent Literature (Jacobs, H. Lee; Mason, W. Dean; Kauffman, Earl)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA57 [MISSING] Correspondence Study: A Summary Review of the Research and, Development of Literature (Mathieson, David E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA58 Self Concept in Adult Participation: Conference Report and Bibliography</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA59 [MISSING] The Use of Mass Media in Religiously Motivated Adult Educators: A Review of the Literature (Clyde, Robert W. Jaberg, Eugene C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA60 Mass Media in Public Affairs: A Review of the Literature (Power, Hilton M.)</unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA61 Digests of Papers Presented to the Adult Research Conference, February 27-28, 1970 Minneapolis</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA62 ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education: Publications,1969-1970</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA63 [MISSING] ERIC Clearinghouse on Adult Education Information Analysis Priorities</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA64 [MISSING] The Mass Media in Cooperative Extension: A Review of Recent Literature (Everly, Jack C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA65 [MISSING] Television: A Viable Channel for Educating Adults in Culturally Different Poverty Groups: A Literature Review (Niemi, John A. and Anderson, Darrel V.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA66 [MISSING] The Use of Mass Media in Adult Education in Countries Outside the U.S. and Canada: A Literature Review (Cassirer, Henry R.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA67  "I'm Beginning to Think Like the Bird!" Or, Social and Philosophical Issues in the Use of Mass Media in Adult Education: A Review of the Literature (Blakely, Robert J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA68 [MISSING] The Mass Media in Adult Education in the Developing Countries: A Literature Review (Guevlette, David G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA69 Cost Benefit Analysis and the Adult Educator: A Literature Review (Steele, Sara M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA70 Abstract of Papers Presented to the National Seminar on Adult Education Research February 1969, Toronto (Grabowski, Stanley M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA71 [MISSING] Needed: A New Coalition for Public Affairs Education (A Review of the Literature) (Johnson, Eugene I.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA72 The Education of the Mentally Retarded Adult: A Selective Review of the Literature (Long, Huey B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>ECA73 The Preparation of Adult Educators: A Selected Review of the Literature Produced in North America</unittitle><container type="Box">8</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Fund for Adult Education series (FAE)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE1 [MISSING] Economic Reasoning, An Introduction to (Robinson, Marshall A. and Morton, Herbert C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE2 Readings for the Executive Seminar, 2d edition  (Brooks, Shepherd)</unittitle><abstract>Vol. I, Vol. II</abstract><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE3 An Introduction to Economic Reasoning: A Manual for Discussion Group Participants and Leaders (Robinson, Marshall A. and Morton, Herbert C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE4 An Introduction to Economic Reasoning: Book of Readings (Robinson, Marshall A.; Morton, Herbert C.; Calderwood, James D.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE5 Looking at Modern Painting: A Discussion Leader's Guide (Field, Frances)</unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE6 Looking at Modern Painting: A Study Discussion Program (Department of Art - University Extension - University of California, L.A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE7 An Introduction to the Humanities: A Guide for Discussion Leaders (Humanities Staff University of Chicago)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE8 What to Listen for in Music (Copland, Aaron)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1939">1939</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE9 An Introduction to the Humanities: Book of Readings and Music Supplement (University of Chicago)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE10 Humanities: Adult Education Series: 10 Units Introducing Painting, Music and Literature, Revised (Ashbrook, William; Carpenter, Marjorie; Dudley, Louise; Sterling, Alfred)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE11 FAE Avenue to the Arts A. Authors - Biographical Sketch - Titles (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE12 FAE Avenue to the Arts B. Table of Contents (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE13 FAE Avenue to the Arts C. Part one - Part two (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE14 FAE Avenue to the Arts D. Part three - Session IV (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE15 FAE Avenue to the Arts E. Part three - Session V (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE16 FAE Avenue to the Arts F. Part three - Session VI (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE17 FAE Avenue to the Arts G. Part three - Session VII &amp; VIII (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE18 FAE Avenue to the Arts H. Part three - Session IX (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE19 FAE Avenue to the Arts I. Part four - Session X (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE20 FAE Avenue to the Arts J. Part four - Session X &amp; XI (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE21 The Educational Experience (Redfield, Robert)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE22 A Study of Participants in the Great Books Program (Davis, James A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE23 The Great Awakening: Including a Plan for Education for Leadership in the U.S. (Fletcher, C. Scott)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE24 Education for Public Responsibility (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE25 Accent on Learning (Burch, Glen)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE26 A Comparative Study of Lecture and Discussion Methods (Hill, Richard J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE27 Studies in Adult Group Learning in the Liberal Arts (Kaplan, Abbott)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE28 Able People Well Prepared (Shilen, Ronald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE29 A Ten Year Report of the Fund for Adult Education 1951-1961: Ford Foundation</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="fae30"><did><unittitle>FAE30 [MISSING] Great Issues in American Politics: Part I (Hofstadter, Richard)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did><note><p>See also Administrative files: <ref target="ad-giap">"Great Issues in American Politics"</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE31 [MISSING] The Happy Republic</unittitle><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE32 Readings in the Ways of Mankind Vol. 1, Vol. 2 (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">10</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE33 Readings in the Ways of Mankind: Discussion Leader's Guide</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE34 Looking at Modern Poetry (Freedman, Leonard, ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE34A Discovering Modern Poetry (Drew, Elizabeth and Connor, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE34B Discovering Modern Poetry (Drew, Elizabeth)</unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE35 Ways to Justice (Goldsmidt, Walter and Sinclair, Lester)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954/1955">1954-1955</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE36 Looking at Modern Paintings: A Discussion Leader's Guide (The Fund for Adult Education) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE37 Residential Colleges: Some New Developments in British Adult Education (Hunter, Guy)</unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE37A Looking at Modern Paintings (Freedman, Leonard)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE38 Education: The Challenge Ahead (Fletcher, C. Scott)</unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE39 The Perkins Lectures: Popular Government and Foreign Policy (Perkins, Dexter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40 Ways of Mankind: How to organize a listen-and-talk group in your own home</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40A Exploring the Ways of Mankind (Goldschmidt, Walter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40B Discussion Leader's Guide for Use with Exploring the Ways of Mankind (Goldschmidt, Walter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40C Ways of Mankind: An Adult Discussion Program (Goldschmidt, Walter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40D Ways of Mankind (National Association of Educational Broadcasters)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40E The Ways of Mankind: A Discussion Leader's Guide (The Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40F A Word in Your Ear: A Study in Language (Essay No. 1 in the series of experimental discussion programs on "The Ways of Mankind")</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40G The Ways of Mankind Adult Discussion Series: How People Live Together Different Times and Places (The Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE40H Ways of Mankind Discussion Leader's Guide</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE41 You and Modern Art (Langsher, Jules)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE42 The Citizen and the Mass Media (Dale, Edgar and Kilbourn, Robert W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE43 You and the Mass Media Part I; Supplementary readings; Part II;  Additional readings to Session III (Seldes, Gilbert)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE44 [MISSING] You and Your Community</unittitle><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE44A Our Community (Mial, Dorothy and Curtis)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE44B Obstacles to Healthy Community Growth (Dodson, Dart W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE44C The Future of the Community (McKee, Elmore)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE44D Participant's Manual (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE44E Aging in the Modern (World University of Michigan)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">11</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE45 Shakespeare and His Theatre (Canadian Association for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE46 The Power to Govern (Odegard, Peter H. and Rosenblum, Walter G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE47 Transition and Tension in Southeast Asia (Peffer, Nathanial)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>FAE48 You and Modern Art (Fund for Adult Education)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries" id="lce"><did><unittitle>Library of Continuing Education at Syracuse University series (LCE)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE1 Directory of Adult Education Association (Vaughn, Betty Jane)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE2 Directory of Adult Education Association (DeCrow, Roger;  Ironside, Diana J.; Vaughn, Betty Jane)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE3 University Adult Education: A Selected Bibliography (DeCrow, Roger; Ironside, Diana J.; Vaughn, Betty Jane)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE4 Directory of Adult Education Association (Ironside, Diana J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE5 Directory of Adult Education Organizations (Vaughn, Betty Jane)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE6 [MISSING] Recent Acquisitions: Adult Education Periodical Holdings and Adult Education Newsletter Holdings (DeCrow, Roger; Ironside, Diana J.; Vaughn, Betty Jane)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LCE7 [MISSING] International Seminar on Adult Education (Ziegler, Warren L., Seminar Director)</unittitle><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Landmark and New Horizons series (LNH)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LNH1 Report on the 1969 Galaxy Conference of Adult Education Organizations (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="lnh2"><did><unittitle>LNH2 The Cooperative Extension Service: Paradoxical Servant (Miller, Paul A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-lnh2">LNH2 The Cooperative Extension Service: Paradoxical Servant</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LNH3 A Tale of Three Cities: Elsinore-Montreal-Tokyo (Kidd, James Robbins)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1974">1974</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>LNH4 The Worker's Educational Association: Aims and Achievements (Fieldhouse, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries" id="mss"><did><unittitle>Manuscript series (MSS)</unittitle></did><altformavail><p>Many of the MSS documents have been digitized and are available online.  To view these document, please click <extref href="http://library.syr.edu/digital/guides/a/AlexanderNCharters/ms_docs.htm">here</extref>.</p></altformavail><c03><did><unittitle>MSS1 Aids to Access - Resources for Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1978">1978</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS2 Professional Development of Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS3 Desarrollo Professional de Educadores de Adultos (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss4"><did><unittitle>MSS4 Publications in Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1978">1978</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS5 Who We Are: What Some Educators Say About Their Characteristics, Competencies, and Roles (Charters, Alexander N. and Hilton, Ronald J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS6 Continuing Education for Educators of Adults: The Roles of Research (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss7"><did><unittitle>MSS7 Syracuse University Resources in Adult Education (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1978">1978</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss8"><did><unittitle>MSS8 Periodicals, Newsletters, &amp; Indexes in E.S. Bird Library and Clearinghouse of Resources for Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald P.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1978">1978</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS9 Accessibility to Resources for Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS10 Acquisition List Pamphlet File - E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS11 Abstracts of Dissertations and Theses: Syracuse University Graduates in Adult Education (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">12</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss12"><did><unittitle>MSS12 Publications in Continuing Education, Revised (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS13 Acquisition List Pamphlet File - E.S. Bird Library - Revised (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss14"><did><unittitle>MSS14 Clearinghouse Resources for Educators of Adults. Four Year Report October1975-June 1979) (Charters, Alexander N., Project Director)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS15 Syracuse University Resources in Adult Education,  Revised (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss16"><did><unittitle>MSS16 Adult and Continuing Education Collections: A Descriptive List of Manuscript Holdings in Syracuse University Libraries (Charters, Alexander N., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss17"><did><unittitle>MSS17 Adult Education Masters' Theses and Doctoral Dissertations on Microfilm in S.U. Library (Charters, Alexander N., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss18"><did><unittitle>MSS18 International Handbook of Resources for Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N., ed.)</unittitle><abstract>2 versions, 6.76 and 10.76</abstract><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did><note><p>See also related collection <archref href="charters_an.htm#iprof-hrea">Alexander Charters Papers: Professional correspondence-subject files: International Handbook of Resources for Educators of Adults</archref>.</p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS19 Personal Papers of Frank C. Laubach: Documents of Laubach Literacy, Inc. (Chmaj, Deborah R. and Wolde, Menbere, compilers)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1974">1974</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS20 The Paul Hoy Helms Library in Liberal Adult Education (Charters, Alexander N., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS21 The What and the How of the Syracuse Collection (Stubblefield, Harold)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1984">1984</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did><note><p>In some lists, MSS21 is given as "Omnibus Series (Charters, Alexander N.), 1965."  However, that is not what is in the collection.</p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS22 Audio Tapes - E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976">1976</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss23"><did><unittitle>MSS23 Adult Education Sound and Video Recordings - E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N. and Abbott, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1982">1982</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss24"><did><unittitle>MSS24 Omnibus Series - E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976">1976</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS25 Humanizing Adult Education Research: Five Stories from the 1930's (Hilton, Ronald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1982">1982</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss26"><did><unittitle>MSS26 Publications in Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1983">1983</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss27"><did><unittitle>MSS27 Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education on Microfiche (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1983">1983</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>See <ref target="mss36">MSS36</ref> for later version.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS28 [MISSING] Continuing Education Photograph Collection: by Event and Person (Charters, Alexander N. and Davis, Carolyn)</unittitle><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss29"><did><unittitle>MSS29 Adult Education Periodicals and Newsletters - E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N. and Gschwender, Edward)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1983">1983</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>See <ref target="mss41">MSS41</ref> for later version.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS30 [MISSING] Acquisition List Pamphlet File - E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N. and Goodman, Edward)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1983">1983</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS31 SUPCE and SUREA: Publications and Resources for Educators of Adults  (Stubblefield, Harold W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1983-11">1983 Nov</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss32"><did><unittitle>MSS32 Syracuse University Resources for Educators of Adults A Retrospective View: Looking into the Future (Charters, Alexander N. and Vaughn, Betty Jane)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1986-01">1986 Jan</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>See <ref target="mss53">MSS53</ref> for later version.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss33"><did><unittitle>MSS33 Historical and Research Materials Related to Adult Continuing Education (Frost, Jane B., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1988">1988</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>See <ref target="mss35">MSS35</ref> for later version.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss34"><did><unittitle>MSS34 The Adult Education Collection at Syracuse University (Charters, Alexander N., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1989">1989</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p></p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss35"><did><unittitle>MSS35 Historical and Research Materials Related to Adult Continuing Education (Frost, Jane B., compiler)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision/update of <ref target="mss33">MSS33</ref></p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss36"><did><unittitle>MSS36 Publications in Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision/update of <ref target="mss27">MSS27</ref>.  See <ref target="mss45">MSS45</ref> for later version.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss37"><did><unittitle>MSS37 Adult Education Sound &amp; Video Recordings (Charters, Alexander N. and Abbot, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><note><p>Revised and updated <ref target="mss23">MSS23</ref>.  See <ref target="mss48">MSS48</ref> for later version.</p></note><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS38 Bibliography of Materials Autographed by Educators of Adults</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS39 Finding Aid to Alexander N. Charters Materials in Archives (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS40 Abridged Descriptive Subject Listing for Adult and Continuing Education Research Collection</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss41"><did><unittitle>MSS41 [MISSING] Adult Education Periodicals and Newsletters – E.S. Bird Library.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision/update of <ref target="mss29">MSS29</ref></p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss42"><did><unittitle>MSS42 Adult Education Acquisitions List: Pamphlet File, E.S. Bird Library (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision/update of MSS30</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS43 Some Observations: Early Years of Committee/Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO) (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss44"><did><unittitle>MSS44 Comparative Studies in Adult Education: A Review (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1992">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss45"><did><unittitle>MSS45 [MISSING] Publications in Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1996">1996</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision of <ref target="mss36">MSS36</ref>.  See <ref target="mss49">MSS49</ref> for later version.</p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss46"><did><unittitle>MSS46 Photographs in Adult and Continuing Education (A); Descriptive Subject Headings (N) (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1995">1995</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss47"><did><unittitle>MSS47 SUPCE Supplements to MS 13, 29, 35, 37, 38 (Charters, Alexander N. and Keenan, Terrance)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1995">1995</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss48"><did><unittitle>MSS48 Adult Education Sound and Video Recordings (Charters, Alexander N. and Abbot, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2003">2003</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision/update of <ref target="mss37">MSS37</ref></p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss49"><did><unittitle>MSS49 Publications in Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N. and Shablak, Scott)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2003">2003</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container><note><p>Revision/update of <ref target="mss45">MSS45</ref></p></note></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS50 Adult Educational Journals and Associations (Charters, Alexander N. and Shablak, Scott)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2003">2003</unitdate><container type="Box">13</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>MSS51 Adult and Continuing Education Pamphlets, Materials and Fugitive (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004-03">2004 (Mar)</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss52"><did><unittitle>MSS52 Syracuse University Adult and Continuing Education: Pamphlets, Materials and Fugitive (Shablak, Scott and Cooper, Natasha)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004-08">2004 (Aug)</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss53"><did><unittitle>MSS53 Syracuse University Resources for Educators of Adults: A Retrospective View: Looking into the Future (Charters, Alexander N. and Shablak, Scott)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2006">2006</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container><note><p>Revision/update of <ref target="mss32">MSS32</ref></p></note></did></c03>
      <c03 id="mss54"><did><unittitle>MSS54 Continuing Education at Syracuse University, 1973 (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005-05">2005 (May)</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>      <c03 id="mss55"><did><unittitle>MSS55 Comparative Adult Education: An Overview (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1988">1988, </unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2007">2007, </unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2008">2008</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Notes and Essays in Continuing Education for Adults series (NES)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES1 The Pooling of Ignorance (Smith, Russell F.W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES2 Report to Atlanta Convention (CSLEA)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952">1952</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES3 Evaluating Courses not Students (Miller, Harry L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES4 Social Roles of the Middle-Aged (Havighurst, Robert)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES5 Television and the University (University of Chicago)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES6 A School for Optimists (McGee, Paul)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES7 The Liberation of the Adult (Kallen, Horace)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES8 Adult Education as a Time-Binding (Hayakawa, S. I.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES9 Mass Society and Liberal Education (Mills, C. Wright)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES10 Teaching a Human Relations (Malumud, Daniel I.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES11 Faculty Organization at Rutgers (Demarest, G. Stuart)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES12 Psychological Needs for Adults (Murphy, Gardner and Kuhlen, Raymond G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES13 Schooling for Maturity (Diekhoff, John S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES14 The Residential School in American (Pitkin, Royce S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES15 Professional Preparation of Adult Educators</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES16 Reality and Purpose: A Visitor's Reflections on Some Aspects of American Adult Education (Elsdon, Konrad. T.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES17 Adult Education in the Liberal Arts Colleges (Crimi, James E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES18 Liberal Education (Carnegie Foundation)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES19 Especially for, Adults (Whipple, John B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES20 The Marginality of Adult Education (Clark, Burton R.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES21 I Want Many Lodestars (Schwertman, John B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES22 Learning and Teaching Through Discussion (Hill, Ida Stewart and Hill, William Fawcett)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES23 Pleasures in Learning (Division of General Education of New York University)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES24 Major Trends in Higher Adult Education (Houle, Cyril O.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES25 Liberal Education for Adults Re-Examined: The Queens College Program (Belth, Marc and Scheuler, Herbert)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES26 Higher Adult Education: Its Place and Function (Simons, Hans)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES27 A Report on University Adult Education in Australia and New Zealand (Sheats, Paul H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES28 Aims in Adult Education: A Realist View (Broudy, Harry S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES29 Week-End Learning in the USA (Schacht, Robert H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES30 Adult Education in Colleges and Universities, Liberal Adult Education (Liveright, A. A. and Miller, Harry L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES31 Adult Education in the British West Indies (Houle, Cyril O.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES32 On Teaching Adults: An Anthology (Miller, Marilyn V., editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES33 People, Programs, and Persuasion: Some Remarks About Promoting University Adult Education (Stern, Milton R.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES34 Today and Tomorrow: Three Essays on Adult Education in the Future (Taylor, G.; Blackwell, G. W.; Mead, Margaret)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES35 Challenge to the University: An Inquiry into the University's Responsibility for Adult Education (Burch, Glen)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES36 The University and Community Education (Haygood, Kenneth)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES37 Educational Imperative: The Negro in the Changing South (Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES38 The Few and the Many: Two Views on Public Affairs Education (Freedman, Leonard and Power, Hilton)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES39 Meanings of Work (Levy, Sidney J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES40 Psychological Backgrounds of Adult Education (Kuhlen, Raymond C., editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES41 Sociological Backgrounds of Adult Education (Burns, Hobart W., editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES42 Ordered Pluralism: A Philosophical Plan of Action for Teaching (Barton, George E.)</unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES43 Perspective on Automation: Three Talks to Educators (Theobald, Robert; Johnston, John W. C.; Weinberg, Jack)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES44 Growing Time (DeCrow, Roger, editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES45 Meaning and Metaphor (Goldberg, Maxwell H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES46 A Live Option: Potentials for the Evening College (Haygood, Kenneth, editor)</unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES47 A Turning to Take Next: Alternative Goals in the Education of Woman (Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES48 Education in the Peace Corps: Evolving Concepts of Volunteer Training (Pagano, Jules)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES49 Toward a Homeodynamic Society (Blakely, R. J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES50 Institutional Backgrounds of Adult Education: Dynamics of change in the Modern University (Ingham, R. J., editor)</unittitle><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES51 Oakland Papers: Symposium on Social Change and Educational Continuity (Whipple, James B. and Woditsch, Gary A., editors)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES52 Speaking for Myself: A Humanist Approach to Adult Education for a Technical Age (Deinum, Andries)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES53 Political Backgrounds of Adult Education: The University in Urban Society (Cummings, Thomas, editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES54 The Continuing Task: Reflections on Purpose in Higher Continuing Education (Houle, Cyril O.; Blackwell, Gordon W.; Kallen, Horace M.; Whipple, James B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES55 A Critical Balance: History of CSLEA (Whipple, James B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES56 On Behalf of Adult Education: A Historical Examination of the Supporting Literature (Cotton, Webster E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES57 Anthropological Background of Adult Education (Tax, Sol; Diamond, Stanley; Rainwater, Lee; Mangin, William; Bharati, Ahehananda)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES58 Of Messages and Media: Teaching and Learning by Public Television (Alter, Henry C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="nes59"><did><unittitle>NES59 The System of Adult Education in Yugoslavia (Savicevic, Dusan M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes59">NES59 The System of Adult Education in Yugoslavia</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes60"><did><unittitle>NES60 Liberal Education Reconsidered: Reflections on Continuing Education for Contemporary Man (Whipple, James B.; Goldman, Freda H.; Haygood, Kenneth Siegle, Peter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes60">NES60 Liberal Education Reconsidered: Reflections on Continuing Education for Contemporary Man</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes61"><did><unittitle>NES61 Aim: From Concept to Reality (Wedemeyer, Charles A. Najem, Robert E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes61">NES61 Aim: From Concept to Reality</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes62"><did><unittitle>NES62 Dilemmas of American Policy: Crucial Issues in Contemporary Society (Cook, Samuel Dubois; Stern, George G.; Green, Thomas F.; Weiner, Anthony J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes62">NES62 Dilemmas of American Policy: Crucial Issues in Contemporary Society</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes63"><did><unittitle>NES63 Knowledge is Power to Control Power (Blakely, Robert and Lappin, I.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes63">NES63 Knowledge is Power to Control Power</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes64"><did><unittitle>NES64 The University and Community Service (Whipple, James B. and Chertow, Doris)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes64">NES64 The University and Community Service</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes65"><did><unittitle>NES65 Essays on New Careers: Social Implications for Adult Educators (Riessman, Frank; Rosen, Sumner M.; Featherstone, Joseph; Gartner, Alan)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes65">NES65 Essays on New Careers: Social Implications for Adult Educators</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes66"><did><unittitle>NES66 Essays on the Future of Continuing Education Worldwide (Ziegler, Warren)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes66">NES66 Essays on the Future of Continuing Education Worldwide</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES67 Toward the Educative Society (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="nes68"><did><unittitle>NES68 Sensitivity Training: Processes, Problems and Applications (Blumberg, Arthur)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="nes69"><did><unittitle>NES69 Ends and Means: The National Conference on Continuing Education in Nursing (McHenry, Ruth W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes69">NES69 Ends and Means: The National Conference on Continuing Education in Nursing</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes70"><did><unittitle>NES70 Residential Continuing Education (Houle, Cyril O.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes70">NES70 Residential Continuing Education</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="nes71"><did><unittitle>NES71 Selected Concepts from Educational Psychology and Adult Education for Extension and Continuing Educators (Leagans, J. Paul; Copeland, Harlan G.; Kaiser, Gertrude E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-nes71">NES71 Selected Concepts from Educational Psychology and Adult Education for Extension and Continuing Educators</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>NES72 International Seminar on Publications in Continuing Education (Charters, Alexander N. and Rivera, William M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Occasional Papers (CSLEA) series (OCP)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP1 Adult Education Programming Form and Function (Tuskegee Institute)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP2 National Trends in Higher Adult Education (Liveright, A. A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP3 Liberal Education for Community Clubs (Rhode, William E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP4 Liberal Orientations for Vocational Teaching (Miller, Harry L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP5 Adults That Grew in Brooklyn and Some That Didn't (Stern, Bernard H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP6 [MISSING] We Need a Philosophy (Diekhoff, John S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP7 New Eyes for Old: The Quest for Education (McKenna, Richard)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP8 The Human Enterprise (Rodney, Robert M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP9 Promoting High Standards of Professional Excellence (Horn, Francis H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">14</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP10 Inter-Association Cooperation Reconsidered (Spengler, Edwin H.; McMahon, Ernest E.; Winters, Clifford)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP11 The Case Against the Adult Dropout (Sheats, Paul)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP12 Significant Developments in Continuing Higher Education (Liveright, A. A. and Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP13 Purposes of the Evening College: Reflections in 1953 (Houle, Cyril O.; Blackwell, Gordon W.; Kallen, Horace M.; McGrath, Earl J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP14 Participation of Adults in Education: A Force-Field Analysis (Miller, Harry L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP15 Daytime School for Adults: A New Program Dimensions at University (Gordon, Morton)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP16 The College and Its Community: A Conference on Purpose and Direction in the Education of Adults (papers presented at University of Wisconsin by personnel from southern Negro colleges and northern universities)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP17 Toward a National Center for Higher Continuing Education (Hudson, Robert B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP18 The Mass Media in Adult Education (Ohliger, John)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp19"><did><unittitle>OCP19 Accent on Adults: The Small College Program at Brooklyn (Jacobson, Myrtle S. and Offenbacher, Deborah I.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-ocp19">OCP19 Accent on Adults: The Small College Program at Brooklyn</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp20"><did><unittitle>OCP20 Faculty Perceptions of Continuing Education at Syracuse University (Porter, Lee)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-ocp20">OCP20 Faculty Perceptions of Continuing Education at Syracuse University</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp21"><did><unittitle>OCP21 Community Service and Continuing Education (Whipple, James B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-ocp21">OCP21 Community Service and Continuing Education</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp22"><did><unittitle>OCP22 Adult Education and the Disadvantaged Adult (Anderson, Darrel and Niemi, John)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-ocp22">OCP22 Adult Education and the Disadvantaged Adult</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP23 The New Environment: Questions for Adult Educators (Blakely, R. J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp24"><did><unittitle>OCP24 Lifelong Learning or Lifelong Schooling: A Tentative View of the Ideas of Ivan Illich (Ohliger, John and McCarthy, C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-ocp24">OCP24 Lifelong Learning or Lifelong Schooling: A Tentative View of the Ideas of Ivan Illich</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp25"><did><unittitle>OCP25 The Learning Force: A More Comprehensive Framework for Educational Policy (Moses, Stanley)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did><note><p>See also Drafts, notes and galleys: <ref target="dng-ocp25">OCP25 The Learning Force: A More Comprehensive Framework for Educational Policy</ref></p></note></c03>
      <c03 id="ocp26"><did><unittitle>OCP26 Real Estate Tax Exemption for Continuing Education Programs (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP27 The Hill and the Valley: The Story of University College Through 1964 (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP28 Response to Need: A Case Study of Adult Education Graduate Program Development in the Southeast (Kozoll, C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP29 Agenda for Comparative Studies in Adult Education: International Expert Meeting Report form the International Expert Meeting</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP30 Toward Gog and Magog, or, A Critical Review of the Literature of Adult Group Discussion (Osinski, F.; Ohliger, John; McCarthy, C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP31 Historical and Cultural Influence Upon the Development of Residential Centers for Continuing Education (Jessup, F.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP32 Paul Freire: A Revolutionary Dilemma for the Adult Educator (Grabowski, Stanley, editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP33 The Challenge of Modern Church-Public Relations (Reagan, M., editor, and Chertow, Doris)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1972">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP34 Consumer Education Programming in Continuing Education (Charters, Margaret)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP35 Conceptual Learning: Mollusks to Adult Education (Carlson, R.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP36 Toward a Working Philosophy of Adult Education (Apps, J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP37 Adult Education in Church and Synagogue (Long, H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP38 Evaluating the Attainment of Objectives in Adult Education: Process, Properties, Problems, Prospects (Steele, Sara M. and Brack, Robert E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP39 Educational Television in Its Cultural and Public Affairs Dimension: A Selected Literature Review of Public Television as an Issue in Adult Education (Carlson, Robert A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP40 The Use of Instructional Television in Adult Education (Blakely, R. J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1974">1974</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP41 The Syracuse Black Community (Sacks, Seymour and Andrew, Ralph)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1974">1974</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP42 Development, Demonstration and Dissemination: Case Studies of Selected Special Projects in Basic Education (Beder, Harold W. and Darkenwald, Gordon G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1974">1974</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP43 The University Council on Education for Public Responsibility, 1961-1965 (Davis, Granville D.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1975">1975</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP44 Comparative Studies in Adult Education: An Anthology (Bennet, Clif, editor; Kidd, J. Roby; Kulich, Jindra)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1975">1975</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP45 Continuing Education of Adults in Colonial America (Long, Huey B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976">1976</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP46 Training Teachers of Adults: Models and Innovative Programs (Grabowski, Stanley)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976">1976</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP47 Adults in Transition</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP48 Understanding Group Behavior (Miller, Harry L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP49 CSLEA Newsletter Continuing Education for Adults, July 1961-May 1968</unittitle><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP50 How Much Does Adult Experience Count (Stearn, Bernard H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP51 A Turning to Take Next (Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP52 Invitation to Literature: Discussion Guide (Smith, Russell F. W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP53 Our Modern Art, the Movies (Callenbach, Ernest)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP54 Scientists at Work (Sayvetz, Aaron)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP55 Understanding Group Behavior (Miller, Harry L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP56 Leading Group Discussion, Part I, II, III (Miller/Berger); Supplementary Readings (CSLEA); Discussion Guide (CSLEA); Training Guide (CSLEA)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954, </unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP57 Folder of Newsletters (CSLEA)</unittitle><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP58 [MISSING]</unittitle></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>OCP59 The Contributions of Alexander N. Charters to the Field of Adult Education (Siddiqui, Dilnawaz)</unittitle><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
   </c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Single publications (PRE)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE1 New Directions for Adult Education: Introduction (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE2 [MISSING] Adult Education Procedures, Methods and Techniques: A Classified and Annotated Bibliography 1953-1963 (Aker, George)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE3 Leading Group Discussions: A Discussion Guide</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">15</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE4 Part I - Fostering the Growing Need to Learn: Designs for Continuing Education Manpower (Charters, Alexander N. and Blakely, Robert J.) (unpublished)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE5 Part II - A Selected Annotated Bibliography for Continuing Educators for Health Manpower (Charters, Alexander N. and Blakely, Robert J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE6 Part III - A Report of Some Significant Activities in Continuing Education for Health Manpower n the U.S. (Charters, Alexander N. and Blakely, Robert J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE7 Part IV - A Critique of Descriptions of Terms in Continuing Education for Health Manpower (Charters, Alexander N. Blakely, and Robert J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE8 Fostering the Growing Need to Learn (Charters, Alexander N. and Blakely, Robert J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE9 [MISSING] Newsletter</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE10 French Universities and Adult Education</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PRE11 [MISSING] List of Institutions and Individuals Active in University Adult Education </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Papers on Adult Education, University College publications (PUC) (Blue Books)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC1 Special Report on University College (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955">1955</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC2 Some Motivational Aspects of College Training (Snygg, Donald)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC3 Learning Theory and Its Application to Classroom Teaching (Thelen, Herbert)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC4 Learning Theory and Classroom Practice in Adult Education (Getzels, J. W.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC5 Evaluation in Evening colleges (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC6 Course Construction and the Use of Teaching Resources (Liveright, A. A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC7 Continuing Education (Crawford, Finla G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC8 Summary Report on Adult College Students (Knox, Alan B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC9 Looking Ahead in Adult Education (Tolley, William P.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC10 A Report on the Semester in Italy (Adams, John Clarke)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC11 World Affairs Don't Have to be Boring (Cleveland, Harlan)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC12 Learning and Change, the Problems of Evaluation in Liberal Adult Education (Powell, John Walker)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC13 Government in Action, a Final Report on the Experimental Adult Education Program Presented at University College (Schmidt, Karl M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC14 Development of an Objective Instrument for Evaluation of Scientific Maturity in Electrical Engineering (Jutila, Sakari Tampani)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC15 Local Community Leadership (Freeman, Linton C. et al)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC16 The Evening College and Its Relationship to "Community Publics" (Bartlett, Kenneth G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC17 Bottles Old, Wine New; Wine Old, Bottles New (Schwertman, John B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC18 The Free University--Its Role in Education for Public Responsibility and the Future of Our Free Society and the Free World (Fletcher, C. Scott)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC19 The Story of Sagamore (Applegate, Howard L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC20 Many Opinions (Diekhoff, John S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC21 University Adult Education: The Center for Experiment in Education (Liveright, A. A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC22 We Must be Educator-Administrators (Neville, Howard R.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC23 Adult Education in Australia (Hely, Arnold S. M.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC24 Geographers Look at the World (Cressey, George B. Gould, Peter)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC25 The Story of Pinebrook (Applegate, Howard L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC26 The Story of Minnowbrook (Applegate, Howard L.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC27 Metropolitan Decision-Making: Further Analysis from the Syracuse Study of Local Community Leadership (Freeman, Linton C,)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC28 University Adult Education in Some Commonwealth Countries (Raybould, S. G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC29 The Negro in Syracuse: His Education, Employment, Income and Housing (Campbell, Alan K.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC30 A Kind Word for Mankind (Olson, John F.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC31 The Unfinished Business of Human Rights in Syracuse (Willie, Charles V.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>PUC32 An Investigation of the Status of the Student Personnel Program in Evening Colleges (Simonaitis, John)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Reports series (REP)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP101 New Directions in Programming for University Adult Education (Siegle, Peter E. and Whipple, James B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP102 New Directions in Liberal Education for Executives (Siegle, Peter E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP103 New Directions for Alumni: Continuing Education for the College Graduate (McMahon, Ernest E.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP104 New Directions in Degree Programs Especially for Adults (Liveright, A. A. and DeCrow, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP105 The Vassar Institute for Women in Business (Vaughan, Marilyn)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP106 The Changing University (Daigneault, George H., editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP107 University Adult Education in the Arts (Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP108 The Audience for Liberal Adult Education (Knox, Alan B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP109 Administrative Practices in University Evening Colleges (DeCrow, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP110 Reorientation in Labor Education: A Symposium on Liberal Education for Labor in the University (Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1962">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP111 Never Too Late for College: The Brooklyn Degree Program for Adults (Stern, Bernard H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP112 Research Arrangements Within University Adult Education Divisions (Knox, A. B.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP113 A Conspectus to the Self-Study Project of University College, the University of Chicago (Roth, Robert M., editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP114 Metroplex Assembly: An Experiment in Community Education (Johnson, Eugene I.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965">1965</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP115 Bachelor of Liberal Studies: Development of a Curriculum at the University of Oklahoma (Burkett, J. E. Riggiers, Paul C.)</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP116 Creativity Research and Its Implications for Adult Education (Zahn, Jane C.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP117 The Arts in Higher Adult Education: A Second Review of Programs (Goldman, Freda H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP118 Changing Patterns in Continuing Education for Business (Olean, Sally J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP119 Listening Groups: Mass Media in Adult Education (Ohliger, John)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1967">1967</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP120 Adult Education and Adult Needs (Havighurst, Robert J. and Orr, Betty)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960">1960</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP121 Forms and Forces in University Adult Education (Carey, James T.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP122 A Comparison of the Effectiveness of Residential and Nonresidential Learning Situations (Lacognata, A. A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP123 The Development of the University Evening College as Observed in Ten Urban Universities (Carey, James T.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP124 New Perspectives in University Correspondence Study (Wedemeyer, Charles and Childs, Gayle B).</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP125 Evaluating Liberal Adult Education (Miller, Harry L. and McGuire, Christine H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP126 Decision Making in the University Evening College (Daigneault, George H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP127 Teaching Styles and Learning (Solomon, Daniel and Rosenberg, Larry Bexdek, William)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963">1963</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP128 The Continuing Learner (Solomon, Daniel, editor)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1964">1964</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP129 The Exeter Papers: Report of the First International Conference on the Comparative Study of Adult Education (Liveright, A. A. and Haygood, Norwood)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP130 A Study of Adult Education in the United States (Liveright, A. A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP131 Ivory Towers in the Market Place (Dyer, John P.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP132 The Part-time College Teacher (Gowin, D. B. and Daigneault, George H.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961">1961</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP133 Ability and Achievement of Evening College and Extension Students (DeCrow, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1959">1959</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP134 Why Students Drop Out: A Study of Evening College Student Motivations (Carey, James T.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953">1953</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP135 Cumulative Indexes to the Association of University Evening Colleges Proceedings and National University Extension Association Proceedings, 1915-1957</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP136 The Role of Liberal Arts in the University Evening College Curriculum, Pinebrook, N. Y., October <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954 </unitdate> (CSLEA Conference Report)</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP137 Tradition and Innovation in University Adult Education, Swampscott, Massachusetts, October<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954">1954 </unitdate>  (CSLEA Conference Report)</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP138 The University's Responsibility for the General Education of Adults, Chicago, Illinois, March 3-5, <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate>(CSLEA Conference Report)</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP139 The Concerns of the Dean in University Adult Education, Chicago, Illinois, March 5-7, <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate> (CSLEA Conference Report)</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP140 A Report: Administrative Policies and Practices of Evening Colleges (Neuffer, Frank R)</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP141 A Report: A Review of  Center Activities and Projects (CSLEA)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP142 A Report: A Review of  Center Activities and Projects (CSLEA)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP143 A Report: A Review of  Future Directions of the Center and A Report of Current Activities (CSLEA)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1958">1958</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>REP144 CSLEA in Retrospect (Liveright, A. A.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Reprints series (RPR)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR1 "The Evening College."  Houle, Cyril O. <emph render="italic">Journal of Higher Education</emph> Vol. XXV, No. 7</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1954-10">Oct. 1954</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR2 "The University's Role in Adult Education: A Journal Symposium."  (Diekhoff, John S.; Leys, Wayne A. R.; Conley, William H.; Schwertman, John B. <emph render="italic">Journal of Higher Education</emph> Vol. XXVI, No. 1</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955-01">Jan. 1955</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR3 "The American University and Adult Education." Houle, Cyril O. <emph render="italic">Educational Record</emph></unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955-10">Oct. 1955</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR4 "Liberal Education Reexamined" Horn, Francis H. <emph render="italic">Harvard Educational Review</emph>, Vol. XXVI, No. 4</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956">Fall 1956</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR5 "What's Your Line? The Task of the Adult Educator" Miller, Harry L. <emph render="italic">Adult Leadership</emph>, Vol. 6, No. 3</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-09">Sept. 1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR6 "The Alumni University." Diekhoff, John S. <emph render="italic">Journal of Higher Education</emph>, Vol. XXVIII, No. 7</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-10">Oct. 1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR7 "AUEX Background - From Coffee to Capers to Educational Leadership." Love, Robert A. <emph render="italic">AUEC Newsletter</emph>, Vol. VI, No. 1</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957-11">Nov. 1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR8 "An Exchange of Letters Between Alfred [Albert] Einstein and Sigmund Freud on the Subject Why War?"</unittitle><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>RPR9 "Why Don't We Have Better Teaching for Adults?" Miller, Harry L.</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1957">1957</unitdate><container type="Box">16</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Syracuse University Related publications (SUR)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUR1 To Serve the Public Interest: Educational Broadcasting in the United States (Blakely, Robert J.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03 id="sur2"><did><unittitle>SUR2 Comparing Adult Education Worldwide (Charters, Alexander N. et al.)</unittitle><abstract>hardcover; published by Jossey Bass</abstract><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1981">1981</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUR3 Changing Approaches to Studying Adult Education (Long, Huey B. and Hiemstra, Roger)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUR4 Information Resources for Educators of Adults (Charters, Alexander N.) </unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUR5 CAEO Through the Years (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUR6 [MISSING] The Teaching Profession and the Education of Adults: A Review and an Agenda (Committee on Adult Education World Confederation of Organizations of the Teaching Profession)</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUR7 A Statement on Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (Charters, Alexander N.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976">1976</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03></c02>

   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>William Pearson Tolley Medal series (WPT)</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT1 The Uncommon School (Houle, Cyril O.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1966">1966</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT2 University and The Community (Mehta, Mohan S.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT3 Universities, Adult Education and Social Criticism (Raybould, Sidney Griffith)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT4 Towards Still Greater Professionalism (Bartlett, Kenneth G.)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1971">1971</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT5 Relentless Verity: Education for Being-Becoming-Belonging (Kidd, James Robbins)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT6 "A Rusty Person is Worse Than Rusty Iron" -- Adult Education and the Development of Africa (Bown, Lalage)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1975">1975</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>WPT7 The Promise and Pragmatism of Adult Education (White, Thurman)</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1979">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03></c02>












</c01>
<c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle></did>
   <c02><did><unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1982" type="inclusive">1966-1982</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"Accent on Social Philosophy"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Adult Education Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1976" type="inclusive">1970-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Adult Education Clearinghouse</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/1974" type="inclusive">1964-1974</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>   <c02><did><unittitle>ACHE, NAPCAE, NEA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970" type="inclusive">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Apps, Jerrold</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Autographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Bartlett, Kenneth G.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Bown, Lalage</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Carlson, Robert A.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1974" type="inclusive">1969-1974</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Chicago Tribune</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1975" type="inclusive">1972-1975</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>CPAE</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle><unitdate normal="1965/1984" type="inclusive">1965-1984</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Carbons</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Mailings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1974" type="inclusive">1970-1974</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Doris Chertow</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Crime Book</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Dubnick, Phyllis</unittitle><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Krinsky, Fred</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Schwartz, Harry</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Council on Continuing Education</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Cross, Wilbur</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Darkenwald, Beder, Merozow</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate><container type="Box">17</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Discussion leadership guide - inquiries</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Dissertation abstracts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1982" type="inclusive">1979</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Distribution contracts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1971" type="inclusive">1968-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Even, Mary Jane</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02 id="eom-cont"><did><unittitle>"Evolution of Man" - contract agreement</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>   <c02 id="eom-corr"><did><unittitle>"Evolution of Man" - correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1971" type="inclusive">1966-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: American Foundation for Continuing Education (AFCE) series (AFC): <ref target="afc68">AFC68 Evolution of Man</ref></p></note></c02>

   <c02><did><unittitle>"Exploring the Universe" - correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1972" type="inclusive">1960-1972</unitdate><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"Exploring the Universe" - permissions</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>   <c02><did><unittitle>"Exploring the Universe" - photograph permissions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1982" type="inclusive"></unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Form letters</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"Future of Religion"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02 id="ad-giap"><did><unittitle>"Great Issues in American Politics"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did><note><p>See also Publications: American Foundation for Continuing Education (AFCE) series (AFC): <ref target="afc33"> 	 	 	AFC33 Great Issues in American Politics Part I</ref>; Publications:  	 	Fund for Adult Education series (FAE): <ref target="fae30">FAE30 Great Issues in American Politics Part I</ref></p></note></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Greer, Loyal</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Houle, Cyril O.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>I.B.M.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Inventories</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1978" type="inclusive">1968-1978</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Jacobson, Nolan Pliny</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Jessup, Frank</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Kozoll, Charles</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"List of Publications," Charters, Alexander N. and Holmwood, Donald [same as MSS26]</unittitle>   <unitdate normal="1983" type="inclusive">1983</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>"Concerns About Adult Education" (Schroeder, Wayne)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1982" type="inclusive"></unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c03>      <c03><did><unittitle>"New Media"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c03>

      <c03><did><unittitle>"Why Adults Learn" (Tough, Allen)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1982" type="inclusive"></unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><container type="Box">18</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Memos </unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>   <c02><did><unittitle>Memos from Alexander N. Charters</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1976" type="inclusive">1972-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"Memo from Syracuse"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1976" type="inclusive">1972-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Miller, Paul</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Moses, Stanley</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1973" type="inclusive">1971-1973</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"Mystery of Matter" - records and permissions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1963/1971" type="inclusive">1963-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>National Institute for Adult Education - England (NIAE)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>New York Associaton for Continuing Education (NYACE)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1975" type="inclusive">1969-1975</unitdate><container type="Box">18</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Non-profit corporation reports</unittitle><abstract>includes articles of incorporation</abstract><unitdate normal="1964/1969" type="inclusive">1964-1969</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Office procedures</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Ohliger, John</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1975" type="inclusive">1971-1975</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Organizer's manual, AFCE</unittitle><unitdate normal="1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Oxford Press projects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1973" type="inclusive">1966-1973</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Pardoen, Alan R.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Penfield, Kathleen</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Peters, John M.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1977" type="inclusive">1975-1977</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Problems</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1980" type="inclusive">1966-1980</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>6 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">19</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1979" type="inclusive">1977-1979</unitdate><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">19</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Form letters</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Raybould, Sidney G.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970" type="inclusive">1970</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Readings in American foreign policy</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1958/1960" type="inclusive">1958-1960</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Readings in world politics</unittitle><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>   <c02><did><unittitle>Records (financial)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1977" type="inclusive">1970-1977</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Redman, George</unittitle><unitdate normal="1976" type="inclusive">1976</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Rivera, William</unittitle><abstract>curriculum vitae, summary of professional experience</abstract><unitdate normal="1992" type="inclusive">1992</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>School of Education minutes</unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Science and international relations</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Carnegie endowment</unittitle><unitdate normal="1965" type="inclusive">1965, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Permissions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1971" type="inclusive">1967-1971</unitdate><container type="Box">19</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>Working papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">20</container></did></c03></c02>   <c02><did><unittitle>Science and public policy - correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1972" type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Science and world affairs</unittitle></did>

      <c03><did><unittitle>Biographies</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle> Illustrations</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle> Reading lists</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>"Ways of Mankind"</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Whipple, James</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Young, Louise</unittitle><abstract>correspondence</abstract><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02></c01>
<c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Syracuse University Resources for Educators of Adults (SUREA)</unittitle></did>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Annual report</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Collection descriptions and lists</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Descriptive subject headings</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Drafts</unittitle><abstract>annotated draft of a description of the adult education collections -- possibly an early draft of <ref target="mss34">MSS34</ref> which was later split into several different MSS series publications</abstract><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1979/1987" type="inclusive">1988-1989</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>General correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1987" type="inclusive">1973-1987</unitdate><physdesc><extent>5 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02 level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Memos</unittitle></did>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SU-AE Memo nos. 1-76</unittitle><physdesc><extent>3 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">20</container></did></c03>
      <c03><did><unittitle>SUREA Memo nos. 1-9</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c03></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>National Center for Higher Education Management Systems</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Notes (Alexander N. Charters)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Printed material</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>Stensland, Per Gustaf</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980" type="inclusive"></unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>
   <c02><did><unittitle>SUPCE,  SUREA statements</unittitle><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02>     <c02><did><unittitle>Syracuse University Libraries</unittitle><abstract>correspondence with library personnel regarding donors, gifts, cataloguing, and other matters related to the adult education collections</abstract><physdesc><extent>2 folders</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1979/1987" type="inclusive">1979-1987</unitdate><container type="Box">20</container></did></c02></c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>


