<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!-- TEMPLATE VERSION 1.9, 7/18/2007-->
<!-- Changed entity files to txt rather than xml, don't suppose it matters which they are (?) -->

<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
   <!--All items are required unless marked OPT.  Any optional items 
not used should be commented out so that they don't appear in the viewable
 document.-->

<eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="NSyU" identifier="watson_paradise">watson_paradise</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Bill and Marie Watson Paradise Press Collection</titleproper>
            <subtitle>An  inventory of the collection at Syracuse University</subtitle>
         <author encodinganalog="Creator">MRC</author></titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;<lb/></publisher>
            &su_address;
            <date normal="2006-03-08" encodinganalog="Date">7 Feb 2008</date>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Michele Combs
            <date normal="2006-03-08">7 Feb 2008</date>
         </creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="Language">English</language>
         </langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <!--Enter revisions in the format "## date - ## change (## initials)"--><revisiondesc>
         <list>
            <item></item>
         </list>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="MARC21">
      <did>
         <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
         <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">
         &su_name; <lb/> &su_address;
         </repository>
         <origination label="Creator: ">
            <persname encodinganalog="100">Watson, William, 1917-2006.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Bill and Marie Watson Paradise Press Collection</unittitle>
         <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1950/2006" type="inclusive" label="Inclusive Dates: ">1950-2006</unitdate>
           <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" normal="1990/2006" type="bulk" label="Bulk Dates: ">1990-2006</unitdate><physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: "><extent>2 linear ft.</extent></physdesc>
         <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">Bill Watson and his wife Marie were long-time "artists in residence" for Paradise Press, a small private press owned by Hal Leader in Buffalo, New York.  The collection includes printed material from Paradise Press as well as a few items from Watson's previous press, Wm. J. Keller, Inc., a small amount of biographical material, an essay by Watson on Unitarian Universalism, and two books.</abstract>
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " countrycode="US" repositorycode="NSyU">2590472</unitid>
         <langmaterial label="Language: " encodinganalog="546"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
            
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
         <head>Biographical History</head>
         
      <p>William (Bill) Watson (1917-2006) attended the University of Buffalo where he earned a degree in business.  Soon after graduation his love of books (he amassed at one time a substantial book collection that included a Kelmscott Chaucer) led him into the world of publishing when he and his brother acquired Wm J. Keller, Inc. in Buffalo, New York.  Although the original arrangement was for Bill to handle the business end and his brother to do design work, they soon swapped roles.  The press had a varied clientele including numerous college and university yearbooks, and was the first in western New York to do photo offset printing.  In 1938 Marie Woods, a Syracuse University graduate in journalism, came to work for them, and in 1941 Marie and Bill were married.</p><p>In addition to his work with Keller Press, Bill was a member of the Salisbury Club of Buffalo, a group of bibliophiles whose namesake was the city's first printer.     In 1954, Wm J. Keller, Inc. published <emph render="italic">The Story of the Salisbury Press</emph>, in the foreword to which Watson wrote, "This little book chronicles the story of Buffalo's first press and the newspaper that issued from it...From that far-off day until now, the printing industry has continued to flourish in the Niagara region...Here has been formed a mighty concentration of craftsmen, artists and men of business devoted to the graphic arts."</p><p>In 1951 Bill began publishing independently under a private imprint,  Easy Hill Press (so named for its location at the top of a very steep incline), which produced letterpress work for Wm. J. Keller, Inc. and also collaborated with the University of Buffalo's rare books and manuscripts collections to publish many rare and collectible editions for the Salisbury Club.   Among Easy Hill's works were James Joyce's <emph render="italic">Epiphanies</emph>, a posthumous work never before published, and a volume of Mark Twain's commentary <emph render="italic">On the Art of Writing</emph>.  Bill's love of fine printing included artwork as well, particularly fine engravings.  For the Joyce book, he had an engraving made of  a Constantin Brancusi sketch of James Joyce found in the University of Buffalo collection; for the frontispiece of the Twain book,  he commissioned noted wood engraver John DePol to create an original wood engraving of Twain's Delaware Avenue home.    In a 2003 letter, DePol wrote of this piece, "It is one of my favorites!"  Easy Hill Press editions may be found today in the rare book rooms of many major university libraries.</p><p>In the early 1980s Bill and Marie closed the Keller press  and moved to Toronto.  Toronto (and retirement) failed to satisfy them, and the Watsons soon returned to Buffalo where they met Hal Leader, the owner of Printing Prep.  Leader had been a student of Emil Sahlin who in turn had trained with Roycroft's Elbert Hubbard and been one of Roycroft's best typographers.  In 1973 Leader and Sahlin formed Paradise Press, a typesetting division of Printing Prep that produced fine printing and advertising copy with a hand-operated press and movable type.    After Sahlin's death in 1983, Leader moved the Paradise Press equipment -- an antique Vandercook press and several founts of type -- to the back room at Printing Prep.   According to Leader, the name originated from a conversation he had with Sahlin:  "I told Emil, 'You're 78 years old now. If you don't feel good, you don't come to work. If you feel like working four hours, you work four hours, if you want to work eight hours, you work eight hours. If a customer comes in with a job and it's too rushed, you don't have to take it... And Emil said, 'My God, if I could do that, it would be paradise.' "   ["Leader of the pack," <emph render="italic">Buffalo Business First</emph>, June 22, 2001]</p><p>Bill, whose love of fine printing had not faded with retirement, was happy to accept Leader's invitation to keep the Paradise Press equipment in use, and by 1990 he and Marie had settled into what would become a fifteen-year tradition of "Keepsakes




," semiannual mailings to friends and family.  The trifold or quarterfold leaflets were usually themed and consist of a combination of artwork and quotations; the quotations were collected and chosen by Marie, the art selected by Bill.  Production duties were also shared, with Bill handling the typesetting and layout while Marie was responsible for proofing and copyediting as well as pulling the copies (usually 100-250).   Bill and Marie would accept no money for their work and no subscriptions.  For both of them, the pieces were produced simply for the joy of the work; as Hal Leader recalled, "It was like they were always saying 'I love you' to each other when they were working."</p><p>In 2003 Marie suffered a stroke and grandson Jonathan Senchyne joined Bill to take over responsibility for pulling copies.  Marie died in 2004; Bill continued to issue occasional mailers until he died in 2006.  The last item printed by Paradise Press was a Keepsake "celebrating the love and spirit of Bill Watson."  </p><p>[Portions of this biographical sketch provided by Jonathan Senchyne.]</p></bioghist>
      
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
         <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
         <p>The <emph render="bold">Bill and Marie Watson Paradise Press Collection</emph> is divided into Personal material, W. J. Keller, Inc., and Paradise Press.</p><p><emph render="bold">Personal material</emph> includes clippings, the memorial broadside published on Bill Watson's death in 2006, some Unitarian Universalist Church material, and two books.   The two books are <emph render="italic">Trial of the Masks</emph>, a book of poetry by Gene Magner, for which Watson did the type design and printing, and the inaugural issue of <emph render="italic">Living Forge</emph>, "the literary and arts journal of the rust belt," founded and co-edited by Watson's grandson Jonathan Senchyne.  The latter is inscribed and signed by Senchyne to his grandparents.  <emph render="italic">Living Forge</emph> includes a strike of the original DePol Twain house block, which was the one Bill had used when teaching Senchyne how to print blocks.</p><p> Four <emph render="bold">Wm. J. Keller, Inc.</emph> items date from Watson's early years: a type sample book and three  Christmas items -- one for Wm. J. Keller, Inc. itself, one "published by the Niagara Frontier Transit System of Buffalo as their 1950 Christmas greeting to passengers," and one  a Christmas greeting from Bill and Marie.</p><p><emph render="bold">Paradise Press</emph> material consists primarily of the "Keepsakes" printed by Watson and his wife Marie under the Paradise Press imprint.    The plentiful and beautiful artwork in the Keepsakes came from engravings from Watson's Easy Hill Press days and from his extensive collection of original woodcuts, including many by Thomas Bewick.  Bewick was one of Watson's favorite illustrators and many of the Keepsakes feature his woodcuts (see for example the 2002 holiday issue).  Other artists include John DePol (the 1999 holiday Keepsake features his wood engraving commissioned by Watson for the  Easy Hill edition of Mark Twain's <emph render="italic">On the Art of Writing</emph>), Edward Gorey (1992 holiday, March 1999),  and William Blake (2000 holiday).   On some of the items Bill used letterhead nameplates designed for himself and Marie in the 1960s by well-known English engraver, designer, and typographer Reynolds Stone (Stone's work also appears in the 1997 and 2001 holiday issues, June 1999,  spring 2005, and on Watson's business card).  </p><p>The Watsons were members of the Shaw Festival and friends of the Festival's long-time artistic director Christopher Newton; as a consequence theatre is a frequent theme of the mailings.  Other themes include sports, politics, travel, and writers and writing.  Other Keepsakes of particular interest are summer 1995 (on the death of Mickey Mantle), a 1996 issue of  Nixon quotes,  spring 2003  (Bill's story of how he and Marie met), spring 2005 (biographical sketch of Roycroft typographer Emil Sahlin) and the holiday 1997 issue entirely on Reynolds Stone .</p><p>The Paradise Press material also contains an unfolded set of Keepsakes and a box of notes on index cards, primarily quotations.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
         <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
         <p>Personal material is arranged alphabetically by type.  Paradise Press Keepsakes are arranged chronologically; index cards are in the order received, with most being grouped by theme or topic.  Wm. J. Keller, Inc. material is arranged alphabetically by type.</p>
      </arrangement>
      
      <!--<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
         <head>Related Material</head>
         <p>## (MARC 544 1)</p>
      </relatedmaterial>-->
      
      <!--Use archref, not extref, to link to related collections.--><!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
         <head>Separated Material</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
      </separatedmaterial>-->
      
      <!--<otherfindaid encodinganalog="555">
         <head>Other Related Finding Aids</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p>
      </otherfindaid>-->
      
      <controlaccess>
         <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
         <!--For each, include source if possible (aat, lcsh, local, etc). Some have defaults set in the template.-->
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Publishing, printing and book arts</subject><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Watson, Marie, 1916-2004.</persname><persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Watson, William, 1917-2006.</persname>
         <!--<famname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">##</famname>-->
         <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Paradise Press (Buffalo, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf">Wm. J. Keller, Inc.</corpname>
         <!--<title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf">##</title>-->
         
         <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing.</subject><subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Small presses -- New York (State)</subject><!--<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">##</geogname>-->
         <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Books.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Broadsides (notices)</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Leaflets.</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Manuscripts (document genre)</genreform><genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Quotations (texts)</genreform>
         <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Publishers.</occupation><occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Printers.</occupation>
         <!--<function encodinganalog="657">##</function>--></controlaccess>
      
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
         <head>Access Restrictions</head>
         <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
         <head>Use Restrictions</head>
         <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
materials in this collection.</p>
      </userestrict>
      
      <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
         <p>Bill and Marie Watson Paradise Press Collection, <lb/> &su_name; </p>
      </prefercite>
      
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
         <head>Acquisition Information</head>
         <p>Gift of <persname role="donor">Jonathan Senchyne</persname>.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      
      <!--<appraisal encodinganalog="583">
         <head>Appraisal Information</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p>
      </appraisal>-->
      
      <!--<accruals encodinganalog="584">
         <head>Accruals</head>
         <p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p>
      </accruals>-->
      
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>Inventory</head>
         <c01 level="series">
         <!--C01 @LEVEL must be set to 'series' to show up in TOC.-->
            <did>
               <unittitle>Personal material</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle><emph render="italic">Living Forge</emph> (Senchyne)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2003" type="inclusive">2003</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02>
         <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Memorabilia</unittitle>
                  <abstract>business card, clippings</abstract><unitdate normal="2006" type="inclusive">2006, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1988/2006" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Memorabilia (oversize)</unittitle>
                  <abstract>Bill Watson memorial "Keepsake"</abstract><unitdate normal="2006" type="inclusive">2006</unitdate>
                  <container type="Oversize">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle><emph render="italic">Trial of the Masks</emph> (Magner)</unittitle>
                  <abstract>includes clipping about Magner</abstract><unitdate normal="1950" type="inclusive">1950</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Unitarian Universalist Church</unittitle>
                  </did>
            <c03><did><unittitle>Essay</unittitle><unitdate normal="1985" type="inclusive">1985</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did></c03><c03><did><unittitle>Printed material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1987" type="inclusive">1987, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1988/2006" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did> </c03></c02></c01><c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Paradise Press</unittitle></did><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Keepsakes"</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1990/2006" type="inclusive">1990-2006, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1990/2006" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <physdesc><extent>4 folders</extent></physdesc><container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Keepsakes" (not folded)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1990/2006" type="inclusive">1990-2006, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1990/2006" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Oversize">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes (on index cards)</unittitle>
                  
                  <container type="Oversize">2</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02></c01>
      <c01 level="series"><did><unittitle>Wm. J. Keller, Inc.</unittitle></did><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Printed items</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1950" type="inclusive">1950, </unitdate><unitdate normal="1950/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02><c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Type sample book</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1931/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container type="Box">1</container>
                  
                  
               </did>
            </c02></c01></dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
