<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../ead_dtd/ead.dtd" [
<!ENTITY scrc_name SYSTEM "scrc_name.txt">
<!ENTITY su_address SYSTEM "su_address.txt">
<!ENTITY su_name SYSTEM "su_name.txt">
<!ENTITY subjindex SYSTEM "subjindex.txt">
<!ENTITY summitref SYSTEM "summit_ref.txt">
]>

<!--Derived from Summit record.  Matches template version 1.7.-->
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21">
  <eadheader audience="internal" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="DC" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" identifier="white_h" mainagencycode="NSyU">white_h</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="Title">Horace White Papers</titleproper>
        <subtitle>An inventory of 
                        his papers 
                        at Syracuse University</subtitle>
        <author encodinganalog="Creator">--</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="Publisher">&su_name;
          <lb/></publisher>&su_address;
        <date encodinganalog="Date" normal="1970/1980">1975?</date></publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>[Derived from Summit]
                           
        
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2007-03-12">12 Mar 2007</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="Language" langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <list>
        <item>3 Mar 2009 - converted to EAD (MRC)</item>
      </list>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="MARC21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <head>Overview of the Collection</head>
      <repository id="scrc" encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository: ">&su_name;
        <lb/>&su_address;</repository>
      <origination label="Creator: ">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">White, Horace, 1865-1914.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" label="Title: ">Horace White Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" label="Inclusive Dates: " normal="1903/1914" type="inclusive">1903-1914</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="300$a" label="Quantity: ">
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">10.0 linear ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract: ">
                    Papers of the American lawyer, legislator, politician.  New York State Senator representing Onondaga County, and Lieutenant Governor, later Governor, upon the resignation of Charles Evans Hughes.  Correspondence (1900-1912), includes 4400 incoming letters and 4000 outgoing carbons; personal financial records (1903-1914); speeches; and photographs.   Correspondents include Nicholas Murray Butler, George Fisk Comfort, Chauncey M. Depew, Alan C. Fobes, Frank W. Higgins, Charles Evans Hughes, Seth Low, Frank A. Munsey, Benjamin B. Odell, Thomas C. Platt, Elihu Root, Jacob G. Schurman, William H. Taft, James W. Wadsworth, Andrew Dickson White, and other White family members, and Timothy L. Woodruff.</abstract>
      <unitid countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099" label="Identification: " repositorycode="NSyU">148751</unitid>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="546" label="Language: ">
        <language langcode="eng">
                          English
                       </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <head>Biographical History</head>
      <p>Horace White (1865-1943) was an American lawyer, state legislator, and Republican governor of 
New York.  He lived and practiced law in the city of Syracuse for more than thirty years.</p>
      <p>Horacw White was born at Buffalo on 7 October 1865, first son of Horace Keep and 
Marion (Strong) White. The White family was prominent in the affairs of 
upstate New York, and Horace's uncle, Andrew Dickson White, was the first 
president of Cornell University.  A family tree is available 
        
        <extref href="white_h_famtree.png">here</extref> (if online), or at the end of this finding aid (if in hard copy).</p>
      <p>Graduated from Cornell in 1887 and the Columbia University Law School in 
1889, White studied law in the Syracuse office of Frank Hiscock before entering 
practice in Syracuse, where his firm of White, Cheney, Shinaman, and O'Neill 
was long located in the White Memorial Building. In 1896 he began the first 
of six consecutive terms as a Republican state senator, representing Onondaga 
County. As chairman of the Committee on Cities he played an influential role 
in the development of chartering provisions for second-class cities in the 
state and in the drawing of the first charter for the City of New York at the 
time of the consolidation of 1898. Other of his
legislative work concerned the civil service law and additional reforms.</p>
      <p>In 1908 Horace White was elected lieutenant-governor on the Republican ticket 
headed by Charles Evans Hughes, then running for his second term. White 
became governor on 6 October 1910, when Governor Hughes resigned after being 
named an associate justice of the United States Supreme Court, and served
as governor until 1 January 1911. He did not seek his party's nomination to 
succeed himself.</p>
      <p>Remaining a prominent figure in the political, business, and social life of 
Syracuse for more than thirty years after he left the governor's chair, he 
served as president of the Post-Standard Company in Syracuse and was long a 
trustee of Cornell University. He married in 1903 Mrs. Jane (Lines) Denison, 
who died in 1937. They had no children. He died in New York on 27 November 
1943, survived by his brothers Andrew S. and Ernest I. White.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
      <head>Scope and Contents of the Collection</head>
      <p>The 
        
        <emph render="bold">Horace White Papers</emph> at the George Arents Research Library at Syracuse 
University are the incomplete correspondence files of Horace White for the 
six years preceding his governorship, along with personal financial files 
from a wider period and some miscellaneous items. With the exception of fewer 
than a half dozen items, all the papers date from 1903 to 1914.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph> (1905-1912, with a few letters from 1900) includes letters 
from Horace White's personal, office, and State Fair files, dating chiefly 
from the years when he was a state senator and the New York lieutenant-
governor. Besides portions of his legislative and routine political 
correspondence, there is family correspondence with Andrew Dickson White, 
former president of Cornell University, Andrew S. and Ernest I. White, 
lawyers in Syracuse, and Horace K. White, the father, also a Syracuse lawyer. 
Arrangement of the correspondence is under the headings of incoming, 
outgoing, and other letters.</p>
      <p>Approximately 4400 incoming letters date from January 1905 to May 1910, with some additional letters from 1911 
and 1912. Gaps in the letters are numerous; in particular, note the following gaps:</p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>1905 Apr 19 - 1906 Jan 10
          
          <lb/>1906 May 2 - 1907 Jan 5
          
          <lb/>1907 Apr 29 - 1907 May 5
1907
          
          <lb/> Jun 6 - 1907 Dec 14
          
          <lb/>1908 Apr 23 - 1908 May 13
          
          <lb/>1908 Jun 27 - 1908 Sep 25
          
          <lb/>1909 May 29 - 1909 Dec 3
          
          <lb/>1910 May 28 - 1911 Jul 12
          
          <lb/>1911 Jul 14 - 1912 May 28</p>
      </blockquote>
      <p>
Approximately 4000 outgoing letters, represented by carbon copies and, in 
rare instances, by returned originals, date from January 1905 to May 1910. In box 15 is a 
section of other letters that includes correspondence of Timothy L. Woodruff, 
a former New York lieutenant-governor who was then chairman of the New York 
State Republican executive committee, and letters of other New York State 
political figures. </p>
      <p>Some notable correspondents, with counts on their incoming letters and the 
copies of Horace White's letters to them, follow.</p>
      <blockquote>
        <list>
          <item>William S. Bennett 2 incoming/1 outgoing</item>
          <item>Nicholas Murray Butler 1/5</item>
          <item>George Fisk Comfort 3/2</item>
          <item>Chauncey M. Depew 2/4</item>
          <item>Hamilton Fish 1/0</item>
          <item>Alan C. Fobes 14/0</item>
          <item>Frank W. Higgins 9/15</item>
          <item>Charles Evans Hughes 23/18</item>
          <item>George F. Johnson 1/0</item>
          <item>Seth Low 2/2</item>
          <item>Frank A. Munsey 1/0</item>
          <item>Benjamin B. Odell 4/5</item>
          <item>Thomas C. Platt 4/7</item>
          <item>Theodore Roosevelt 1/4
(TR secretarial, 4)</item>
          <item>
Elihu Root 3/3</item>
          <item>Edward Schoeneck 0/19</item>
          <item>Jacob G. Schurman 14/12</item>
          <item>Lyman C. Smith 0/3</item>
          <item>William Howard Taft 3/11</item>
          <item>James W. Wadsworth, Jr. 2/3</item>
          <item>Andrew Dickson White 7/0</item>
          <item>Andrew S. White</item>
          <item>33/38
Ernest I. White</item>
          <item>40/67
Horace K. White</item>
          <item>51/83
Timothy L. Woodruff 72/64</item>
        </list>
      </blockquote>
      <p>These letters to White are often from 
Syracuse firms and individuals, indicating their stands on the gas and 
insurance scandals and subsequent reforms, the eight-hour workday, home rule 
for the state's cities, police reform of New York City, the nation's first 
workmen's compensation law, many other reforms, Onondaga County politics, and 
the New York State Fair Commission. There are letters from office seekers, 
requests for appointments and other favors, and copies of letters to the 
editors of the Syracuse Herald and Post. Approximately half of the letters 
are addressed to him as chairman of state Senate committees.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Financial files</emph> contain receipted bills 
describing household expenses, medical charges, and expenditures for clothing, 
club and organization memberships, hotels, restaurants, and the like, with 
some occasional accompanying correspondence. Also there are itemized bills 
for telegrams sent. The bills are partly missing for 1913 and are fragmentary 
for the years 1909, 1910, and 1914. All other years between 1903 and 1912 are 
thoroughly represented.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Miscellaneous material</emph> dates primarily from 1909 and 1910. There are speeches of Horace White, documents relating to the New 
York State Fair, items of memorabilia, including a few photographs, and 
documents that relate to matters of public policy and others that relate to 
legal cases preseumably argued by the White law firm.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351$a">
      <head>Arrangement of the Collection</head>
      <p>Incoming correspondence is chronologically arranged; letters dated only to the year are filed at the end of the letters 
for that year.  Outgoing correspondence is alphabetically arranged by name of correspondent.  Nineteen letters damaged by oil are separately wrapped and 
placed in box 15 at the end of the correspondence section; typed copies of 
those letters have been prepared and placed in the appropriate folders in the 
sequence of letters.  Financial files are grouped by year and within each year are arranged alphabetically.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <head>Related Material</head>
      <p>Additional Horace White correspondence 
is located in various other collections; please search the finding aids for "White, Horace" for a complete listing.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <!--<separatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 0">
      <head>Separated Material</head>
      <p>## OPT (MARC 544 0)</p>
    </separatedmaterial>--><!--
            <otherfindaid encodinganalog="555"><head>Other Related Finding Aids</head><p>## OPT (MARC 555)</p></otherfindaid>
            -->
    <controlaccess>
      <head>Subject and Genre Headings</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">Politics, government and public administration</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="local">New York State</subject>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Comfort, George Fisk, 1833-1910.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Depew, Chauncey M. (Chauncey Mitchell), 1834-1928.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Fobes, Alan C.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Higgins, Frank Wayland, 1856-1907.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Low, Seth, 1850-1916.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Munsey, Frank Andrew, 1854-1925.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Odell, Benjamin B. (Benjamin Barker), 1854-1926.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Platt, Thomas Collier, 1833-1910.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1846-1926.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">White, Horace, 1865-1914 Archives.</persname>
      <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf">White family.</persname>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Legislators -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Governors -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Onondaga County (N.Y.) -- History.</subject>
      <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Politicians -- United States.</subject>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Correspondence.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Financial records.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographs.</genreform>
      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Speeches (documents)</genreform>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Governors.</occupation>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Legislators.</occupation>
      <occupation encodinganalog="656" source="lcsh">Politicians.</occupation>
    </controlaccess>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <head>Use Restrictions</head>
      <p>Written permission must be obtained from SCRC and 
                       all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any 
                       materials in this collection. </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Preferred citation for this material is as follows:</p>
      <p>Horace White Papers,
        
        <lb/>&su_name;</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <head>Acquisition Information</head>
      <p>Gift of the 
        
        <corpname role="donor">Bersani Construction Co.</corpname>, 1962.</p>
      <p>The Horace White Papers at Syracuse University are only a part of the 
correspondence and other files that were stored at the White home at 742 
James Street in Syracuse, where Horace White lived for nearly forty years 
before his death in 1943. Overlooked by family members who cleared the house, 
the papers were uncovered in the property's carriage house in 1962 shortly 
before the house's demolition. By that time the papers had been rifled by 
vandals, with individual letters and whole packets removed, accounting for 
the many gaps in the correspondence. The missing files have not yet been 
recovered. The surviving papers were given to Syracuse University by the 
Bersani Construction Company in 1962.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <!--
            <appraisal encodinganalog="583"><head>Appraisal Information</head><p>## OPT (MARC 583)</p></appraisal>
       --><!--
            <accruals encodinganalog="584"><head>Accruals</head><p>## OPT (MARC 584)</p></accruals>
       -->
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Inventory</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Incoming</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950-01-03/1905-03-31">1905 Jan 3-1905 Mar 31</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1905-04/1906-02">1905 Apr 1-1906 Feb 25</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1906-02/1907-01">1906 Feb 26-1907 Jan 31</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">3</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1907-02/1907-04">1907 Feb 1-1907 Apr 29</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">4</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1907-05/1908-03">1907 May 5-1908 Mar 28</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1908-04/1909-01">1908 Apr 2-1909 Jan 31</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">6</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909-02/1909-03">1909 Feb 1-1909 Mar 31</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">7</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909-04/1910-01">1909 Apr 1-1910 Jan 30</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">8</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1910-02/1912-10">1910 Feb 1-1912 Oct, </unitdate>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <container type="Box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Outgoing</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Abbott - Cuyler</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Daingerfield - Hoyt</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Hubbard - Phillips</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Pickard - Thurston</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Tibbals - Zischang</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Unidentified</unittitle>
              <container type="Box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Other letter files</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1900">1900, </unitdate>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1905/1910">1905-1910, </unitdate>
                <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
              </unittitle>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>8 folders</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <container type="Box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial files (receipted bills)</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1905">1903-1905</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <container type="Box">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1906/1907">1906-1907</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <container type="Box">17</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1908/1911">1908-1911</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <container type="Box">18</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1912/1914">1912-1914</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <container type="Box">19</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Miscellanea</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Family record of Henry D. Denison</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1845/1855">circa 1850</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Laurent Manor Company application and related documents</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>5 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909/1910">1909-1910</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal statements and related documents</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>7 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1908/1910">1908-1910, </unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legislative documents</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>3 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1905">1905,</unitdate><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Fair</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Financial report</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909">1909</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous paper</unittitle>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>7 items</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909/1911">1909-1911</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous printed material</unittitle>
              <physdesc>
                <extent>3 items</extent>
              </physdesc>
              <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909">1909</unitdate>
              <container type="Box">20</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Fair Commission, minutes of meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909/1910">1909-1910</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>4 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Printed speeches of Horace White</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Report, "Free Education at Cornell University"</unittitle>
            <abstract>typescript copy, 43 pp</abstract>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1904/1914">circa 1909</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reports</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>3 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Resolutions and petitions</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>7 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909/1910">1909-1910, </unitdate>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Speech by Horace White upon leaving the state senate</unittitle>
            <abstract>typescript copy, 1 p.</abstract>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Statements by Horace White on public issues</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>3 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1906">1906, </unitdate>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1903/1914">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Trustees of Public Buildings, minutes of meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909">1909, </unitdate>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1910">1910</unitdate>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>2 folders</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous items and fragments</unittitle>
            <physdesc>
              <extent>3 items</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous printed material</unittitle>
            <container type="Box">20</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
