<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0057.xml">nnan0057</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Henry Grunthal curator correspondence, 1967-1969</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">©2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Henry Grunthal curator correspondence</unittitle><abstract>Contains official correspondence from Grunthal's work as curator of the American Numismatic Society, mostly relating to the cost and historical values of coins, medals, and paper money.</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/grunthal" role="xeac:entity">Grunthal, Henry, 1905-2001</persname></origination><unitdate normal="1967/1969">1967-1969</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>2 cubic feet (2 boxes)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>Henry Grunthal, 1973</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6040/6244148348_c39d64205d_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6040/6244148348_c39d64205d_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6040/6244148348_c39d64205d_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6040/6244148348_c39d64205d.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Henry Grunthal (1905-2001) of the Riverdale section of the Bronx in New York City was born in Cologne, Germany, and was the son of numismatist and medal publisher Hugo Grunthal. He joined the American Numismatic Society (ANS) staff in 1953 as assistant to the chief curator and moved up to the position of curator of European and modern coins, a position he held until his retirement in 1973. His main activities at the ANS were building, labeling, and organizing the collections and assisting members with the identification and appraisal of coins, paper money, and medals. He was educated at the Friedrich Wilhelm University in Berlin, the University of Jena, and at the Sorbonne in Paris, where he studied archaeology and art history. He also studied numismatics under Kurt Regling in Berlin and Geheimrat Pick in Gotha. In 1938 he emigrated to the United States from Germany to work for Stack's Rare Coins in New York City. After retirement he was an independent numismatic consultant in New York City, where he also conducted auctions with Edward Gans at Numismatic Fine Arts. He wrote several articles for publications such as The Numismatist and Coin World and co-authored two books, Carolingian Coinage and The Coinage of Peru. He was awarded the American Numismatic Association Medal of Merit in 1970. Grunthal also received an ANS medal marking fifty years of continuous membership in 1979. He had been a member of the American Numismatic Association since 1929 and was active in both the Bronx Coin Club and the New York Numismatic Club, both of which he served as president.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Henry Grunthal papers, 1967-1969, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject>Coins--Collectors and collecting</subject><subject>Medals--Collectors and collecting</subject><subject>Paper money--Collectors and collecting</subject><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/grunthal" role="xeac:entity">Grunthal, Henry, 1905-2001</persname><corpname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/american_numismatic_society" role="xeac:entity">American Numismatic Society</corpname><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300103035">Rubbings (Visual works)</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Contains correspondence between Grunthal and his colleagues and members of the American Numismatic Society (ANS), coin collectors, and the general public about the cost and historical values of coins, medals, and paper money. The letters also include queries about the identification of coins and potential acquisitions, visits to the ANS, and the recommendation of dealers. Some queries were passed along to the ANS from other organizations, such as universities and galleries. Answers to queries include identification summaries, estimated values, and sources to consult. The collection includes both the letter received and the letter sent and occasionally coin rubbings. Letters are from all over the world, including Hong Kong, Canada, Tasmania, West Bengal India, Toronto, Singapore, Malaysia, Nicaragua, Uganda, England and Italy.</p></scopecontent></archdesc></ead>