<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0060.xml">nnan0060</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Charles Austin Hersh numismatic research materials, mostly late 1900s</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">©2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Charles Austin Hersh numismatic research materials</unittitle><abstract>Research materials pertaining to Hersh’s coin collections and his scholarly interest in Roman Republican and Macedonian coins.</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/hersh" role="xeac:entity">Hersh, Charles Austin, 1923-1999</persname></origination><unitdate normal="1970/1999" type="inclusive">mostly late 1900s</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>14 cubic feet (9 boxes and loose materials)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>Part of a notebook page from the collection</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6118/6312667612_5e6971e743_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6118/6312667612_5e6971e743_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6118/6312667612_5e6971e743_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6118/6312667612_5e6971e743.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6118/6312667612_5e6971e743_z.jpg" xlink:label="Medium 640"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Charles Austin Hersh (1923-1999) was a banker, collector of ancient coins, and numismatic scholar. He grew up in Elizabeth, New Jersey, graduated from Thomas Jefferson High School in 1940, and attended Amherst College before enlisting in the Army Air Corp, where he flew in thirty missions during his World War II service. He built up his collection and made contacts throughout the world during the war years. Returning to Amherst, he received his degree in 1946 and went on to earn an M.A. in history from Harvard in 1948. His love of coins eventually led him in 1950 to devote himself full time to numismatic scholarship at the British Museum, where he stayed for three and a half years. He published two groundbreaking articles in Numismatic Chronicle, "Sequence Marks on the Denarii of Publius Crepusius" (1952) and "Overstrikes as Evidence for the History of Roman Republican Coinage" (1953). Upon returning to the United States in 1953, he went into banking, working for Valley National, Bank Leumi, Chelsea National, and Republic National. Hersh became a member of the American Numismatic Society in 1947, a fellow in 1963, and a life fellow in 1997.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Charles Austin Hersh numismatic research materials, mostly late 1900s, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject>Coins, ancient--Collectors and collecting</subject><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/hersh" role="xeac:entity">Hersh, Charles Austin, 1923-1999</persname><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300262918">Offprints</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300048715">Articles</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300048719">Card indexes</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300026074">Sales catalogs</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300026931">Drafts (Documents)</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300028051">Books</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300046300">Photographs</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300027123">Checklists</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Contains research materials pertaining to Hersh’s coin collections and his scholarly interest in Roman Republican and Macedonian coins. Includes published items, some annotated by hand, such as offprints and reprints of articles, article drafts, coin lists, reference books, entire dealer catalogs, and two cubic feet of coin photographs and listings torn from catalogs. Manuscript items include bound handwritten catalogs with detailed descriptions of coins, card indexes to published, articles on ancient coins, and small notebooks. There are numerous negative and print photographs of coins, some of which are numbered and in sleeves, including those of Roman quadrigati, some arranged into what is presumably his own classification scheme, and a small number of Oath Scene Gold images. Also present are empty coin envelopes from Hersh’s collection and photographs of coin hoards and other materials held at several museums.</p></scopecontent><dsc/></archdesc></ead>