<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0166.xml">nnan0166</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Scrapbook of newspaper column With the Coin Collector, 1937-1951</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date normal="1937/1951">1937 - 1951</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid written by Arnold Tescher and encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2015</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="item"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Scrapbook of newspaper column With the Coin Collector</unittitle><abstract>Clippings of the column "With the Coin Collector" from the New York Herald Tribune.</abstract><physdesc><extent>1 Scrapbook</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination/><unitdate normal="1937/1951">1937 - 1951</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository></did><controlaccess><persname>Andrews, Ralph Barry</persname><persname>Kehr, Ernest Anthony</persname><genreform>Clippings</genreform><genreform>Scrapbooks</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content</head><p>Contains newspaper clippings collected from 1937-1951 on numismatic subjects. Majority are from the New York Herald Tribune (NYHT) under the column name “With the Coin Collector” and having no author byline noted. Ralph Barry Andrews authored the column followed by Ernest Anthony Kehr. The column ran from the 1930s until August 1, 1943, when it was discontinued. The articles almost always appeared each week in the paper’s Sunday edition. Additional loose (non-affixed) articles from 1937 and 1939-1942 are foldered. Topics range from ancient to modern coin issues and both American and foreign coins and medals with foreign issues predominating. Also included is a mix of general interest, numismatic stories for the non-numismatic public from other newspapers – New York Times, New York Sun, and Daily Mirror, as well as the NYHT. These discuss the new coin designs for the Roosevelt dime, (NYHT, Jan. 18, 1946, 1947), the Franklin half-dollar, (NYHT, Jan., 1948) and the “non existent” 1943 copper cent (NY Times, NY Sun, April, 1947.) Various articles about the new (1938) Jefferson nickel including a photo of the designer’s original design: “German-Born Sculptor Designs Jefferson Nickel” (NYHT, April 22, 1938); “Jefferson Nickel is Approved, Minting to Start by September” (NY Times, July 22, 1938) noting that the original design was revised by the US Mint with consumer reactions to the new nickel. Also included: various obituaries of ANS officers including Edward T. Newell and Howland Wood; articles about coin discoveries and their values; and two 19th century articles, “Old Coins and the Prices They Bring” (1877); “Our Oldest American Coins – The Fascination and Utility of the Numismatic Mania” (ca. late 1880s).</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Scrapbook of newspaper column With the Coin Collector, 1937-1951, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict></archdesc></ead>