<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0046.xml">nnan0046</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Paul R. Eden papers, 1954-1964</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">©2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Paul R. Eden papers</unittitle><abstract>Correspondence, manuscripts, and typescripts relating to Eden’s efforts to gather information on the mints of various countries.</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/eden" role="xeac:entity">Eden, Paul R. (Paul Randell), b. 1923</persname></origination><unitdate normal="1954/1964" type="inclusive">1954-1964</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>1 cubic foot (3 boxes)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>Part of a letter to Eden on coinage figures from the Royal Mint, London, March 28, 1963</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6285778405_8a6c66bbcd_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6285778405_8a6c66bbcd_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6285778405_8a6c66bbcd_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6285778405_8a6c66bbcd.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6119/6285778405_8a6c66bbcd_z.jpg" xlink:label="Medium 640"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Paul R. Eden (b. 1923) of Madison Heights, Virginia, specialized in coins of the world. Although born in Virginia, Eden enlisted in the Canadian Army in 1940. He was stationed in Europe and Africa during World War II and was wounded in the invasion of Sicily in 1943. He married Doris Elizabeth Harper of the British Army’s Women’s Auxiliary Territorial Service in 1945. Having been trained in telegraphy during his overseas service, he was employed by the Chesapeake &amp; Ohio Railroad in Virginia after leaving the Canadian Army in 1947. He retired from the railroad in 1962, having been afflicted with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS or Lou Gehrig's disease). Eden bought his first coins in England in 1945, but didn’t begin collecting in earnest until 1953, when he started concentrating on dime- and sixpence-sized coins, about which little documentation existed. His research into the coins would result in a series of articles on the mintage figures for various countries. The first of what would be called “mintage manuals” was published in the New Zealand Numismatic Journal (July, 1961), with subsequent articles appearing in Numismatic Scrapbook Magazine, World Coin Bulletin, and World Coins.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Paul R. Eden papers, 1954-1964, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject>Coins--Collectors and collecting</subject><subject source="lcsh" authfilenumber="sh85085885">Mints</subject><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/eden" role="xeac:entity">Eden, Paul R. (Paul Randell), b. 1923</persname><persname authfilenumber="44312470" source="viaf">Buttrey, Theodore V., 1929-</persname><persname authfilenumber="92956963" source="viaf">Benson, Lauren</persname><persname>Christenson, Henry, 1915-1979</persname><persname authfilenumber="30767960" source="viaf">Gaytan, Carlos</persname><persname>Godwin, Glenn</persname><persname>Hewitt, Lee F., 1911-1987</persname><persname>Hubbard, Clyde, b. 1916</persname><persname>Johnson, D. Wayne</persname><persname>Peck, William B</persname><persname authfilenumber="23714028" source="viaf">Remick, Jerome H</persname><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/williamson" role="xeac:entity">Williamson, Raymond H., 1907-1997</persname><persname authfilenumber="278486695" source="viaf">Zander, Randolph</persname><corpname authfilenumber="139572032" source="viaf">Gorham Manufacturing Company</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="130221075" source="viaf">Scovill Manufacturing Company</corpname><corpname>Jones Memorial Library (Lynchburg, Va.)</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="155372317" source="viaf">Royal Canadian Mint</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="134296767" source="viaf">Great Britain. Royal Mint</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="147602522" source="viaf">Virginia State Library</corpname><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300026877">Correspondence</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300028569">Manuscripts (Document genre)</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300028577">Typescripts</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Correspondence, manuscripts, and typescripts relating to Eden’s “mintage manuals” and his efforts to gather information on the mints of various countries. Topics include number of coins minted, authorizing laws, alloy percentages, weights, diameters, and the date on the coin versus the mintage dates. Eden corresponded with government and private mints, libraries, and numismatic specialists, including Lauren Benson (Davenport, Iowa), Theodore V. Buttrey (Yale), Henry Christensen (Hoboken), Carlos Gaytan (Mexico), Glenn Godwin (Binghamton, New York), Lee F. Hewitt (Numismatic Scrapbook Magazine editor), Clyde Hubbard (Mexico), D. Wayne Johnson (Shawnee Mission, Kansas), William B. Peck (White Plains, New York), Jerome H. Remick (Canada), Whitman Publishing (Wisconsin), Jones Memorial Library (Lynchburg, Virginia), Raymond H. Williamson (Lynchburg), Randolph Zander (Alexandria, Virginia), American Numismatic Society (New York City), Birmingham Mint (England), Gorham Manufacturing Company (Providence, Rhode Island), Royal Canadian Mint, Royal Mint (London), Scovill Manufacturing (Waterbury, Connecticut), U.S. Mint, and Virginia State Library. Some of the correspondence relates to Eden’s efforts to sell his collection, and other letters, particularly those of William B. Peck, at times address topics unrelated to coins, such as Eden’s health. Eden also corresponded with representatives of Australia, British Honduras, British North Borneo, China, Cuba, Bulgaria, Serbia, Montenegro, Luxembourg, El Salvador, Venezuela, Danzig, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Fiji, Hong Kong, Hungary, Iceland, Jamaica, Liberia, Liechtenstein, Rumania, and Uruguay.</p></scopecontent></archdesc></ead>