<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0027.xml">nnan0027</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>P.K. Anderson notebooks, mid-1900s</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">©2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>P.K. Anderson notebooks</unittitle><abstract>Notebooks with information on coins and tokens of Europe, European colonies, and the United States (first century B.C. to the 1900s), and a handwritten index to all four volumes of Numismatic Review (1943-1947).</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/anderson" role="xeac:entity">Anderson, P.K. (Paul Kenneth), 1894-1968</persname></origination><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930/1968">mid-1900s</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>1 cubic foot (1 box)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>A section of a page from one of the notebooks</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6166/6186749786_460076f940_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6166/6186749786_460076f940_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6166/6186749786_460076f940_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6166/6186749786_460076f940.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>P.K. (Paul Kenneth) Anderson (1894-1968) of Goteborg, Oklahoma, was an engineer and numismatist who published articles (circa 1930s-1960s), mostly on Spanish coins, in The Numismatist, the monthly magazine of the American Numismatic Association (ANA), and other publications. He served on the board of governors (1955-1961) and as president (1963-1965) of the ANA. His collection of Spanish coins was bequeathed to the American Numismatic Society.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><custodhist><head>Custodial History</head><p>Held by ANS since 1969.</p></custodhist><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>P.K. Anderson notebooks, mid-1900s, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject source="lcsh">Coins--Collectors and collecting</subject><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/anderson" role="xeac:entity">Anderson, P.K. (Paul Kenneth), 1894-1968</persname><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300264354">Notebooks</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="300026554" source="aat">Indexes (Reference sources)</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="300026059" source="aat">Catalogs (Documents)</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Twelve loose-leaf notebooks dating from the mid-20th century, one of which contains a handwritten index to all four volumes of Numismatic Review (1943-1947). The other eleven notebooks contain notes on coins and tokens of Europe, European colonies, and the United States (first century B.C. to the 1900s), with descriptions, grading, hand-drawn illustrations, and references to published sources. Topic headings listed in the eleven notebooks are (1) Argentina, Colombia, Costa Rica, Guatemala, Mexico; (2) Peru, Philippine Islands, Puerto Rico, Santo Domingo, U.S.A., Venezuela; (3) Antigua, Azores, Bahamas, Barbados, Bermuda, Brazil, British Colonies, British Guiana, British Virgin Islands-Buck Island, Cuba, Curacao, Danish West Indies, Dominica, Dominican Republic, Dutch Guiana, England &amp; Scotland, French Guiana, Grenada, Guadeloupe, Haiti, Holland, Jamaica, Martinique, Montserrat, Nevis, New South Wales, Paraguay, St. Bartholomew, St. Eustatius, Santa Lucia, St. Martin, Salvador, The Saints, Tobago, Tortola, Trinidad, Vieque; (4) Celtiberian, Latin, Roman, Visigothic, Moorish; (5) Castile &amp; Leon, Aragon &amp; Navarre; (6) Ferdinand &amp; Isabella; (7) Charles &amp; Johanna, Philip II, Philip III, Philip IV, Philip IV (countermarked); (8) Catalan Revolt &amp; French Occupation, Agramont, Banolas, Barcelona, Bellpuig, Besalu, Camprodon, Cataluna, Gerona, Manresa, Olot, Perpignan, Puigcerda, Roussillion, Solsona, Tagment, Tarrasa, Tarrega, Vich, Villa Franca Del Panades, Charles II, Philip V; (9) Charles III (Pretender), Luis I, Ferdinand VI, Charles III, Charles IV, Jose Napoleon; (10) Ferdinand VII, Isabella II; and (11) Isabella II (continued), Charles V (pretender), Provisional Government, The Interregnum, Amadeo I, Republic of Andorra, Canton de Cartagena, First Republic, Charles VII (pretender), Alfonso XII, Alfonso XIII, 2nd Republic, Civil War Issues, Francisco Franco.</p></scopecontent><dsc/></archdesc></ead>