<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0045.xml">nnan0045</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Henry Russell Drowne papers, 1884-1927</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">©2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Henry Russell Drowne papers</unittitle><abstract>Correspondence, research notes, drafts, and printed versions of articles, mostly pertaining to paper money, fractional currency, and stamps used as currency.</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/drowne" role="xeac:entity">Drowne, Henry Russell, 1860-1934</persname></origination><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1884/1927">1884-1927</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>0.1 cubic feet (1 box)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>Henry Russell Drowne</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6161/6214647417_7bba16c512_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6161/6214647417_7bba16c512_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6161/6214647417_7bba16c512_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6161/6214647417_7bba16c512.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>New York City native Henry Russell Drowne (1860-1934) was a wool merchant with the firm of Laurie, Mann Drowne until 1911 and was the son of fire insurer Henry Thayer Drowne (1822-1897). A collector of paper money, he specialized in U.S. fractional currency. After becoming a resident member of the American Numismatic and Archeological Society (later the American Numismatic Society) in 1882, he went on to serve in many positions, including historiographer, secretary, second vice president, first vice president, and secretary. In addition, he was a governor (1911-1934), sat on the council (1905-1934), and was active on several committees, including Paper Money and Publication of Medals. Drowne was charter member #59 of the American Numismatic Association, a life member of the New York Genealogical and Biographical Society, and a member of the New-York Historical Society, the Rhode Island Society of the Cincinnati, and the Sons of the Revolution of the State of New York, for which he wrote A Sketch of Fraunces Tavern and Those Connected with Its History (1919). He died in a fire at his home in New York City at 306 West 78th Street on November 15, 1934. Numerous tapestries, antiques, and paintings, including Rembrandts and Whistlers, were lost in the fire.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Henry Russell Drowne papers, 1884-1927, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject>Paper money -- Collectors and collecting--United States</subject><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/drowne" role="xeac:entity">Drowne, Henry Russell, 1860-1934</persname><persname>Wismer, D. C. (David Cassel), 1857-1949</persname><persname>Wormser, Moritz, 1878-1940</persname><persname authfilenumber="91219339" source="viaf">Chapman, Henry, 1859-1935</persname><corpname authfilenumber="147677671" source="viaf">New Hampshire Historical Society</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/united_states_dept_of_the_treasury" role="xeac:entity">United States. Dept. of the Treasury</corpname><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300026877">Correspondence</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300046300">Photographs</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300028577">Typescripts</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300033973">Drawings (Visual works)</genreform><corpname>American Numismatic Society--Officers</corpname><corpname>American Numismatic Society--Trustees and Councillors</corpname></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Contains the following correspondence: a letter from Thomas Cunningham on fractional currency (1888), two letters from United Stamp Company (Chicago) about envelopes that held stamps used as currency (1914), a letter from Dr. Valentine to George Blake regarding the value of a paper note (1920), a letter from Henry Chapman listing paper money found in the New Hampshire Historical Society (1920), a letter from D.C. Wismer discussing bank notes in his collection (1925), and a letter from Moritz Wormser of the American Numismatic Association regarding a paper submitted by Drowne for a convention (1927). Also includes notes, typescripts, and published versions of articles on topic such as fractional currency and the use of stamps as wartime currency. These include “Fractional Currency Information” (Numismatist 40, 1927), “U.S. Postage Stamps as Necessity War Money” (American Journal of Numismatics 52, 1918), and a handwritten draft of “Recollections of Coin Dealers and Collectors” (Numismatist 34, 1921), several pages of which were written on the back of Lawrie, Mann &amp; Drowne letterhead. Also present are typed and corrected reports of the American Numismatic Society’s Committee on Paper Money (1922), which he chaired; a handwritten description of Drowne’s paper money collection; notes on his ancestors William Drowne and Solomon Drowne; a list of questions about fractional currency submitted to the U.S. Treasury along with a reply (1884); and numerous hand drawn illustrations and two sheets of photographs of envelopes, presumably pertaining to his article “U.S. Postage Stamps as Necessity War Money.”</p></scopecontent></archdesc></ead>