<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0053.xml">nnan0053</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>George J. Fuld papers, 1956-1957, 1988-2007</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>George J. Fuld papers</unittitle><abstract>Correspondence, photographs, and research notes relating to Benjamin Franklin medals along with inventories and appraisals of the John J. Ford, Jr., R. Henry Norweb, Jr., and Waldo Newcomer collections.</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/fuld" role="xeac:entity">Fuld, George J., (George Joseph), 1932-2013</persname></origination><unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/2007">1956 - 2007</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>1 cubic foot (2 boxes)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>Benjamin Franklin medal photograph from the collection</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6095/6238714058_fbb5a1ae84_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6095/6238714058_fbb5a1ae84_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6095/6238714058_fbb5a1ae84_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6095/6238714058_fbb5a1ae84.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>George J. Fuld (1932-2013) of Owings Mills, Maryland, was born in Baltimore, graduated from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology with an Sc.D. in 1957, and was a consultant and vice president of Fuld Brothers (1954-1960) before working as a radiation researcher with Goodyear Tire (1963-1967). He married his wife Doris in 1955 and with her owned Dorge Approvals, a philatelic auction business that conducted sales during the 1970s. He served as editor of The TAMS Journal, published by the Token and Medal Society, became auction manager for Bowers and Ruddy in 1980, and was later vice president and director of auctions at Pacific Coast Auction Galleries of Santa Barbara, California. He wrote extensively on medals and tokens, and with his father Melvin coauthored numerous articles and other works on Civil War tokens. He is also known for having established a token rarity scale.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>George J. Fuld papers, 1956-1957, 1988-2007, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject>Tokens--Collectors and collecting</subject><subject>Medals--Collectors and collecting</subject><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300026877">Correspondence</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300028673">Compact discs</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300213177">Machine-readable</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300027045">Inventories</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300046300">Photographs</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300027200">Notes</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300048715">Articles</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300027474">Appraisals (Records)</genreform><persname>Fuld, Melvin, 1901-1987</persname><persname authfilenumber="56609913" source="viaf">Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790</persname><persname>Ford, John J., 1924-2005</persname><persname authfilenumber="18848007" source="viaf">Norweb, Emery May, 1895-1984</persname><persname>Newcomer, Waldo, 1867-1934</persname><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/fuld" role="xeac:entity">Fuld, George J., (George Joseph), 1932-2013</persname><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/norweb_jr" role="xeac:entity">Norweb, R. Henry, 1918-1995</persname></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Contains (1) correspondence, photographs, notes, and articles relating to Benjamin Franklin medals and tokens, (2) Fuld’s appraisal (1995) of the collections of R. Henry Norweb, Jr. (1918-1995), (3) inventory (2004) of the collections of John J. Ford, Jr. (1924-2005), and (4) inventory (2007) of rarities in the collection of Waldo Newcomer (1867-1934). Research notes and letters, some of which are to and from George’s father Melvin, pertain to articles appearing in a special edition of the Numismatist devoted to Franklin (December, 1956). Includes a typescript of an article, “Boston School Medals,” by June Pond, that appeared in the publication. Later correspondence (1988-1993) also relates to Franklin medals. Also present are photographs and lists of various Franklin medals, a list of Melvin and George Fuld’s Franklin Medals, and assorted nineteenth and twentieth century articles on Franklin and related medals, including “The Medals of Franklin: A Catalog of Medals, Tokens, Medallions, and Plaques Issued in Honor of Franklin,” edited by Phil Greenslet for the Token and Medal Society (1990). The Norweb appraisal is of Washington medals, miscellaneous medals, colonials, and tokens left to him by his mother, Emery May Norweb (1895-1984). The catalogs of Ford’s collections are in the following categories: Hard Times tokens, Territorial tokens, Merchant tokens, New York Merchant tokens, Miscellaneous Merchant tokens (from all states except New York), Political tokens, Civil War tokens, Sutler tokens, Medals, Washingtonia, Indian Traders tokens, Post Traders tokens, Game Counters, Transportation tokens, Counterstamped tokens, and Cotton tokens. Includes a compact disc containing a computer file of the Ford inventories and photographs of the rarities possessed by Newcomer.</p></scopecontent></archdesc></ead>