<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0064.xml">nnan0064</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Herbert E. Ives coin catalog and card index, mid-1900s</titleproper><author>David Hill</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher><date normal="2011">2011</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2011</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Herbert E. Ives coin catalog and card index</unittitle><abstract>Contains the manuscript Catalogue of Florentine Florins, a binder of notes, and two card indexes to coins.</abstract><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/ives" role="xeac:entity">Ives, Herbert E. (Herbert Eugene), 1882-1953</persname></origination><unitdate normal="1940/1953" type="inclusive">1940 - 1953</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><physdesc><extent>1 cubic foot (1 box)</extent></physdesc><daogrp><daodesc><p>Herbert E. Ives (Image courtesy of Lucent Technologies)</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6244165597_8ec30daf1a_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6244165597_8ec30daf1a_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6244165597_8ec30daf1a_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6244165597_8ec30daf1a.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6244165597_8ec30daf1a_z.jpg" xlink:label="Medium 640"/></daogrp></did><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Herbert E. Ives was born in Philadelphia on July 21, 1882. His father, Frederic Ives, was a distinguished scientist who had invented techniques for color photography and the half-tone process which made it possible to reprint photographs in magazines and newspapers. The younger Ives attended the University of Pennsylvania, where he earned his bachelors degree in 1905, and Johns Hopkins University, where he earned his doctorate of philosophy in 1908. Upon graduation, Ives held a series of positions in industrial research, but his greatest successes came during his tenure at Bell Laboratories, which he joined in 1919 after serving in the U.S. Army Signal Corps during World War I, where he did early work in aerial photography. It was during his years at Bell that Ives became known as one of the world's leading electron-optical physicists. Ives joined the ANS as an associate member in April 1924. By 1925, he had been elected a Fellow. In 1937, Ives was named a Patron of the ANS because of his gift to the Society of twenty-two medals awarded to his father for his scientific accomplishments. Ives was first elected to the ANS Council in January 1934 and remained on the Council until his death in November 1953. In January 1942, Ives was elected the 14th president of the ANS, succeeding Stephen H.P. Pell. Ives' numismatic interests focused on three types of gold: English nobles, Venetian ducats, and Florentine florins. Ives served as president through 1946 and he died on November 13, 1953. Upon his death, he bequeathed to the ANS his extensive collection of gold coins.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Collection open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Herbert E. Ives coin catalog and card index, mid-1900s, Archives, American Numismatic Society</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><controlaccess><subject>Coins, Florentine--Collectors and collecting</subject><subject>Coins--Collectors and collecting</subject><subject>Gold coins--Collectors and collecting</subject><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/ives" role="xeac:entity">Ives, Herbert E. (Herbert Eugene), 1882-1953</persname><persname authfilenumber="8855772" source="viaf">Simpson, A. Carson</persname><corpname authfilenumber="139637527" source="viaf">Museo archeologico di Firenze</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="132333836" source="viaf">Museo nazionale del Bargello (Florence, Italy)</corpname><corpname authfilenumber="134857252" source="viaf">British Museum</corpname><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300027045">Inventories</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300256200">Grey literature</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300046300">Photographs</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300264354">Notebooks</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300026877">Correspondence</genreform><genreform source="aat" authfilenumber="300048719">Card indexes</genreform><corpname>American Numismatic Society--Officers</corpname><corpname>American Numismatic Society--Trustees and Councillors</corpname><genreform authfilenumber="300026059" source="aat">Catalogs (Documents)</genreform></controlaccess><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Contains (1) a manuscript entitled Catalogue of Florentine Florins listing items from the museums and collections of the American Numismatic Society, Herbert E. Ives, A. Carson Simpson, Florence-Archeological Museum, Florence-Bargello, Vienna, British Museum, and Munich, with coin photographs pasted in and an inventory of collections and loose photographs attached; (2) a small loose-leaf binder containing Ives’ notes; (3) a letter from Henry Grunthal on the gold florin of Wenceslas II of Liegnitz (January 12, 1948), and (4) two card indexes, some with photographs of coins, with the following categories: Greece, Rome, France, Flanders, Italy, Venetian Gold and Imitations, Florins (Florence), Florins-Imitations, Spain, Portugal, Germany, England, and Scotland.</p></scopecontent></archdesc></ead>