<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b"><eadid mainagencycode="US-nnan" countrycode="US" url="http://numismatics.org/archives/ark:/53695/nnan0127.xml">nnan0127</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Andrew C. Zabriskie scrapbook, 1893-1894.</titleproper><author>Arnold Tescher</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><date>© 2013</date><address><addressline>American Numismatic Society Archives</addressline><addressline>75 Varick Street, 11th floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10013</addressline></address><publisher>American Numismatic Society</publisher></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>Finding aid encoded by David Hill using EADitor ©2013</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date normal="2017-04-29">April 29, 2017</date><item>Imported into EADitor. Some normalization has occurred to apply EAD 2002
							schema validation and conform to EADitor basic requirements.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Descriptive Summary</head><unittitle>Andrew C. Zabriskie scrapbook</unittitle><abstract>Scrapbook compiled by Andrew C. Zabriskie containing items dating from May 1893 to July 1894.</abstract><physdesc><extent>1 scrapbook</extent></physdesc><langmaterial><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial><origination><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/zabriskie" role="xeac:entity">Zabriskie, Andrew C. (Andrew Christian), 1853-1916</persname></origination><unitdate normal="1893/1894">1893-1894</unitdate><repository>American Numismatic Society</repository><daogrp><daodesc><p>Illustration from an article in the scrapbook on the opening of St. Luke's Hospital in New York City.</p></daodesc><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_s.jpg" xlink:label="Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_q.jpg" xlink:label="Large Square"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_t.jpg" xlink:label="Thumbnail"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_m.jpg" xlink:label="Small"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_n.jpg" xlink:label="Small 320"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3.jpg" xlink:label="Medium"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_z.jpg" xlink:label="Medium 640"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_c.jpg" xlink:label="Medium 800"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_f9ca5f50e3_b.jpg" xlink:label="Large"/><daoloc xlink:type="locator" xlink:href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8402/8619864434_4ee53230e6_o.jpg" xlink:label="Original"/></daogrp></did><scopecontent><p>Scrapbook compiled by Andrew C. Zabriskie containing items dating from May 1893 to July 1894. There are 79 pages mostly of newspaper clippings, some correspondence, fliers, and some photographs describing a variety of local issues, events, business dealings, and personalities. Included are many articles citing Zabriskie’s business associations and his involvement with church and civic matters. Noteworthy is a considerable amount of space devoted to the laying of the cornerstone of the new St. Luke’s Hospital in New York City on May 6, 1897. Andrew Zabriskie was chairman of the Committee of Arrangements for the event. In honor of the occasion, the American Numismatic Society issued a gold medal commemorating the hospital’s completion and bearing the portrait of the founder, Rev. William Augustus Muhlenberg. There are copies of the medal, in other metal types, in the Society’s collection. The medal was executed for the Society by sculptor Victor D. Brenner, himself a Society Associate member (1894) and a die cutter. Other articles of numismatic interest include a story about Indian peace medals presented to chiefs visiting George Washington; a bill proposed in Congress to lease or sell a portion of the property owned by the U.S. Mint in Charlotte, North Carolina; the discovery of $500 in continental currency at a Zabriskie family farm in New Jersey; and a list of names and address of members of the Joint Committee on the Improvement of the United States Coinage, including Andrew Zabriskie. On the lighter side, there is an article revealing research “proving” the presence of dangerous microbes on bank notes of the Spanish Bank of Havana. Of general historical interest is an article announcing the sale of an autographed letter by Nathan Hale to his uncle dated September 24, 1774, with the letter reproduced in its entirety.</p></scopecontent><controlaccess><genreform authfilenumber="300027341" source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="300026867" source="aat">Clippings (Information artifacts)</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="300224742" source="aat">Fliers (Printed matter)</genreform><genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform><corpname>American Numismatic Society--Officers</corpname><persname authfilenumber="19539766" source="viaf">Muhlenberg, William Augustus, 1796-1877</persname><persname authfilenumber="http://numismatics.org/authority/zabriskie" role="xeac:entity">Zabriskie, Andrew C. (Andrew Christian), 1853-1916</persname><corpname authfilenumber="159464591" source="viaf">St. Luke's Hospital (New York, N.Y.)</corpname></controlaccess><bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Andrew C. Zabriskie was born in New York City in 1853 to one of the largest real estate owning families in that city. After graduating from Columbia University, Zabriskie would help manage the family's real estate business. He was a member of the New York National Guard from 1873 through 1897, and eventually rose to the rank of Captain. (Later in life he would be known as "Captain Zabriskie" due to this service.) A member of the ANS for forty-two years, Zabriskie first joined the ANS in 1874 and became a life member in 1894. He served initially as Third Vice-President from 1880-83 and then as First Vice-President from 1884-96 before finally being elected President of the ANS in 1896. He remained as President until his resignation in December 1904. In 1908, when the Society's constitution was amended to create the office of Honorary President, Zabriskie, along with Daniel Parish, Jr., was elected Honorary President for Life. Zabriskie's tenure as president was marked with a financial crisis that led Zabriskie to advocate for the merger of the ANS with the New-York Historical Society. When that proposal was rejected by the membership of the ANS, Zabriskie resigned from the presidency. He was succeeded by Archer M. Huntington. During his career, Zabriskie amassed a large collection, the most significant of which were Lincoln medals and Polish coins and medals. In 1873 he wrote A Descriptive Catalogue of the Political and Memorial Medals Struck in Honor of Abraham Lincoln that has since become the basis for those collecting Lincoln pieces. Zabriskie died on September 16, 1916.</p></bioghist><accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>Item open to all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Andrew C. Zabriskie scrapbook, 1893-1894, Archives, American Numismatic Society.</p></prefercite><userestrict><head>Restrictions</head><p>Copyright restrictions may apply. Permission to publish or reproduce must be secured from the American Numismatic Society.</p></userestrict><dsc/></archdesc></ead>