<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nnod">APsaA-1</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>American Psychoanalytic Association Records</titleproper>
                <author>Winthrop Group</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2008">2008</date>
                <publisher>Oskar Diethelm Library</publisher>
                <address>
<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
<addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
<addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by the Oskar Diethelm Library.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>American Psychoanalytic Association Records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1920/1996" type="inclusive">1920 - 1996</unitdate>
            <abstract>The American Psychoanalytic Association (APsaA) Records at the Oskar Diethelm Library include materials from the 1920s through 1996, including correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, surveys, reports, press clippings, audio and video recordings, and publications generated by the officers, committee chairmen, and members of APsaA. </abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>174 linear feet (384 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50059988">American Psychoanalytic Association</corpname>
            </origination>
								     <repository>
                <corpname>Oskar Diethelm Library</corpname>
                	<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://psych-history.weill.cornell.edu/osk_die_lib/"/>
            </repository>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>The American Psychoanalytic Association was founded in 1911 by Welsh neurologist and psychoanalyst Ernest Jones with the support of Sigmund Freud. Other founders of the organization were Adolf Meyer, James Jackson Putnam, G. Lane Taneyhill, John T. MacCurdy, Trigant Burrow, and G. Alexander Young. The APsaA is the second oldest psychoanalytic organization in America after the New York Psychoanalytic Society, which was founded a few months before by Abraham Arden Brill.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50059988">American Psychoanalytic Association</corpname>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>The American Psychoanalytic Association (APsaA) Records at the Oskar Diethelm Library include materials from the 1920s through 1996. A few records - the constitution and by-laws – date from 1930. The collection consists of correspondence, memoranda, meeting minutes, surveys, reports, press clippings, audio and video recordings, and publications generated by the officers, committee chairmen, and members of APsaA. The collection also contains the Central Office files of the Executive Assistant, the Executive Secretary, and the Administrative Director. The inventory includes Record Group Descriptions and Series Descriptions for the APsaA records. Following the Series Descriptions are annotations describing noteworthy documents that may be of interest to researchers.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Written permission must be obtained from the Oskar Diethelm Library and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
        </userestrict>
    
        
    
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="f028d3_APsaA-final.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>