<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nnod">carr_arthur</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Arthur Carr PhD Collection Finding Aid</titleproper>
								<author>Janice Quinter</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="1989">1989</date>
								<publisher>Oskar Diethelm Library</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by the Oskar Diethelm Library.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>Arthur Carr PhD Collection</unittitle>
							<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960/1988">1960 - 1988</unitdate>
							<abstract>The collection is comprised of letters and photographs from four individuals sent to Arthur Carr and a reel-to-reel audiotape of an interview by Arthur Carr with the adult Little Hans, Herbert Graf. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>.21 linear feet (1 box)</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n84150273">Carr, Arthur C.</persname>
            </origination>
											     <repository>
                <corpname>Oskar Diethelm Library</corpname>
                	<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://psych-history.weill.cornell.edu/osk_die_lib/"/>
            </repository>
						<unitid>1988.0001</unitid>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
            <p>The Arthur Carr Collection of letters and photographs was donated by Arthur Carr, Ph.D. in July 1988. In June 1989, Arthur Carr donated an audiotape of his 1960 interview with the adult little Hans, Herbert Graf. </p>
        </acqinfo>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>There are no access restrictions on this material.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Dr. Carr was Professor of Clinical Psychology in Psychiatry of the Westchester Division of New York Hospital-Cornell Medical Center. A reel-to-reel audiotape of an interview by Arthur Carr with the adult Little Hans, Herbert Graf, is an accretion to this collection. Hans was the first born (1903) of psychoanalyst Max Graf, who was one of Freud's closest disciples. Four and a half year old little Hans had a sexually oriented phobia that started after the birth of his sister. He was seen by Freud. Psychoanalysts hailed the story of little Hans as the first confirmation of Freud's theory of infantile sexuality obtained by direct observation of a child. It was also the first example of child analysis and the first control analysis on record. </p>
            <p>Brief biographical information for the four individuals in the letters and photographs is provided below.

Lauretta Bender, M.D. (1897-1987) A psychiatrist with a variety of posts throughout New York whose professional interests included adolescence, children and neurology.

Carney Landis, Ph.D. (1897-1962) A psychologist who taught at Columbia University and whose research included work in psychopathology, brain function, and vision. 

Henry Murray, Ph.D. (1893-1988) A psychologist who was a pioneer in the development of personality theory and taught at Harvard University for almost 40 years. He was one of the early American-born psychoanalysts and a selector of undercover agents for the Office of Strategic Services in World War II.

Zygmunt A. Piotrowski, Ph.D. (1904-1985) A psychologist who taught at taught at Columbia University and New York University and whose interests included personality, projection tests, and prognosis.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n84150273">Carr, Arthur C.</persname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no92029985">Graf, Herbert, 1903 or 1904-1973</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n86114077">Bender, Lauretta, 1897-1987</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79076462">Landis, Carney, 1897-1962</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50034265">Murray, Henry A. (Henry Alexander), 1893-1988</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85187429">Piotrowski, Zygmunt A., 1904-1985</persname>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>The collection is comprised of letters and photographs from four individuals sent to Arthur Carr and a reel-to-reel audiotape of an interview by Arthur Carr with the adult Little Hans, Herbert Graf. The audiotape is supplemented by a transcription and a letter by Arthur Carr, and an obituary of Herbert Graf, 1973. Two articles about the possible source for the name of Little Hans complete this donation. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Written permission must be obtained from the Oskar Diethelm Library and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_a049f901cdc903ad4e874da67496bda2" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>No series</unittitle>
						
					
    </did>
				<c id="c_9936e44622eae2bd9e24f891b0bb61b9" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Lauretta Bender, photographs and notes </unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973/1983">1973 - 1983</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_0ea8670dbc1ab1634f44e159433b53e5" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Carney Landis, photograph and postcards </unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate">c. 1960</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_2d9923a86ee349f85cb21885b88e8bf7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Henry Murray, photograph and note, obituary</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1978/1988">1978 - 1988</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_5de0938ad409149f061acf2feacb54c4" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Zygmunt A. Piotrowski, note </unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive">1971</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_4cf46373b0b5eaa304390cb4f6dde9c4" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Herbert Graf (Little Hans), audiotape, correspondence, and obituary</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive">1960</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    <unitdate normal="1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate">Undated</unitdate>
                    </did>
				</c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>