<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nnod">guiteau_charles</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Charles Guiteau Papers Finding Aid</titleproper>
								<author>Janice Quinter</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="1989">1989</date>
								<publisher>Oskar Diethelm Library</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by the Oskar Diethelm Library.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>Charles Guiteau Papers </unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1881/1912" type="inclusive">1881 - 1912</unitdate>
							<abstract>This collection contains papers on the trial of Charles Guiteau, who was the assassin of President James A. Garfield. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>.42 linear feet (1 box)</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50018818">Guiteau, Charles J. (Charles Julius), 1841-1882</persname>
            </origination>
											     <repository>
                <corpname>Oskar Diethelm Library</corpname>
                	<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://psych-history.weill.cornell.edu/osk_die_lib/"/>
            </repository>
						</did>
        <acqinfo>
            <p>The Charles Guiteau Papers relating to the assassination of President James Garfield were purchased at auction from Charles Hamilton with funds provided by Mr. &amp; Mrs. Charles H. Blatt.</p>
        </acqinfo>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>There are no access restrictions on this material.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Charles Julius Guiteau was the assassin of President James A. Garfield. He shot the President on July 2, 1881, and Garfield died on September 19, 1881. The trial is considered important in forensic psychiatry and hinges on the issue of moral insanity. Guiteau wanted to be proved sane, stating that his act was committed for the greater good of the country and was sanctioned under orders from "Jesus Christ &amp; Company." Judge John K. Porter, the eminent prosecuting attorney, was successful in proving Guiteau sane enough to differentiate between right and wrong, the definition of criminal responsibility under the M'Naghten Rule. The trial also continued the controversy over the extent to which heredity and environment contributed to aberrant behavior. The trial began in the fall of 1881 and was completed in January 1882. Guiteau was hanged June 30 of that year.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50018818">Guiteau, Charles J. (Charles Julius), 1841-1882</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n50015182">Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh88006961" source="lcsh">Presidents Assassination</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85050558" source="lcsh">Forensic psychiatry</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2007003620" source="lcsh">Insanity defense</subject>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n88682030">Porter, John K. (John Kilham), 1819-1892</persname>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>The papers pertain to the trial of Guiteau for the assassination of President Garfield. The documents consist chiefly of trial notes of John K. Porter, the prosecuting attorney, and his preparation for trial. Included are legal notes on testimony of expert witnesses in cases of insanity, notes on his delusion, and notes on the trials of Ludwig Steiner and Mary Harris, both for murder involving legal insanity. Some of the trial notes contain numerous interesting quotes from Guiteau. Among other papers, there are a list of witnesses for the prosecution that served on the defense (including Guiteau's brother, John), lists of expert witnesses examined by the government and by the defense, legal precedents on insanity pleas, and a summary of Guiteau's evidence. Two printed pamphlets complete the collection: "Memorial Address on the Life and Character of James Abram Garfield," by Hon. James G. Blaine, and "A Protest Against the Destruction of Jury Trials," which is a reprint of a speech by James Garfield about the Milligan case trial in l866. The range in dates of the collection is 1881 - 1885, with the publication date for the reprint being 1912. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Written permission must be obtained from the Oskar Diethelm Library and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_28d7cc212d78871fd9c6f090ac400733" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>No series</unittitle>
						
					
    </did>
				<c id="c_31d69575c51a854327da4ef3411d9049" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Notes on expert testimony in cases of insanity, including cases of Mary Harris and Ludwig Steiner in cases involving "moral insanity"</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1881/1882">1881 - 1882</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_ff4d67ab7890f43d1c474f16fe41db91" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Notes of Reynold’s examination and of others</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1881/1882">1881 - 1882</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_ffc8ff6129e668469c36619df6cccce0" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>List of experts examined by the government in rebuttal, list of experts examined by the defense, letter written by E. A. Bailey to John K. Porter, and quotes by Guiteau, Guiteau’s evidence</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1881/1882">1881 - 1882</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_9c41df521472e4f180d5b5df0a6dc908" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Information re: Shaw and Edward's testimony, notes on Reynolds, comparison to M’Naghten’s case, notes on religious inspiration of Guiteau, and list of witnesses for government</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1881/1882">1881 - 1882</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_89fb54d58cbe3f67fcbd31c6ae6287a8" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>News clipping re: Porter and Union College and notes including quotes by Guiteau, religious inspiration, court papers, letter written by Guiteau's brother, John N. Guiteau, to General Carr</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1881/1885">1881 - 1885</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
                <c id="c_0afec61b23c18ccc513181533b0ff849" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Pamphlets: "Memorial Address on the Life and Character of James Abram Garfield" by Hon. James G. Blaine and "A Protest Against the Destruction of Jury Trials," reprint of a speech by Garfield in the Milligan case tried in 1866</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1882/1912">1882 - 1912</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>