<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nnod">landis_bernard</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Bernard Landis PhD Papers Finding Aid</titleproper>
								<author>Janice Quinter</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="1989">1989</date>
								<publisher>Oskar Diethelm Library</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by the Oskar Diethelm Library.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>Bernard Landis PhD Papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
							<abstract>Bernard Landis, Ph.D. was a Clinical Associate Professor of Psychology in Psychiatry of Cornell University Medical College. The collection includes materials on seminars conducted by Erich Fromm in Locarno, Switzerland in 1974, including audio cassette tape recordings. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>.42 linear feet (1 box)</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no00054743">Landis, Bernard, 1926-</persname>
            </origination>
											     <repository>
                <corpname>Oskar Diethelm Library</corpname>
                	<address>
									<addressline>DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts</addressline>
								<addressline>Weill Cornell Medical College</addressline>
                    <addressline>525 East 68th Street, Box 140</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10065</addressline>
                </address>
							<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://psych-history.weill.cornell.edu/osk_die_lib/"/>
            </repository>
						<unitid>1978.0001</unitid>
        </did>
        <acqinfo>
            <p>Gift of Bernard Landis, 1978.</p>
        </acqinfo>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>There are no access restrictions on this material.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Erich Fromm was born in Frankfurt, Germany in 1900. He was awarded his Ph.D. in 1922 from the University of Heidelberg and also studied at the University of Munich and at the Psychoanalytic Institute in Berlin. He taught in Germany and in Mexico, and in the United States at Bennington College, Michigan State University and New York University. He was a founder and trustee of the William Alanson White Institute.</p>
            <p>Fromm was a psychoanalyst and developed his own system of treatment which he called "humanistic psychoanalysis." Major intellectual influences on his life were the Talmud, Buddhism, Karl Marx, J. J. Bachofen on Mother right and symbolism, and Sigmund Freud. He attempted to construct a system of ethical values based on the knowledge of human behavior. Fromm wrote many books commenting on contemporary society, read by laymen and professionals alike, including on alienation. He was active in the peace movement of the 1960’s and in the humanist socialist movement. He died in 1980.</p>
            <p>In 1974 Dr. Bernard Landis organized a psychology course in Locarno, Switzerland and brought a class of twenty-two students from the Purchase Campus of the State University of New York to Switzerland, to co-teach with Erich Fromm an intensive three-week seminar on current trends in psychoanalysis.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no00054743">Landis, Bernard, 1926-</persname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80010148">Fromm, Erich, 1900-1980</persname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="2659869" source="geonames">Locarno (Switzerland)</geogname>
            <subject authfilenumber="n83748432" source="lcsh">Psychoanalysis</subject>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>There are eight cassette tapes recording seminars Fromm presented to the students. The tapes are numbered from 4 through 10. A brief essay by Bernard Landis describing his personal feelings about Fromm and the seminar accompanies this collection, in addition to Landis' summary of the contents of the seminar. Snapshots of Fromm complete the collection. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Written permission must be obtained from the Oskar Diethelm Library and all relevant rights holders before publishing quotations, excerpts or images from any materials in this collection.</p>
						</userestrict>
					
    
    <dsc>
            <c id="c_c2d89994215fd7e213869710109b36a2" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>No series</unittitle>
						
					<container type="box"/>
    </did>
				<c id="c_55d2fa9d7ac1426a1e740c50a7e4198d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>No file title [eight audio cassette recordings of Erich Fromm seminars, Bernard Landis essay, and photographs?]</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box">1</container>
    </did>
				</c>
            </c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>