<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
    <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nncm">nncm0001</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Alan Berkman Papers</titleproper>
                <author>Archives &amp; Special Collections, Columbia University Health Sciences Library</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <date normal="2016-07-14">July 14, 2016</date>
                <publisher>Columbia University Medical Center</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Augustus C. Long Health Sciences Library</addressline>
                    <addressline>701 West 168th Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10032</addressline>
                </address>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by user nncm.</creation>
            <langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>Alan Berkman papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1960/2010">1960 - 2010</unitdate>
            <abstract>Correspondence, court documents, pamphlets, prison diaries, parole records, oral history transcripts, interview transcripts, memoir drafts, poems, speeches, articles, awards, certificates, diplomas, photographs, clippings and digital video document the life and death of physician and political activist Alan Berkman (1945-2009), a physician from Middletown, New York who became radicalized as a medical student while attending Columbia University’s college of Physicians and Surgeons (MD 1971). He was later involved in two robberies. The first attributed to members of the May 19th Communist Organization and Black Liberation Army. His papers also contain records relating to the reinstatement of his medical license and career after his release from prison. He was Assistant Professor of Clinical Epidemiology and Clinical Sociomedical Sciences in the Mailman School of Public Health.</abstract>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4 cubic feet (10 boxes)</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
            <origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no00049104">Berkman, Alan</persname>
            </origination>
            <unitdate normal="1985/2000" type="bulk">1985 - 2000</unitdate>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Augustus C. Long Health Sciences Library</corpname>
                <address>
                    <addressline>701 W. 168th Street</addressline>
                    <addressline>New York, NY 10032</addressline>
                </address>
                <subarea>Archives &amp; Special Collections</subarea>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://library-archives.cumc.columbia.edu/"/>
            </repository>
        <unitid>M-0019</unitid>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict>
            <p>DVDs are closed until preservation imaging completed.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <bioghist>
            <p>Alan Berkman, physician, member of the Black Liberation Army and “Resistance Conspiracy Six,” convicted criminal, fugitive, prisoner and AIDS activist, was born September 4, 1945 in Brooklyn, the second of four children to father Samuel Berkman, and mother Mona. His family moved to Middletown, New York, where his father owned a plumbing and building supply company. He attended Cornell University (BA 1967) and the College of Physicians and Surgeons of Columbia University (MD 1971). He married physician Barbara Zeller and had two daughters, Sarah Machel (b. 1976) and Harriet Josina Clark (b. 1980).</p>
            <p>Berkman became radicalized as a medical student at Columbia University. One year after he enrolled in the College of Physicians &amp; Surgeons, the Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) famously occupied Columbia’s Morningside Heights campus in protest of the University’s research ties to the Vietnam War and its relations with Harlem residents. Berkman claimed that his experience working with minority populations in poor communities awakened him to the class and racial divides he had been protected from as a white person growing up in Middletown, N.Y. He was also personally affected by hearing Kwame Toure (then Stokely Carmichael) speak about the Vietnam War.</p>
            <p>His commitment to fighting oppression is shown throughout his life’s work. In 1971, he treated prisoners injured during the Attica Prison riot in New York. In New York City, he interned at the North East Neighborhood Association (NENA) Community Health Center and the Betances Health Center, and was staff physician at Lincoln Hospital in the Bronx. In 1973, he and his future wife, Barbara Zeller, treated injured participants of the American Indian Movement (AIM) during the occupation at Wounded Knee on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation. </p>
            <p>On October 20, 1981, members of the American militant groups, the May 19th Communist Organization, the Black Liberation Army, and the Weather Underground, robbed a Brink’s armored car, stealing $1.6 million, in Nanuet, New York, resulting in the deaths of two police officers and a Brink’s guard. Berkman treated the gunshot wound of one perpetrator, but refused to collaborate with the FBI investigation. In May 1982, he was charged for civil contempt of a federal grand jury. These charges terminated with his arrest in December of that same year for providing medical treatment to a fugitive. He was also charged as an accessory after the fact to bank robbery and murder. He was released on bail but failed to appear in court; he went underground. On September 4, 1984, Berkman and an accomplice participated in the gunpoint robbery of a Connecticut supermarket, stealing $21,480. </p>
            <p>Under surveillance by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, Berkman and fellow fugitive
Elizabeth Ann Duke were arrested in May 1985 outside Doylestown, Pennsylvania, in possession
of firearms and a key to a nearby garage containing 100 pounds of dynamite. Berkman went to
trail in what is known as the Resistance Conspiracy case involving five additional defendants:
Marilyn Jean Buck, Linda Sue Evans, Susan Rosenberg, Timothy Blunk, and Laura Whitehorn;
all charged with the 1983 U.S. Senate bombing and other bombings claimed by the clandestine
May 19 Communist Organization or M19CO – a splinter group of the Weather Underground,
whose members splintered from the Students for a Democratic Society (SDS). Elizabeth Ann
Duke skipped bail and is still at large in 2016.</p>
            <p>In 1987, Berkman was convicted on felony charges and for skipping bail. He was also convicted in the State of Connecticut for robbery in the first degree. While incarcerated, Berkman was diagnosed with cancer, specifically Hodgkin’s lymphoma. Due to his health problems, Berkman was often in custody of U.S. Marshals’ Service, but served time at the U.S. Medical Center for Federal Prisoners at Springfield, the Federal Medical Center at Rochester, and at United States Prison Marion. He criticized the quality of his health care while in custody, with particular aim at Marion Prison’s carcinogenic water. </p>
            <p>Identifying as political prisoners, Berkman and the other Resistance Conspiracy defendants based their political work on anti-imperialist principles. His wife, Barbara Zeller, advocated on his behalf and other U.S. political prisoners by distributing literature and initiating letter writing campaigns. </p>
            <p>On July 2, 1992, he was released from prison on parole. His case was deliberated by the New York State Board for Professional Medical Conduct and signed a consent agreement allowing him to reinstate his medical license. Under the terms of his probation and the reinstatement of his medical license, his medical practice was supervised by another physician, Dr. Harold Osborn. His state license was on probation March 1992-March 1994.</p>
            <p>He served as Medical Director for El Rio Treatment Services (1993) and Highbridge-Woodycrest Center (1994), both in the Bronx. He entered the Harlem Hospital Physician Assistant Program (1994) and became a research fellow at Columbia University HIV Center for Clinical and Behavioral Studies (1995). He was appointed Assistant Professor of Clinical Psychiatry (1988). He left Highbridge-Woodycrest Center in 2003 after accepting a full-time faculty position at the Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University. He was made Assistant Professor of Clinical Epidemiology and Clinical Sociomedical Sciences. His parole ended March 1997.</p>
            <p>Outside of his academic appointments, Berkman founded Health Global Access Project (GAP), an AIDS patient advocacy group that lobbied the Clinton administration to require less expensive, generic drug equivalents to be sold by U.S. pharmaceutical companies to foreign countries, resulting in a dramatic reduction in the cost of AIDS medications internationally.

He died on June 5, 2009 in Manhattan, survived by his wife and two children. 
</p>
            <list>
                <head>References</head>
                <item>Day, Susie. "Political Prisoners: Guilty until Proven Innocent." Sojourner: The Women's Forum, February 1989, 17. </item>
                <item>Hevesi, Dennis. "Alan Berkman, 63, Activist Doctor, Dies." The New York Times. 2009. Accessed July 12, 2016 http://www.nytimes.com/2009/06/15/nyregion/15berkman.html?_r=0. </item>
                <item>"Alan Berkman," Wikipedia. Accessed July 12, 2016. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Berkman#cite_note-NYTObit-1. </item>
            </list>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n82123512">Black Liberation Army</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2006129933">Committee to Fight Repression (U.S.)</corpname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2001079812">Joseph L. Mailman School of Public Health</corpname>
            <corpname authfilenumber="http://socialarchive.iath.virginia.edu/ark:/99166/w6z40mqr">May 19th Communist Organization.</corpname>
            <corpname authfilenumber="no2011154362" source="lcnaf">Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.). New York Region</corpname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh93005197" source="lcsh">AIDS activists</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2009114520" source="lcsh">AIDS (Disease)--Epidemiology</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85005612" source="lcsh">Anti-imperialist movements</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85052244" source="lcsh">Fugitives from justice</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010117083" source="lcsh">Trials (Political crimes and offenses)--United States</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh98001482" source="lcsh">Political activists--United States</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh98005422" source="lcsh">Prisoners--Civil rights</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2007004674" source="lcsh">Protest movements--United States</subject>
            <subject>Radicalism--United States.</subject>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300128347" source="aat">black-and-white photographs</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300128359" source="aat">color photographs</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300264677" source="aat">DVDs</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="gf2014026115" source="lcgft">Interviews</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="gf2014026481" source="lcgft">Poetry</genreform>
            <persname>Zeller, Barbara</persname>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300027590" source="aat">legal documents</genreform>
            <genreform>plaques (flat objects)</genreform>
            <genreform authfilenumber="300264821" source="aat">printed ephemera</genreform>
        </controlaccess>
        <scopecontent>
            <p>This collection consists of correspondence, form letters, oral history transcripts, interview transcripts, court and trial documents, parole certificate, appointment letters, diplomas, medical licensure records, research study applications, biographies, curricula vitae, memoir drafts, poems, articles, notes, speeches, prison diaries, clippings, pamphlets, photographs, certificates and awards, plaques, and digital video. The bulk relate to Berkman’s legal issues; his trial and prison term are well documented through court documents and correspondence with legal counsel, friends and family. His papers contain only one folder relating to his role as founder of Health GAP.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <userestrict>
            <p>Open for research.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <dsc>
            <c id="c_a19f5718d169d15a08eda5f92fb66749" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Biographical</unittitle>
                    <unitdate certainty="circa">1960-2010</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Timelines, chronologies, diplomas, certificates, awards, interview and oral history transcripts, obituaries, and letters of condolences document the life and death of Alan Berkman. This series contains personal correspondence not relating to his legal issues or medical career. Includes an album presented to him upon his release from prison, materials relating to his memorial held by the Mailman School of Public Health, Columbia University. The Cornell University Class of 1967 25th reunion yearbook includes a story about Berkman written by classmate Susan Mokotoff Reverby (pages 40-41).</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_93ec911310a7658d6be21d79763cff00" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Legal</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1973/2001">1973 - 2001</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Legal documents include original letters, as well as facsimiles and photocopies of correspondence, from defense attorneys Ronald L. Kuby, William M. Kunsler, Susan V. Tipograph, and William Mogulescu; Public Defender Rosemary Herbert; the Parole Commission; Bureau of Prisons; and other offices on behalf of Berkman regarding his medical condition. Part of these efforts involved requests to transfer Berkman to a different prison to meet his medical needs, the change in his security classification, and ultimately, his release on parole. Includes letters written on behalf of Berkman to the Parole Commission or the presiding judge, advocating for his release.</p>
                    <p>Contains court documents from Berkman’s trial including FBI evidence presented to the court, such as fraudulent passports, driver’s licenses, leases and other documents seized at The Alameda apartment in Baltimore and a garage in Philadelphia. Also includes surveillance photographs used as evidence. Folders are arranged chronologically.</p>
                    <p>Prison correspondence is arranged either chronologically or alphabetically, when dated or identified by correspondent, and is primarily comprised of original letters written in Berkman’s hand. These letters were also transcribed in chronological order (2 folders; February 18, 1986-February 16, 1988). Of note is a drawing and letter to Berkman by Mumia Abu-Jamal. Letters to and from Amnesty International and Barbara Zeller relate to the quality of prison healthcare received by Berkman. A letter from William Morales, member of Puerto Rican separatist group the Fuerzas Armada de Liberacion Nacional Puertorriquena (FALN), predates Berkman’s incarceration. It was written by Morales from Bellevue Hospital, postmarked April 21, 1979, before Morales escaped prison with the aid of the Black Liberation Army.</p>
                    <p>The file on the Congressional hearing regarding the quality of prison healthcare contains a packet: Alan Berkman, MD: Political Prisoner, circa 1988. Duplicates of statements, letters, an interview from the Philadelphia Inquirer, articles and other materials reproduced in the packet may be filed elsewhere. Berkman co-authored with Richard Clapp, the leaflet, “Suppressed Government Study Documents Health Risks of Water at Marion Prison,” distributed by the Committee to End the Marion Lockdown (after 1986). </p>
                    <p>The series also contains many pamphlets advocating the release of Berkman and other political prisoners, published by the Campaign to Support the Resistance Conspiracy Case Defendants and the Emergency Committee for Political Prisoners.</p>
                    <p>Also included in this series is a transcript from a televised debate “Should we grant amnesty to America’s political prisoners?” Debates? Series on PBS April 1998. The panel included Ron Kuby, a civil rights lawyer, Berkman, and Safiya Bukhari, National Jericho Program coordinator. The “con” perspective consisted of Charlie Rose, Ted Cruz, and Peter Thiel.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_004002525d55c5cd94c2e8a2d3d85856" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Medical career</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1972/2009">1972 - 2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The bulk refers to work after his release from prison. Health GAP materials includes notes, timeline, and articles. The Conference on Global AIDS folder contains notes and printouts of slides.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_89c965bf44958011aad4b8c48aebe89f" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1977/2009">1977 - 2009</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Berkman’s writings describe his experience in prison, particularly regarding his health and cancer status. Prison diaries contain his observations of other prisoners, guards, and multiple other aspects to his life behind bars. He worked to develop his previous writings into an autobiography. His papers include correspondence (1994) relating to this book project. After his release and death, others may have re-worked his writings, interviews, correspondence, and press release statements, into his memoir. It was never published. </p>
                    <p>He gave one or more speeches for Queer Women &amp; Men United in Support of Political Prisoners (QUISP), one in honor of Mumia Abu-Jamal. Includes two folders of poetry. Additional poetry may be found in Berkman’s outgoing prison correspondence.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="c_04fb878a537d4feb7c90743c973d191b" level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>Non-print media</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1963/2010">1963 - 2010</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Photographs, plaques, three-dimensional glass awards, and digital video. Includes photograph and postcard reproductions of the mural Roots of Freedom/Raices de Libertad by Miranda Bergman, Raul Valdez and Ambray Gonzalez. Alan Berkman is depicted. 

Lectures and speeches were recorded to DVD. Other digital video includes his memorial celebration and the published film, Pills Profits Protest (2005). Some photographs are adhered to album pages. Photographic prints of FBI evidence and Mumia Abu-Jamal are filed with Series: Legal.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c>
        </dsc>
        <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
            <bibref>
                <extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="9f739b_BerkmanContainerList.docx" xlink:role="application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.wordprocessingml.document"/>
            </bibref>
        </otherfindaid>
    </archdesc>
</ead>