<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0006</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>James Everett Perdue Papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-05-21">May 21, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Zachary Vickery.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>James Everett Perdue Papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1963/1991" type="inclusive">1963 - 1991</unitdate>
							<abstract>The professional collection of James E. Perdue, the seventh President of SUNY Oswego and covers the years from 1963 to 1991.  Dr. Perdue oversaw the ongoing physical transformation of the campus landscape and growth in its student and faculty ranks. He spearheaded the opening of the academic quad that includes Hewitt, Penfield Library and Lanigan, Mahar and Tyler Halls; several residence halls including what is known as “New Campus”; dining halls; the Culkin administration building and other spaces still of great use.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>2 linear feet</extent>
							<extent>3 boxes</extent>
            </physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitid>2001.015.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>Collection is open to the public.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>James Everett Perdue was the seventh president of S.U.N.Y. Oswego from 1965 until 1977.  Under his presidency,  S.U.N.Y. Oswego grew in many ways. Dorms, dining halls, Hewitt Union, Penfield Library, the administration building and various academic halls were built. Relations between the college, faculty and students were also improved during the period of student unrest in the early 1970's. Dr. Perdue left S.U.N.Y. Oswego in 1977 to become associate chancellor at S.U.N.Y. and was succeeded by Virginia Radley.  Perdue retired in 1983 and spent the next several years involved in various academic projects around the country.  
In 1991, Dr. Perdue wrote his autobiography.  
</p>
						<p>Dr. James E. Perdue died in 1998.</p>
        </bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5130081" source="geonames">Oswego (N.Y.)</geogname>
        
        <subject authfilenumber="sh85028315" source="lcsh">College presidents</subject>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>Included in the series is an autobiography, photographs, Perdue Inauguration papers, S.U.N.Y. Oswego 125th Anniversary papers, speeches, articles, pamphlets, college memorandum, reports, consultations, correspondence, and information on student unrest at Oswego during the 1970's.</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions. </p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_0a07aca4c953884aa77791b89db528a7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Autobiography       </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The autobiography of James E. Perdue,  "The First Seventy-Five Years 1916-1991: An Autobiography", 375 pages, published in 1991. It details his thoughts on his family and life. Included is correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs and genealogical information.

Sections:

In the Beginning
The First Teaching Position 
Courtship 1938
The Wedding and After, 1939-1942
A New Home, A New Job, A New Baby
The War Years, 1941-1945
Harvard and On, Late November 1943
New York City and Brooklyn
Atlantic Sea Duty
Home From The Wars
The Deanship
1965
1966
1967
1968
1969
1970
1970 Afterthoughts
1971
1972
Europe
August 1, 1972 -- Back At Work
1974
1975
1976
1977
1978
1979
1980
1981
1982
1983
1984
1985
1986
1987
1988
1989
1990
1991
Appendix:
     Perdue Family Heritage -- genealogy information, photographs, correspondence, newspaper clipping.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_b48fac2d30aafaee1b86e061c8d370d3" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Autobiography copy 2</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>"The First Seventy-Five Years 1916-1991: An Autobiography".  copy 2</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_9a7c44cbed4fd752cd74e0b99e4be9cd" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">1960's - 1970's</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Several photographs of Perdue in a group, by himself and also a picture taken by Perdue that was used as the cover photo for the S.U.N.Y. Oswego Student Directory 1973-74. 

The photographss were taken in the 1960's and early 1970's.  Others identified in some of the group photos are Janice Cromp, Gary Hoppee, Hilda Bohall, and Taylor Harter.  There are 8 photographss total, one a duplicate.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_dc8219705c3423cfd7ae6458c389dc51" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Perdue Inauguration</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1966">1966</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Materials relating to the inauguration of James Perdue on May 14, 1966, as the 7th president of S.U.N.Y. Oswego.  
Included are:

Invitation to the inauguration.  Bifold.  8 1/4" x 5 1/8"

Inauguration program.  10 1/4" x 7 1/4".  12 pp.  Saturday, May 14, 1966 @ 11:00.  Location:  Mary V. Lee hall, Oswego, New York.   2 copies.   Includes:
Processional -- College Band, George J. Cuppernull, Director
Presiding -- Charles Yager, Professor of Chemistry
The National Anthem
Invocation-- The Reverend Frederick R. Mills, Christ Church
Anthem "Psalm 150"-- The Symphonic Choir, The College Orchestra, Maurice O. Boyd, Director
Remarks-- Samuel B. Gould, President of the State University of New York
Presentation of the President -- George M. Penney, Chairman, College Council
Installation of the President -- Samuel B. Gould, President of the State University of New York
Inaugural Address-- James E. Perdue, President of State University College, Oswego
Benediction-- The Reverend Robert Hall, St. Mary's Church
Recessional-- College Band.
Includes lists of names -- 
Delegates from Learned Societies, Foundations and Professional Organizations
Delegates from Colleges and Universities [inserted in program is supplemental list]
Delegates from Colleges and Universities of The State University of New York.

Also includes Inaugural Committee members.
Inserted in program are six cards [tickets?] measuring 5 1/4" x 2 1/4".  The front of each card is printed "Inauguration '66, Spring Weekend".  The reverse:
Sunday, May 15th, Major Attraction, Louis Armstrong Concert, Lee Hall, 8:00 p.m.
Saturday, May 14th, Inaugural Ball, Lakeside Dining Hall, 9:00 p.m.
Friday, May 13th, Jam Session ("The Invictas"), Campus School Parking Lot, 10:00 p.m.
Friday, May 13th, Symphonic Choir Spring Concert, Sheldon Auditorium, 8:00 p.m.
Friday, May 13th, Phi Sig Beauty Contest, Sheldon Auditorium, 4:30 p.m.  2 copies.

6 copies of a booklet.  2 of the copies are in envelopes.
Includes:
Inaugural Convocation agenda
Events of Inaugural Weekend
Inaugual Remarks by Samuel B. Gould, President of the State Univeristy of New York.
"The Analytic and the Synthetic" by James E. Perdue.  3-page transcript of speech.

Expression of gratitude card from Dr. James Everett Perdue "on the occasion of his installation as the Seventh President of State University of New York College at Oswego".  5 3/8" x 4 1/8"

36-page issue of  "The Oswegonian".  photocopy.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_90a9e04fb4eb1fb348e10f43b38ab200" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>State University of New York 25th Anniversary</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1973">1973</unitdate>
					<container type="">1-5</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>State University of New York 25th Anniversary       

Various materials pertain to the anniversary celebration at Oswego and in Albany at S.U.N.Y.. 
The celebration at the Oswego campus was to commemorate the 25th year of SUNY campuses.

Included is correspondence, pamphlets, conference speakers, memorandum, financial records, speeches, S.U.N.Y. Albany Symposium materials, and conference planning papers. 

The 25th Anniversary celebration took place at Oswego the weekend of October 8-11, 1973. </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_5c0df25befb2801d2934508676119433" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Articles and Pamphlets</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1965/1980">1965 - 1980</unitdate>
					<container type="">1-6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Articles, booklets and pamphlets were either written by Perdue or contain a speech or excerpt by him. There are five booklets written between 1965 and 1980.  

The Oswegonian.  January 15, 1965, article.  "Dr. Perdue Named SUCO President".

1970 booklet, "Freedom and Responsibility on Campus" contains two chapters written by Dr.Perdue.  Table of Contents:
I.  Freedom and Responsibility on Campus:  An Overview
II.  The College Communinity:  Present Tension and Future Shock
III.  The Oswego Strike:  What Happened?
IV.  Communications Within the College
V.  The Changing Process of Education
VI.  Minority Groups
VII.  The College Community and Political Action.

A Presidential Farewell.  Announcement and reservation form.  

Included here is an 81-page booklet, "Proceedings First Annual Convocation of Distinguished Faculty" with a speech by Dr. Perdue.  May 2, 1980.  Includes:
Memorandum from Chancellor Clifton R. Wharton regarding the Proceedings of Convocation of Distinguished Faculty.  Includes supporting papers.

Opening Remarks by James E. Perdue, Vice Chancellor for Academic Programs, Policy and Planning.

Academic Climate and Potential of the State Univeristy of New York by Dorothy Rogers.  16 pp.
Academic Climate and Potential of the State University of New York by Kingsley L. Greene. 19 p
Academic Climate and Potential of the State University of New York by Henry L. Bretton.  10 pp.
Academic Climate and Potential of the State University of New York by Dr. Warren H. Thomas.

State Unversity of New York Proposal for Honors Program.  6 pp.
Remarks and Dialogue from Chancellor Clifton R. Wharton.  6 pp.

President's Convocation.  September 12, 1967.  Bifold.  Dr. Perdue, SUNY Oswego President.

A Testimonial Luncheon and Reception in Honor of Dr. James E. Perdue.  Trifold.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_ab76fae53942c82e36b4299c73dd30bc" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memorandums</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1966/1970">1966 - 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Various college memos regarding policies, meetings, news releases, budgets, benefits, reports and administration issues. The memos were written between 1966 and 1977, with the highest concentration being during the mid-1970's. There are about 200 memos contained in three folders.

Subjects include:
Consortium Activity - Institutional Development Study Project.
Speech by Samuel B. Gould - Mission and Purpose.
Third Annual Faculty Assembly agenda and policies.
Copy of "A Plan of Action" from Dr. Perdue.
Promotions Procedures.
Advisory Committee on the Selection of a Dean.
Faculty salaries.
Urban unrest.
Campus student unrest.
Proposed faculty bylaws.
Registering students in programs prior to the time the programs have been approved.
Movement for a moratorium on college activities.
Equal Employment Opportunity.
Term appointments for 1970-1971 academic year.
Academic calendar changes.
Wooden gavel made by Herbert S. Graves, class of 1930. Added to Dr. Sheldon's collection.
Faculty library privileges.
Local grievance procedures.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_8a374a6e7cdc686a74f976ebf9e0383d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memorandums</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1971/1973">1971 - 1973</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-8</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Memorandums to and from Dr. Perdue pertaining to policies, meetings, news releases, budgets and administration issues.

Subjects include:
Report from Summer Conference Committee -  "Freedom and Responsibility on Campus".
Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation electrical line changes.
Budget cuts.

City of Oswego / Niagara Mohawk construction projects resulted in loss of 500 campus parking spaces.

Faculty bylaws.
State Dental Insurance Plan.
Middle States Association and National Council for the Accreditation of Teacher Education.
Oswego County United Fund Drive.
New identification card for college community.
Equal Employment Opportunity Policy Statement.
Budget
Bylaws
Library staff and budget.
Incident report.
Hot line to Deputy to the Chancellor for major campus emergencies.
State of New York Take Stock in America '72 Savings Bond Campaign.
Travel expenses and use of automobiles policy statement.
Microfilming machines usage.
Microfilm Library Inventory.
Safety Responsibilities.
Anne Commerton appointed Acting Director of Libraries effective January 1, 1973.
Recruitment Account Expenditures.
First draft of local Master Plan submitted to Chancellor's Office.
Annual reports.
Reaction to State of College message.
Call to faculty for upcoming faculty meeting - quorum needed.
Vaccinia [Smallpox] Vaccination.
Memo to all supervisors, re:  summer responsibilities.
Call to upcoming faculty meeting; new appointments listed.
Seminar for Academic and Administrative Officers.
1973-1974 Campus Telephone Directory.
Address by Professor Fred Hoyle.
Personnel shifts.
1973-1974 faculty committee list.  
Criteria and procedures for Graduate Faculty membership.
A Report on Energy Conservation Activities.
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_b04727b22a72808a811153b9f2507c1c" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memorandums</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1974/1977">1974 - 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-9</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Incoming and outgoing memorandums - Dr. Perdue pertaining to administration issues, meetings, policies, budgets and reports.

Subjects include:
Master Theses
Energy / budget concerns
Administrative Internship Program
Equal Employment Opportunity Program
Interviews for Executive Vice President and Provost positions.
Annual Report formats.

Memo from Lynn Hemink to All Classified Service Personnel concerning civil service law and attendance rules.

Employee Tuition Waivers.
New Faculty Orientation
Sabbatical Leave.
1974-1975 College Directory.
Personnel Responsibility Areas.
Discretionary salary increases.
1974-1975 faculty committee list.
American Council on Education Academic Administration Internship Program.
Telephone tolls.
Campus financial situation.
Building temperatures
Faculty Assembly bylaws.
New York State Office of Employee Relations and CSEA negotiations impasse.
Faculty and Staff Responsibilties in the Event of a Strike.
Budget  -  30% cut in telephone service.
Travel expenses to SUNY-Wide Committees.
Graduate Studies Dean vacancy.
Temperature reduction in all campus buildings.
Search for candidates for the position of Dean of Arts and Sciences.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3c67644d6a459e6ff6dfb502dfea5184" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>State of the College Message</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1967/1976">1967 - 1976</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>State of the College Messages from 1967 to 1976.  There are no reports contained here for 1972 and 1974. Each report is a summary of the framework, development and issues of the academic year. </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_758bea9cbc5f8e26ab5a591d11b2ac24" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Reports</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1965/1973">1965 - 1973</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-11</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Reports

"Report for October 1965"  was submitted by Dr. Perdue to Samuel Gould, the President of S.U.N.Y. Albany.   The report documents staff activities, curriculum, publications and research, student affairs.   8 pp.

New York State Education Department Evaluation Report of the college.  January 1970.  22 pp.


"The College in Capsule - 1972-73"  [3 pp] is an overview of the college regarding:
New Academic Programs
Student Health Services
Student Government
New Academic Appointments
Oswego Overseas
Hewitt Union
Residence Hall Life
Learning Resources
Third Curriculum
Community Service Center
Facilities Programming</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_cd046ce939a5c587ade464dd3246058d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Report to the Chancellor </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1971/1972">1971 - 1972</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-12</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The "President's Annual Report to the Chancellor" for 1971-72.   The report was written by Dr. Perdue.  6 pp.   Includes:  Student Affairs, Academic Affairs and General Administration.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_786a4d914b6a2c143eca0a5648e3fd32" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Annual Report of the President </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1972/1976">1972 - 1976</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-13</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Annual Report of the President 

Annual Report of the President, 1972-1973.  21 pp.
Includes:  
Academic Affairs
    Evaluation of Professional Faculty and Staff
    Student Enrollments
    Faculty Workload
    Role of Departmental Chairman
    Curricular Revision
    Center for the Improvement of Instruction
    Communication
    Administrative Reorganization
    Accountability
    Student Advisement
    Continuing Education
    Graduate Education
    Division of Arts and Sciences
    Division of Professional Studies
    Division of Graduate Studies
    Academic Support Services
    Administrative Affairs
    Student Affairs
Graduate Admission Report, August 1972 - June 1973
Report on Proposals, July 1, 1972 - June 30, 1973
Schematic of Philosphy and Direction
Division of Student Affairs Functional Organization chart.

Annual Report of the President, 1973 - 1974.  12 pp.
Includes:
Overview
College Calendar
Enrollment
Accomplishments and Direction
Administrative Affairs 
    Personnel
    Computer Center
    Auxiliary Services
Security
Maintenance &amp; Operations
Business Affairs
Student Affairs
Curricular Innovations and Revisions
Program Revisions
New and Revised Academic Policies
Administrative appointments
Department chairperson designations or redesignations.
Selected Problems and Recommended Actions.

Annual Report of the President, 1975 - 1976.  13 pp.
Includes:
Strategies for Survival
Acadmic Affairs
Curricular Innovations and Revisions
Faculty Assembly actions
Department chairperson designations or redesignations
Academic Services
    Language Laboratory
    Learning Resources Center
    Penfield Library
    Personnel Office
    Student Financial Aids
    Veterans' Affairs
    Inservice
Administrative Affairs
Computer Center
Campus Security
Budget Office
Maintenance Department
Business Affairs
Student Affairs
Office of the President
    Equal Employment Opportunity
    College Development</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_a9c828c04ab8cde7eaf99983e1806f3b" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Presidential Review Report</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1969/1974">1969 - 1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-14</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Presidential Review Report  1969 - 1974 submitted by Dr. James E. Perdue, President, State University of New York College at Oswego.  30 pp.  
Includes:
President's Statement of Self-Assessment, 1969-1974
Table of Contents:
Prologue 1965-1969
Review 1969 - 1974, An Overview
Time - Line Chart - following page 4
External Relationships
Internal Relationships
Institutions Tone Set by the President
Administrative Leadership and Management
Academic Leadership and Management
Appendix --
    A.  Academic Programs Approved since 1969
    B.  Comparison of Projected Headcounts and FTE's to Actual Headcounts and FTE's
    C.  Current projections through 1980
    D.  Total Faculty by numbers, ranks, degree preparation
    E.  Comparative Budgets</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_2017e77de239627759f98922ed51c8d4" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Presidential Purview Report</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1965/1978">1965 - 1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-15</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>A Presidential Purview of S.U.N.Y. Oswego: Challenges, Changes and Accomplishments, 1965 to 1978 by James E. Perdue.  39 pp.
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d4e64102babc5b1c0f367bd0c0d85cf6" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Sponsored Research Report</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1981">1981</unitdate>
					<container type="">1-16</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Nature and Needs of Sponsored Research in Four-Year Colleges and Two-Year Agricultural and Technical Colleges of the State University of New York". 37 pp.

Handwritten note under title on title page, "Special project assigned to me by Chancellor 1981.  JE Perdue."
Contents:
Introduction
Improving Sponsored Research
Faculty Criticisms From Two-Year Colleges
Faculty Suggestions For Improvement From Two-Year Colleges
Faculty Criticisms From Four-Year Colleges
Faculty Suggestions For Improvement From Four-Year Colleges
Conclusions and Recommendations
Faculty Questionnaire
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_fd83d7256d4e02d81082b784a415b166" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Consultancy  </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970">1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-17</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Consultancy

A report for a consultancy which Perdue participated in for Robert Finch, the Counsellor to the President of the United States. 

The report is entitled "Selected Problems Facing Higher Education in the 1970's", dated November 2, 1970.  34 pp.   The report was pieced together by 6 consultants total (including Dr. Perdue).  Also included are 2 items of correspondence, 1 memorandum and a newpaper article regarding the project.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_fc149b692ca1003d8750f74530792c6e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1963/1990">1963 - 1990</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-18</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The next 10 folders contain various personal and professional correspondence ranging from 1963 to 1990.  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.  This first folder contains incoming and outgoing [although most correspondence is carbon copies of typed outgoing correspondence from Dr. Perdue] correspondence pertaining to his 1965 move from Colorado to Oswego, New York, including congratulations and acknowledgements.

The correspondence is in chronological order.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_38009e80e03be02eb2c5f3c325098af7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1966/1971">1966 - 1971</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-19</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence from students, and correspondence pertaining to speaking engagements, etc.  Incoming and outgoing.  Typed and handwritten.

In chronological order.  Also included is a typed quote by Dr. Richard Piez.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_ea8a0f64b283a976e577f7bc4661cdf7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1965/1977">1965 - 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-20</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>SUNY Oswego related correspondence.  Incoming and outgoing.  Typed, including carbon copies.  
In chronological order.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_c275432610e95fa37cd696fe0570d1b0" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1963/1965">1963 - 1965</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-21</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence pertains to early Oswego contact, trip expenses and SUNY Oswego information.  Chronologically ordered.

Incoming and outgoing typed correspondence, some on carbon paper.
Correspondents include:
Harry W. Porter, Provost, State University of New York, Albany, New York.
Harry E. Charlton, Director of Public Information, State University College, Oswego, New York.
George M. Penney, Chairman of the College Council, State University College, Oswego.
Charles F. Wells, Acting Secretary, College Council, State University College, Oswego.
Dr. Charles S. Turner, Acting President, State University College, Oswego.
Dr. Kenneth E. Young, President, State University College, Cortland, New York.
W.H. Cowley, David Jacks Professor of Higher Education, Stanford Univeristy.
J. Lawrence Murray, Vice President, State University of New York, Albany, New York.
Clarence Leighton, Oswego Palladium-Times, Oswego, New York.
Miss Helen Hagger, College Librarian, State University of New York, Oswego, New York
Dr. Leonard G. Boonin, Associate Professor of Philosophy, State University College, Oswego.
William Adams, President, Associated Student Body, State University College, Oswego.
Dr. J. Sherwood Dunham, Acting Dean, State University College, Oswego, New York.
Dr. Emmet C. Stopher, Chairman, Department of Mathematics, State University College.
David G. Berry, Director, Atmospheric Science Research Center, SUNY, Albany.
Dr. Joseph Leese, Professor of Education, SUNY @ Albany.
Dr. Jack L. Nelson, School of Education, SUNY @ Buffalo.
Mrs. George L. Richardson, Syracuse, New York.
Dr. Erwin Palmer, Academic Advisory Committee, SUC, Oswego, New York.
Dr. James E. Allen, Jr., Office of the Commissioner, SUNY, SED, Albany, New York.
Roman Tratch, Department of Psychology, State University of New York College, Oswego.
Mrs. Ben H. Bohall, Oswego, New York
Rev. Richard F. Ryan, S.J., President of Regis College, Denver, CO.
Rev. Robert E. Hall, Chaplain, Newman Hall Catholic Center, Oswego, New  York
Virginio L. Piucci, Acting Director, Division of Elementary + Secondary School Education, SUCO
Carl James Holmes, Syracuse, New York.
Dr. Robert W. Rock, Dean of Students, State University College at Oswego
Kenneth E. Dawson, Executive Secretary-Treasurer, American IA Association, Inc.
The Sisters of Theta Chi Rho, Oswego, New York.
Shirley Walker, Funnelle Hall, SUCO
Mary Brown, Secretary to the President, State University College at Oswego
Dr. W. Seward Salisbury, Chairman, Department of Social Studies, SUCO
Dr. Leonard Becker, Administrative Assistant, SUCO
Dr. Gardner Wells, SUCO
President, Sigma Gamma Fraternity, SUCO
Edward P. Boardway, President, Civil Service Employees Assoc., Inc., Oswego Chapter</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3644e4c2eaa3b31aa6f2053127d12e3e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-22</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Evaluation of the Chief Administrative Office, 1974, evaluates the Perdue administration at SUNY Oswego.

Includes memorandums from:
Lynn D. Hemink
Donald R. Mathieu, Chairman, Faculty Assembly

Correspondence from:
James S. Smoot, Vice Chancellor for University-Wide Services and Special Programs, Albany, New York.

- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
Faculty Evaluation of Chief Administrative Officer invitation/directive.  May 6, 1974.  

Administrative Evaluation of President Perdue.  May, 1974.  3 pp.

Evaluation of the President's Performance.  (Minority Report by the Students).  11 pp.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_fb0be659a4b5e2fda165e3cec0b89559" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1977">1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-23</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence pertains to Dr. Perdue's move from Oswego to Albany, New York.

Correspondence between Dr. Perdue and Ernest L. Boyer.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_1fead02e64e56fad5a813e7d61851b9b" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1977/1981">1977 - 1981</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-24</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence - Dr. George T. Land and others.

Handwritten note from JE Perdue, "Some of my correspondence with Dr. George T. Land - author, consultant and lecturer at universities and businesses such as General Motors.  Geo and I did several things together at a number of colleges". 
 
Correspondence is arranged chronologically.  1977 - 1981.  Handwritten and typed.

Correspondents in addition to Dr. Land:

President Donald E. Walker, Southeastern Massachusetts University, North Dartmouth, Mass.
Attached to correspondence is a 1977 seven-page article, "The Halitosis Strategy of Survival" by Donald E. Walker.  

George Keller, SEARCH, A journal of scholarly research.  

Dr. Gabriele L. Rico, School of Humanities + the Arts, San Jose State University, San Jose, CA
Attached is a five-page "studen evalution of clustering."

Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., Chancellor, SUNY, Albany, New York.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_1d589b95e69f43390c2ee06a5f72a7b6" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence-Robert Greenleaf </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1977/1990">1977 - 1990</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-25</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Incoming and outgoing, handwritten and typed, correspondece between Robert Greenleaf and Dr. Perdue.
A note from JEP, "Letters to Robt Greenleaf, author.  comments on his ideas + Mss."

Additional correspondents include:
Hugh G. Lally, Promotion Director, Paulist Press
Ralph L. Spencer, Acting Provost, SUNY Oswego

Constantine B. Simonides, Coference Convener, Center for Applied Studies, Conference on Undergraduate Leadership Potential, Nashville, Indiana.

Rev. Oliver F. Williams, C.S.C., University of Notre Dame.

Larry Spears, Executive Director, The Robert K. Greenleaf Center.

- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
"Is It More Blessed To Give Than To Receive?" by Robert K. Greenleaf.  Excerpt from Friends Journal, Quaker Thought and Life Today.  May 1, 1976.  photocopy.  2 pp.

Commencement talk by Michael Greenleaf [handwritten note - "18 year old grandson"], Solebury School, New Hope, Pa.  June 5, 1976.  3 typed pages.

"Robert Greenleaf:  The gentle taskmaster of servant leaders".  2 pp.  Not cited.  n.d.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_b2b224d34d498225ac3d500bb83c20ee" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1977-01/1977-03">January, 1977 - March, 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-26</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Personal correspondence pertain to Dr. Perdue's move to Albany, New York, from Oswego. 
Incoming and outgoing correspondence.  Handwritten and typed.

Correspondents include:

Margaret A. Smith, Administrative Assistant to the President, SUNY College @ Old Westbury.
Lew O'Donnell, SUNY Oswego
David W. Pelland, Menter/Rudin/Trivelpiece Law Offices, Syracuse, New York
Mrs. George L. Richardson, Syracuse, New York.
Norris W. Goldsmith, Oswego, New York.
Joan Van Keuren, Director, Student Financial Aids, SUNY Oswego

Father Hall, St. Mary's Church, Oswego, New York
Sandy Sternlicht, SUNY Oswego
Vernon A. Tryon, SUNY Oswego
Dr. Girgis Ghobrial, SUNY Oswego
Albert W. Brown, President, SUNY Brockport
T. William Hall, Syracuse University

Gary T. Durham, Director of Security, SUNY Oswego
Jean W. Eddy, SUNY Oswego
Kenneth E. Young, President, The Council on Postsecondary Accreditation.
John J. Connolly, President, Dutchess Community College, Poughkeepsie, New York.
Robert Johns, Robert Johns &amp; Associates, Rapid City, South Dakota.
Joseph V. Julian, Syracuse University

Robert E. Wehrle, Regional President, Marine Midland Bank, Syracuse, New York.
John S. Toll, SUNY Stony Brook
Thomas F. Powell, SUNY Oswego
John T. Bernhard, President, Western Michigan University
Craig Shaw Fehlhaber, Graduate Assistant, Department of Industrial Arts and Technology.
George N. Rainsford, President, Kalamazoo College, Kalamazoo, Michigan

Geoff Lilndsay, Editor, the Oswegonian
Arthur Sabatini, SUNY Oswego
Foster Brown, Pompano Beach, Florida
Louis T. Benezet, SUNY Stony Brook
Judi Brownell, SUNY Cortland

Dr. Clark D. Ahlberg, President, Wichita State University, Wichita, Kansas.
President Howard J. Burnett, Washington and Jefferson College, Washington, PA
President Elmer Jagow, Hiram College, Hiram, Ohio

Dr. Carroll V. Galbreath, Assistant Regional Commissioner for Postsecondary Education, Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Dallas, Texas.

Mrs. Olla Rickett, Tampa, Florida</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_f46a3d2b16bc983cce0d0694fc78a6e7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1977-04/1977-12">April, 1977 - December, 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-27</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Personal correspondence to and from Dr. Perdue pertaining to his move from Oswego to Albany, New York.  
Incoming and outgoing.  Handwritten and typed, including carbon copies.  
Correspondents include:

Bruce Dearing, University Professor of Humanitites in Medicine, SUNY Upstate Medical.
Lynn D. Hemink, SUNY Oswego
Susan Fratkin, National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges.
Henry Angle, Fulton, New York.
Dr. James A. Smith, Oswego, New York
Grace Maxon, Oswego, New York.
Claire M. Merlehan, Oswego, New York

Dr. Joseph H. Johnson, Chairman, Presidential Search Committe, National College of Eduction, Wilmette, Illinois.

Mrs. Edward Siegel, Roslyn, New York
Hilda G. Bohall, Oswego, New York
Mr. &amp; Mrs. L.V. Lieb, Oswego, New York
Fred Plank, SUNY Oswego
William P. McGoldrick, Director, Community Relations + Development, SUNY Oswego
Dr. Virginia Radley, Acting President, SUNY Oswego

Dr. James Soluri, SUNY Oswego
Dr. Jerry Exline, SUNY Oswego
Raymond Doersam, SUNY Oswego
Layden E. Brown, Chairman, Oswego College Council
Dr. Frank Robinson, Vice President for Administrative Affairs, SUNY Oswego
Mrs. Roland Clark, Oswego, New York

Albert Hoefer, Jr., Ithaca, New York
Lester J. Gosier, Bay Shore, New York
William H. Green, Oswego County Savings Bank, Oswego, New York.
Harold Schwartz, President, JOMAR Plastics, Port Chester, New York
Lester J. Gosier, Chairman Science Department, Bay Shore Union Free School District.

Dr. James Gemmell, Associate Director, Academic Collective Bargaining Information Service, SUNY, Albany, New York.
William J. Purvis, Oswego, New York
Hugo Groppi, Director, SUNY Program Abroad, Pisa, Italy.

President Donald E. Walker, Southeastern Massachusetts University.  Attached is 13-page paper, "New Policies for Changing Institutions".  

Dr. Ernest L. Boyer, Commissioner of Education, Department of Health, Education + Welfare.
Alvin Goldberg, Chairperson, Department of Speech Communication, University of Denver.
Dr. Donald R. Mathieu, Dean of Arts and Science, SUNY Oswego
W.H. Cowley, Palo Alto, CA.
Dr. James F. Kelly

Cynthia Parsons, Education Editor, The Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Massachusetts.
Harold G. Cassidy, Professor-at-Large, Hanover College, Hanover, Indiana.
Asa G. Hilliard, Dean, School of Education, San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA.
Joseph Duffey, Chairman, National Endowment for the Humanities, Washington, D.C.
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3a094cc7ec14a8d5689ef7e7512aa35e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>"A Response to the 70's" report </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1973-03">March, 1973</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-28</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>A Response to the 70's.  State University College at Oswego's Reply to the 1972 Master Plan of State University of New York.  First Draft.  March, 1973.  James E. Perdue, President.  94 pp.

Table of Contents:

Introduction
I.  The Region, The State, and Admissions
          Regionalism
          Admissions programs
          Freshman class profile
          Transfer students
          Gifted high school students
II.  The Academic Programs
           General studies
               Energy studies
               Communications programs
               Programs of interdisciplinary and multidisciplinary nature
          "Classical College"
          Teacher Education
               Continuing education of teachers
          Technical studies
          Career studies
                Health science
                Practicum
           Honors programs
           International education
           Graduate programs
                Interdisciplinary and multidisciplinary programs
                Lifelong learning
III.  Faculty and Staff
          Consultation on programs existing and proposed
          Equal opportunity employment procedures
          Excellence in teaching
          Non-teaching professionals
               Student affairs
          Research
IV.  The Student and Campus Life
          Time-shortened degrees
           Deferred admissions and "step-out" programs
           External degrees
           Off-campus programs
           Practicum and internships
           Intercultural understanding
           Retirees and senior citizens
           Student rights
           Library
           Campus School
           Alumni, community and public affairs
V.  The Seventies</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_adb5f72aac1d2ddf7b7127ff033c20a1" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Publication </unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-29</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>"Morsels for Meditation, Gleanings Over the Years" by James E. Perdue. 76 pages.

A second copy was added.  It includes additional pages and expanded sections.  The book includes passages / quotes from books and magazines collected over the years by Dr. Perdue.  They have been arranged into ten catagories:  
Administration
Deans &amp; Presidents
Leadership
Learning
Liberal Education
Morality--Honor--Ethics
Power
Religion
Teaching
Communication -- Writing

In addition is inserted [not attached to original spiral binding] is "The Career Development Quiz".  6 pp.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_7bce8b168bd6437c55096f5c93a33b01" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>President's Statement </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-30</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>1969 two-page statement concerning pilot program. (3 copies)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_63bb6188b7fb61abc9740ebcf977228c" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Requests for Department Statements</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1965/1966">1965 - 1966</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-31</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence, memorandums and statements concerning a request from Dr. Perdue to department chairs and administrative officers.  Dr. Perdue asks that two statements be submitted concerning outstanding characteristics and limitations and a second statement concerning administrative philosophy and role.

Included are responses from George F. Lambert, Dean of Men; R. W. Rock; the Dean of Women; the Dean of Students; the Division of Student Personnel.
A one-page typed meeting agenda, May 27, 1966 is included.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_2049966426bdbe4e4901d3e8992de68d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Justification, requests, promotions, job vacancies</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1971">1971</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-32</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>35 typed memorandums and correspondence with attachments that include justification for position reports.  Correspondence is between James E. Perdue and State University of New York administration.  

Correspondents include:  
Dr. Ernest L.  Boyer
Dr. James A. Frost
Dr. Harold Delaney
Thomas J. Peterson
Dr. Harold Delaney
Harvey Randall</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_0692f006da8baa643f0b8c7d722f3af7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches-audiotapes</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1959/1974">1959 - 1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-33</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>5 audiotapes contain speeches by Dr. Perdue.  
Dates range from 1959 to 1974.

All audiotapes are TDK Professional Master Series.  IECI/TYpe1 Normal Position.  Acoustic Master.  AM 60
Identifying handwritten labels on each:

Pres. Perdue / Freshman Assembly / 9/19/59.
Pres. Perdue / Stillwater / July 31, 1961.
Pres. Perdue / 9/17/63 / A+S Faculty.
Pres. Perdue Inauguration 1966.
SUNY Oswego President Perdue.  8/29/74.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_14450c113a659f8b6c293f9c396faa7f" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1965/1969">1965 - 1969</unitdate>
					<container type="">2-1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches and related materials were either written or given by James Perdue.  The speeches were given between the years 1965 and 1969.  Speeches include messages to the faculty, addressing issues and concerns or were given at special events such as commencements, dinners or conferences. The length of the speeches range up to 29 pages.  There are several speeches with the notes attached.  Five speeches are also available here on audiotape. These range from 1959-1974 and are addressed to faculty, Inauguration speeches or Assembly speeches.

The Post-Modern Mind.  Commencement Address.  University of Denver.  June 11, 1965.
Graduate Education:  Fact or Fiction.  Graduate Luncheon.  July 28, 1965.  2 copies.
A Communicty of Scholars.  General Faculty meeting.  September 9, 1965.  2 copies.
The Analytic and the Synthetic.  Inaugural Address of Dr. Perdue.  May 14, 1966.

President's Convocation for Freshmen.  September 11, 1966.  29 pp.   5 1/2" x 8 1/2" typed pp.  Summer Session Conference.  Miami.  November 1967.  8 typed pages with editing notes.

Statement for disruptive activities.  1968.    3 carbon copies.
Today in the First Day of the Rest of Your Life.  For Special Issue of Oswegonian.  President's Message.  May 28, 1969.   2 typed pages, carbon copy.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_26fbd0dd068d060d48794962b7b82991" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970/1975">1970 - 1975</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches are arranged chronologically.  This folder is a continuation of folder 02-01.

Speeches include:

Members of the Graduating Class of 1970.  3 typed pages.
The College Community.  2 typed pages.  August 5, 1970.
September 1970.  President's message.  2 pp.  carbon copy.
The Community and the College:  A Challenge for the Seventies.  Draft.  September 1970.

Greetings to Class of 1971 from Dr. Perdue.
President's Speech.  October 6, 1972.  16 typed pages with editing notes.
Draft of President's message.  1 typed page.  n.d.
Handwritten "speech to new students.  1/12/75"

Liberal Education:  What Is It?  Remarks to the Board of Trustees of the State University of New York, February 25, 1975.  J.E. Perdue.  25 typed pages.
Award of Merit Dinner speech.  May 1975.  4 typed pages.  4 handwritten pages.
Speech to the Faculty.  Dr. James E. Perdue.  September 4, 1975.  3 typed pages.  3 copies

American Association of State Colleges and Universities Proceedings, 1975.  Article by Dr. Perdue on pps. 15-24.  "President to Presidents Lecture."  Complete 83-page journal.

President-to-Presidents Lecture.  15th Annual Meeting of American Association of State Colleges and Universities.  November 12, 1975.  11 typed pages.  2 copies.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_f758f62f1b238da8d06a704b7a34b412" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1975/1976">1975 - 1976</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches

1975 Speech to the Faculty, 3 pp.
1976 speech, "A Framework for Change", 6 pp.  2 copies

Draft of Oswegonian editorial by President Perdue.  June 1976

Speech to New Faculty.  August 30, 1976.  
Handwritten speech to General Faculty.  September 13, 1976

Small folder of speeches, some edited copies on a variety of subjects.  1976

43-page speech on the nature/function of colleges and universities.  No title, date or further citing.  </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_853b3fda91f0536025d20412288fde59" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Five photographs mounted for a display.

Group photograph - Dr. Perdue, center; Virginia L. Radley, right.  Unidentified gentleman on the left.

Dr. Perdue on a bicycle

Dr. Perdue with six individuals [students?] and bicycle.

Dr. Perdue with large group of students on campus near Hewitt Union.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_0818030db138329a49dc379743af3073" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>1970's- Student Unrest </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1964/1970">1964 - 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-5</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>1970's- Student Unrest    

Various materials such as newspaper articles, magazine articles and miscellaneous memos, newsletters, position papers and pamphlets that approach the problems of and reasons behind the student unrest are included in box 3.
 
Five reports by The University of Denver including -
"The Workshop on Liberal Arts Education"  7 pp, 1964
April 1969 "Discipline Code for the University of Denver" 30 pp
April 1969 "Code of Procedures for all Agencies" 11 pp
1969 memorandum from Chancellor Maurice B. Mitchell concerning the attached "Declaration of Student Demands"  14 pp
1969 "Principles of Student Life at the University of Denver". 2 pp

June 1969 article from "Higher Education and National Affairs" publication, "Consensus on Handling Campus Disorders Urged by National Commission".  7 pp

Congressional Record, 91st Congress, "Congress Looks at the Campus:  The Brock Report on Student Unrest". 7 pp

"Mid-Elders To The Rescue" by Stan Haring, WE:HE/ME System for human relations founder.  2 pp

20-page publication of the EFL College Newsletter, 1970.  "Guidelines on University Organization" published by the Association of Universities and Colleges of Canada. 17 pp

"Campus Disorders 'Are You Ready For This?'" by the Association of Physical Plant Administrators, April 1970.  6 pp

"Just Law &amp; Civil Order" pamphlet, Christopher News Notes, May 1970.

May 1970 letter from Robert F. Goheen, Princeton University, to Princeton Alumni, Parents and Friends. 3 pp

"Overcommunication or A Forgotten Right:  The Right to Affirm", address by Daniel J. Boorstin, June 7, 1970.  12-page pamphlet

University of Buffalo memorandum from Thomas T. Frantz, Secretary pro tem, June 1970.  

Press release from Harvard University, June 1970 from the office of the Vice Chancellor concerning the election and class schedules.  2 pp.   Attached is a 1-page description of Cornell University's Fall Semester Plans.

6-page position paper "in opposition to the 'Princeton Plan' for a political-activity recess in colleges and universities in the Fall of 1970." by Keith Spalding, President, Franklin and Marshall College, June 1970.

Two 1970 letters of correspondence between Logan Wilson, President of the American Council on Education and Randolph W. Thrower, Commissioner, Internal Revenue Service.  Attached is June, 1970, 4-page "Guidelines on Questions Relating to Tax Exemption and Political Activities Statement of the American Council on Education".

Higher Education and National Affairs publication, June, 1970, "ACE Issues Guidelines About College Political Activity.  Tax Exemption".  12 pp.

3-page report by the Board of Trustees of the California State Colleges,  "Committee on Faculty and Staff Affairs" concerning salary increases  July, 1970. 

University of Denver newsletter excerpt, "Excerpts From a Letter to a Concerned Parent." 
1 page.

"Students Assess Their Colleges and Universities: Historical Backgrounds" by Donald T. Williams, Jr., University of Washington. 10 pp. with 2 page bibliography.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_52b98f96d8ddd8399eeb5939a16dee52" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">1960's - 1970's</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Eleven photographs are identified in detail in Photo record 2001.015.0002.  a. - x.

Also includes:
Three photographs used in a display.
Individuals identified:
The Perdue Family
Eleanor Filburn
Gus Silveira</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e51d61cee52f84f66a9849d6552a09f8" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence - Jossey-Bass Inc., Publishers</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1977/1978">1977 - 1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Corresopndence - Josey-Bass Inc., Publishers

Correspondents include:
JB Hefferlin, Director of Special Projects, Jossey-Bass Inc., Publishers
Dr. Lynn D. Hemink, SUNY Oswego
Allen Jossey-Bass, President, Jossey-Bass, Inc.

Papers:  
"Development in Young Adulthood:  Characteristics and Competencies in Education, Work, and Social Life" Edited by Samuel Messick.  6 pp.

"The Art of Administration" by Dr. Perdue.  September 6, 1977.  5 pp.  2 copies.

Small informational booklets:
Guidelines for Jossey-Bass Authors. 8 pp.
Guidelines for Edited Collections.  7 pp.
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d30eeef61d7f4ec8837c51a1f39b9dbc" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence - Jossey-Bass Inc., Publishers   </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1979/1982">1979 - 1982</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-8</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence - Jossey-Bass, Inc., Publishers

Four paper folders inserted in the folder include:

1979-1981:
1981
1981 + n.d.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_fa41b9981ed621fb5d8e688023c7ba0e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Journal Articles and Reports</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1964/1973">1964 - 1973</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Journal Articles and Reports  

Articles include" "Education in Utopia" by Bruce Dearing, from "Alumni Review", Lebanon Valley College, 1964.  4 pp.  

"Education and Research" from Ford Foundation Annual Report, 1968.  1 page. 

"The University and Student Dissent" by Robert S. Morison, from "Science", March 1969.  
1 page

2-page excerpt from U. S. News and World Report, July, 1969, "Needed Immediately:  200 College Presidents".  

"The Hampton Institute Strike of 1927, A Case Study in Student Protest" by Edward K. Graham, reprint from "The American Scholar"  15 pp.  Includes "Postscript:  The 1969 Demonstrations" by Margaret Mead.  

"The New Left and the Old Law" by William A. Stanmeyer, reprinted from the "American Bar Association Journal", April 1969.  5 pp.

"Co-Ed Living" by Betty Rollin from "Look" magazine, 1969.  6 pp.

"Danger: proceed at the risk of rationality" by Robert J. Schaefer.  "Relevance or Revolt" by Edmund W. Gordon.  Both from "Perspectives on Education", 1969.  16 pp

"Where is all began - Berkeley, 5 Years Later, Is Radicalized, Reaganized, Mesmerized" by A. H. Raskin from The New York Times Magazine, 1970.  18 pp.

"Dr. Pitzer Looks at the '70's"  from Alumni Almanac, 1970.  1 page.

"The Spirit of '70, Six Historians Reflect on What Ails the American Spirit" from Newsweek, July, 1970.  16-page excerpt including the following articles:  
"The Age of Rubbish" by Richard Hofstadter.  
"We Will Meet As Enemies" by Andrew Hacker.  
"A Massive Breakdown" by Eugene D. Genovese.  
"A Case of Hypochondria" by Daniel J. Boorstin.  
"Again - Don't Tread on Me" by Staughton Lynd.  
"The Velocity of History" by Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr. 

Time magazine excerpt, October, 1970 - "Investigation, Kent State: Another View".  1 page.

Time magazine, November, 1970 - "Man in the Middle"  1 page.

Colorado College magazine excerpt, 1970.  16 pp.  Included:
"A New Kind of Calendar for a Block Course Plan".  

"The Colorado College Plan:  An Academic Program Changes, But a Commitment Does Not" by Barbara M. Arnest.  

"'Scientia et Disciplina'':  The Motto as Background for the New Course Plan" from a memorandum by Glenn E. Brooks.  

"To Decide, Introspection, discussion, and lesser decisions, then faculty endorsement of an academic change."  

"The Student In An Age of Unrest" by N. Edd Miller, President, University of Nevada.  4 page excerpt from "New York State Bar Journal", February, 1971. 

"The Squaring of America"  4 page interview with Herman Kahn.

"The Recovery of Civility, Notes for the Long Trek Back" by Ferdinand Mount.  Reprint of July 1973 "Encounter".   8 pp.

"New Threats to Academic Freedom" by John H. Bunzel.  4 pp.

Higher Education and National Affairs excerpt, Vol. XVIII, No. 24.  "Nine Presidents List 'Practical Lessons' Of Campus Disruption".  2 pp.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d490ab880f9a24a32fd9d405f4860358" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Campus Unrest - Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970/1974">1970 - 1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Campus Unrest - Newspaper clippings    

The National Observer, May, 1970, "On Campus: A 'Malaise' or a 'Deterioration in Values'?"  Excerpts from speeches by Vice President Spiro Agnew and Kingman Brewster, Jr., Presdient of Yale University.  1 page.

The National Observer, May, 1970, "Attacking Crisis Rhetoric, A Minority Report on the Woes of the Cities" by James Meahger.

"How to Prevent the Destruction of the University", address by Leland C. Marsh, May 1970.
  
"Much Talk But Little Action on Campus Reform" by Fred M. Hechinger, August 1970, New York Times article.

"Blazers and Slacks: New Police Image" by Martin Arnold, New York Times article, August, 1970.   2 pp.

New York Times article, 1970, "Brewster Explains Campus Unrest" by Peter Kihss.

Palladium TImes article, September, 1972, "Need Some New Values, He Says".

Los Angeles Times article by Robert J. Dolan, "Social Struggle in U.S. Pits Middle Class Against Upper Middle Class, Says Author."  

National Observer article, July, 1973, "Sifting Revolution's Ashes for Salvage" by Fred Hechinger.

New York Times, April, 1974, "The Mood on Campus" by Leslie Epstein.

"Winds of change hit academic world" by Dr. Benjamin Fine.

"Student Trustees a Small Minority" by William K. Stevens.

"Heyns is Leaving a Placid Campus" by Wallace Turner.

"Combat on the Campus" by Dr. Max Rafferty.

"Regents Asked to Keep Angela Davis".

"U.C. Prof. Raps Angela Ouster".

"Governor Urges Link to Students" by Bill Kovach.  New York Times article.

"Many Are Schooled, But Few Are Educated" by Russell Kirk.  

"Youth's Faith . . ."

"Hitch Warns U.C. Faculty To Change" by Larry Spears.

"Campus Violence Decried by Bundy, Ex-Harvard Dean Assays Future of Universities" by M. A. Farber.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_0679ca5cbf25e01442ded4d7afeaf962" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Student Unrest-newspaper clippings </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1969/1970">1969 - 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="">3-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Student Unrest-newspaper clippings    

Newspaper clippings pertaining to student unrest include:

"Radicals Cause Concern" reprint from 'The Breeze', Madison College newspaper, 1969.

New York Times, June, 1969, "Gardner Decries College Violence".

"Evans Lauds Parents at Graduation". 2 pp.

"College Students Are Unbelievably Innocent" by John Roche, National Observer, January, 1970.

"The Ideal Of the University" by Robert Paul Wolff book review by Peter Brooks.  The New York Times Book Review, January 1970.

"Student Participation" by Ursula Von Eckardt, January, 1970.

"USC Takes Giant Strides Under Topping" by William Trombley.  Reprinted from Los Angeles Times, April, 1970.  5 pp.

"A Student's Plea: Don't Let Radicals Win by Default" by Steven Kelman, The National Observer, April, 1970.

"College Urged to Develop Better Links to Students" by David E. Rosenbaum, April 1970, The New York Times.

"On Moderation", Palladium Times, May, 1970.

"It's Time To Stop Apologizing To Youth" by Dr. K. Ross Toole, copy of May 1970, St. Louis Globe Democrat article.

"Proffesor says adults must grab the reins" by Dr. K. Ross Toole, Post Standard, May, 1970.

"U.C. Grads Like New Rites" by Larry Spears, Oakland Tribune, June, 1970.

"32 States Fight Campus Unrest", New York Times, June, 1970.

"Middle American: The Country's New Hero?" by James Meagher, The National Observer, January, 1970.

"Indictment of Universities Examined" by John E. Corbally, Jr.

"Universities: For Campus Freedoms", November, 1970.

"Defenders of Campus Freedom", November, 1970.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_751e53f645a9a8af9626ae716fd8f489" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Student Unrest - Kent State  </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970">1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Student Unrest - Kent State      

Newspaper articles, journal article and Kent State magazine are included.

"Kent State Students Protest Grand Jury Charges".

"Death on the Campus", The Des Moines Register, May, 1970.

"Some Kind of Insanity", Chicago Daily News, May, 1970.

"Kent and Its College: The Chasm Widens" by Richard T. Cooper, reprint from the Los Angeles Times, June, 1970.   2 pp.

"Kent" magazine.  June 1970.  28 pp.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_47ec5f7b03a5aba26678ca067311d393" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>SUNY Oswego newspaper clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1967/1970">1967 - 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-5</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>SUNY Oswego newspaper clippings 

Newspaper clippings are dated 1967 - 1970 &amp; n.d.  

"SUCO President and Statesingers Coming Here for Special Program Saturday", Oswego Valley News, February, 1967.  2 copies with 2 postcards of the First Methodist Church of Fulton attached.

"The Harsh Options in Quelling Riots", The Palladium-Times, May, 1970.  

Letter to the Editor, The Palladium Times, May, 1970 from Vivian R. Pyke.

"Letter to the Editor from Lawrence Ulstein. n.d.

Statement from George E. Pitluga, Professor of Astronomy.

"Committee To Promote Better Climate Urged". n.d.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_32aef649bb7f59e3918047bd52c8b73a" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>SUNY Fredonia newspaper clippings </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970">1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>SUNY Fredonia newspaper clippings    

Three newspaper clippings pertain to SUNY Fredonia.

"Group Of Fredonia SUNY Students Presents Demands" by Philip J. McGan.  Evening Observer, March, 1970.

"College Council Approves Three Motions On Social Regulations", n.d.

"Orderly Sit-in; Teacher Claims He's Out, College Class Conducted In Hallway Outside Of President Lanford's Office" by Philip J. McGan, n.d.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e6fd10a8d17d0c00688f815816e9e4a7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>SUNY Buffalo-newspapers &amp; clippings </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1969/1970">1969 - 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>SUNY Buffalo-newspapers &amp; clippings   

Two complete issues and one excerpt of UB Alumni News, 1960 &amp; 1970 concerning student unrest.

Buffalo Evening News clippings: 

"UB Council Issues Positions Paper on Unrest: Vows Decisive Action to Keep Campus Peace".  

"Bennis Quits UB Post; Student-Faculty Sessions Oppose Police Presence"
"Bennis Letter Claims 3 Administration Errors"

"Judge Tells UB To Show Cause In Suspensions"

"Fredonia State Rejects Bid For More Student Power" by Agnes Palazzetti, March, 1970.

"State U Body To Air UB Crisis", Courier Express, March, 1970.  This section of the newspaper includes numerous articles under the aforementioned banner.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_4ab7cbe6389be9c938c9eae670bddde1" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Stanford University newspapers &amp; clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970">1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-8</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Three issues of The Stanford Observer are included, December 1969, May 1970 &amp; June 1970, published by Stanford University, Stanford, California, concerning student unrest, etc.

Stanford Observer excerpt, June, 1970, letter from A. L. Inderbitzen with a response from Stanford President K. S. Pitzer.

Tribune Editorial Page, June 1970 article, "Stanford's Pitzer Resigns".

"Pitzer Quits As President Of Stanford, Blames War, Disruptions in Decision", n.d.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3cb4da749cc39c11a4b57dc44516df9a" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Reports  </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970-04/1970-06">April, 1970 - June, 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-9</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Reports include:

President's Committee on the Nature and Basic Characteristics of the University.  
April 28, 1970.  Interim Report.  3 typed pp.  2 copies.

The President's Committee on Undergraduate Education.  An Interim Report, June, 1970.  
7 typed pp.  Includes:
The study included seven sub-committees with specific focus:
     Expanding educational opportunity
     Interdepartmental opportunities
     Research
     The curriculum
     The Bachelor of General Studies degree
     The Bachelor of Arts degree
     The Bachelor of Science degree
Sections of report --
Rocommendations
The Freshman Year
The Sophomore and Junior Years
The Senior Year
     Submitted and signed, John W. Walcott, Recorder.  June 17, 1970.

Graduate Committee Minutes.  April 23, 1970.  re:  The Study of Education at Oswego.  1 page.
Graduate Committee Minutes.  June 4, 1970.  re:  The Study of Education at Oswego (SOE)
Graduate Committee Commentary.  June 5, 1970.  re:  The Study of Education at Oswego.

Memo from Lou DeRitter, For the Committee on Instructional Programs
to:  Dr. Paul Briand, Editor, President's Study of Education at Oswego
re:  1970 Interim Report.  2 pp.  photocopy.

Memo to Steering Committee; Study on Education Committee
Subject:  Preliminary Report, The President's Committee on Overseas Campuses.
April 28, 1970.  Signed Robert Steinen, Committee Member.  2 pp.  photocopy.

May Report of the Admissions and Financial Aids Committee.  6 typed pp.

The President's Committee on Counseling, Academic Advisement and Placement (CAP) memo.  April 28, 1970.  2 typed pp.  photocopy.

Students and the Extra-Curriculum by Sally J. Rist.  5 typed pp.  copy.

Table of Contents page to "Women's Education Committee:  Interim Report".  Includes:
Introduction
     General Philosophy of Committee
     Function
Status of Women Faculty
     Comments Concerning the Student Questionnaires
     Ratio of Women to Men on Staff at Different Ranks
     Sex Ratio on Academic Faculty
     Analysis of Staff Members by Sex
     Observations Concerning Current Status of Women Faculyt by Division and Department
     Women in Administration
Status of Women Students
     Admissions Policy
     Report from Infirmary
     Special Regulations
     Placement of Women Graduates
     The Earnings Gap
     Library Holdings Concerning Women
Tentative Recommendations
Annotated Bibliography
Plans for Fall
Submitted by Dorothy Rogers, Chairman.  Carl Davis, Joanne Fischetti, Barbara Gerber, Fran Janus, Patricia Peterson, Marilyn Smiley.

Interim Report of the Calendar Committee.  5 pp.  copy.

Provisional Weather Commentary to the College Physical Environmental Committee by Robert B. Sykes, Jr., Director, LOTEL.  Submitted 1 May 1970.  18 typed pp.  Copy is a little faded, portions can be hard to read.  

Report on Pollution Subcommittee of President's Committee on the Campus Environment.  6-page report plus 3 memos.  copies.  Subcommittee members:  Rose Fehr, American Studies Major, Senior; John Judd, LOTEL; George Maxwell, Biology; Paul Moskowitz, Biology Major, Junior; Paula Stobnicke, Biology Major, Senior.

Student Report on Library Evaluation.  1 page.  copy.

Memo.  From:  President's Library Committee
To:  Steering Committee
re:  Preliminary Report of Activities.  May 1, 1970.  2 typed pp.  Copy is faded, difficult to read.

Memo to Dr. Paul Briand
From:  Robert Canfield
April 27, 1970
re:  Progress Report, Committee on Scholarly Activities (formerly the Research Committee); Study of Education.  1 typed page.

President's Committee, Faculty and Other Teaching Personnel Preliminary Report.  
May 4, 1970.  2 typed pp., faded text.

Teaching Activity 2-page typed report.  Copy is faded.  Attached is article, "Statement on Faculty Workload".  Excerpt from AAUW Bulletin.  n.d.  3-page copy is very faded, difficult to read.

Report of Committee XVI:  Administrative Structure of the University.  May 1, 1970.  2-page typed report.  Warren E. Steinkraus, Chairman.  David Pelland, Secretary.

Study of Eduation at Oswego.  May 1970.  Memo
to:  Dr. J.S. Dunham
from:  H. Garber, Chairman
re:  Tentative recommendations of committee on Institutionalizing Educational Review and Innovation, Committee #17.  3 typed pp.

Interim Report of the Committee on Community Affairs, Study of Education, State University College at Oswego.  4 typed pp.  Submitted by Louis W. Herborg, Chairman.

Preliminary report of the President's Committee on Black Studies.  May 1, 1970.  2 typed pp.  Respectfully submitted by David J. Winslow, chairman.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_bd1d80c1af12c99423e0c9e35584ba90" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Transcripts of Faculty Discussion Groups</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970-04-15/1970-06-15">April 15, 1970 - June 15, 1970</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Transcripts of Faculty Discussion Groups
Includes:

Minutes of Discussion Group I, Faculty Meeting, June 4, 1970.  2 typed pp.  copy. 

Minutes of Discussion Group II (Room 102L, June 3, 1970)
Moderator:  Professor L. Koenigsberg
Recorder:  Mr. Henry B. Angle
3 typed pp.  copy.

Report of Discussion Group III.  4 typed pp.  copy. 

Report of Discussion Group IV.  June 15, 1970.  4 pp.  copy. 

Memo.  to:  The Conference Committee
from:  Thomas R. Jensen, Moderator of Group VI.
June 8, 1970.  3 typed pp.  copy. 

Report of Discussion Group VII
Moderator:  H. Nash
Recorder:  R. Hubbard
June 15, 1970.  4 typed pp.  copy. 

Memo.  June 5, 1970
to:  Dean Wheeler and Members of Group VIII
from:  Fred Fischer, Moderator.  Phil Downum, Recorder
re:  Report of the June 3rd Meeting of Group VIII in 102a Lanigan
3 typed pp.  copy.

Report of Discussion Group IX
June 3, 1970.  2 typed pp.  copy.

Report of Discussion Group X
June 8, 1970.  1 typed page.  copy.  
James Soluri, Chairman
Donald R. Mathieu, Recorder.

Report of Discussion Group XI
June 3, 1970.  2 typed pp.  copy.

Group XI Discussion Group.  1 page.  3 questions.  n.d.

Report of Subcommittee IV on Minorities of the President's Summer Conference Committee.       5 typed pp.  n.d.  

Report of Sub-Committee IV on Minorities of the President's Summer Conference Committee.     6 typed pp., carbon copy.  William B. George, Chairman.  Judy Paratore, Sally Rist.

Report of Sub-Committee IV on Minorities of the President's Summer Conference Committee.
6 typed pp.  copy.  William B. George, Chairman.  Judy Paratore, Sally Rist.

Correspondence to Mr. James E. Perdue from William R. Valentine, Regional Director, Office for Civil Rights, Department of Health, Education and Welfare, New York, New York.  3 pp., copy
April 15, 1970.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d762949aa43c99687976d9037ca29952" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Reports</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1970/1977">1970 - 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-11</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Reports.  Includes:

Abstract:  Group V for June 3, 1970 - Discussion
Pitluga, Chairman.
June 16, 1970.  6 typed pp.  

Results of Faculty Opinionnaire re the Strike
July 6, 1970.  3 typed pp.  copy

The Conference Committee.  Handwritten note - July 8, 1970.  3 typed pp.  copy.

The College Community.  August 5, 1970.  Signed James E. Perdue, President.  2 typed pp.

Sub-Committee on the College Community and Political Action.  Report to President's Conference Committee.  August 5, 1970.  7 typed pp.

Memorandum.  
to:  President James Perdue and the Summer Conference Committee
from:  Joe Orcutt
August 5, 1970
Subject:  Necessity for legitimizing student voices
2 typed pp.

Summer Conference Committee
Subcommittee on Communication -- Interim Report -- August 12, 1970
Subcommittee Members:  Joseph Hecht, Richard Hyse, Roger McLaughlin, Linda Syrell, Paul Wagner.  5 typed pp. with two attachments.

Memo
to:  Members of the Conference Committee
from:  H. Van Schaack
re:  Proposed Statement on Drugs
August 14, 1970.  1 typed page

Minutes, Sub-Committee on the College Community and Political Action.  July 12, 1970
Present:  Joe Orcutt, Peter Hertz, Fred Bartle
Absent:  George Pitluga.  3 typed pp.  copy

August 21, 1970
Memo:  Conference Committee
From:  Fred Bartle
Subject:  Additional Comments to Report of Sub-Committee on the College Community and Political Action.  3 typed pp.  copy

Why is Oswego?  College and Community, Character and Commitment..  A Self-Study of Education at Oswego College of Arts and Sciences, State University of New York.  Edited by Paul L. Briand, Jr.  Progress Report.  August 4, 1970.  38 typed pp.  copy.

Whys is Oswego?  College and Community, Character and Commitment.  A Self-Study of Education at Oswego College of Arts and Science, State University of New York.  
Edited by Paul L. Briand, Jr.  Progress Report.  September 1970.  Newspaper version.  8 pp.

Freedom and Responsibility on Campus.  48 typed pp.  copy

Freedom and Responsibility on Campus.  Final Report of the Summer Conference Committee.  Edited by Paul L. Briand, Jr.  Autumn 1970
72-page published version.  

Minority Groups Visited.  High Schools Visted by Mr. Brown, 1969-1970 and Mr. Powell, Spring of 1969.  2 typed pp.  copy

Procedures as Adopted to be Employed by the Natural and Mathematical Sciences Division Promotion and Merit Committee (1975).  2 typed pp.  copy.

Final Report of the Division of Professional Studies Reorganization and Planning Committee.  May 26, 1977.  31 pp. </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_5dce8552a9355f78db77b68988ef26b8" level="item">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Framed portrait </unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					</did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Framed portrait of Dr. James Perdue.  
Gold frame 21" x 17".  Linen matt with gold trim.  Linen is soiled.
Black &amp; white photograph.  14" x 10.5"
View of campus behind Dr. Perdue.  

The framed portrait was transferred to the college archives from University Development after being removed from Sheldon Hall.  </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>