<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0005</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Skinner Family Papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-05-01">May 1, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Kathryn Johns-Masten.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>The Skinner Family Papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1815/1876" type="inclusive">1815 - 1876</unitdate>
							<abstract>Personal papers of the Skinner Family. Includes correspondence reflecting the events and activities which affected the lives of early pioneer families in Central New York.  </abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                
            <famname>Skinner Family</famname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitid>2009.076.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>This collection is open to the public with restrictions, as some items are fragile and are damaged.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>The Skinner family consisted by Timothy Skinner (1761-1843), Ruth Warner Skinner, his wife (1770-1849), and their nine children – Warren, Cynthia, Alanson, Avery, Hiram, Dolphus, Barton, John, and Albert.  Growing up in Westmoreland, New Hampshire, the Skinner children, like so many other young men and women in the early nineteenth century, moved west from their parental home to settle across upstate New York and Ohio.  At least three of them (Warren, Dolphus, and Barton) became ministers, and one (Albert) became a doctor.  Others became teachers, farmers, or businessmen. 	</p>
						<p>Letters in this collection center principally around three of the children – Cynthia, Avery, and Hiram – who settled in Union Square (now Maple View), Oswego County, New York.  Letters from Avery’s wife, Charlotte, also form an important part of the collection. </p>
            <p>Cynthia Skinner, the second oldest of the siblings, migrated to Brownville, Jefferson Co., New York in 1824.  After her marriage to Hiram Walker in February 1829, she settled with him on his farm in Union Square, New York.	</p>
            <p>Avery Skinner (1796-1876), the fourth child in the family, became one of its best known members.  Operating a tavern in Union Square, at the junction of the busy Rome-Oswego and Syracuse-Watertown trade routes, he was well-known not only for his business activities but also for his Universalist religious beliefs and his Democratic politics.	</p>
            <p>As a young man Avery attended the Chesterfield (New Hampshire?) Academy, teaching in winters to pay his expenses.  He migrated to Watertown in 1816 where he remained for six years  as a teacher.  In 1823 he relocated in Union Square, where he not only names the village but built the first tavern, set up a mail route and became the first postmaster, an office he held until his death.  In addition to his other business activities he helped develop plank roads in the 1840s, was a member of the first Board of Trustees of the Rensselaer-Oswego Academy in Mexicoville, and was a promoter and director of the Syracuse Northern Railroad.	</p>
            <p>Building on his local prestige, Skinner became a prominent Democratic politician in Oswego County, holding various county and state offices from 1826 through the mid-1840s.  On the county level he served as county treasurer from 1826 to 1838 and as an appointed judge of the Court of Common Pleas from 1828-1839.  On the state level, he was elected a member of the assembly in 1831 and 1832 and later (1838-1844) served as state senator.  In 1846 he ran for Congress but was defeated by William Duer.</p>
            <p>He married twice.  His first wife, Eliza Huntington (1804-1833) died shortly after the birth of her fifth child.  In 1934 Skinner married Charlotte P. Stebbins (1802-1888), a long-time friend of the family.  He had several children – Lucretia, Timothy, Solomon, Avery, Eliza, James, Charlotte, Albert, Charles and Mary Grace.  Some of these died in childhood but others went on to become prominent citizens in their own right.  Timothy, for example, became a lawyer in Mexicoville, and Charles became Superintendent of Schools in New York State.  Avery Skinner dies in Union Square on November 24, 1876.	</p>
            <p>Hiram Skinner (1801-1831) was the fifth child of Timothy and Ruth.  He moved to Union Square in 1825, where he began business as a storekeeper.  He failed in business as a result of extending long-term credit to his customers.  He later sustained injuries after a bad fall and became virtually a ward of his wealthier brother, Avery.  He married his wife, Noralla, in 1831.</p>
        </bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            
        <subject authfilenumber="sh99001596" source="lcsh">Anti-Masonic movements</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85141081" source="lsch">universalist</subject>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5143396" source="geonames">Watertown (N.Y.)</geogname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="7275439" source="geonames">Union Square (N.Y.)</geogname>
        <geogname authfilenumber="5094550" source="geonames">Westmoreland (N.H.)</geogname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85047009" source="lcsh">Families.</subject>
            <persname>Hutchins, Wellington</persname>
            <persname>Sabin, Claire</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Alonson</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Avery</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Barton</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Charles R.</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Charlotte</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Cynthia</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Hiram</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, John</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Mary Grace</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Ruth</persname>
            <persname>Skinner, Timothy</persname>
            <persname>Walker, Cynthia Skinner</persname>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>Personal letters makes up the bulk of the Skinner family papers.  Most of these letters were written by Cynthia Skinner Walker, Hiram Skinner, and Avery Skinner to their parents in Westmoreland, New Hampshire.  Some of the correspondence is also between Avery and his second wife, Charlotte Stebbins Skinner, while Avery was in New York State Legislature in Albany.  Most of this material dates between 1815, when Avery moved to Watertown from his parental home, and 1844, when he returned to Union Square from his last term in the state legislature.  There is also some material relating to two of Avery’s children (Charles and Mary Grace), some genealogical information on the Skinner family, Avery Skinner’s will, and some clippings and photographs.	</p>
						<p>The collection is particularly valuable for the information it contains on family relationships.  Avery, Hiram, and Cynthia’s letters to their parents reflect fond remembrances of the happy home life they enjoyed as children.  And correspondence between Avery and Charlotte provides interesting insights into their marital and family life.  The collection also illustrates the problems experienced—particularly by Avery and Hiram—in establishing oneself in the world.  Finally, the letters contain material on the religious attitudes of the Skinner family (most of whom were Universalists), a few references to Anti-Masonry, and some information on life in Watertown and Union Square.</p>
        </scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="7449d9_Container_List_Skinner_Family_MS004.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    
    <dsc>
            <c id="c_537dd1e1e5f094a3b796f2b0e6b35052" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1815/1826">1815 - 1826</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-02</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>001 - Letter dated December 2, 1815, from Avery Skinner boarding at Mr. Stebbins in Hinsdale to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  (Mentions to send regards to his sister Cynthia.)  3 pages.

002 - Letter dated June 8, 1817, from Avery Skinner in Watertown to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  (Mentions that he had received a letter from Cynthia.)  4 pages.

003 - Letter dated March 2, 1818, from Avery Skinner in Watertown to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  1 page.

004 - Letter dated February 12, 1819 from A?? in Watertown to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

005 - Letter dated June 10, 1821 from Alonson Skinner in Watertown to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH. Letter from Avery Skinner to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH, (Mentions Cynthia).  4 pages.

006 - Letter dated September 17, 1821 from Avery Skinner in Watertown to his mother Ruth Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

007 - Letter dated May 4, 1822 from A. Skinner in Watertown to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

008 - Letter from A. Skinner to John Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  2 pages.

009 - Letter dated August 17, 1823 from Avery Skinner in Mexico, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH,  (Writes that he is building his house and mentions Cynthia).  4 pages.

010 - Letter dated March 29, 1824 from Avery Skinner in Union Square, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  (Mentions Cynthia)  4 pages.

011 - Letter dated August 8, 1824 from Claire Sabin to Miss Charlotte Stebbins in Mexico, NY.  4 pages.

012 - Letter dated November 27, 1824 from Avery Skinner in Union Square, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  (Mentions Cynthia in Brownville and that she may visit him).
4 pages.

013 - Letter dated April 25, 1825 from Cynthia Skinner in Mexico, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from Avery.  4 pages.

014 - Letter dated October 30, 1826 from A. Skinner in Union Square, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

015 - Letter dated December 3, 1826 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square, NY to Timothy and Ruth Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from Avery.  4 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        <c id="c_17ea4e1040b3e2b6ff5e09294ed3e242" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1827/1833">1827 - 1833</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-03</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>016 - Letter dated September 4, 1827 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square to Timothy and Ruth Skinner in Westmoreland, NH. (Mentions that he write to Cynthia soon)  Second part of letter is from Avery Skinner.  (Mentions that he will write to Cynthia and invites her to visit in the fall)  4 pages.

017 - Letter dated February 20, 1829 from Cynthia Skinner Walker in Union Square to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter, written over a page of Cynthia's, is from Hiram Walker.  Avery Skinner writes a short note.  4 pages.

018 - Letter dated April 26, 1829 from Cynthia S. Walker in Union Square to Miss Charlotte Stebbins in Watertown, NY.  3 pages.

019 - Letter dated October 25, 1829 from Hiram Walker in Union Square to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from Cynthia.  Third part of letter is from Avery.  4 pages.

020 - Letter dated December 20, 1829 from Cynthia S. Walker in Union Square to Charlotte Stebbins in Watertown, NY.  4 pages.

021 - Letter dated March 13, 1831 from Hiram Skinner to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  (Mentions Cynthia)  Second part of letter is from Avery to his parents.  Third part of letter is from Avery to Cynthia.  4 pages.

022 - Letter dated February 5, 1832 from Avery Skinner in Albany to Timothy in Westmoreland, NH.  Letter dated February 8, 1832 from Avery in Union Square to Timothy Skinner.  6 pages.

023 - Letter dated June 22, 1832 from Avery Skinner in Albany, NY to Barton Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  3 pages.

024 - Letter dated June 16, 1833 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  3 pages.

025 - Letter dated November 24, 1833 from Avery Skinner in Albany, NY to Charlotte Stebbins.  6 pages.

026 - Letter dated December 31, 1833 from Avery Skinner in Albany, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  3 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_a38414c85154c39db24a8067bb382a63" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1834/1837">1834 - 1837</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-04</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                <p>027 - Letter dated March 2, 1834 from Cynthia S. Walker in Union Square to Charlotte Stebbins.  Second part of letter is from Avery Skinner to Charlotte Stebbins.  4 pages.

028 - Letter dated March 17, 1834 from Avery Skinner in Union Square to Charlotte Stebbins.  3 pages.

029 - Letter dated March 22, 1834 from Avery Skinner in Union Square to Charlotte Stebbins in Watertown, NY.  3 pages.

030 - Letter dated August 3, 1834 from Avery Skinner in Union Square to Charlotte Stebbins.  4 pages.

031 - Letter dated August 10, 1834 from Charlotte Stebbins in Pamelia, NY to Avery Skinner in Union Square, NY.  4 pages.

032 - Letter dated August 24, 1834 from Avery Skinner in Union Square to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

033 - Letter dated September 22, 1834 from Rufus Stebbins in Watertown, NY to Mrs. Charlotte Skinner.  2 pages.

034 - Letter dated January 25, 1835 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

035 - Letter dated March 15, 1835 from Cynthia in Union Square to Barton Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from H. Walker to Barton Skinner.  Third part of letter from Avery Skinner to Barton Skinner dated March 18, 1835.  4 pages.

036 - Letter dated February 24, 1836 from Avery Skinner to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from Hiram Skinner to his parents.  Third part of letter is from Cynthia Skinner Walker to her parents.  4 pages.

037 - Letter dated June 11, 1837 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from Avery Skinner to his parents.  6 pages.

038 - Letter dated October 29, 1837 from Cynthia Walker in Union Square to Timothy and Ruth Skinner.  Second part of letter is from Hiram Walker to Barton Skinner.  2 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        <c id="c_6142b5895ca682f1e655915259a0f1cd" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1838/1839">1838 - 1839</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-05</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>039 - Letter dated January 11, 1838 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner.  3 pages.

040 - Letter dated January 21, 1838 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner.  3 pages.

041 - Letter dated March 11, 1838 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner.
3 pages.

042 - Letter dated March 28 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner.  
3 pages.

043 - Letter dated June 10, 1838 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner.
3 pages.

044 - Letter dated June 13, 1838 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner in New York, NY.  2 pages.

045 - Letter dated June 24, 1838 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner.
3 pages.

046 - Letter dated July 13, 1838 from Avery Skinner in New York, NY to Timothy Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

047 - Letter dated November 14, 1838 from Avery Skinner in Albany, NY to Timothy Skinner.
4 pages.

048 - Letter dated November 14, 1838 from Avery Skinner in Albany, NY to Charlotte Skinner.  4 pages.

049 - Letter dated November 19, 1838 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square to his parents.  Second part of letter is from Hiram Skinner to Barton Skinner.  4 pages.

050 - Letter dated February 10, 1839 from Avery Skinner in Albany, NY to Barton Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  3 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e089f3b5e000fa6a9c517923cfd40e7c" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1840/1844">1840 - 1844</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-06</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>051 - Letter dated June 9, 1840 from Avery Skinner at City Hall, New York, NY to his wife Charlotte Skinner.  4 pages.

052 - Letter dated November 15, 1840 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner in Albany, NY.  3 pages.

053 - Letter dated January 30, 1841 from Charlotte Skinner in Union Square to Avery Skinner in Albany, NY.  2 pages.

054 - Letter dated March 17, 1841 from Avery Skinner in Albany to Charlotte Skinner.  
4 pages.

055 - Letter dated March 26, 1841 from Avery Skinner in Albany to Charlotte Skinner in Watertown, N.Y.  4 pages.

056 - Letter dated May 1, 1841 from Avery Skinner in Albany to Charlotte Skinner.  4 pages.

057 - Letter dated May 26, 1841 from Avery Skinner in Albany to his brother B. Skinner.  
3 pages.

058 - Letter dated October 12, 1841 from Avery Skinner in Albany to his brother Barton Skinner.  3 pages.

059 - Letter dated January 15, 1843 from Hiram Skinner in Union Square to his brother Barton Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  Second part of letter is from Avery to Barton.  
4 pages.

060 - Letter dated July 30, 1843 from Cynthia S. Walker in Union Square to her mother expressing her sympathy on the death of her father.  Second part of letter is from Cynthia to her brothers and sisters.  Third part of letter is from Avery to his mother.  4 pages.

061 - Letter dated August 6, 1843 from Avery Skinner in Union Square to Barton Skinner in Westmoreland, NH.  4 pages.

062 - Letter dated August 15, 1844 from Avery Skinner in Union Square to his brother B. Skinner.  2 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_68bb725cc5e45fc369748a7f0d8c666b" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence  </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1871">1871</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-07</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>063 - Letter dated April 11, 1871, from Charlie in Watertown, NY, to his mother.  4 pages.

064 - Letter dated May 14, 1871, from Mary Grace to her mother.  5 pages.
(Avery Skinner's Children)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_b7d38518f4a2eba38a34d35d123993bb" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Writings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1857/1860">1857 - 1860</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-08</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>065 - A trip to Saratoga by Mary G. Skinner, undated.  4 pages.

066 - "The Literary Star" by Charles R. Skinner, January 1857.  8 pages.

067 - "The Literary Star" by Charles R. Skinner, February 1857.  8 pages.

068 - "The Literary Star" by Charles R. Skinner, March 1857.  8 pages.

069 - "The Literary Star" by Charles R. Skinner, May 1857.  8 pages.

070 - "The Scholars Evening Banner" by Mary G. Skinner and Wellington Hutchins, undated.  32 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_f1e5ac4db0c0f84a20b63f0b49c4d293" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Legal Document - Will   </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1861">1861</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-09</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Avery Skinner's will of 1861.  3 pages.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            
            <c id="c_b70b8a3a7a3618a45384f3b3f735f1d1" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings     </unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>072 - Article on old tavern at Union Square.  Undated.  Not cited.

073 - Obituary of Avery Skinner.  Undated.  Not cited.

074 - Obituary of Avery Skinner.  Undated.  Not cited.

075 - Obituary of Avery Skinner.  Undated.  Not cited.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>