<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0004</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Virginia Radley Papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-04-28">April 28, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Zachary Vickery.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>Virginia Radley Papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1973/1997" type="inclusive">1973 - 1997</unitdate>
							<abstract>Professional collection of  Dr. Virginia Radley, the eighth president of SUNY Oswego. Dr. Radley, the first woman president of a state-operated campus in the SUNY system, led the way to bolstering Oswego’s strong commitment to academic quality. She shepherded the establishment of the college’s Honors Program, Quest day of scholarly and creative activity and other endeavors that continue to provide depth and diversity to the Oswego experience.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>2.33 linear feet</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2003028456">Radley, Virginia L.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitid>1999.007.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>Collection is open to the public</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Dr. Virginia Radley was the eighth president of SUNY Oswego from 1978 to 1988. She came to Oswego in 1974 as provost and executive vice president. Radley became acting president for two months in 1976 and was inaugurated  president on October 7, 1978. Virginia Radley was the first woman president in SUNY. During her term as president she increased the enrollment of minorities at SUNY Oswego and supported affirmative action in recruiting and promoting faculty and staff. Academic excellence was stressed, and she revised a general education program and developed the honors program in Liberal Studies. She also worked for women's rights and better academic advising.  Sheldon Hall was placed on the register of historic landmarks during her administration. She resigned in 1988 to teach English.</p>
            <p>Dr. Radley was Chairman of the English Department at Russell Sage College, Troy, New York in 1966.  She received a B.A. from Russell Sage College, an M.A. from the University of Rochester and an M.S. and Ph.D. from Syracuse University.</p>
            <p>She taught at Goucher College and lectured at Syracuse University and Nazareth College.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79056448">Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5130081" source="geonames">Oswego (N.Y.)</geogname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80047758">Krupsak, Mary Anne</persname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2010005107">Eggers, Melvin A.</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n81052939">Ferraro, Geraldine</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n86031758">Ludwig, Coy L., 1939-</persname>
            
        <subject authfilenumber="sh85028315" source="lcsh">College presidents</subject>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>Contains Radley's correspondence starting from 1973 and ending in 1993.  Contains newspaper clippings and other published material about Radley from the 1970's to the 1990's. There are copies of her speeches from 1974 to 1975. Contains copies of her published work, information about her inauguration and information about her resignation. Also includes a  plaque presented to Dr. Radley.</p>
						<arrangement>
                <p>Chronologically and by type of record.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <p>The Virginia Radley Papers were largely together and arranged prior to the added work done in 1999. In March 1999, the scattered fragments of Radley's Papers which had been filed elsewhere were gathered together and added to the existing arrangement to make one intact collection. New sources of information by or about Virginia Radley were also interfiled with the already processed Radley papers in the possession of Special Collections. Most of these were from Lynn Ekfelt at St. Lawrence University, but one folder apparently was sent by Dr. Radley to Nancy Osborne in 1994. Some clippings from other collections were also rounded up and added.

The series of appointment books was received by Special Collections' Coordinator Nancy Osborne from Dr. Natalie Woodall.  

Addition papers were added in 2006.  Papers were gathered from throughout Special Collections, additional newspaper clippings were added and photographs were scanned into this record.</p>
        </scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_2a10dfc754586e7a1845fee7a3cd1f6e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1973/1974">1973 - 1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-01</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Letters from the office of Dr. Virginia L. Radley.  Correspondents include:

Dr. Robert McFarland, Assistant Dean of Graduate Studies, SUNY Albany.

Elizabeth Luce Moore, Board of Trustees, State University of New York.

Richard C. Wheeler, Associate Dean for Academic Affairs, SUNY Oswego.

C. Peter Magrath, President, SUNY Binghamton.

Also includes schedule of activities for Dr. Radley, Provost of Undergraduate Education.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        <c id="c_a727c9283dddbf48f1d340f5d60e8962" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976/1977">1976 - 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Papers relating to invitations to Dr. Radley to submit her name for college president at a variety of colleges.  Correspondents include:

Charles M. Evans, Associate Provost, SUNY Albany.

Patti McGill Peterson to Dr. Walter E. Beach, Mount Vernon College, Presidential Search Committee, Washington, D.C.

Francis B. Nimick, Jr.,Chairman, Presidential Search Committee, Chatham College,
Pittsburgh, PA.

David L. Powers, Presidential Search Committee, Colby-Sawyer College, New London, New Hampshire.  

James F. Kelly, Acting Chancellor, SUNY, Albany, NY.  

Donna Shavlik, Associate Director, American Council on Education, Washington, D.C.

Jennie Farley, Assistant Professor, New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY.

Mary Anne Krupsak, Lieutenant Governor, State of New York, Albany.

Mrs. Maurice T. (Beth) Moore, SUNY, Albany, NY.

Sally C. Nevius, Board of Trustees, Mount Vernon College, Washington, D.C.

Henry Strong, Washington, D.C.

Bruce Dearing, Professor, Upstate Medical Center, Syracuse, NY.

Leyden E. Brown, Presidential Search Committee, SUNY Oswego.

Dorothy Rogers, Professor, SUNY Oswego.

(Formerly 1/9/194)
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_bd43befe8bf6c2552f14501f002a943c" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence- People off campus  </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Letters of congratulations and support.  Correspondents include:

Reatha Clark King, President, Metropolitan State University, Saint Paul, MN.

Coy L. Ludwig, Tyler Art Gallery Director, SUNY Oswego.

Lewis C. Popham, 3rd., Dean, Continuing Education &amp; Summer Sessions, SUNY Oswego.

John R. Zagame, Assemblyman, Albany, NY.

Memorandum from Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., to the Board of Trustees, State University of New, Albany, NY.  Re:  Appointment of Virginia L. Radley as President, College at Oswego.
Includes Dr. Radley's vitae.  

Melvin A. Eggers, Chancellor, Syracuse University.

James W. Hall, Empire State College, Saratoga Springs, NY.

Robert McLaughlin, President, Herkimer County Community College, Herkimer, NY.

Carol A. Hawkes, Vice President for Educational Affairs and Dean of the College, Hartwick College, Oneonta, NY.

Doris L. Eder, Dean of Faculty, Schenectady County Community College, Schenectady, NY.

Barbara Meinert, State Education Department, Albany, NY.

Alvin P. Lierheimer, Associate Commissioner for Higher Education, State Education Department, Albany, NY.

Dr. Cash Kowalski, Vice President for Academic Affairs, SUNY, Agricultural and Technical College, Morrisville, NY.  

William F. Kahl, President, Russell Sage College, Troy, NY.

James J. Parry, Labor Relations Coordinator, State University System of Florida.

Frank P. Piskor, President, St. Lawrence University, Canton, NY.

Nenah E. Fry, Dean, Wells College, Aurora, NY.

Carol George, Hobert &amp; William Smith Colleges,  Geneva, NY.

Richard C. Jones, President, SUNY Cortland.

Harriet F. Bradley, Vice Rector, George Mason University, Fairfax, VA.

John R. Haines, Director, State Education Department, Albany, NY.

Helen B. Power, Regent Emerita, Univerity of the State of New York, State Education Dept.

Sister Marie Augustine, Nazareth College.  

Richard C. Schmidt, M.D., President, Upstate Medical Center, Syracuse, NY.

Stuart Steiner, President, Genesee Community College,  Batavia, NY.

Barbara R. Frey, Vice President for Academic Affairs, SUNY Buffalo.

Charles B. Neff, Provost for Academic Programs, State University of N.Y., Albany.

William R. Porter, Vice President for Academic Affairs, SUNY Maritime College, Fort Schuyler, Bronx, NY.

Dallas K. Beal, President, SUNY Fredonia.

George Keller, Assistant to the Chancellor, Editor, Search, a Journal of Scholarly Research, Albany, NY.

Jane Graham, Assistant to the Executive Vice Chancellor, SUNY, Albany, NY.

Francis T. Farenthold, President, Wells College, Aurora, NY.

Dr. Edward N. Garno, Supervisor of Communications and Personnel, Hudson City School District, Hudson, NY.

W. Robert Holmes, Associate Director, Schenectady County Community College.

Priscilla J. Angelo, Associate Director of Student Services, St. Lawrence University, Canton, NY.

Carol Bollinger, Director, Board of Cooperative Educational Services, Johnstown, NY.

John S. Toll, President, SUNY StonyBrook.

Oscar Smukler, Acting President, Erie Community College, Buffalo, NY.

Richard C. Debus, Assistant Vice President for Administration, Empire State College.

Marcia B. Dugan, Director of Public Relations, Keuka College, Keuka Park, NY.

Charles M. Evans, Dean, College of Arts &amp; Sciences, University of Evansville, IN.

Arthur J. Dudley, Chief, SUNY State Education Department, Albany, NY.

Frederick M. Binder, President, Juniata College, Huntingdon, PA.

J. W. Peltason, American Council on Eduacation, Washington, D.C.

Walter E. Beach, Assistant Director, APSA, Washington, D.C.

Robert D. Larsson, President, Schenectady County Community College.

Robert A. Kidera, President, Nazareth College of Rochester, NY.

Peter D. Pelham, Vice President, Institute of International Education, Washington, D.C.

T. Edward Hollander, Chancellor, State of New Jersey Department of Higher Education.

Mauro S. Zulli, Acting President, State University, Agricultural and Technical College, Farmington, NY.

Elizabeth A. Brinkman, Associate Professor, Wittenberg University, Springfield, OH.

Lewis C. Popham, 3rd, President-Elect, Association for Continuing Higher Education.

Jacquelyn Anderson Mattfeld, President, Barnard College, Columbia University, NY.

Virginia Kemp, Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs, SUNY Geneseo.

Lawrence K. Pettit, Commissioner of Higher Education, The Montana University System, Helena, MT.

David L. Powers, Assistant to the President for Development, Colby-Sawyer College, New London, NH.

Eileen M. Kolynich, Director, Career Planning &amp; Placement, Fordham University.

D. Kenneth Baker, President, Harvey Mudd College, Claremont, CA.

William S. Fuller, Executive Director, Nebraska Coordinating Commission for Postsecondary Education, Lincoln, NE.

Harold Delaney, Associate Executive Director, American Association of State Colleges and Universities, Washington, D.C.

Dr. Mary Ann Biller, Dean, Empire State College, Lower Hudson Regional Learning Center at White Plains, NY.

Carl J. Schneider, Dean of Graduate Studies, Monclair State University, Upper Monclair, NJ.

Francis N. Hamblin, President, Lock Haven State College, Lock Haven, PA..

Carey W. Brush, Vice President for Academic Affairs, SUNY Oneonta.

Robert MacVittie, President, SUNY Geneseo.

Corinne C. Turner, Chairman of the Board of Trustees, Colby-Sawyer College, New London, NH.

Martha E. Church, President, Hood College, Frederick, MD.

Reatha Clark King, President, Metropolitan State University, Saint Paul, MN.

Barbara Wetheimer, Director, Institute for Education &amp; Research on Women and Work, Cornell University.

Barbara W. Newell, President, Wellesley College.

William W. Jellema, President, Wartburg College, Waverly, Iowa.

Alberta Arthurs, President, Chatham College, Pittsburgh, PA.

Harriet D. Hudson, Provost and Dean, St. Mary's College of Maryland.

Virginia L. Lester, President, Mary Baldwin College, Staunton, VA.

Edwin T. Carine, Jr., Director, Middle State Regional Office, The College Board, Bethlehem, PA.

John J. Connolly, President, Dutchess Community College, SUNY Poughkeepsie.

Leonard R. Kershaw, Assistant Director, State of New York Executive Department Office of Employee Relations, Albany, NY.

Richard D. Robbins, Associate Dean, The Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD.

Robert Kirkwood, Executive Director, Commission on Higher Education, Philadelphia, PA.

Stanley J. Drazek, Chancellor, University of Maryland, University College, College Park, MD.

Brunetta R. Wolfman, Academic Dean, Wheelock College, Boston, MA.

Joseph N. Hankin, President, Westchester Community College, Valhalla, NY.

Peter J. Cayan, President, North Country Community College, Saranac, NY.

Stephen L. Weber, Vice President for Academic Affairs, St. Cloud State University, St. Cloud, Minnesota.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_6be09c89f17a27b1ae91430a00e10590" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence- People on Campus</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Letters, memorandum and cards of congratulations and support.  
Correspondents include:

Fred Bartle, UUP Executive Committee.
Women's Health and Physical Education Department.
John Kares Smith, Associate Professor, Communication Studies.
Lois Jackim.
David M. H. Richmond.
John C. Fisher, Chairman, Faculty Assembly.
Financial Aids Office.
Lois Jean Coleman.
George H. Koenig.
Ellen Hemink.
Helen and Dave Glick.
Dick Pfund, Director, Learning Resources Center.
Mark H. Salter, Editor, "On The Case".
Nevart Boghasian, Elementary Education.
Jon Bartow.
Robert H. Peterson.
George Scheck.
Mandy Bratton, student.
Joan Huff.
Herb Garber.
Constance Finlay, Director, Waterbury Hall.
Marcia C. Moore.
Sandy Sternlicht.
Ted DiPasquale.
Ann Robson, Alumni Association.
Stephen Torok.
Bob Sykes.
Dr. Stephen Meisel, Chairman, Reading Education Department.
Coy L. Ludwig.
T. C. Eckersley, Associate Professor and Chairman, Department of Art.
Mary H. Glann.
Elizabeth hull, Political Science Department.
Johnson G. Cooper, Professor Emeritus.
Elearnor Filburn.
Dr. Arthur Sabatini, Acting Director of International Education.
Albert C. Leighton.
Lewis B. O'Donnell.
Martin J. Lindenmayer, President, Student Association.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_2a4fe47645f79edf3ab6c1a122d0ea40" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence- Local People</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="">1-5</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Letters of congratulations and support.  Correspondents include:

Warren P. Zoni, Zoni Bros. Furniture and Appliance.
Peter L. Dziedzic, Assistant Secretary, Columbia Banking Saving and Loan Association.
Cathy Richardson, Syracuse, NY.
Burton Ramer, District Supervisor, Oswego County Board of Cooperative Educational Services, Mexico, NY.
David W. Pelland, Menter, Rudin &amp; Trivelpiece, Syracuse, NY.
Gerald J. Ware, Assistant Banking Officer &amp; Manager, Marine Midland Bank, Oswego, NY.
Bruce H. Whitney, Vice President, Marine Midland Bank, Oswego, NY.
William J. Bower, Superintendent of Schools, Board of Education, Fulton, NY.
Charles W. Gilbert.
H. Douglas Barclay, Senator, State of New York.
Foster S. Brown, Pompano Beach, FL.
Edward P. Caraccioli, Principal, Fitzhugh Park School, Oswego.
Jacob K. Javits, New York State Senator.
Emmett J. Schnepp, Justice, Supreme Court, Hall of Justice, Rochester, NY.
Mr. and Mrs. Lester Gosier ('37), Bay Shore, NY.
Andrew D. Virgilio, Assemblyman 133rd District, New York State.
Robert W. Brutsch, Field Director, Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Co., Milwaukee.
Joan Fitzgibbons.
Margaret L. Lovell.
Madge Tompkins.
Leila C. McBride, Hamburg, NY.
Charles F. Wells.
Francine Wattman Frank, Albany, NY.
Helen H. Burnside, Dean, School of Nursing, University of Hawaii at Manoa.
Donald W. Watson, (class of 1977), Fitzgibbons-Sindoni, Inc., Mexico, NY.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_a45ab25caa1e45a8d659fb9a4ed0c010" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence- Friends                                                                                                                                                                 </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Cards and notes of congratulations and support.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_0888ef7b200a7244b612af68818d75d4" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence- Friends</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Letters of congratulations and support.  

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_990443841db16fd301b9bf08d455a824" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Certificates of Congratulation</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-8</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Two Certificates of Congratulations on the Appointment of Dr. Virginia L. Radley's appointment as President.  One certificate is from SUNY Cortland.  The second certificate is from Dutchess Community College.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_8d161edd318e6ec7a8373e049777f85d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memoranda</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976/1988">1976 - 1988</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-12</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Memoranda from the office of Dr. Virginia L. Radley.
Recipients and subjects include:

Dr. Donald Mathieu
Dr. William Drake, English Department Chairperson.

The College Community
Chancellor's Award for Excellence in Administrative Services
List of eligible candidates.

The Faculty
Reviewing mission statements.

The Faculty and Staff
Search committee for the Dean of Arts and Sciences.

The Faculty and Staff
Presentation by David C. Crockett.

The College Community
Invitation for applications for the position of Acting Assistant to the President for Community Relations.

The College Community (Draft)
Evaluate the performance of acting administrators now in positions for one year.

Faculty and Staff
Alumni Phonathon.

The Faculty
State car utilization.

Campus Community
Hiring freeze and fiscal restraints.

The College Community
Position freeze.

The College Community
State budget.

Members of the College Council
Proposal to cut faculty and staff positions.

The College Community
College Policy on Sexual Harassment.

Faculty + Staff
Budget.

All Faculty, Resident Assistants and Professional Staff
National Collegiate Alcohol Awareness Week reception.

Members of the College Community
Executive Vice-President/Provost Appointment.

(Formerly 1/9/157)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_45f99a4c9fc64a0cbee59e0816e95269" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>College Policies/Reports</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1986">1986</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-13</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Information dealing with Forsight, women in SUNY college at Oswego and college policy on sexual harassment. President's 1986 report to SUNY administration on budget  and other campus issues.

(Formerly 1/9/140)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_4263b701e78f8b1638b65f2d13d9e9d5" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1973/1975">1973 - 1975</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-14</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

Involvement of Women in the Governance Process:  Decision Making.  December 1973.  
17 typed pages.   Includes 11-page draft with editing notes.

Exceeding One's Grasp:  A view of excellence.  SUNY Brockport Honors Convocation speech.  April 3, 1974.  Includes 9-page typed draft with editing notes, Honors Convocation program, and thank you letter from John C. Crandall, Vice President for Instruction and Curriculum, State University College at Brockport.  2 copies of speech.

The Man Faces of Eve:  Some SUNY Firsts.  Six typed pages.  n.d.

Speech given to the open meeting of the Academic Policies Council on 
September 11, 1975.  Six typed pages with editing notes.

"Discipline Versus the 'Viewless Wings of Poesy' " by Virginia L. Radley.  Reprint from Liberal Education, Vol. XLIX, No. 4, December 1963.  Six pages.

Untitled speech on post-secondary education.  n.d.  12 typed pages.

Untitled speech on the historical context within which women have moved, stood still, or fled in and from the groves of academe.  n.d.  4 typed pages.

Welcome speech at the opening ceremonies of the 1975 New York State Association of Intercollegiate Athletics for Women's Volleyball Tournament.  1-page typed speech.

Trends in Adminstration of Higher Education in the 70's.  Thirteen page draft with editing notes.  26-page speech with editing notes.  

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_17f6267f0891cf738b9679d9199aa6ff" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976/1977">1976 - 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-15</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

"Smite the Sounding Furrows".  Address given by Dr. Virginia L. Radley, Executive Vice President/Provost, State University College at Oswego, at a conference entitled, "Road to Survival:  Financial Management in a Changing Environment," sponsored by the State Education Department, February 25, 1976.  Thirteen typed pages with bibliography.  Also includes six pages of handwritten notes.  Edited.

Remarks on Expectations for the Administrative Team.  June 1977.  Includes memorandum, typed with editing notes, and handwritten notes.  10 pages.  Two copies of typed memorandum.

Invitation from Delat Kappa Gamma, Alpha Iota Chapter, to speak at meeting.  June 1977.

Speech to Resident Assistants.  August 1977.  Seven handwritten pages.

Welcome new students.  Third Curriculum.  August 30, 1977.  Nine handwritten pages.

Speech to freshmen.  August 30, 1977.  Eight pages of handwritten notes.

Founder's Day Address.  Russell Sage College.  October 6, 1977.  
Eight pages.  3 copies.

Informal Evening with Waterbury and Scales Hall at Waterbury.  October 11, 1977.  
6 handwritten pages.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_6c1c37eb05205cea5766f367eface79e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978-01/1978-04">January, 1978 - April, 1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-16</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

State of the college.  March 1978.  Seven handwritten pages.

View from a new president.  March 1978.  Six handwritten pages.

Issues and/or concerns of VLR at Oswego.  Two handwritten pages.

Talk to Vice Presidents.  January 9, 1978.  Six handwritten pages.

Welcome to new students.  January 15, 1978.  Four handwritten pages.

Talk to Vice Presidents.  February 6, 1978.  Two handwritten pages.

State of the college.  February 1978.  Five typed pages.

Rotary Club.  April 25, 1978.  Seven typed pages, 1 page of handwritten notes.  Edited.

Industrial Arts speech.  April 29, 1978.  14 pages, includes edited version, handwritten notes and copy.

RA's and assistants.  April 1978.  Five handwritten pages with newspaper clipping.

(Formerly 1/9/194)
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_f718b490103ce6d7d83bdd49fa5e3caa" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978-05/1978-12">May, 1978 - December, 1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-17</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

ROTC speech.  May 5, 1978.  Six pages.  Typed.

Remarks to YWCA.  May 9, 1978.  Eight pages with editing notes.  Typed.

Speech to Faculty.  May 10, 1978.  Five handwritten pages, one typed.

Alice Foley Lecture:  Nazareth College of Rochester.  July 19, 1978.  Eight pages.

Address to Freshman.  August 1978.  Three typed pages.

Faculty meeting.  August 31, 1978.  Six typed pages with editing notes.

I.A. Speech.  Fall 1978.  Seven handwritten pages.

New York State Education Department Upper Mohawk/Hudson Conference.  
September 26, 1978. Nine typed pages with editing notes.

"The Infinite Kingdom of Mind".  Inaugural address.  October 7, 1978.  Seven typed pages.

Notes for speech to the American Council on Education Forum on Credentials.  
October 27, 1978.  Five typed pages with editing notes.

Remarks for the Modern Language Association.  Special Session:  The Teaching of Literature and Values.  December 1978.  Seven typed pages with editing notes.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_96027bbb77cfdba4d0bdef9cdd831452" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1979-01/1979-04">January, 1979 - April, 1979</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-18</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

State of the College.  January 1979.  Six pages.  Typed and handwritten, edited.

President's List.  February 4, 1979.  Six handwritten pages.

State of College - One Year After.  Spring 1979.  Three handwritten pages.

"Circe and the Colossus:  Seductive actors on the Horizon".  March 1979.  3 copies.

NAWDHC.  April 7, 1979.  Three typed pages, edited.

Remarks in Wisconsin in a plenary session, "Personal Advancement Issues".  April 1979.
5 typed pages, edited.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_a69f08a751f1b76f213b3a2ab86d1ecb" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1979-05/1979-12">May, 1979 - December, 1979</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-19</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

Mansions of Mind.  Maria Regina College.  May 1979.  Commencement Address.  
5 typed pages, editing notes.

Convocation.  School of Education.  Syracuse University.  May 11, 1979.
3 typed pages.  3 copies.

Marion High School Commencement.  June 22, 1979.  Three typed pages.  3 copies.
Also includes correspondence between Dr. Radley and Marion High School representatives.  Commencement progam.  

To New Faculty and Staff.  September 4, 1979.  Four handwritten pages.

Remarks for the Opening Faculty Meeting.  September 6, 1979.  Five pages, editing notes.

SUNY Retention newsletter.  October 1979.  Ten pages.

To Faculty and Students, re: budget.  December 1979.  Eleven handwritten pages.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_7da5f3de5754ef1221b8b68c53c4990d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1980-01/1980-05">January, 1980 - May, 1980</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-20</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

Remarks to the General Faculty.  March 13, 1980.  Nine typed and handwritten pages, edited.  Also includes 13-page edited version.

Speech for AWPENY's conference.  March 15, 1980.  Thirteen typed pages, edited.  Also includes Anne Mackey Lecture program, Kiamesha Lake, New York.

Remarks to Chatham Hall.  April 18, 1980.  Handwritten notes, 5 pages.

Research talk.  April 23, 1980.  Handwritten notes, 6 pages.

"Wingspread Conference Speech.  The 1980's:  Women and Higher Education".  Seven typed pages, edited.

General Faculty meeting.  April 30, 1980.  Seven pages, edited.

"Upward Mobility for Women".  May 6, 1980.  8 pages, edited.

Remarks to be made to the Conference of Presidents.  
May 11, 1980.  Five typed pages, edited.

Retirement dinner.  May 19, 1980.  Two pages, handwritten, edited.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_21589270fd76832e9ceb78943a00e0d5" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1980-06/1980-12">June, 1980 - December, 1980</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-21</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

Elizabeth Barrett Browning.  Conversations in the Discipline.  Brockport, New York.
June 13, 1980.  Seven typed pages.  3 copies, two with editing notes.  

St. Lawrence Conference.  June 22-24, 1980.  Eight typed pages, edited.  Draft.

General Faculty Meeting.  September 4, 1980.  Three typed pages, edited.  

Outline of Remarks to Faculty Chairpeople.  September 11, 1980.  
Seven typed pages, edited.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_b889c79bb97c5b7167153fa2f1001205" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1981-01/1981-05">January, 1981 - May, 1981</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-22</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley includes information about the State University and SUNY Oswego and the following:

Faculty Assembly speech.  February 5, 1981.  Includes a 12-page version, edited, and a 7-page version and a 4-page draft.  Typed.

Faculty Meeting.  March 18, 1981.  Includes and 6 and 7 page versions.  Typed.

Annual Conference of the American Industrial Arts Association speech, "Excellence in Teaching".  March 24, 1981.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_a971126a147d6ce3e95972259b13b724" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1981-06/1981-12">June, 1981 - December, 1981</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-23</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

Retirement dinner for faculty and staff on Thursday evening, June 11, 1981.  2 typed pages.

Bryn Mawr Summer Institute.  July 27, 1981.  14 typed pages.  Also includes 15-page typed  draft, edited.

Sheldon Associates.  August 22, 1981.  Two typed pages, edited.

New Students.  August 31, 1981.  Two page draft, edited.

General Faculty speech.  September 3, 1981.  Ten typed and handwritten pages, edited.

New Professors.  September 10, 1981.  One typed page.

"How To Shrink Effectively, Humanely".  October 14, 1981.  Five typed pages, edited.

"Welcome to all . . . at your Alma Mater".  n.d.  3 typed pages.  Photocopy with lyrics and music, "Gaudeamus Igitur".   "Circe and the Colossus:  Seductive Factors on the Horizon".  (March 1979, Calif.)  9-page typed speech.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_2f6cef2fee53f20ab3147f8c5eb32fcc" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1982-01/1982-04">January, 1982 - April, 1982</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-24</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley includes the following:

"What Steps are Being Taken to Facilitate Full Realization of Female Potential?"  5 typed pages, edited.  n.d.

6 handwritten pages, "re:  deployment, retraining, reallocation".  n.d.

Approaches to Leadership:  The Team Concept.  10 typed pages.  n.d.

The Sounding Furrows Smote Again:  Leadership and Common Sense.  13 typed pages.  Second draft.  Includes bibliography.  n.d.

How to Shrink Effectively, Humanely.  4 typed pages.  n.d.

Faculty Meeting.  February 4, 1982.  Nine typed pages, edited.  2 copies.

Languages at Oswego.  February 1982.  Two typed pages with editing notes.

Faculty Speech.  Draft.  3 typed pages, edited.   n.d.

Salvation Army Dinner.  March 25, 1982.  Draft.  3 typed pages.  Includes event program.

Guest Editorial for Palladium-Times.  March 23, 1982.  2 typed pages.

"Sauntering Among the 'Bloomsberries' "  February 10, 1982.  Friends of Penfield Library speech.  3 typed pages with editorial notes.  Includes 4 photocopied pages from 1921 publication excerpt, "To Lytton Strachey".

9 pages of handwritten notes for address given at American Studies Association, R. Freeman Butts Lecture.  November 5, 1981.

7 pages of handwritten notes of the State of SUNY.  March 1982.

Research and Truth.  Remarks by Dr. V. L. Radley, at Quest 1982.  April 7, 1982.  
Four typed pages.

College Open House.  April 19, 1982.  Eight pages of handwritten notes.

Freedom and Responsiblity.  April 28, 1982.  Guest editorial, Palladium-Times.  
3 typed pages.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_6d8be2e723b6832f155a1ff6def114e1" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1982-05/1982-12">May, 1982 - December, 1982</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-25</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

Managing for Growth with Diminishing Resources Or How To Do More With Less.  Draft.
Skytop speech.  November 18, 1982.  Nine typed pages, edited.   3 copies.

October 16, 1982, speech to 1,100 parents.  10 typed and handwritten pages, edited.

Faculty Speech.  September 2, 1982.  Six typed pages.

Enhancing Public Perception of Quality of SUNY's Programs.  September 1982.  Draft.  
4 typed and handwritten pages, edited.

American Council on Education Fellows Program in Florida.  September 1982. 
Eleven typed pages, edited.

Sheldon Association Luncheon.  August 7, 1982.  Three handwritten pages.

Say Not the Struggle Nought Availeth.  July 18, 1982.  Bryn Mawr.  
12 typed pages, edited.

Cultivating External Constituencies.  Draft.  July 18, 1982.  Bryn Mawr.  
10 typed pages, edited.

The Best of All Possible Worlds.  Wells College Honors Convocation.  May 11, 1982.  
10 typed pages, edited.   Includes Wells College press release pertaining to the Dr. Radley and the Honors Convocation.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_0db758df637d91918ea89c09b5827675" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1983">1983</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-26</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley include the following:

Press release quoting Dr. Radley about SUNY Oswego fiscal issues.  December 1983.

8 pages of handwritten and typed notes for "Dr. Spencer's class".  November 11, 1983.

Remarks for AAUW.  November 1983.  Eight typed pages titled, Networks.

Meeting of Admissions staff.  October 19, 1983.  Seven handwritten pages.  Also includes State University of New York College Admissions Personnel bifold, "Operation Inform '83".

Sheldon Associates.  August 1983.  Three pages of handwritten notes.

5-page typed draft titled, "Mentoring".  July 1983.  Includes editorial notes.

Faculty Senates speech.  April 15, 1983.  Two typed pages with editorial notes.

3-page typed speech with editorial notes.  Title - "Open House".  April 11, 1983.

Talk to Student Association Senate.  March 2, 1983.    4-page draft with editorial notes.

Draft of Faculty Meeting speech.  February 10, 1983.     10 typed pages.

"Guides, Philos. + Friends" - Mentors.  8 handwritten pages with editorial notes.  n.d.

Conversations in the Disciplines.  April 1983.  One typed page.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3ebf521255eba2de4b9189cc26191001" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1984">1984</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-27</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of  Dr. Virginia L. Radley include the following:

6 pages of handwritten notes for an unspecified speech.  n.d.

Speech to Faculty.  August 27, 1984.  3-page typed draft with editorial notes.

Speech to Food Service Personnel.  August 20, 1984.  3-page typed draft with editorial notes.

Alumni Weekend speech.  July 15, 1984.  4-page handwritten notes.

Language Fair.  May 5, 1984.  4-page typed speech.

Speech to Faculty.  April 1984.  6 pages, typed and handwritten.  Includes the following topics - Observations for Fall 1984, Preliminary Assessment Indicates, faculty recognition, budget, the Oswegonian, and admissions.

Notes for Presidential Forum.  March 1984.  Eight handwritten pages.

Faculty Meeting remarks.  February 8, 1984.  Six handwritten pages.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_de668ca65e261fdc8fae40692de6dec7" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1985">1985</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-28</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Speeches of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

General Faculty Meeting.  February 6, 1985.  Seven handwritten pages.  Attached is an article from Science, Vol. 227, January 1985, by Constance Holden, "Restoration of the Humanities Urged.  NEH chairman decries 'garage sale' look of college curricula; says it's time to get back to the classics".  


"The Interior World of the Intellect:  Jubilee Celebration at Marymount Manhattan College in New York City".  November 24, 1985.  Seven typed pages with editing notations signed Dr. Virginia L. Radley.

"Professors Convocation Recognition".   October 1985.  Two typed pages with editing notes.  Unsigned.

Chamber of Commerce Breakfast.  October 7, 1985.  Three handwritten pages.  Unsigned.

5-page handwritten speech to the faculty.  September 1985.

"Topics for Speech to the Men's Honor Society".  September 19, 1985.  Seven typed pages.  2 copies.  Attached are two letters from Oswego graduates Joanne Cono and Melissa Bettinger.  Also included is a copy of a handwritten letter to Governor Cuomo from an Elderhostel participant, Ceil Gordet.

Alumni Welcome.  July 13, 1985.  Thirteen pages of handwritten notes (red ink).

Sheldon Association.  July 1985.  Five pages of handwritten notes (red ink).

Faculty Retirement Dinner.  May 30, 1985.  Nine handwritten pages.

Networking.  April 19, 1985.  3 pages of handwritten notes.  Includes pamphlet for New York Women's Studies Association Eighth Annual Conference (at SUNY Oswego),  "The New Feminist Scholarship.  Images &amp; Visions".  Also includes "Bridging the Gap: Networking for Women" announcement, agenda and registration form.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e4d0b32685f3bf427296389986bb0260" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Speeches</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-29</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Undated speeches of Dr. Viginia L. Radley including the following:

Fidessa-Duessa:  Perceptions of a Woman Administrator in a Male Dominated Institution.  
Speech delivered by Dr. Virginia L. Radley, Executive Vice President/Provost, State University College of Arts and Sciences, Oswego, New York.  15 typed pages.  2 copies.

7 pages of handwritten notes.  n.d.  "The next 100 years - "

6 pages of handwritten notes.  n.d.  "What every woman Ph.D. should know if she aspires to be an administrator".  

Middle States Chairs.  n.d.  8 handwritten pages.

"Women in management".  n.d.  4 pages of handwritten notes.

Wingspread Conference Speech.  "The 1980's:  Women and Higher Education".  
7 typed pages with editing notes.  Onionskin.

Presidential statement.  The issue of quality.  7 typed pages with editing notes.  n.d.

"Upward Mobility for Women".  5 typed pages.  n.d.  Onionskin.

"Women and the Arts".  4 typed pages with editing notes.  n.d.

Also includes notes for untitled and undated speeches.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e1143e07ac3b40e36849f052813b41c1" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Published works</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1963/1974">1963 - 1974</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-30</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Published works of Dr. Virginia L. Radley including the following:

"Discipline Versus the 'Viewless Wings of Poesy' " by Virginia L. Radley.  Reprint from Liberal Education, Vol. XLIX, No. 4, December 1963.  Pages 1-6.  
Three reprints.  Two photocopies.

"The Humanist Dean and Management Systems".    
Reprint from Liberal Education, May 1974, Vol. LX, No. 2.  Pages 228 - 235.
4 copies (variations and 1 photocopy)

"Involvement of Women in the Governance Process:  Decision Making".  2 typed copies.  
16 pages.  Published by the New York State Education Department.  Spring 1974.

 "Christabel:  Directions Old and New".  
Studies in English Literature.  Volume IV, Number 4, Autumn 1964.
Pages 531 - 541.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_770187761c9a86a90eed378dea00fd3e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Inauguration</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-31</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Papers relating to Dr. Virginia L. Radley's inauguration as the eighth President of SUNY Oswego.  Included are the following:

Correspondence and memorandums, meeting minutes, in regards to the planning and administrative duties for Dr. Radley's inauguration.
Correspondents include David Nellis, Dr. Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., Public Ceremonies Committee, Provost Ralph Spencer, Dr. Dorothy Rogers, Patti M. Peterson, Margaret Richardson, Rosemary Nesbitt, David Glick, Lynn Hemink, Michael D. Jones, Steven D. Sucher, Dr. J. Michael Adams, Dr. John Knapp, Henry Angle, Donald Batchelor, Margaret Richardson, Dr. Judy Wellman, and Martin Lindenmayer.

Flyer for the President's Colloquia, October 5 - 7, 1978.  Two copies.
Colloquium introduction.  3 typed pages.
Inauguration agenda.  5 pages.

"Oswego Alumni Association Presents Homecoming Dinner and Presidential Ball, October 7, 1978".  Program.  Bifold with insert of agenda.  

"Alumni and Parents Homecoming Weekend featuring The Installation of Virginia L. Radley Oswego's Eighth President.  October 6 - 8, 1978.  Trifold program with photographs.

"The Inauguration of Dr. Virginia L. Radley as the eighth President of The State University of New York College of Arts and Sciences at Oswego".  Bifold program with Schedule of Events insert.  3 copies.

"The Infinite Kingdom of Mind".  Inaugural address of Dr. Virginia L. Radley.

President's Colloquia schedule of events with correspondence from participants - Joseph Weicha, Ronald Brown and Diana Balmori.  "The Language of the Discipline".

(Formerly 1/9/92)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d62575aadf074b17eef2a8b992784968" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dr. Virginina L. Radley- Resignation</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-32</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Letters, memorandum, publications, remarks and newspaper clippings concerning Dr. Virginia L. Radley's resignation.  Correspondents include the following:

Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., Chancellor, State University of New York.
Dr. Jerome B. Kosimer, Executive Vice Chancellor, State University of New York.
John T. Sullivan, Jr.
Office of Public Affairs news release.  September 3, 1987.
Faculty Meeting remarks by Dr. Radley.  September 3, 1987.
John Kares Smith, Professor of Communications Studies, SUNY Oswego.
Helena Howe, Cayuga County Community College President Emeritus.
Muriel Allerton
"City Will Be Poorer When Radley Exits".  Palladium-Times, September 8, 1987.
Sanford Sternlicht
Dorothy P. Heindel
Elizabeth Ward, Director, Russsell Sage College Alumnae Association.
Coy (Ludwig?)
Humphrey Tonkin, President, Potsdam College.
Howard L. Simmons, Ph.D., Associate Director, Middle States Association.
Jeffrey W. Hurrin (Class of '79), SUNY New Paltz.
Prentiss Carnell III, President, Albany Business College.
Frank Horton, U.S.Congressman, New York.
F. H. Ratzeburg, SUNY Oswego professor, Psychology Department.
Sylvia Chu, SUNY Oswego.
Andrew D. Hopkins, University of Rochester.
Dr. Sherron Knopp, Williams College.
Susan Donnelly, Registrar, Bunker Hill Community College, Boston, MA.
Judith Davidson Moyers, Board of Trustees, State University of New York.

Also included is Dr. Virginia L. Radley's vitae.  Bifold.  4 copies.

(Formerly 1/9/217)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_fe07823b86d10fcd864647ca43ba955f" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dr. Virginia L. Radley- Biography</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-33</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>2-page typed biography of Dr. Radley.  Not cited.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_c24116249bbaa3c62c7040b287328796" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Other correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1978/1994">1978 - 1994</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-34</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence from the office of Dr. Virginia L. Radley.  Correspondents include:

Dolores B. Schmidt, Assistant Vice Chancellor for Affirmative Action, SUNY.
Dr. Foster S. Brown
John J. Castle (Class of 1934)

Grace McCarthy Knitter writes about her memories of Oswego as a child (1906 - 1916).

Harriette Laudise writes concerning a donation of copies of newspaper clippings about Emily Howland.

Phebe M. King writes concerning publications and papers by and about Emily Howland.

Margaret Karch Lasky
David Nellis

Talk by Dr. Dorothy Rogers.  Founders Day.  Professor Recognition Ceremony.  
September 10, 1981.  Four typed pages.

Paper by Dr. Dorothy Rogers.  "The All-Time Greats".  6 typed pages.  n.d.  Includes information about Hermann Krusi, Richard K. Piez, Ralph W. Swetman, Caroline L. G. Scales, Isaac B. Poucher, Matilda Cooper Poucher, Amos Farnham, Margaret K. Smith, Henry Straight, Emma Dickinson Straight, Caroline V. Sinnamon, Clara Armstrong, Hideo Takamine, Ellor Carlile Ripley, Mary Sheldon Barnes, and Earl Barnes.

Judy Wellman

Anne C. Edmonds, College Librarian, Mount Holyoke College.  
Memories/biography of Dr. Radley.  July 1983.

(Formerly 1/9/92)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_2c66d8a91d798af461d3c1f34229b036" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Dr. Virginia Radley- Photographs  </unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">1980's</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">1-35</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>12 black and white photographs.  Digital versions of these photos can be found in the Image Management area of this record.  Photograph descriptions as follows:

       Dr. Radley in academic robes.  (Part of 2006.024 Accession.)  5" x 7"

-2   Dr. Radley and 3 unidentified male students at Shady Shore.  5" x 7"

-3   Dr. Virginia L. Radley, far right.  5" x 7"

- 4   Dr. Radley.  Head and shoulders, partial profile.  3" x 2".  Two photographs.

- 5   Dr. Radley, left, at Shady Shore greeting an unidentified woman.  c. 1980's.  5" x 7"

- 6   Foster S. Brown, left, and Dr. Virginia L. Radley in front of Shady Shore.  
        c. 1980's.  8" x 10"

- 7   Dr. Virginia L. Radley at her desk in Culkin Hall.  c. 1980's.  5" x 7"

- 8   Dr. Virginia L. Radley.  c. 1980's.  5" x 7"

- 9   Dr. Virginia L. Radley, left, in academic robe and mortat board.  5" x 7"

- 10  Dr. Radley at her desk.  1985.  From the Undergraduate Catalog, page 3.  
         ( 5" x 7".  2 copies.  Third copy is 8" x 4"

- 11   Dr. Virginia L. Radley, right, at podium.  Torchlight Ceremony.  1987.  Sheldon Statue 
          is in the background.  8" x 10"

- 12   Dr. Radley at podium.  c. 1970's.  8" x 10"

(Photos 2 through 12 were formerly with archive # 52/1/192)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_1e2096998df032844334343a418da841" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1974/1979">1974 - 1979</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley, including the following:

"Highest Ranking Woman in SUNY".  The Oswegonian, August 1, 1974.

"Addresses AAUW.  Broader Issues of Higher Education Dr. Radley Topic".  
The Palldium-Times.  December 2, 1974.

"Radley defies college stereotype" by Dick Schulman.  
The Oswegonian.  December 21, 1976.

"Radley's Name Not Included On Faculty List".  Palladium-Times.  March 6, 1978.

Letters to the Editor in response to March 6th article.  Palladium-TImes.  March 19, 1978.

Press release from the Office of Public Relations concerning the appointment of Dr. Radley as president of SUNY Oswego.  March 22, 1978.

"Dr. Radley New SUNY Oswego President".  Palladium-Times.  March 22, 1978.

"Oswego president.  Woman joins SUNY elite".  Syracuse Herald-Journal.  March 23, 1978.

"Dr. Virginia Radley Named SUNY Oswego President" by Luther F. Bliven.  
Syracuse Post-Standard.  March 23, 1978.

"Radley chosen as eighth SUCO president" by Scott Stafford.  
Oswegonian.  March 24, 1978.

"Dr. Radley Receives Permanent Nod from Trustees".  Perspective.  March 29, 1978.

"Oswego college president a former Nazareth dean".  Rochester Democrat and Chronicle.  March 30, 1978.

"Krupsak seeks student action".  Syracuse Herald-Journal.  March 30, 1978.

"Oswego college president a former Nazareth dean" by Kevin Dilworth.  
Rochester Democrat and Chronicle.  March 30, 1978.

"Krupsak Sees 'Overreaction' Possible in Lake Ban".  Palladium-Times.  March 30, 1978.

"Dr. Radley Moving to Form Adminstrative Team".  Palladium-Times.  April 24, 1978.

"Adminstrative Team Members Sought by SUCO President".  
Palladium-Times.  May 22, 1978.

"Radley Named to Bank Council".  Palladium-Times.  May 25, 1978.

Photograph of Dr. Foster S. Brown and Dr. Virginia L. Radley in front of Shady Shore.  Syracuse Herald-Journal.  October 1978.

"The Boss at Oswego" by Richard G. Case.  Empire magazine, The Syracuse Herald-American.  August 27, 1978.

"Iron Fist in a Velvet Glove.  SUNY Oswego's new president, Virginia Radley, has definite ideas about how a college should be run".  Syracuse Alumni Quarterly, Fall 1978.  3 copies

"Inauguration of Radley to highlight Alumni weekend".  Oswegonian, September 28, 1978.

"Medal of Office Designed For Radley Innauguration".  Palladium-Times, October 5, 1978.

"President's Colloquia Features Inaugural Program".  Palladium-Times, October 6, 1978.

"Dr. Radley Inaugurated as President at SUNY Oswego".  Includes photograph.
The Palladium-Times.  October 7, 1978.

"College president inauguration.  Radley takes reins".  
Syracuse Herald-American.  October 8, 1978.

"Dr. Radley Assumes Presidency at SUCO".  Palladium-Times, October 9, 1978. 
Includes 4 photographs with captions.

"Virginia Radley:  Ready When the Opportunity Came".  November 15, 1978.

"Women Have Played Role in Development of SUCO".  
Palladium-Times, December 4, 1978.

"Woman Heads SUNY College".  Palladium-Times. January 31, 1979.

"Dr. Radley Honored By Legislature".  March 12, 1979.

"Legislature commends President Radley".  April 1979.  The SUNY News.

"College President Declares Hiring Moratorium.  Budget Sparks Action".  
Palladium-Times, November 9, 1979.

"Now on Sentry Board - Dr. Radley In Demand".  Palladium-Times, November 29, 1979

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_47a226c18161bdf1fe0903ee7f1d7362" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings                                                             </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1980/1981">1980 - 1981</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-2</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley.

"Demonstrating Role Model".  February 18, 1980.  Syracuse Post-Standard.

"Radley Muzzling Council?"  Palladium-Times, February 21, 1980.

"Research Pact Signed Here".  Photograph and caption, "Officials at SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry and SUNY Oswego sign cooperative programming pact to increase inter-campus cooperation in research, public service and educational programs in the natural and environmental sciences.  Seated (from left) are Dr. Ralph Spencer, Oswego provost; Dr. Edward Palmer, ESF president; Dr. Virginia Radley, Oswego president; and Dr. Donald Behrend, ESF vice president for program affairs.  Standing (from left) are ESF and Oswego officials including Dr. Ronald Scrudato, Dr. James Geis, Dr. Robert Gubbi Sachidanandan, Dr. Kathryn Martin, and Dr. John Gannon".  Palladium-Times, April 25, 1980.

"Overview of women in higher education" by Dorothy Austin. 
Milwaukee Sentinel.  April 29, 1980.

"Women in Higher Education:  Past, Present, Future.  Highlights of Wingspread Conference, April 28 - 29, 1980".  Comment.  June, 1980.

"So You Want to Be a College President" by Lee Hall.  
The Chronicle.  July 21, 1980.  Page 48.

"SUCO Union Attacks Radley".  Oswego Valley News, December 23, 1980.

"Low Morale at SUCO".  Oswego Valley News, March 10, 1981.

"Women Presidents Make the Grade at Area Colleges".    Includes article on Dr. Radley and Patti McGill Peterson.
The Post-Standard.  November 3, 1981.

"SUCO President Explains Firing Procedure".  The Post-Standard.  November 24, 1981.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_c0e420a1e534ee1cbe573c6cdb6daebf" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1982">1982</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-3</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley.

"Women's World 1982.  19th Century Scholar Is 20th Century Woman".  
Palladium-Times.  January 11, 1982.

"Contract Signing -- Peg Hamilton (front row far right) watches as Dr. Virginia Radley puts her signature on a one-year pact that will allow the Senior Citizens Nutrition Program to move to the Swetman Hall cafetorium effective Monday.  Also on hand for the signing Wednesday morning were Oswego County Opportunities Executive Director Peter Geiter (front row, far left) and college administrators Dr. Willard Schum (top right) and Bernie Henderson (top left). . . "  Palladium-Times, February 27, 1982.

"Despite rumors, Radley's staying".  Oswegonian News.  March 11, 1982.

"SUCO President to Give Talk at Salvation Army".  
Oswego County Messenger, March 11, 1982.

"SUCO President To Address Reps On Budget Impact".  
Oswego County Messenger, March 12, 1982.

"Dr. Radley In Washington:  Aid Cuts Foreshadow Problems".  
Palladium-Times, March 16, 1982.

"D'Amato Calms Fears Of College Presidents".  March 18, 1982.

"SUCO President Deplores 'Pot Shots' ".  Oswego County Messenger, March 29, 1982.

"There is danger in ignorance concerning 'Gulliver' ".  
Dr. Donald Vanouse.  Oswegonian.  April 22, 1982.

"Freedom, Responsibility Go Hand in Hand" by Dr. Virginia Radley.  
Palladium-Times.  May 12, 1982.

"Radley forum" by Andy Leahy.  Oswegonian News.  May 13, 1982.  

"Two Oswego County Women To be Honored".  
Oswego County Messenger, September 9, 1982.

"Radley Speaks Out On Education".  Palladium-Times, September 15, 1982.
"Educator Honored - Dr. Virginia Radley . . . is presented with the 'Trailblazer in Education' award by Dr. Helena Bain Howe on behalf of the Central New York chapter, National Organization of Women".  
Oswego Valley News, October 28, 1982.

"9 Unsung Heroines to Be Honored. 
The Oswego County Messenger.  September 27, 1982.

"Chamber of Commerce Honors Dr. Radley" by Antone Clark.  
Palladium-Times.  December 1, 1982.

"Women's rating guide gives Syracuse University just 1 star" by Hart Seely.
Herald-Journal Metro.  December 1, 1982.

"Chamber of Commerce Honors Dr. Radley".  Palladium-Times, December 1, 1982.

"Radley looks ahead to college's future plans" by Patricia Culligan.  
Oswegonian.  December 2, 1982.

"Radley:  SUNY in Trouble" by Antone Clark.  The Palladium-Times.  December 2, 1982.

"Oswego State Scores Well in Women's Guide to Colleges".  
The Post-Standard.  December 3, 1982.

"An Impressive Public Figure".  Palladium-Times.  December 3, 1982.

"Radley comments on Oswego as an institution" by Patricia Culligan.  
Oswegonian News.  December 9, 1982.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d27c702b3142c8c39101d6015ba84d04" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1983">1983</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-4</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley.

"The Business Behind The School".  Palladium-Times, January 11, 1983.

"SUCO Faculty Weighs Strategies to Fight Cuts" by Mike Grogan.  
Post-Standard.  February 11, 1983.

"SUCO Faculty Talk of Saving Jobs" by Mike Grogan.
The Post-Standard.  February 3, 1983.

"Budget Cuts Hitting Home" by Steve Yablonski.  Palladium-Times.  February 5, 1983.

"SUNY College President Clarifies Stance on Budget, Position Cuts.  
Oswego County Messenger.  February 11, 1983.

"SUNY President Issues Call To Arms" by Joanne Berman.  
The Palladium-Times.  February 11, 1983.

"Radley Restates Plea for Autonomy on Local Campuses".  
Post-Standard, February 22, 1983.

"Finance 101.  College cuts spell $7 million loss to Oswego".  
Oswego Accent Plus.  February 24, 1983.

"SUCO's Radley to take five-month study leave" by Mike Grogan.  
Syracuse Herald American.  April 10, 1983.

"Women-only schools serve purpose:  college heads" by Mark D. Frank.  
Syracuse Herald American.  October 9, 1983.

"Two College Presidents Champion Women's Schools" by Mark D. Frank.
Buffalo Evening News.  October 28, 1983.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_6b9f9d18520afe9f7d58927d45641191" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1984">1984</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-5</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley.

"The Women Oswegonians Admire".  Palladium-Times, January 11, 1984.

"Horton Selects Radley For Committee".  Palladium-Times, January 28, 1984.

"Hike rent on Radley's on-campus home; College council member".  
Syracuse Herald Journal, February 16, 1984.

"Former SUCO Presidents say Sheldon Beach Never Open to Public".  
Post Standard, March 7, 1984.

"Oswego Releases Report on Plans for Sheldon Beach".  Post Standard, March 9, 1984.

"Council OKs Suing SUCO Over Beach Use".  Post Standard, March 13, 1984.

"Radley Wants Autonomy Over Budget" by Antone Clark.  
Palladium-Times.  March 20, 1984.

"Oswego's desires for a swimming hole splits town and gown.  College estate or public beach?"  Palladium-Times, March 25, 1984.

"College Head Addresses 13 Honorees, Guests" by Natalie Pitzer.
Union-Sun &amp;   April 9, 1984.

"Cahill Sues SUCO Chief to Reopen Sheldon's Beach".  Post Standard, August 29, 1984.

"State Represents Radley in Sheldon Beach Suit".  Post Standard, September 21, 1984.

"Radley:  Sheldon Hall Plan May be in Trouble".  Post Standard, October 4, 1984.

"Dr. Radley Presented With Service Award By Russell Sage".  
Palladium-Times, December 7, 1984.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3f93b7466625af2a4630d808cca0f1a0" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1985/1988">1985 - 1988</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-6</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley.

"Cahill's Beach Suit Dismissed".  Pallaldium-Times, January 31, 1985.

"Court:  SUCO Can Ban Swimming at Sheldon Beach".  Post Standard, February 1, 1985.

"Dr. Radley Receives Research Grant".  Palladium-Times.  July 24, 1985.

"Madame President Reigns at Oswego". Central New York Business Review, August 1985.

"Radley is Named".  Palladium-Times.  January 15, 1986.

"Coach Accuses Radley of Harassment" by Maggie Reed. 
Palladium-Times.  March 7, 1986.

"Radley Cites Three For Academic Excellence".  Palladium-Times.  April 26, 1986.

"Wealth Matters, Radley Says To Students".  Palladium-Times.  May 16, 1986.

"Radley Makes Recommendation To Appoint Moody As Dean".  
Palladium-Times.   August 6, 1986.

"Radley to Participate In Women's Conference".  Palladium-Times.  October 20, 1986.

"Boronkay Appointed Associate Dean".  Palladium-Times.  November 19, 1986.

"Radley Extends Hours For Guns".  Palladium-Times.  March 5, 1987.

"Radley Sees A 'Grim, Awful' Budget".  Palladium-Times. March 19, 1987.

"SUNY's first woman president resumes teaching and research" by Julie Harrison Blissert.  State University of New York focus on Women.  March 1988.

"If There's Something Unique Oswego offers . . ."
Campus News.

The Sage Alumnae Magazine.  Volume 8.  Includes article, "Virginia Radley Receives Crockett Award".  Page 7.
</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_65300be0d6be34259bec8c14545c13e3" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1992/1993">1992 - 1993</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-7</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Newspaper clippings and other published materials relating to Dr. Radley.

"Radley Named Scholar in Residence".  Sage Times.  January 29, 1993.

"Woman educator made history with SUNY Oswego post".  
Post-Standard.  March 13, 1992.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_42f3c9991ead371f1b297bd0c63a8886" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Proposal for a Competency-Based Teacher Education Program</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1983">1983</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-8</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Proposal for a Competency-Based Teacher Education Program leading to the Degree, Master of Science in Education, Major in Industrial Arts and Technology by State University of New York, College of Arts and Sciences at Oswego.   41 pages included appendix and supporting correpondence.

(Formerly 1/9/194)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_7bbd277ae2d3e2f054c5b586b6028c30" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Publications</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1984/1986">1984 - 1986</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-9</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The US Undergrad, Vol. 1, No. 1, Fall 1984.  The Newsletter of the Undergraduate Alumni Association, SUNY Oswego.  Front page article includes Perspective from President of College - Dr. Virginia Radley.  2 copies.

125th Commencement, Class of 1986.  </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_d11c7adec0e93e88dba70bebac81b151" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memorandum of Understanding</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1980-04">April, 1980</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-10</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Memorandum of Understanding between The State Universty of New York, College of Environmental Science and Forestry and The State University of New York at Oswego signed by Dr. Virginia L. Radley and Edward E. Palmer.

SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry and SUNY Oswego signed cooperative programming pact to increase inter-campus cooperation in research, public service and educational programs in the natural and environmental sciences.  See folder 02-02 for newspaper photograph and caption.  1 page.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3f86644d43d5ab1763f32f8b559f7814" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memorial Service signature book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1999-04">April, 1999</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-11</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Memorial Service signature book. Ringed binder.
Also included memorial service invitation (2 copies).
Five pages of signatures.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_3c6311cbd372f02212c6472951f78ff5" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Appointment book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1974/1975">1974 - 1975</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-12</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Dr. Radley's appointment book includes handwrittten notes, receipts (from hotels, restaurants, stores), and vouchers (loose and stapled).

Black cover, spiral-bound.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_0cf4253295d1a7a168723289dd9c89fa" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Appointment book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976-01/1976-07">January, 1976 - July, 1976</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-13</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Dr. Radley's appointment book includes handwritten notes, lists, receipts (loose and stapled) and vouchers reflecting her travels, meetings, and lectures.

Black cover, sprial-bound.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_c5b94574e367e8c273246071fb8f294b" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Appointment book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976/1977">1976 - 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-14</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes handwritten notes and a few loose notes and miscellaneous papers.  Also included is Dr. Radley's business card while Executive Vice President - Provost.  

Black cover, sprial-bound.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_58ca2f3aa48f6d729d6f4776a9d1ea0b" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Appointment book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976-08/1977-04">August, 1976 - April, 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-15</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The appointment book is very full of handwritten notes, business receipts, vouchers, and statements reflect Dr. Radley's travels, lectures and professional life.  

Many loose papers.  Handle with care and concern for original order.
Black cover, sprial-bound.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_564975628accd7be4630d5d83f5b8004" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Appointment book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976-07/1977-06">July, 1976 - June, 1977</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-16</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Appointment book contains handwritten notes, a few loose notes, official college calendar, Board of Trustees schedule of meetings, College Council schedule of meetings and miscellaneous papers relating to SUNY Oswego.

Black cover, spiral-bound.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e41fc18015b533dc310a446d35919a08" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Appointment book</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1976/1980">1976 - 1980</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-17</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>These papers relate to the loose and stapled papers in Dr. Radley's appointment books, including 1976 European trip receipts from restaurants and hotels.  Also includes 1976 correspondence, and1979 application for license in the citizens radio service. 
Spiral notebook has handwritten label, " Dr. V. L. Radley 1976 spring to summer log.  Florence, Italy, Belgium, SUNY study programs ".  Handwritten notes.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_dda579969bc38aacd3b62e486f9c2c0f" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>SUNY College at Oswego:  Its Second Century Unfolds</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">2-18</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    
                <p>"SUNY College at Oswego:  Its Second Century Unfolds"by Dorothy Rogers.  1988.  
Signed bookplate from Virginia L. Radley, former president of SUCO and member of the Edward Austin Sheldon Society.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_4c7e9b113b18591f35a621f609412778" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>SUNY Oswego plaque</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">3-1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Plaque has the following information:

" College at Oswego.
 State University of New York.
Let Each Become All He Is Capable Of Being.
1948
1861 "

The plaque is mounted to a green felt covered board and framed.  Below the plaque is a brass label, " President Virginia Radley ".</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_91a6ae10db06261b99c38e302f13f381" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Framed portrait of Dr. Virginia Radley</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">4-1</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Framed portrait of Dr. Virginia Radley.
Gold frame 21" x 17".  Linen matt with gold trim.  Linen is soiled.
Black &amp; white photograph.  14" x 10.5"

The framed portrait was transferred to the college archives from University Development after being removed from Sheldon Hall.  </p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>