<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0060</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Anne Commerton Papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-08-04">August 4, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Zachary Vickery.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>Anne Commerton Papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1972/1979" type="inclusive">1972 - 1979</unitdate>
							<abstract>Papers of Penfield Library Director Anne Commerton include correspondence, speeches, writings and publications.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>0.2 linear feet</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n86117228">Commerton, B. Anne</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitid>2009.051.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>Collection is open for research.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Anne Commerton was a U.S. Air Force librarian from 1957 - 1964.  She served as serials librarian at Syracuse University from 1964 - 1968.  She was public services librarian at SUNY Oswego from 1968 - 1973.  In 1973 she was appointed Director of Libraries and Learning Resources at SUNY Oswego.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n86117228">Commerton, B. Anne</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            
        <subject authfilenumber="sh85076491" source="lcsh">Librarians</subject>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>Papers of Penfield Library Director Anne Commerton include correspondence, speeches, writings and publications.</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_5324a5a80083c957ad1a7d27530e80f9" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Articles, book review</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1972/1979">1972 - 1979</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-01</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Article written by Anne Commerton for "The Bookmark" January-February 1973 issue.
Includes the publication and correspondence between Ms. Commerton and the Bureau of Academic + Research Libraries, the editor of "The Bookmark" and "The Bookmark" staff.
Also includes a carbon copy of the typed article sent for publication, "The Changing Scene in SUNY Libraries".

Typed paragraph concerning the aquisition of a computer terminal for retrieval of bibliographic information for the library.  10.10.1973. Handwritten note at top, "for newsletter".

Reprint of article, "Union or Professional Organization? A Librarian's Dilemma". "College of Research Libraries" publication. March 1975. Pages 129-135. 2 copies.
Also includes a 15-page typed draft of article including editing notes.

Book review of "Collective Bargaining in Higher Education: Its Implications for Governance and Faculty Status for Librarians.  Proceedings of a Preconference Institute Sponsored by Academic Status Committee, Association of College and Research Libraries, at San Francisco, June 27 and 28, 1975. Edited by Millicent D. Abell". Includes typed review (2 copies), 1 carbon copy and an edited typed copy. Also includes cover letter from Ms. Commerton to Richard D. Johnson, editor of "College + Research Libraries".

"Priority Number One: Survival". May 1978 speech for the Association of College Research Libraries (ACRL). Includes a typed copy with editorial notes, photocopy with editorial notes and carbon copy with editorial notes.

Article written for newsletter (Penfield newsletter?). Five year anniversary (Ms. Commerton's Library Directorship) highlights. August 1978. 2 typed pages.

South Central Research Library Council speech at Cornell University. September 9, 1978. 8 typed pages with editorial notes.

"Keeping Statistics at Happydale College, September 29, 1978".  Scenarios and questions. 2 typed pages.

Speech at Rochester Regional Research Library Council, Nazareth College.  October 4, 1978.  10 typed pages.

Letter to Anne Roberts, SUNY, Albany, concerning speech at Rochester Regional Research Library Council.

Speech at Syracuse University Conference, March 30, 1979.  "Reference and Research Resources".  2 typed pages with editorial notes.  Also includes photocopies of research articles and handwritten notes.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_febb7f78962c8bcd11b877b8ebdfb87d" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence, articles</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1979/1987">1979 - 1987</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-02</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Correspondence pertaining to Anne Commerton's speech at the October 1979 NYLA conference in Syracuse.  Includes 3 typed copies of two speeches including editorial notes.

April 25, 1980, speech at Syracuse University Alumni Banquet, "Where Have the Good Times Gone?".  2 typed copies, 1 with editorial notes.  6 pages each.

Statement before Assembly Task Force on Infrastructure, Speaker Stanley Fink, Chairman.  November 13, 1981.  3 typed pages submitted by B. Anne Commerton, Chairperson, Legislative Committee, NYLA, SUNY Oswego.

Letter from Nancy W. Lian to Gloria Glaser concerning enclosed 11-page manuscript written by B. Anne Commerton and Nancy W. Lian, "The New York Library Association Legislative Program".  

1982 correspondence from B. Anne Commerton concerning the Legislative Log.  Includes other undated Legislative Logs and handwritten notes.

Typed obituary notice for Penfield Library.  Also includes two pages of supporting facts.
Uncited.  n.d.

Correspondence pertaining to an article written by Anne Commerton.  1986.  The Bookmark article is not included.

SUNY Library Association Annual Conference Debate on Faculty Status questionnaire.
June 11, 1987.  2 pages.  Results from questionnaire.  4 pages.  Correspondence pertaining to Anne Commerton's acceptance of invitation to serve on panel discussion at the conference.  Also includes Ms. Commerton's vita.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_7ffb8a8f3830d9cdf207e4f118a77f96" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Article, notes</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-03</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Article written by Anne Commerton, "Building Faculty/Library Relationships:  Forging the Bond".  11typed pages.  Second typed copy with editorial notes.  Also includes handwritten copy.

Handwritten outline, "Institutional planning for OCLC Interlibrary Loan".  Includes 6 handwritten index cards.

"Women in Administration.  Director of Libraries".  1 typed page.   Not cited.  n.d.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>