<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0001</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Guide to the Henry A. Ford Papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-04-02">April 2, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Kathryn Johns-Masten.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>The Henry A. Ford Collection</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1832-01-01/1956-12-31" type="inclusive">January 1, 1832 - December 31, 1956</unitdate>
							<abstract>Personal papers of Henry A. Ford a missionary during the mid-1800s.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>5 linear feet</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="nr93032671">Ford, Henry A., 1819-1858</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitdate normal="1832-01-01/1919-12-31" type="bulk">January 1, 1832 - December 31, 1919</unitdate>
        
            
            
            
        <unitid>2011.013.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>This collection is open to the public.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Henry A. Ford was born in 1819 in Lisle, New York, son of a Presbyterian minister. His father served a church in Broome County, New York. Dr. Ford was educated at Williams College in 1842 and then studied medicine at New York University until 1850.</p>
            <p>In 1850 he married Olivia and entered service at the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions as missionary physician at Gabon, in West African country of Gabon from 1850-1854. He was accompanied by two other men, Best and Bushnell. When they arrived at Gabon they joined the Bushnell, Walker and Preston families. For the next four years Ford worked closely with the natives and learned a great deal about the region. Reverends Best and Wilson explored inland Africa during the years 1852-1853.</p>
            <p>In 1855 Ford received the appointment of Commercial Agent from the United States, and resigned as a missionary. He returned to the United States and wrote African Fever Book.   In 1856 Ford resigned his post as Commercial Agent and went back to Gabon to work as a missionary doctor. There he continued his missionary work until he died on February 3, 1858, in Gabon.  Ford is the author of "Observations on the Fevers of the Western Coast of Africa". </p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="nr93032671">Ford, Henry A., 1819-1858</persname>
        <geogname authfilenumber="2400553" source="geonames">Gabon</geogname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n85185672">Seward, Frederick William, 1830-1915</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="n85198599" source="lsch">Anderson, Rufus</persname>
            <persname>Appleton, John </persname>
            <persname>Ford, Olivia</persname>
            <persname>Goodwin, Dolli</persname>
            <persname>Walker, William</persname>
            <persname authfilenumber="no90000707" source="lcsh">Wilson, John Leighton</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85052662" source="lcsh">Gabon--History--1839-1960</subject>
            
            
            
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2008169160">American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. West Africa Mission</corpname>
        <subject authfilenumber="sh85083080" source="lcsh">Medicine--History</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010102122" source="lcsh">Missionaries, Medical--Gabon--Biography</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010113216" source="lcsh">Slave trade--Africa, West</subject>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>The Henry A. Ford Collection is part of a large number of collections and materials gathered by Charles M. Snyder, former History Professor at the State University College at Oswego.  The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, printed materials, books, ledgers, and photographs dealing mostly with Henry A. Ford, his wife Olivia and their associates.  The collection consists of correspondence and other papers relating chiefly to Henry A. Ford's missionary activities in Gabon including
parts of a daily journal from 1854 to 1856, medical notes and family letters. Also included are missionary booklets, newspaper clippings and other miscellaneous materials. Mentions the slave trade in and around West Africa.</p>
            <p>The collection has been divided into several series:  correspondence, manuscripts, printed materials, ledgers, books, photographs, and miscellaneous.  The manuscripts and correspondence have been divided into two sub-groups; original and copies.  At present it is not known who copied either the correspondence or the manuscripts.</p>
						<arrangement>
                
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions.</p>
						</userestrict>
					
        
    <otherfindaid type="eaditor_upload">
					<bibref>
						<extptr xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="5df792_Container_List_Henry_A_Ford_MS002.pdf" xlink:role="application/pdf"/>
					</bibref>
				</otherfindaid>
    <dsc>
            <c id="c_9552e693ec13c3980191d45fb30ab29a" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1832/1962">1832 - 1962</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-01 to 01-27</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p> Original correspondence precedes copied items. Both are arranged with incoming letters preceding the outgoing
ones. Dr. Henry Ford’s letters are arranged first in chronological order, followed by his wife’s correspondence. The file B 11 has been kept together due to the subject. It contains all letters dealing with the subject of Dr. Ford’s
appointment and resignation as Representative to the United States Government at Gabon, West Africa. It contains correspondence between Ford, Olivia and his colleagues and the government. File A 16 contains both
original and copied material of Dr. Charles M. Snyder’s correspondence with the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. This file also contains a list of correspondence in the American Board of Commissioners for
Foreign Missions collections on Dr. Ford and his associates.
Please see accompanying file Container_List_Henry_A_Ford_MS002.pdf for folder-level description.</p>
                    
                    
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
        <c id="c_c261a5beb77e0e1f6e15723582a365fa" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1834/1919">1834 - 1919</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-28 to 03-07</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p> Manuscripts are divided into original and copied. Dr. Ford’s journals are filed first. Due to the subject matter Dr. Ford’s personal notes on California and his medical notes have been kept together. Please see accompanying file Container_List_Henry_A_Ford_MS002.pdf for folder-level description.</p>
                    
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_ae4b2cd1c7e241307b392d67e64647f4" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Printed Material</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">1896 + n.d.</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">04-01 to 04-03</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Printed materials have been filed according to subject or type. These are religion, school, maps and newspapers.
Their connection with Dr. Ford is not yet known. The printed material is all original. Please see accompanying file Container_List_Henry_A_Ford_MS002.pdf for folder-level description.</p>
                    
                </scopecontent>
    
				<c id="c_93aafed8528252b7440b354cb44004af" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Religion</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
                <c id="c_f8e25d4f5614979bae8e1115590d0386" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>School</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
                <c id="c_9032818f748509855a4368696b3e41a4" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Maps and Newspaper Articles</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
            </c>
            <c id="c_190d9a7459025e8f59ebf86603f80e6b" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Books</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1893/1897">1893 - 1897</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box">04</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>The original owners of the books contained in the collection are unknown.</p>
                </scopecontent>
                
    
				<c id="c_b126ee7f5173aa9d2198ca90742c554a" level="item">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Webster, Daniel. The Bunker Hill Monument: Adams and Jefferson –Two Orations. [Boston, 1893]</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1893">1893</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
                <c id="c_d78233bb6e4d9d2b3369ad4976045271" level="item">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Bendir, J.R. Die Hochzeitsriese. [Boston, 1897]</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1897">1897</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
            </c>
            <c id="c_6c20962ed62361d148ab21daa98d23d9" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Ledgers</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">04-04</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>This series contains two book ledgers whose subject, origin, and dates are unknown. Their relationship to Dr. Ford is also unknown.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				<c id="c_2e7e99c7fb8c16f1538cd071e91bd5aa" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Unidentified Ledger</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
                <c id="c_0b33b56ebca0c20bd056bfc0f01dc6dc" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Unidentified Ledger</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
            </c>
            <c id="c_e6ced76a56f0372d7fa7b76ac12e5fdf" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">04-05 to 04-06</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Two folders have been established containing those materials that are unidentified and unable to be filed within a particular series.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				<c id="c_111725c4ee1982e95df6302df8f61c3e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
                <c id="c_8a6547163d687fdd1360dfbed39dff4c" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    </did>
    
				</c>
            </c>
        <c id="c_f118729a4c74c8822972b2161e18acd7" level="series">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">n.d.</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box">05</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>There are numerous photographs that are well preserved and in excellent condition. Unfortunately they are unidentified and undated.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>