<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0061</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>The Charles S. Turner papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-08-06">August 6, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Zachary Vickery.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>The Charles S. Turner papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1948/1984" type="inclusive">1948 - 1984</unitdate>
							<abstract>Papers relating the years Dr. Charles S. Turner was affiliated with Oswego State College.  Dr. Turner was college dean, acting college president, director of education and department chairman.  Papers include correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs and memorandums.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>0.25 linear feet</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitid>2005.052.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>Collection is open for research.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Dr. Charles S. Turner was born in Centralia, Missouri.  Dr.  Turner graduated from Northeastern Missouri State Teachers  College and earned a master's degree in 1936 and a doctorate in  1940.   He was associate head of the SUCO Department of Education in 1941 and was department chairman from 1948 - 1954.  He was  SUCO director of education from 1954 - 1963.    In 1960 he was  appointed dean of the college.   From 1963 -  1965 Dr. Turner was  interim president of the college.</p>
            <p> In 1968 Dr. Turner worked with Dr. Halas Jackim and Dr.  Harold Keeler in an assignment Brazil with the State University  team under a contract with the U.S. Agency for International  Development to provide a program of technical assistance to  Brazilian primary education.</p>
            <p>Dr. Turner was Immediate Past President of the Central Zone  of the New York State Teachers association, member of the New  York State Council for Administrative Leadership and the New York State Education Department's Committee of Eleven.  He was a  member of the following professional honor societies:  Blue Key,  Kappa Delta Pi and Phi Delta Kappa.  He served on the Board of  Trustees of the Oswego County Savings Bank.</p>
            <p> Dr. Turner was married to Evelyn Shoemaker and they had a  son, Charles, and a daughter, Nancy.
He retired from the college in May 1970 after 29 years as teacher and administrator.</p>
            <p>Dr. Charles S. Turner passed away in June 1984.  He resided  in Oswego, NY.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n88643793">Barnes, Mary Sheldon, 1850-1898</persname>
            <corpname>Alford, Harold D.</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5130081" source="geonames">Oswego (N.Y.)</geogname>
        <persname>Hewitt, Hazel Frances</persname>
            <persname>Hulme, Francis</persname>
            <persname>Miller, Thomas</persname>
            <persname>Piez, Richard K.</persname>
            <persname>Rice, Harvey Mitchell, 1907-1992</persname>
            <persname>Riggs, James G.</persname>
            <persname>Rogers, Dorothy</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n2012189057">Snygg, Donald, 1904-1967</persname>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="no2002005733">Swetman, Ralph Waldo, 1886-1957</persname>
            <persname>Turner, Charles</persname>
            <persname>Yager, Charles</persname>
            <subject>College presidents</subject>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>Papers relating the years Dr. Charles S. Turner was affiliated with Oswego State College.  Dr. Turner was college dean, acting college president, director of education and department chairman.  Papers include correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs and memorandums.</p>
						</scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_856d6af76725e3cd995f963335d19eec" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>President's Office</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-01</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>17 typed cover letters (carbon copies) for Annual Report from acting SUNY Oswego president, Charles S. Turner.  Recipients include:
Charles H. Foster, University Controller, SUNY
John C. Crary, Jr., Counsel, SUNY
Ruth V. Files, Associate Counsel, SUNY
J. Lawrence Murray, Executive Vice President, SUNY
Dr. Harry Porter, Provost, SUNY
Dr. David S. Price, Assistant Vice President, SUNY
Dr. John H. Slocum, Vice President for Administration, SUNY
Elwin Stevens, Assistant Vice President, SUNY
Miriam Taaffe, Associate Budgeting Analyst, SUNY
Otto J. Teegen, State University Archietect
Dr. Hermann Cooper
Dr. Samuel B. Gould, President, SUNY
Dr. Frank T. Lane, Acting Executive Dean, SUNY
Dr. Howard Dillingham, President, Ithaca College
Dr. Thomas R. Miller, President, Edinboro State College
Dr. Harvey M. Rice, President, Macalester College
Walter Phillips

Attached to a sample of the letter is a 3-page list of 50 names - possible recipients.


Formerly 1/35/120.  Folder 1- 37.  Presidents, Charles S. Turner.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_195c7240a3e50ed177a85c36ed02807a" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>President's Office</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-02</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Acknowledgments and thanks for Annual Report to Charles S. Turner, Acting President, SUNY Oswego.  29 letters.  Correspondents include:

Frank C. Moore, Chairman, Board of Trustees, SUNY
Hermann Cooper
Howard Dillingham, Ithaca College
John H. Slocum, Director of Indonesian Project, SUNY
Thomas R. Miller, President, Edinboro State College
Frank T. Lane, Acting Executive Dean, SUNY
Foster S. Brown, President, St. Lawrence University
Dorothy Barclay
Leland F. Lyons, Vice-President, New York Life Insurance Co.
Robert D. Helsby, Executive Deputy Industrial Commissioner, State of NY Dept. of Labor
C. B. Murray, Executive Secretary, NYS Teachers Retirement Board
Arthur S. Torrey
Walter M. Wilmshurst, President, St. Lawrence County National Bank
Selden T. Williams
Frank A. Augsbury, Jr.
Eugene G. Bewkes, Director of Education, Edward John Noble Foundation
Benjamin Blackford, President, State National Bank of Connecticut
G. Howard Goold, Executive Secretary, New York State Teachers Assocation
Boyd E. Golder, SUNY Board of Trustees
Florence Griffin Martin
Mrs. Nobu Masuda (on behalf of President Hamilton), Secretary to the President, 
                                                                                                                  University of Hawaii
Lester E. Rounds, Superintendent, Central School District No. 1, Suffern, NY
Edward F. Crawford, The Assembly of the State of NY
Roy G. Vilas, Cyrus J. Lawrence &amp; Sons
Walter P. Phillips
Cilfton C. Flather, Dormitory Authority of the State of NY
Foster S. Brown, President, St. Lawrence University
Eben Griffiths
Ann Kray, St. Lawrence University


Formerly 1/35/120, Folder 1-38.  Presidents, Charles S. Turner.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_ca13e8059be754a60ab071cb897483eb" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memorandums</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1963/1965">1963 - 1965</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-03</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>15 typed memorandums from Charles S. Turner, Acting President, State University College, Oswego, N.Y.   Recipients include the faculty, Oswego's traveling faculty, Oswego faculty on leave, Department Chairmen, and  Administrative Council.  Subjects include reports on status of building construction on campus, faculty promotions, events on campus and transition to Dr. James Perdue's college presidency. 

Formerly 4/41/107, Memorandum, Office of President, folder 1-25.</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_c442b144947f51e633db025e7c8107d0" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Charles S. Turner</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1948/1979">1948 - 1979</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-04</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Copies of newspaper clippings dating 1948 - 1984.  Subjects include Oswego Normal School influence in Japan, college dean appointment, acting president appointment, Brazilian education project, retirement, Oswego Board of Education, Dr. Turner's obituary, and the establishment of a scholarship in his name.

Transcript of oral history notes found in Dorothy Rogers' papers. 9 pages. (50/3/31)   Also, photocopies of Dr. Rogers' index cards.  Dr. Rogers interviewed Donald Snygg and Charles S. Turner.  No date, but premusably prior to the 1961 publication of Dr. Rogers' 
"Oswego:  Fountainhead of Teacher Education".

Photocopy of OH 148 index  (3 pages) and transcript (25 pages).  Oswego County Oral History Program interview.  Interviewee:  Dr. Charles Turner.  Interviewer:  Brian M. King.  February 26, 1979.
</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_ab0dcfd618c470a289c69ce5fe2d4433" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
						<unitdate certainty="approximate">1950s - 1960s</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-05</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>a.  Group photograph.  Dr. Charles S. Turner, third from left with 10 unidentified men. 1950's

b.  Group photograph.  Dr. Turner, standing.  2 unidentified men are seated. 1960's

c.  Group photograph.  Dr. Turner, standing, far right.  Also published in the Syracuse Herald Journal.  April 22, 1968 with the following caption:  "Brazilian Educators.  Seven Brazilian educational administrators who are studying elementary education curricula and preparation in the United States are pictured with their interpretors and their State University College at Oswego liaison officer, Dr. Charles S. Turner.  Pictured after conferring with college administrators are, seated, interpreter Terezinha Piancastelli, Cleci Mayer, Leila M. D. Franca, Anita Martelli and Neide Xavier.  Standing are Jorge E. B. C. Moraes, Father Jose Nunes, Roberto Seida, interpreter Petronio Henriquez and Dr. Turner".

d.  Group photograph.  Alvin M. Westcott, left.  Dr. Turner, right.  Unidentified man in center.  1960's

e.  Group photograph.  Dr. Turner, far left.  Francis P. Hulme, far right.  3 unidentified individuals in center.  1960's</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
            <c id="c_68963f01cd998b382faddc8bad0edb85" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1956/1969">1956 - 1969</unitdate>
					
    <container type="box-folder">01-06</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>a.  Group photograph.  Dr. Charles S. Turner, third from left with 10 unidentified men. 1950's

b.  Group photograph.  Dr. Turner, standing.  2 unidentified men are seated. 1960's

c.  Group photograph.  Dr. Turner, standing, far right.  Also published in the Syracuse Herald Journal.  April 22, 1968 with the following caption:  "Brazilian Educators.  Seven Brazilian educational administrators who are studying elementary education curricula and preparation in the United States are pictured with their interpretors and their State University College at Oswego liaison officer, Dr. Charles S. Turner.  Pictured after conferring with college administrators are, seated, interpreter Terezinha Piancastelli, Cleci Mayer, Leila M. D. Franca, Anita Martelli and Neide Xavier.  Standing are Jorge E. B. C. Moraes, Father Jose Nunes, Roberto Seida, interpreter Petronio Henriquez and Dr. Turner".

d.  Group photograph.  Alvin M. Westcott, left.  Dr. Turner, right.  Unidentified man in center.  1960's

e.  Group photograph.  Dr. Turner, far left.  Francis P. Hulme, far right.  3 unidentified individuals in center.  1960's</p>
                </scopecontent>
    
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>