<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
					<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b">
						<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-nosu">nosu0008</eadid>
						<filedesc>
							<titlestmt>
								<titleproper>Dr. Harvey M. Rice Papers</titleproper>
								<author>SUNY Oswego</author>
							</titlestmt>
							<publicationstmt>
								<date normal="2020-05-22">May 22, 2020</date>
								<publisher>State University of New York at Oswego</publisher>
								<address>
									<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
							</publicationstmt>
						</filedesc>
						<profiledesc>
							<creation>Finding aid created with EADitor by Zachary Vickery.</creation>
							<langusage>Finding aid is written in English</langusage>
						</profiledesc>
					</eadheader>
					<archdesc level="collection">
						<did>
							<unittitle>Dr. Harvey M. Rice Papers</unittitle>
							<unitdate normal="1947/1958" type="inclusive">1947 - 1958</unitdate>
							<abstract>Professional collection of Dr. Harvey M. Rice, fifth President of SUNY Oswego from 1947 to 1952. In the postwar years, the administration of Harvey M. Rice kickstarted a period of ambitious yet sustained growth that also began to turn Oswego into a residential campus. Buildings opened during the Rice administration included our first residence halls (Lonis and Moreland) and student union (in what is now Mackin). Among other noteworthy accomplishments, under Rice’s presidency, Oswego became a founding member of the SUNY system in 1948.</abstract>
							<physdesc>
								<extent>.25 linear foot box</extent>
							</physdesc>
							<langmaterial>
								<language langcode="eng">English</language>
							</langmaterial>
							<origination>
                
            <persname>Rice, Dr. Harvey M.</persname>
            </origination>
            <repository>
                <corpname>State University of New York at Oswego</corpname>
                <address>
                 	<addressline>Penfield Library</addressline>
								<addressline>7060 State Route 104</addressline>
                    <addressline>Oswego, New York 13126-3599</addressline>
                </address>
            </repository>						<unitid>2005.053.0001</unitid>
        </did>
						<accessrestrict>
							<p>Collection is open to the public.</p>
						</accessrestrict>
						<bioghist>
							<p>Harvey M. Rice was born in Pinnacle, West Virginia on January 10, 1907.  He received a B.A. in 1929 from Concord College and a M.A. from West Virginia University in 1933.  He received his Ph.D. at Ohio State University in 1938.  He taught in West Virginia high schools, Ohio State University, and New York State College for Teachers in Albany.  </p>
            <p>He was a lieutenant in the Naval Reserve during World War II.  </p>
            <p>He was a member of Pi Gamma Nx Mu and Alpha Phi Omega societies.  Also, the American Historical Association, Southern Historical Association, New York State Historical Association, New York State Teachers Association, the New York Association of Teachers College faculties, the National Council for Social Studies, and the National Educational Association.</p>
            <p>Dr. Rice was married to Dorothy Dillard and they had two sons.</p>
            <p>Oswego State Teachers College inauguration - Friday, October 24, 1947.  He served as president of the college from 1947 - 1951.</p>
						</bioghist>
						<controlaccess>
            <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n00031034">Wexler, Shlomo</persname>
            <corpname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n80038010">State University College (Oswego, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <geogname authfilenumber="5130081" source="geonames">Oswego (N.Y.)</geogname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="n79021469">Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971</persname>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh85028315" source="lcsh">College presidents</subject>
        
            
            <subject>Mary V. Lee Scholarship Fund -- New York -- Oswego</subject>
            <subject>Alumni -- New York -- Oswego</subject>
        <persname source="lcnaf" authfilenumber="nr92009022">Barnes, Earl, 1861-1935</persname>
            <persname>Carroll, Emelie Frances</persname>
            <persname>Cooper, Herman</persname>
            <persname>Cousins, Minnie C.</persname>
            <persname>Cramer, Florence</persname>
            <persname>Davis, Geo. H.</persname>
            <persname>Dunlap, Mabel</persname>
            <persname>Faust, Ralph M.</persname>
            <persname>Funnelle, Amanda P.</persname>
            <persname>Gokey, Delia</persname>
            <persname>Gould, Frank L.</persname>
            <persname>Griggs, Edward Howard</persname>
            <persname>Helsby, Robert</persname>
            <persname>Hibbert, Esther</persname>
            <persname>Hobbie, Edgar V.</persname>
            <persname>Irland, Mary C.</persname>
            <persname>Jarvis, Mabel A.</persname>
            <persname>Kimber, Jean</persname>
            <persname>Laing, Mary E.</persname>
            <persname>Lee, Mary Victoria</persname>
            <persname>Luiggi, Alice Houston</persname>
            <persname>Park, Joseph C.</persname>
            <persname>Penney, George M.</persname>
            <persname>Rich, Lorimer</persname>
            <persname>Riley, Charles E.</persname>
            <persname>Ripley, Ellor Carlisle</persname>
            <persname>Stoneroad, Rebecca</persname>
            <persname>Thompson, Uldrich</persname>
            <persname>Todd, Estelle</persname>
            <persname>Van Esseltine, Ida M.</persname>
            <persname>Wilson, Lewis A.</persname>
            <persname>Wygant, Bessie Belle</persname>
        </controlaccess>
						<scopecontent>
							<p>The papers of College President Dr. Harvey M. Rice consist of correspondence, memorandums, and copies of newspaper clippings.  Subjects include cornerstone-laying, alumni recollections, requests for information, meetings, Dr. Mary V. Lee Scholarship Fund (totalled $5,629.22 in February 1951), the clock built by Uldrick Thompson, Dr, Rebecca Stoneroad's obituary (1885 Oswego Normal School graduate), letters between Dr. Rice and Governor Thomas E. Dewey, commencements, inauguration invitations, and seal of the college.</p>
						<arrangement>
                <p>Papers were gathered from throughout Special Collections' archives.  Additional copies of newspaper clippings were added.</p>
            </arrangement>
        </scopecontent>
						<userestrict>
							<p>Please contact SUNY Oswego Archives and Special Collections for use restrictions.</p>
						</userestrict>
					<dsc>
            <c id="c_6339008b40767935c9d49bf807cf544e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947/1952">1947 - 1952</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-01</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>77 incoming and outgoing letters.  Typed and handwritten.
Correspondents include Edna H. G. Hindle, Reba Thompson (Uldrick  Thompson's daughter), Earl B. Townsend, Mary Irland, Ellor  Carlisle Ripley, Bradley C. Gray (of Boardman &amp; Gray, Albany,  NY), Francis Williams, Estelle T. Webb (nee Estelle Todd),   Mary C. Blaikie, Elizabeth Wygant, M. C. Cousins, Jean Kimber, Emma  A. Davis Browning, Emily F. Carroll, Paul E. Daly, Lillie B.  Herrick, Mrs. Frederick J. Welch, Alice Houston  Luiggi (author  of  "65 Valiants", Spec Coll LA546 .L7813), Frances L. Barry,  Mabel Dunlap, Ralph L. Blaikie, Esther T. Hibbard, Joseph  Merenda, Margaret M. Richardson, Betty Hutchings, Ida M. Van  Esselstyne, Edgar V. H. Hobbie, Veronica M. Welch, Mrs. Ellor C.  Ripley, George H. Davis, William D. Conklin, Marion R. Geekie,  Katharine Gaylord, and Rabbi Stanley Wexler.

(Formerly 1/5/120, folder 2-32.)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_6aabce1d825b5444d3f0c5f68c38c9d2" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Memoranda</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950-05/1950-06">May, 1950 - June, 1950</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-02</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>97 incoming and outgoing letters from the office of college  president Dr. Harvey M. Rice.  Typed, handwritten and telegrams.   Includes mailing lists and edited versions of invitation letter.  The invitation is to the cornerstone-laying and commencement  program.  There is a 2-page list of platform guests.  1-page list of luncheon guests.
 Invitations (4 copies).  Cornerstone Laying Ceremony for the  Dormitory and Student Union Building program.  (14 copies)

Correspondents include:  Robert H. McCarthy, Charles E. Riley,  Thomas McKay,
George Campbell, Ray C. Malvin, Charles Dehm, Hadwen Fuller,  Ralph Faust, John R. Barry, Harry Maloney, Senator Henry A. Wise, Henry D. Coville, Dr. Lewis A. Wilson, James Allen, Judson  Zimmer, Ray E. Ryan, Otto J. Teegan, Alvin C. Eurich, Clifton C.  Flather, Dr. Hermann Cooper, Lorimer Rich, Sheriff James H.  Bartlett, Maurice McGrath, Charles Foster, Paul Tierney, Ross E.  Sluyter, Everett Furman, John C. Davies, Mayor Frank L. Gould,  Earle J. Machold, William O'Brien, James H. Mackin, William E.  Bouley, Charles H. Foster, E. M. Waterbury, D. M. Tower,  Elizabeth Lee Vincent, Frank C. Moore, L. A. Wilson, George M.  Penney, E. J. Lonis, Earle J. Machold, Geroge H. Campbell,  Frederick W. Crumb, Harry W. Rockwell, Charles C. Ward, Dr.  Oliver C. Carmichael, M. Ellis Drake, J. S. Illick, Reverend John R. Scarlett, O. J. Teegen, Dr. Joseph C. Park, Reverend Patrick  J. Hartnett, Robert Helsby, James H. Mackin, W. G. O'Brien,  Thomas L. McKay, William J. Haggerty, Frank C. Moore, Geroge L.  Hinman, A. W. Schmidt, Albert E. French, Charles  J. Dehm, C. E. Sabin, R. E. Ryan, Edith Fuller, H. C. Fuller,  Arthur H. Dean, Dorothy M. Barclay, Robert H. McCarthy, Robert H. Podzemny, Vice Admiral H. F. Leary and Betty Hawley Donnelly.


(Formerly 1/5/137.  President's Office, Harvey M. Rice.   Memoranda, Cornerstone-laying. Folder 4-8).</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_95c67f6a885506be506d81877769b102" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Presidents, Dr. Harvey M. Rice</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1949/1951">1949 - 1951</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-03</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>28 incoming and outgoing typed letters.
Correspondents include:
Governor Thomas E. Dewey
          - invitation to speak at college commencement in June  1949 with response.
          - congratulatory letter from Dr. Rice in reaction to  radio show broadcast of
                         February 1949.
           - congratulations on election victory.  November 1950.
           - letters of agreement and praise to Governor Dewey.
Paul E. Lockwood,
Guy A. Graves, Jr.,
R. Burdell Bixby - letter of appreciation for arranging Governor  Dewey's visit to Oswego.
Alexander J. Woehrle - construction photographs.
James C. Hagerty.

(Fomerly 1/5/126, folder 3-4)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_437a12fe5f8ec9ca0c3e218424ff5427" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Inauguration invitation, program &amp; banquet program  </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-04</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Invitation with RSVP card and return envelope for the inauguration of Dr. Harvey Mitchell Rice as President of the Oswego State Teachers College.  Friday, October 24, 1947.  (2 copies) 5 1/4" x 8 1/4" - opened flat size.

Program of the inauguration of Harvey Mitchell Rice.  Bifold - 5 1/2 " x 8 1/2".

Inaugural Banquet program.  Banquet was held at the Pontiac Hotel, Oswego, NY.  Includes menu, speakers and music.  4 3/4" x 6" bifold.

(Formerly 1/5/32, folder 1-15)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_e9b6008010be65204a88e14cf384e09e" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Seal of college</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-05</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Interoffice Communication from Harvey M. Rice to Wadsor Scoville (Print Shop, Industrial Arts Department) concerning the University Seal with instructions on changes to be made.  A handwritten note in the right margin, "Wadsor was ill at the time tfd to Paul Hiser which he completed".  Dated October 26, 1950.

Christmas card from President and Mrs. Harvey M. Rice with the new college seal embossed in gold.  Bifold.  5 3/8" x 4 1/4".

Decal of college seal, Outer circle of writing, "Teachers . Oswego . College . Founded 1861".  Middle circle, "State University of New York  1948".  Inner circle, "Let Each Become All He Is Capable Of Being".   6 1/2" square.

(Formerly 49/1/37, folder 1-2.)</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_101a56c6d955a5e9d0bf46115cdced2c" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1959/1960">1959 - 1960</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-06</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>2 letters, one typed and one handwritten to Dr. Dorothy Rogers, Professor of Psychology, State University of New York Teachers College.

October 7, 1959.  From Dr. Harvey M. Rice, president of Macalester College, Saint Paul, Minnesota.  Response to letter from Dr. Rogers concerning the history of the university and Dr. Rogers' upcoming book.  Research.  Dr. Rice lists several additional professional positions added, building construction, Splinter Village, Thomas Miller, Campus School, Master's Degree program in Elementary Education and Industrial Arts.

February 28 [1960?].  From Dorothy Rice (Mrs. Harvey M. Rice).  Mrs. Rice is writing in response to Dr. Rogers' request for information about Dr. Rice's time as college president.  She mentions that during a weekend snowstorm, Dr. Rice drove the college snow plow to clear their driveway.

Scanned copies and photocopies of letters found in 50/3/31, Dorothy Rogers Papers.  Folder 1-17.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_43f9e59c18eee6dd2430780e3fc534a2" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947/1958">1947 - 1958</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-07</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>* Oswego Palladium-Times, Thursday, July 31, 1947.  "Dr. Harvey M. Rice Named College President.  Albanyt Educator Is Successor To Dr. R. W. Swetman".
8 pages of scanned and copied segments of the article.

*Dr. Harvey M. Rice To Be Inaugurated At Buffalo May 16".  Oswego Palladium-Times, Wednesday, April 30, 1952.
2 pages of scanned and copied segments of the article.

"College Yearbook Hoax Amusing To Dr. Harvey Rice".  June 1, 1953.  Uncited.  
Scanned copy of clipping found in 47/4/58, Box 7 of 16.  College Activities.

*Dr. Harvey M. Rice Sees Challenge In Going to St. Paul".  The Palladium-Times, Thursday, January 23, 1958.
3 pages of scanned and copied segments of the article.

Photocopies of newspaper clippings with handwritten dates.  Not cited, but likely Oswego Palladium-Times articles.  List of headlines:

"Dr. Rice HEre to Confer with Faculty Heads.  New President of State Teachers' College Discusses Fall Opening".  Handwritten date, "8-15-47".

"Dinner in Honor of College Head.  Chamber to Welcome Dr. Harvey M. Rice Wednesday Evening, Sept. 24".  Handwritten date, "9-4-47".

"Inauguration of Dr. Rice Oct. 24 to be Spectacle.   Heads of Scores of Colleges and Leading Educators to Come for Event".  Handwritten date, "9-26".

"Invite Public to Chamber Dinner.  President and Mrs. Rice will be Honored Wednesday Night".  Handwritten date, "9-20-47".  

"Warm Welcome At Dinner To College Head.  Dr. and Mrs. Harvey M. Rice Honor Guests at Chamber of Commerce Dinner Wednesday Night at Hotel Pontiac, With 150 Guests Present".  Handwritten date "9-25-47".

"Students Ready Campus for Rice Ceremony Friday".  n.d.

"Completing Plans for Inaugural of New College Head.  Faculty to Give Formal Banquet After Induction of Dr. Rice on Oct. 24".  Handwritten date "10-16-47".

"Head of College at Convocation.  Dr. Rice Formally Presented To Board of Regents".  Handwritten date "10-17-47".  

"Guests at Shady Shore"  Handwritten date "4-26-48".

"Colleges Accept Invitations for Inaugural Rites.  To Send Representatives For Induction of Dr. Harvey Rice on Friday".  Handwritten date "10-21-47".</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
            <c id="c_f4d15a33f44c94210c85c0f1089caf88" level="file">
					<did>
						<unittitle>Study Outline HIstory of the United States, 1865-1947</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					<container type="box-folder">01-08</container>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>A Study Outline History of the United States, Part Two 1865-1947.  
by Harvey M. Rice, Ph.D., Professor of History, New York State College.    
Columbus, Ohio:  Long's College Book Company, 1947.   159 pp.

Table of Contents:

The Transition from War to Peace.
Sixteen Years of Republican Control of the Federal Government.
Greater Economic Changes Occurred in the United State between 1860 and 1900 than Ever Before in History.
Changing Social, Cultural, and Nationalistic Attitudes Accompanied the Economic Revolution, 1860-1900.
The United States Becomes a World Power.
The Progressive Era, 1901-1917.
The World War and Its Aftermath, 1917-1932.
The Era of Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
The United States in the World of Today.
Index.</p>
                </scopecontent>
				</c>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
				</ead>